
   
   
      
         
            Culture Wars

            "The only freight <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> that
counts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>," says former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganaut</ENAMEX> and current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cyberguru</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Gilder</ENAMEX>,
"is the Internet with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>." Java, of course, is the computer-programming
language created by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Microsystems</ENAMEX>. It promises to revolutionize personal
computing, making obsolete the proprietary-software-running desktop and
shifting the center of gravity in the computer world toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, the
largest part of which is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web</ENAMEX>. Heady claims indeed. (What exactly
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX>? Click here to find out.) And yet, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> were called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oak</ENAMEX>--its original
name--it's a safe bet this column would never have been written.

            That's
because the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> since its introduction in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May of 1995</TIMEX> is
fundamentally one of cultural conflict, in which symbols and rhetoric have
played as important a role as underlying technological differences. The
conflict is between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>--most notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNealy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oracle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Ellison</ENAMEX>--on the one hand and ... well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
on the other. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNealy</ENAMEX> puts it, in typically blunt terms, "There's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>,
those in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX>, who live on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death Star</ENAMEX>, and the rest of us, the rebel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>." And in this struggle, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>' supposed ace in the hole,
the "tsunami that will sweep through the economy," in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilder</ENAMEX>'s words, changing
the landscape forever and probably putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slateout</ENAMEX> of business.

            Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNealy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilder</ENAMEX> certainly think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> is, in
fact, a technological transformation so important that those who do not adapt
will be left in the dust. But the intensity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>'s evangelical effort
testifies to the overwhelming importance of marketing and name recognition in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s economy. It's hard to know whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>--which in theory can run on any
platform--really is superior to proprietary systems like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX>. But even if
it is, the history of technology is littered with superior products that never
attained mass appeal. Technology does not, in that sense, speak for itself. If
it did, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> could have simply launched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> and waited for the inevitable to
occur. Whether someone announces a tidal wave is coming, after all, is
irrelevant to the wave's arrival. It crashes on the beach regardless. What we
see with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>, though, is that in the business world a tidal wave can only
exist if someone announces that it's coming.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> has
already been remarkably successful in making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> into a brand name. Oddly,
though, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX> fight for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, at the moment the real
struggle over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> is for the hearts and minds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX>. In that sense,
instead of focusing on the demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> is emphasizing its supply. It's
the "build it, and they will come" approach to business.

            
Of course, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>'s revenue from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Java</ENAMEX> comes
from licensing fees--to, among other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>--software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX>
are its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. But there's a more important reason for the emphasis
on getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to program with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>, namely that it's impossible to get
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to abandon their current operating systems if they don't think
the alternative will be around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years from now</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> has run into this
problem in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> have defected to Windows because fewer
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are writing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>-compatible versions of their programs. The
quickest way to assure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> that your alternative is viable is to show them
the plethora of programs being written for it (or, in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>, in it).
In that sense, you do have to build it before they will come.

            This
helps explain, for example, why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNealy</ENAMEX> so often cites the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400,000</NUMEX> programmers
(including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,500</NUMEX> IBMers) who are programming in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Java</ENAMEX>. It also helps explain why
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's report that most of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> start-up companies
funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doerr's Java Fund</ENAMEX> are writing their software in languages other than
Java stung so much, as did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corel</ENAMEX>'s abandonment of its plan to make its entire
Office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> of programs Java-compatible. You never hear about how many people
are actually downloading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> applets. You only hear about how many companies
are making them. (For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> view of this marketing strategy, click
.)

            There are a few things to keep in mind about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>'s strategy
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> with regard to the consumer market. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, obviously, is that
creating a critical mass of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> turning out programs that work and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want is the crucial task. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thing is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> makes, relatively
speaking, a minuscule amount of money from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java licensing</ENAMEX>. To be sure, it's
almost all pure profit, but in relation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s workstation and server
business, the revenue is nearly irrelevant. What's most relevant for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">role Java</ENAMEX> may play in eroding the desktop market and the proprietary authority
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Windows and Windows NT</ENAMEX>. Insofar as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> makes "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> is the computer"
seem true, it helps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>.

            Finally,
it's possible to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>'s approach to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX> as an embodiment of what's called
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Joy's Law</ENAMEX>, after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Joy</ENAMEX>. "Let's be truthful," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX> said. "Most
of the bright <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't work for you--no matter who you are. You need a
strategy that allows for innovation occurring elsewhere." Accordingly, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">first Sun</ENAMEX> workstations were assembled from off-the-shelf components. And while
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s most important product of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1980s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SPARCstation</ENAMEX>,
featured a high-speed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">processor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>'s own devising, throughout its history
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> has done an impressive job of keeping pace with technological change by
refusing to remain locked into one vision of the future. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, in fact, has always been its adaptability. And it has done best when
it has remained committed to open standards.

            
Now, one could argue that by insisting on
controlling the standards for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> is violating <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Joy's Law</ENAMEX>. A recent letter
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> wrote asking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to give up that control to an
international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> suggested as much. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> has made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java's</ENAMEX> specs and the
source code freely available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX>, in the hope that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>
will bloom. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy counseled</ENAMEX>, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX> works, it won't be because of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>. It'll
be because of what happens everywhere else.

            What will happen everywhere
else, though, is still uncertain. Programmers do seem to find it easier to work
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Java</ENAMEX> than in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C++</ENAMEX>, and certainly the prospect of being able to download a
spreadsheet document and read it without having to download the spreadsheet
program is enticing. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> programs are still considerably slower than those
written for a particular operating system, just as amphibious <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> are not
as good on land as mammals or as good in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>. And even the promise of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> compatibility has not been completely realized.

            That, of
course, is precisely why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX> has become such fertile ground for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cyberevangelism</ENAMEX>. To be sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Gilder</ENAMEX> needs no excuse to write
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block</ENAMEX>-that-metaphor prose like this: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Java</ENAMEX>] opens doors and shatters Windows.
It builds market cap as if by magic. It raises the sun and illumines the road
ahead to a new computer architecture. Give poor Bill a break." But the really
interesting thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilder</ENAMEX> isn't the only one using this kind
of language. Everyone speaks as if the stakes are monumental. Certainly, with
the hype surrounding Windows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95</TIMEX>, and with the introduction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>,
the relationship between cultural hegemony and business success was hinted at.
But with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> seems to be staking everything on that relationship. If you
want to know where the real culture wars are, forget the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX> and think
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redmond</ENAMEX>.

             

         
      
   
