
   
   
      
         
            Something Not to Like About <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Lee</ENAMEX>?

            The virtualization of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> proceeds apace. Inform the gods of re-engineering and
outsourcing that another convert has been won. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Lee Corp.</ENAMEX>,
the venerable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> of baked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goods</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Dean</ENAMEX> sausages, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanes</ENAMEX> T-shirts,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiwi</ENAMEX> shoe polish, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brylcreem</ENAMEX> and, yes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wonderbra</ENAMEX>, announced that it would be
divesting itself of its manufacturing operations to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> whose main
business was the marketing of its brands. Others could make the products. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> just wanted to make them popular.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX>' reaction to the announcement was immediate and positive,
unsurprising since the decision fit nicely with current thinking on the
importance of leanness and farming out production. Underlying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Lee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryan</ENAMEX>'s avid embrace of what he called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"de-verticalization</ENAMEX>" was a confused
combination of reasonable assumptions, misplaced analogies, and an overwhelming
desire to cater to Wall Street's desires--all packaged with the obligatory
rhetorical appeal to the demands of the market.

            In thinking about "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de-verticalization</ENAMEX>" the most obvious
risk is succumbing to nostalgia for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> "actually made
something." When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Ford</ENAMEX> first constructed the mammoth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">River Rouge</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Park complexes</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> were essentially built from scratch,
those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> seemed to many to be symbols of the exaltation of efficiency
over all other goals. Now, with the onset of outsourcing, globalization, and
the virtual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>, those old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> have acquired a patina of humanist
authenticity they could not have had in their own time. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assembly-line</ENAMEX> work,
after all, was seen as replacing the "real" production of skilled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nostalgia,</ENAMEX>
though, tends not to be very useful in understanding either the past or the
present. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryan</ENAMEX>'s rhetorical question--"What is a product and what makes a
product?"--is a good one. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Lee</ENAMEX>'s case, the product is not just the
physical snack <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> or shoe polish. The product is that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Lee</ENAMEX>
name attached or the shoe polish with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kiwi</ENAMEX> on the cover. And if what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Lee</ENAMEX>
can do best is make those products more desirable by making those names more
desirable, it's hard to argue that anyone would be better off with the company
pursuing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fordist</ENAMEX> dream. The idea of comparative advantage applies to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> as well as to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>.

            
For all that, however, there's a lot of smoke
being blown about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Lee</ENAMEX>'s restructuring in particular and about the supposed
evils of vertical integration in general. Press accounts invariably suggested
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Lee</ENAMEX>'s divestment of manufacturing operations would free cash
"currently tied up in low-margin activities." "Slaughtering <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hogs</ENAMEX> and running
knitting machines are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. And they have low returns,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryan</ENAMEX> said of those operations. But it only makes sense to speak of low returns
and low margins if you're making products to sell to others.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Lee</ENAMEX>
doesn't run knitting machines to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX> to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. It runs them
to supply the fabric it uses in its own products. And in theory, it should be
able to make that fabric for itself for less than it would cost to buy it from
a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, because there will be no profit margin built into the price. The
margins are higher, not lower, than they will be after the knitting machines
are sold. That was one of the crucial appeals of vertical integration: It cut
out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">middleman</ENAMEX>. It's possible, of course, that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that specializes in
making fabric will be able to do it more efficiently, so that even with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">markup Sara Lee</ENAMEX> will still come out ahead. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Lee</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-largest
textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. It seems safe to assume that, by now,
it's figured out how to knit efficiently.

            Vertical integration does mean that you need to invest
heavily in fixed assets and then keep investing in upkeep and upgrades. If you
can avoid those costs and still make the products you want at a reasonable
price, you're ahead of the game--which is why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">syrup</ENAMEX> and not bottles
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> contracts out all its manufacturing to hungry Third World <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. (If
the ethics of outsourcing abroad bother you, read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Praise of Cheap</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>.) But vertical integration also offers major
benefits. It keeps you from having to haggle with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> over prices, gives
you total supervision over quality, and allows you to control production. One
of the key impetuses for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX>' push for vertical integration, for
example, was its perennial struggle with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher Body</ENAMEX>, a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> who kept
holding up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> for price increases. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> acquired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>, the problems
stopped.

            Today, of
course, it's hard to find anyone who will defend vertical integration. But
that's essentially the product of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> factors, neither of which has anything to
do with vertical integration per se. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>'s newfound
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assurance</ENAMEX> that competition is the necessary progenitor of efficiency. Since
vertical integration replaces the market with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>--that is, the company
makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> instead of allowing others to bid for the chance to make
it--it must be a mistake, for we know the market's decisions are always right.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, more important, factor is the experience of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> auto industry
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1980s</TIMEX>. Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Big Three automakers</ENAMEX>' move toward
more outsourcing and less in-house parts production has coincided with their
return to profitability, it has seemed logical to pronounce vertical
integration an idea whose time came and went.

            
The problem with this logic is that the auto
industry abandoned vertical integration for one reason: labor costs. The Big
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> didn't give up on it because of just-in-time manufacturing or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> or a desire to focus on the brand. They did it because they
didn't want to pay union wages when they didn't have to. Outsourcing parts
production means that instead of paying a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Auto Workers</ENAMEX> member <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$45</NUMEX> an
hour in wages and benefits, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> can buy parts from a nonunion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> paying
its workers <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14</NUMEX> an hour. Even with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX>'s profit built in, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>'s
still getting a bargain. But it's hard to see how this lesson applies to
industries or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Lee</ENAMEX>--that aren't dealing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Steelworkers</ENAMEX>.

            The
really disconcerting thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bryan</ENAMEX>'s decision, though, is that it seems so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blatantly</ENAMEX> to be more about gaining the favor of Wall Street than about
improving the performance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Lee</ENAMEX> has been a terrific
bottom-line <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three years</TIMEX>, but its stock price has not risen
as sharply as its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>'. In his post-announcement interviews, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryan</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blunt</ENAMEX> about how much this bothered him. "It is increasingly obvious," he said,
"that the investment community does not like asset-intensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>."

            What the investment community does like is short-term
measures designed to boost share prices. So all the money from the sales of the
manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 billion</NUMEX>, is going to a share buyback program,
which is to say that instead of being used to create new wealth, it will simply
be redistributed from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. That's not redeploying assets
to take advantage of what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Lee</ENAMEX> does best. It's redeploying assets to boost
the stock price.

            At this point, of course,
that kind of maneuver should come as no surprise, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> now seem to
spend as much time looking at the stock ticker as at their production lines.
But there is, nonetheless, something melancholic about it, and this is where
the lament about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> actually making products has real resonance. To give
up on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">River Rouge</ENAMEX> in order to build your brand is one thing. But to give up on
River <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rouge</ENAMEX> to buy back shares? That's something else entirely.

         
      
   
