
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planet Hollywood Syndrome</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">downsizing</ENAMEX> was all the rage, Wall Street took a lot of flak for judging
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> too harshly and setting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> for corporate performance so high
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> felt their only option was to slash payrolls. Or,
alternatively, Wall Street was praised for its relentless focus on the bottom
line and its insistence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> become more productive and more
profitable. Either way, the point was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> were taskmasters, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX>
drill sergeants whipping corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> into shape. Now this was never as
true as Wall Street's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> or its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> wanted it to be, but in any
case, it is somewhat beside the point <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>. A quick glance at the Street today
makes one thing clear: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> is over.

            Take
Planet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. This is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) has been a consistent money loser
for almost its entire existence; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) has constructed an entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> around
the highly questionable proposition that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will overpay for mediocre food
in order to sit next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX> rode in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulp</ENAMEX>
Fiction ; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) is spending large sums of money to pay an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> to live
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and build relationships with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">up-and-coming stars</ENAMEX>. This is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, in other words, that should not exist, with "should" implying nothing
about the morality of the burger/movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star alliance</ENAMEX> and everything about its
business prospects.

            
Though it has seen its stock price hit
hard--justifiably--by its most recent woes, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Planet Hollywood</ENAMEX> is forging ahead
with plans to build a giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX> that will feature 564
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>-themed" <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suites</ENAMEX>. ("You can sleep in a bed just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair's</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Exorcist</ENAMEX> !") In order to build this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that it will raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 million</NUMEX> by selling
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year</TIMEX> bonds. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear, Stearns</ENAMEX>, which is handling the deal, is confident
it will be able to sell them. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ,
"I think it's going to go all right. After all, it's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $250 million</NUMEX>."

            Ah, yes.
What's a couple of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred million dollars</NUMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>?

            
Or take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX>. This isn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX> whose old
carry-on bags are all the rage with urban hipsters. This is the tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida</ENAMEX>
airline that owns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX> trademark now, which went bankrupt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> but
now looks as if it's going to be taken over by a soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> from the
former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX> has never--never, that is--turned a profit, and when
it filed for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 11</ENAMEX> it had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> in assets, including the value of
the name, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$147 million</NUMEX> in liabilities. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX> were a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, it would be
put to sleep. But the odds are that it will be resurrected and chew up some
more capital.

            You can
tell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of similar stories about the real estate market, where a huge
construction boom in suburban office space continues, even though no one seems
to know how the space will be filled in an economy growing as moderately as
after a mild slump <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>, is booming again. We seem to have reached the
point where any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that wants to go public can, even if it has never
reported anything remotely resembling earnings. And if it's an Internet company
going public, fuhgeddaboutit. Go ahead and buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferrari</ENAMEX>.

            
As 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> has
pointed out, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> now offers the curious spectacle of capitalism with
too much capital. But the same spectacle seems to be on display throughout the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Certainly since the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economies collapsed, enormous amounts of
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> have poured into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, even as domestic capital
has been more likely to stay at home. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are not saving significantly
more. But the flood of money into mutual funds--where all the money is turned
into investment capital, as opposed to savings accounts that require a
percentage to be held in bank <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">reserves</ENAMEX>--has given fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> more money than
they know what to do with. With the market on a seemingly unstoppable rise,
fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> feel the need to stay fully invested, which means that
eventually, even struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will come back into favor. There's just
too much money out there for them not to.

            There
are, though, a couple of problems with this picture. First, the concept of "too
much capital" is a kind of macroeconomic impossibility. If the supply of
capital truly exceeds demand, the rate of return will drop until the supply
shrinks. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the idea that too much capital can be a bad thing makes little
sense in a world where investment is the key to economic growth. So the image
of lovelorn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> chasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">standoffish borrowers</ENAMEX> can't really be right, at
least not for the economy as a whole. And, in fact, there is no shortage of
would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrowers</ENAMEX>. Consumer debt is nearing all-time highs. The junk bond
market is booming, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> issuing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$109 billion</NUMEX> in junk bonds <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.
In the subprime loan market, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pay interest rates of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 20 percent</NUMEX>
and risk their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> to get access to capital. And although government bond
rates have dropped over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>, the real interest rate is still
high <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> relative to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. There is a demand, then, to match the supply.
The only problem is that this may not be such a good thing.

            
What an economy really wants, after all, is not
more investment per se but better investment. It wants capital to flow to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that will create value--not in the form of a rising stock price but
in the form of more goods for less cost, more jobs, and rising wages--by
enhancing productivity. In the absence of an omniscient central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planner</ENAMEX>,
though, the way to get better investment is to get more investment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planet</ENAMEX>
Hollywoods are the price we pay for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillettes</ENAMEX>.

            In the short term, though,
it's possible to get too many <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planet Hollywoods</ENAMEX> and not enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Intels</ENAMEX>. This is
why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> continued to pump money into overbuilt <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast Asian</ENAMEX> real
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">estate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> "chaebols," and why <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> of all the junk bonds issued in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1980s</TIMEX> ended up defaulting. Markets get caught in self-perpetuating
cycles of undue optimism and hysterical panic. The consequences are never
pretty, which is what's so troubling about the ever rising stock market, the
booming junk-bond market, and the real estate boom.

            This is an economy, after
all, that is doing well but not great, that is still growing slowly in
historical terms, and that has still not shown significant evidence of a real
boom in productivity (with the notable exception of the manufacturing sector).
Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are acting not simply as if there were only sunny skies ahead but
also as if every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, every investment, were going to enjoy the warmth of
the sun. And this means that capital is not playing its necessary disciplining
role. You can't fuel real economic growth with indiscriminate credit. You can
only fuel it with well-allocated, long-term investment. Unfortunately, that's a
principle that doesn't seem to be at work in a capital market that just can't
say no.

         
      
   
