
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian About-Face</ENAMEX>

            It's good, I suppose, always
to be right. It's so good, in fact, that it's worth revising your past
positions when they suddenly look wrong. The key to success in this endeavor,
of course, is never to let on that you've changed your mind at all. For an
object lesson in how to do this, look no further than what's happened to our
understanding of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> in light of its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX> of economic chaos. The
meaning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> crisis has been self-evident to those who believe that the
free market can do no wrong. The collapse of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> stock markets and banking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> has proven that industrial policy doesn't work, that protectionism is a
route to disaster, and state control of credit allocation encourages
inefficiency and corruption. In other words, what's happened in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> is proof
that until the rest of the world becomes more like us, it's bound to
struggle.

            Thus,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Craig Roberts</ENAMEX> argues in a recent issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> that
"industrial policy fostered appalling investment, banking, and monetary
practices," and that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s woes prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> was right and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> were wrong. (Of course, everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> writes purports to show that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was right and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> were wrong.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economist</ENAMEX> holds up
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> as an example of the inevitable failure of any economy bossed by "civil
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">servants</ENAMEX>," while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudi Dornbusch</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>'s problems as a
crisis of "statism." The op-ed pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ,
meanwhile, have wallowed in triumphalist glee, with free-marketeers dancing
happily on the grave of what used to be called "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> miracle."

            Even on its own terms this analysis is startlingly cynical.
After all, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>--which is to say the market--saw
nothing but blue skies ahead for these economies. They showed their faith by
shoving billions into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> equity markets, while foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> contentedly
handed out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> in loans. If <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s problems are systemic and the result of
these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>' statist policies, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>' failure to recognize this
earlier is a strike against the market, not for it. Still more perverse
is that, even as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free-marketeers</ENAMEX> conclude that history is rendering its
verdict on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> model of capitalism, they seem to forget that until the
recent crisis they themselves took great pains to deny that such a model
existed. Until <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> fell apart, supply-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siders</ENAMEX> happily held it up as proof that
the only recipe for economic growth was open markets and nonintervention on the
part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economies weren't like those feeble <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX>
economies, with their high tariffs, easy credit, and corruption. Instead, they
were models of macroeconomic stability, market-driven pricing, and disciplined
borrowing. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX> released its index of economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> now struggling qualified as "free."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> succeeded, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> explained at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the start of this decade</TIMEX>,
because they had among "the least price-distorting regimes in the world."
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> growth prevailed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief economist</ENAMEX> of the World
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Asian</ENAMEX> desk authored a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> book downplaying the presence of
industrial policy in the region, while a concluded that "rapid growth in each
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> was primarily due to the application of a set of common,
market-friendly economic policies." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just last year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> called the East
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economies "highly market oriented, with a long period of relatively free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> ... and limited distortions from government regulations," while arguing
that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> did not rely on industrial policy at all. The
market-friendly interpretation of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s success was intended to counter the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thesis</ENAMEX>--offered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protectionists</ENAMEX>, and by certain
neo-institutionalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>--that trade barriers, subsidized credit, and
strong state support for export-driven industries had been essential to the
development of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economies.

            
Up till now, everyone--right and left--has been
anxious to claim the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> example for their own for one reason: Since World
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War II</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX> are the only examples of successful, sustained
development over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many decades</TIMEX>. (Well, OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mauritius</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Botswana</ENAMEX> have done
well, too.) If they achieved that success through targeted subsidies and
controlled credit, that certainly puts a crimp in free-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX>' plans
for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. Alternatively, if they've done so through free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> and low government spending, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Friedman</ENAMEX> can applaud.

            That
certain of these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>--most notably <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>--relied
heavily on market-distorting devices is indisputable. That these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> grew
at historically rapid rates for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than two decades</TIMEX> is also indisputable. But
the conclusion that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> led to the other is not indisputable. It may very
well be wrong. Similarly, while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> have been remarkably
open, free-market <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, the fact that this is responsible for their rapid
growth is hardly indisputable, either.

            The problem is that, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alwyn Young</ENAMEX> has pointed
out (in a thesis popularized by 
                  Slate
               's own <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>), while
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s growth rates in total production have been incredibly high, its growth
rates in worker productivity have, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> aside, been surprisingly low. In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">postwar years</TIMEX>, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX> have enjoyed enormously high savings rates,
rapid increases in the percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> participating in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX>,
excellent education, and enormous investments in physical capital. In other
words, they've done a brilliant job of mobilizing resources, but not a
brilliant job of mobilizing resources efficiently. But you can mobilize
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> under very different regimes, and just how the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> tigers did it
turns out to be hard to answer within the confines of an
industrial-policy-vs.-free-market argument. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for some examples of the
complexity.)

            What's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">appalling</ENAMEX> is not that supply-siders once argued that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX> were proof of
the free market's virtues. There was a reasonable--if hardly decisive--case to
be made for that point. What's appalling is rather that now that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>
have stumbled, they have disowned them so utterly. The irony is that, if
anything, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> is much more integrated into the global marketplace <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> than
it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> or even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX>. After all, it was foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX>, and
not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, who lent all those now-floundering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five years</TIMEX>. (For more on that point click .)

            
But what <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s newfound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> once loved,
they now despise. One can only imagine the "heads I win, tails you lose"
contortions these thinkers would have offered for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s woes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>. And
while the comparison may be a bit facile, it helps illuminate the crucial point
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> revisionist interpretations of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, which is that they fail to recognize
that one can believe in the virtues of the market while still understanding
that markets sometimes fail.

         
      
   
