
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Monopoly</ENAMEX>?

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">occasional Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> based on the premise that who wins in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is often determined by how the issue is framed. The author neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endorses</ENAMEX> nor condemns any of the views expressed, however laudatory or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repellent</ENAMEX>.
            

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>, a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> will resume hearing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s antitrust case
against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> of violating a consent decree by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">leveraging Windows</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>-percent share of the computer-operating-system market to
corner the browser market with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Internet Explorer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> says it's
"integrating" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX> into Windows. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> says that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> products are separate and
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is illegally forcing computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> to load their machines with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX>--first by threatening to deny them Windows, then by artificially repackaging
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> programs as one. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> faces similar charges from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>,
consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX>, and possibly several state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys general</ENAMEX>.
The press has turned against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, even comparing it to the tobacco
industry. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is so shrewd and powerful, why isn't it winning this
public-relations game? Because it's overplaying tactics and neglecting strategy
on several fronts:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">1 Power</ENAMEX> vs. beneficence. Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> too powerful?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, answers ideology with economic practicality,
touting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s prosperity and taking as much credit as he can. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
isn't committing the sins <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX> are supposed to commit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> argues.
Windows is cheap, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX> is free. Lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are selling software, their
products are rapidly improving, and prices are falling. Thanks to high-tech
capitalism, the economy is booming.

            This
change of subject has earned some good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> stories have quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> vouching for the quality and low price of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> products.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strategy Has Given Users Some Benefits</ENAMEX>," proclaimed a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times headline over a laudatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> story. But whereas
changing the subject usually works in politics, it's not as effective in legal
fights. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s proceedings keep the media spotlight on the question of
monopoly.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Big government</ENAMEX> vs. big business. A
well-known law of politics says that if the debate is about you, you'll lose.
For that reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> says the antitrust case is about governmental power.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> portrays <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Brother</ENAMEX> as the principal threat not just to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>,
but to free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX>, consumer choice, and prosperity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> calls the choice
between private and government control of software "the question at the center"
of the case. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Myhrvold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s chief technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, conjures up
the specter of a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Bureau of Operating Systems</ENAMEX>." Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>
have flocked to this argument.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DOJ</ENAMEX> antitrust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> offers the standard liberal rejoinder: Big business, too, can threaten
consumer choice, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> capable of stopping it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> has repeatedly described <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> as the enemy of "choice," declaring,
"No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX> should be denied the browser of their choice because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
made their computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX> an offer they couldn't refuse."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> will have a hard time
persuading the public that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is coercive, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> exerts
its market-share leverage subtly: It distributes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX> free, negotiates with
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to make IE the default browser on their machines, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">links Windows</ENAMEX> to software and services it wants to promote. These methods allow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> to argue that computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> can add other browsers (such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>'s popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Navigator</ENAMEX>) and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> remain free to switch to them.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
Lessig, the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> enlisted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to sort out the case, is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on subtle methods by which software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> can steer consumer
choices. He has argued that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cyberindustry</ENAMEX>'s hidden "tyranny of code" can be
more pernicious than the clumsy, overreaching <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. These views bode ill for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">3</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Public</ENAMEX> vs. private interest. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
started with the ideological advantage of not being the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> started
with the ethical advantage of not being a private interest. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> appears
to have evened the score by persuading the press to link <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX>, and
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, held hearings on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s alleged misdeeds, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> noted that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novell</ENAMEX>, a rival of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, is a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times observed that at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX>'s anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> conference, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX> were
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> representing them." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> reported that
Netscape was "using" the antitrust case in a marketing campaign.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
has used the image of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>' political influence to portray its own
lobbying as "self-defense." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesmen</ENAMEX> simultaneously profess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
"reluctance" at being forced to stoop to lobbying and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) chagrin at having done
so "belatedly." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> have bought both these spins, alternately praising
and criticizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s virginity, but accepting it as a given. (For

                  Slate
               's view, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s "Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>.")

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Browser</ENAMEX> market vs. operating-system
market. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of the OS
market. Conversely, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 40 percent</NUMEX> of
the browser market, compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX>. On this basis,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick) Rule</ENAMEX>, who has been retained to represent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accuses DOJ</ENAMEX> of suing "a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with a smaller share of sales in order to
protect the ability of its dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> to secure an exclusive." (For
Rule's views on the case see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Case Against the Case Against Microsoft</ENAMEX>" in

                  Slate
               .) But distinguishing between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> markets undermines
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s thesis that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX> and Windows are "integrated."

             

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">5 Technology</ENAMEX> vs. marketing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> says its
linkage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX> to Windows yields "improved features and functionality." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> says
the linkage is a marketing ploy, not a technical necessity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rule</ENAMEX> concedes that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> will gravitate toward the most widely disseminated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standard</ENAMEX>, regardless of whether it is technically the best." Therefore,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> owes its success to "the good fortune of being the pre-eminent
operating system on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> PCs." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows-IE</ENAMEX> marriage the latest
"incremental step" in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s "long history" of absorbing "separate
offerings" (e.g., disk compression and networking) into Windows.

            Critics
interpret this kind of standardization and integration, for all their benefits
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, as triumphs of marketing, not technology. On this view, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
buys out potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> or starves them to death by stealing their
innovations and adding them to Windows. It doesn't create breakthroughs; it
absorbs them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s recent buyouts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WebTV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hotmail</ENAMEX>, the leading
purveyors of TV Internet service and free e-mail, exacerbate this complaint. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> persuades the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows-IE</ENAMEX> integration is just one in a series of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> marketing schemes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> could lose an image war bigger than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> battle.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Platform</ENAMEX> vs. tollbooth. Much of the
debate turns on a contest of metaphors. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> calls Windows a "stable," "open,
integrated platform" that gives software and hardware <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innovators</ENAMEX> "the certainty
they need to build products." The metaphor emphasizes stability's virtues
(facilitating "openness" and "innovation") over its drawbacks (stifling
competition). By sundering IE from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> suggests, the government
would fracture the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> and pull down the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of cards.
Pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> programmers dramatized this point by staging a press conference
at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>, crediting their livelihoods and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s "small business
development" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> platform. The press ate it up.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> counter with less flattering analogies. Citing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
memo, they accuse the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of plotting to parlay its primacy into a
"vig"--i.e., a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookie</ENAMEX>'s percentage--on Internet transactions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX> and others
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foresee Microsoft</ENAMEX> "tollbooths" at entry ramps to the information superhighway.
(For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX>'s views see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Microsoft Menace</ENAMEX>" in 
                  Slate
               .) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> replies that
Windows PCs enable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> to reach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> over the
Internet, cutting out the fee-charging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">middlemen</ENAMEX> who control traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>.
To which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> rejoin: Why not cut out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, too?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desktop</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oracle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netscape</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novell</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>--is developing machines and
a universal programming language (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>) based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, an alternative
platform to the desktop. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> wants to make sure that the desktop (where
Windows holds sway) becomes the platform for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, not the other way
around. That's why network <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> have accused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> of tinkering with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> to frustrate collaboration between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Windows</ENAMEX>-based and non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Windows</ENAMEX>-based
computers. It's also why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is marketing a browser, folding it into
Windows, and battling the antitrust suit. "While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> is
claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX> should not include browsing capabilities," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>
protests, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> are busy incorporating basic operating
system services ... into their browsers."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danger</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX>. Faced with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> challenges--the
antitrust case and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>-paradigm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is pitting the
latter against the former. If the network paradigm is as mature and superior as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> claim, asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, how can the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> deem <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> an
entrenched monopoly? In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> argues, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">paradigm</NUMEX> assault makes
incorporation of a browser "critical for Windows to stay competitive." Windows
must eat the browser market or be eaten.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Technicalities</ENAMEX> vs. tone. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">argumentativeness</ENAMEX> has disastrously overshadowed its arguments. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have
sought the removal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lessig</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>. They've derided a government brief
as proof that "poorly informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have no vocation for software design."
When instructed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to give computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> an alternative to
packaging IE with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> made the alternatives unworkable or
undesirable. This conduct has embarrassed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> and
triggered an avalanche of editorials calling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> rich, ruthless, sneaky,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">petty</ENAMEX>, arrogant, and stubborn.

            Some reports indicate that
this tone-deaf performance has already irked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and has convinced him to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enjoin Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s marketing practices on the grounds that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can't be
trusted to regulate itself. Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> wins the courtroom battle, it
risks losing the war for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>' hearts and minds. The rap on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX> has
always been that they're technically brilliant but socially inept. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
behavior has done little to prove otherwise.

         
      
   
