
   
   
      
         
            Dark <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Days at</ENAMEX> Sunbeam

            Lifeblood hemorrhaging.
Limbs lopped off. A general sense that everything is more than just a little
bit out of control. All in all, not an experience you'd want to go through. But
then, this is what happens when you have an accident with a chainsaw.

            In this
case, the "chainsaw" is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Dunlap</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> and the corporate executive
who has become legendary for his rapid restructuring of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> seemingly
plagued by slow sales, high overhead, and a lagging stock price. The accident
is the sudden collapse of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX>'s heretofore much praised turnaround effort at
Sunbeam, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that always had one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most enduring brand names
but, before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX>, had very little idea of what to do with it.

            
Dunlap, of course, knew. He shut down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX>'s manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, including almost all its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>;
outsourced a higher percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s production; cleaned up
distribution channels; refocused product lines around higher quality items;
fired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. Then he negotiated a sweet contract extension for
himself that included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.75 million</NUMEX> stock options. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> did all this to great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">acclaim</ENAMEX>, at least from Wall Street. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX>'s stock price tripled immediately
after the announcement of his arrival, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following months</TIMEX> it rose
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">another 50 percent</NUMEX>. In his inimitable fashion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX> spoke joyfully of the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> in shareholder wealth he had created.

            Dunlap
is famous for his short attention span. He's described himself as happiest in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> year of a turnaround effort, when urgent decisions have to be made
and implemented and results are immediately visible. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>, though,
he's bored and ready for a new challenge. So everyone expected that once the
restructuring was done at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam, Dunlap</ENAMEX> would either leave or have Sunbeam
acquire another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> upon which he could work his magic. The smart money was
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX>'s departure, probably after selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>, as he
did with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scott Paper</ENAMEX>. But the smart money was wrong--which doesn't mean it
wasn't smart. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> decided to stay. And in part it seems he made that
decision precisely because he wanted to show his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX> (of which

                  Slate
                has been one--click here for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chainsaw Al</ENAMEX>) that he could build for the future as well
as salvage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> from the past.

            
The rap on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX>, after all, was not simply
that he's ruthless in job cutting and cavalier about the relationship between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in which they do business, but also that he's
a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> trick pony. Dunlap may be able to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> put their short-term
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in order, the argument went, but he can't actually turn a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> into a viable long-term enterprise--which may explain why he always
seems to focus on selling a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> after it's been cleaned up. And while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> seems to harbor no trace of self-doubt, the impulse to quiet these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> must have been fairly strong.

            And,
for a time, it looked as if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> actually was the marvelous turnaround story
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX> tells about all his restructuring efforts. It wasn't so much the
rise in the stock price that was impressive, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX>'s presence alone
established the kind of expectations that automatically draw money into a
stock. Instead, it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s turn to profitability after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> upon
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> of losses, coupled with a planned and well-executed expansion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX>'s household product lines and a pretty convincing reinvigoration of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s brand name. It appeared that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> might really be able to
manage.

            
But appearances were wrong. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> has now
announced twice in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> that its sales and profit numbers in the latest
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> will be well below Wall Street's expectations. Also, that sales will
actually be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> below what they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>, which is to say that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is shrinking, not growing. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> has acquired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
consumer products <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">First Alert</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Signature Brands</ENAMEX>--and
the costs of those acquisitions are going to be greater than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> had
previously forecast, even as the logic behind those acquisitions now looks
increasingly iffy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX>'s stock price has fallen by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 40</NUMEX>
percent.

            You
might say, then, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Dunlap</ENAMEX> has now destroyed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.8 billion</NUMEX> in shareholder
wealth. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX>'s stock is just about where it was in the days
immediately following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX>'s appointment as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>. Dunlap, though, insists that
the market has overreacted to the bad news and is missing the real story.
Apparently, the market is an excellent barometer when it treats <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dunlap</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> and
woefully inaccurate when it does not.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poetic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> is always satisfying. But the
real question is what, actually, is wrong with the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX> does business? It
isn't the job cutting per se. For the sake of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> should be adding value with their labor, and they don't get to do that
if there's no market for what they're making. And while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> may have cut too
close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> is not like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Pacific</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX>, where excessive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">downsizing</ENAMEX> clearly hurt their ability to function.

            Still,
the reliance on job cutting is symptomatic of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX>'s real problem, which is
the confusion between profits and growth. For a turnaround to be real, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has to become not merely profitable but also positioned for steady
growth. In the short term, killing slow-moving products, shuttering <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>,
and eliminating layers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> can cut costs so dramatically as to make a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> profitable even if its sales shrink. But making that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> grow in
the future is a very different task.

            
And, in the long term, when there is nothing
left to cut, the only way to increase profits is to increase sales. In this
respect, it's striking that in the press release announcing the latest turmoil,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> said, "I want to stress that getting the right cost structure is only
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step in the process of building a powerful global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>." The fact
that he felt the need to say this suggests he still doesn't fully believe
it.

            Of course, in some sense
Dunlap must think that growth is important, because otherwise he wouldn't have
spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">First Alert and Signature Brands</ENAMEX>.
But here again, it's telling that when he thinks about the long-term
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sustainability of Sunbeam</ENAMEX>, he thinks automatically about acquiring other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Acquisitions are not necessarily mistakes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Electric</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX>, among others, have done a brilliant job of using acquisitions
to strengthen both themselves and the acquired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. But shuffling dollars
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> column to another is not the same as creating wealth. It's not the
same as improving productivity. It's not the same as adding real value to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. And there's just not much evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX> knows how to do any of
those. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, it's not that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> is a short-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>. It's that even
as a long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>, he's thinking about the wrong things.

         
      
   
