
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Drop</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> and early
1980s, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinkers</ENAMEX> were fond of using the phrase "late capitalism" to
describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy. With its intimations of the system's decadence
and inevitable disappearance, the label sounded both descriptive--these were
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of stagflation, skyrocketing interest rates, and high
unemployment--and inspiring. At least if you were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX>.

            You don't
hear much about "late capitalism" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, except insofar as it has morphed,
oddly, into the techno-utopianism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>. But what we should
start hearing about more and more is our own "late bull market," which seems
somehow simultaneously frothy and exhausted. There's no better sign of this
than the occasional fits of anxiety that have begun to grip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> who for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> have dismissed talk of overvaluation as irrelevant. As a case in
point, consider the recent travails of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>.

            To all outward appearances, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> remains among the
strongest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> on the planet. It reported earnings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month ago</TIMEX> that
were typically impressive, with earnings up sharply and news of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-for-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
stock split. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Animal Kingdom</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX> opened this
month to phenomenal business, and advance buzz on the latest animated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film, Mulan</ENAMEX> , has been very good. Mystery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Hiaasen</ENAMEX> did come
out with a short book blasting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> for, well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disneyfying</ENAMEX> the world, but if
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> goes by without an article or book on that subject, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX>
knows he's doing something wrong. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has even got credit for an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX>-winning film since its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> released <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Will</ENAMEX>
Hunting .

            There were
a few question marks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s results in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last quarter</TIMEX>, arising
mainly from the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s sales grew hardly at all. But for the first
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> after the earnings report came out, all the good news drove the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock to a new all-time high. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, after all, is everything a
modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is supposed to be: media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>, high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of an
immensely powerful brand, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> at outsourcing. What could go wrong?

            
Well, the interesting thing is that nothing has
gone wrong, and yet in the course of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s stock fell <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX>,
a fairly hefty tumble for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with a market cap of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$79 billion</NUMEX>. What
happened testifies partly to the continued power of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> on Wall
Street but also to the fact that at these heights, it's very easy to become
suddenly--and often justifiably--afraid. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wile E. Coyote</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are
able to skate across the air until they look down, at which point <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> is
often fast and hard.

            That
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">analogy</ENAMEX> is inexact, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> have been more than willing to give many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> the benefit of the doubt, but those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> tend to be either
Internet stocks, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>-drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, or merger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. The punishment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s stock received, on the other hand, shows that when the Street changes
its mind, even blue chips are not immune.

            In essence, what happened was that a few brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>
downgraded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s stock from "buy" to "accumulate" or to "hold" or to "sell
immediately." (Actually, there is no "sell immediately" recommendation, though
common wisdom on the Street is that you should do so if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> begin falling
past your windows.) Raising concerns about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s broadcasting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> reduced their earnings estimates while also suggesting that at these
prices, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s stock might be overvalued. Considering that we live in a time
when stock-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gurus</ENAMEX> produce brand new measures of valuation on the
spot--"See, you should buy this, because although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has no earnings,
it's trading at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just 80</NUMEX> times the cost of the phone calls its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> make in
any <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month</TIMEX>"--the suggestion that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> might actually be
overvalued was enough to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> streaming to the doors.

            Since the
concerns the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> raised were not new, you might see this as evidence that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are now in the same fragile frame of mind as little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who have
stayed up way past their bedtimes. But these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> were also real. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>--which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> owns--together paid an incredible <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9.2 billion</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>
for the exclusive rights to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sunday Night Football</ENAMEX>, and they may not
have the ratings to justify that. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> is suffering from a declining revenue
base, mainly because its prime-time ratings are beyond dismal. True, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most profitable TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent months</TIMEX> has started
pressuring cable systems to increase the fees they pay for the right to carry
it. Still, recouping <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>--the cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> contract--may
be more than even it can pull off.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> is certainly doing its best to put a
smiling face on its recent woes. It's been running full-page ads in the Wall
Street Journal saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> offers "no pandering" and "upscale
momentum." While pandering is bad, I guess, it's hard to resist the thought
that describing yourself as "upscale" means that you're not. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s "What a
difference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> makes" ad, meanwhile, argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> is the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> among
the coveted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18-49</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, if you leave out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. This is sort of like
saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pacers</ENAMEX> are the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>, if you leave out
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottie Pippen</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisner</ENAMEX>, who's actually underrated as a pop-culture maven (he was
responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Days and Welcome Back</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kotter</ENAMEX> ), insists
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s downturn is cyclical and that it will soon return to life. But it's
interesting to remember that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisner</ENAMEX> was actually hesitant to buy a TV network
and that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Katzenberg</ENAMEX> who pushed hard for such an acquisition,
though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> only bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cap Cities/ABC</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katzenberg</ENAMEX> had left. With
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s brand name perhaps stronger than ever--its theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>,
and merchandising machine booming--the fact that the part of the company
unconnected from that brand is struggling must make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisner</ENAMEX> wonder whether this
was an investment that needed to be made.

            Ultimately, what's most important about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s struggle
to turn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> around is how impressive it makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s management of its
own franchise look. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> of almost uninterrupted superlative
performance--which not even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katzenberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX> contretemps could
seriously slow down--it's almost impossible to remember how close <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> was to
being dismantled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX>. The brand that we now think of as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">irresistible</ENAMEX> seemed tired and used up, and this now seamlessly efficient
company lacked even a formal business model before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>. A lot of what has
happened at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>--better advertising, smarter merchandising, revitalizing the
animation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>--looks obvious in retrospect. But it was only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisner</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> that a brand has to be updated and nurtured if it's to flourish
that made those decisions so obvious.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s problems, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>,
will be much harder to solve, if only because they have much to do with network
television as a whole and not just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> in particular. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s long-term
future seems about as guaranteed as that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Electric</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX>' recent flight from quality, as you might call it, was not completely
irrational. But it tells us more about this edgy and anxious market than it
does about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>. In a market where <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> seems like the long term, the
fact that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years from now</TIMEX> the mouse will still be roaring somehow just
doesn't really matter.

         
      
   
