
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers 1</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">NOW</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 4</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX>" assembled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, to praise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>,
repent their sins, and pledge to take charge of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>.
Nearby, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Organization for Women</ENAMEX> chanted: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Racist</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sexist</ENAMEX>, anti-gay! Born-again bigots, go away!" Usually, the media sympathize
with this particular criticism of conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>, but not this time.
How did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> succeed where the religious right has often failed?
By framing old stereotypes in new ways.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> vs.
responsibility. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX>'s chief rap on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> is that it tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to take
"leadership" at home. This connotes unequal power, a no-no among rights-based
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> plays down the power
aspect and plays up the opposite aspect: male responsibility for domestic
tasks. This drives a wedge between communitarian and rights-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">isolating NOW</ENAMEX> from its usual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> also
argues that the "biblical" (as opposed to "secular") meaning of leadership
is service and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>, while instructing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> to submit to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">husbands</ENAMEX>, also instructs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> to submit to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>. This has led to the
bizarre spectacle of scriptural debates on TV chat shows, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesmen</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Ireland</ENAMEX> argue chapter and verse. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> wins not by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">refuting Ireland</ENAMEX>'s exegesis but by displaying subtlety in its own--by arguing,
for example, that a true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> recognizes his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s talents and takes the
initiative to help them flourish. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> comes away persuaded that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> is
much more open-minded than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>. Conversely, by showing no
flexibility, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> comes across as though she's against the missionary
position.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Misogyny</ENAMEX> vs. masculinity. Critics
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accuse PK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of crusading against "the feminization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." True, they
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">goad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to action by accusing them of acting like sissies. But they also teach
that masculinity lies in moral strength, not in money, power, or stoicism. They
preach vulnerability, humility, contrition, intimacy, sharing, weeping,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tenderness</ENAMEX>, and surrender. They deride "machismo." Humility, they say, includes
letting your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> pay the bills if God gave her better math skills than you and
letting her pursue the professional dreams God planted in her. Which explains
why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Koppel</ENAMEX> has compared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McCartney</ENAMEX>, a former football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>,
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Alda</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Segregation</ENAMEX> vs. self-help. As with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Million Man March two</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> have assailed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX>'s "exclusion" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. But McCartney
frustrates this criticism by differing from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways. He has made
racial inclusion a central project of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX>, and he has stipulated that gender
segregation must be a temporary means toward integrating and reconciling the
sexes.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCartney</ENAMEX>'s rationale for temporary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">segregation</ENAMEX> draws heavily on liberal themes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>, he argues, have been
culturally uprooted and stripped of their identity. They need space to protect
and repair themselves. This argument combines the religious right's standard
defensive posture (we're not imposing our values; we're just protecting them
from assault) with liberal gender protectionism (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> should be educated
separately from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> so as to free them from cultural pressure) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">multiculturalism</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> must preserve their unique masculine culture).

            According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCartney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> dominate church attendance and have their own
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s only refuge. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> won't open up
and cry in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s presence because it's not "safe." They need the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> to assure them of their masculinity so that they can break down without
feeling like sissies. This message has induced some liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> to call the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers pathetic</ENAMEX>, thereby undermining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX>'s portrayal of them as
dangerous bullies.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Materialism</ENAMEX> vs. idealism. In politics,
practical benefits usually beat principle. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> feel less oppressed by
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>' pretensions to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> than by the work that falls to them
because of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>' neglect. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have won over many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and
assuaged feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> by addressing the latter problem. "Be <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to the
dryer," they tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. "Turn off the television and empty the dishwasher." They
instruct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> to spend more time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and to forswear adultery,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abandonment</ENAMEX>, and domestic abuse. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> routinely embarrasses feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> by
producing testimony from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who love the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> has transformed their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>' behavior.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Condemnation</ENAMEX> vs. compassion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> make much ado of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX>'s injunctions
against abortion and homosexuality. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> has lambasted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCartney</ENAMEX> for
speaking at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Rescue</ENAMEX> rallies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and for promoting a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
ballot measure that would have restricted laws protecting gay rights. Usually,
the media view these positions as mean, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> take a softer approach.
They never speak of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> as an organized threat. And when asked about
homosexuality, they always subsume it in a general rule against extramarital
sex.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reproach</ENAMEX> vs. repentance. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> have criticized moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who blame <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> for untimely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pregnancies</ENAMEX> and abortions. Now along comes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> to blame <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Instead of
advocating legislation against abortion, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> instructs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to stop having sex
outside marriage and to stop pressuring their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> and girlfriends to have
abortions. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who construe this as an attack on abortion rights, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> paraphrase the liberal slogan that NOW famously applied to abortion:
"If you don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX>, don't marry <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> talk far less about abortion and homosexuality than their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> do. They're more interested in spiritual
self-flagellation and renewal. Their ventures into social topics focus on
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, domestic violence, adultery, divorce, illegitimacy, crime, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> decay.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puppets</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX> accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> of
being too friendly with the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> of the religious right: media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> (who gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> its initial seed money and promotes it on his radio
network), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX> (who promotes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> on television), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> (who
heads the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX>-backed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research Council</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> denies engaging in
politics with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> is acting as their
"religious-right marketing tool."

            Far from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protecting PK</ENAMEX>'s reputation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> keep trying to get inside its blouse. PK
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Phillips</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> assembly to set aside
politics and focus on God, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Rescue</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FRC</ENAMEX> showed up to
distribute pamphlets. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FRC</ENAMEX> invited the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to sign petitions for the
Partial<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">-Birth Abortion Ban</ENAMEX>, thereby adding their names to its political
database. Others who have signed up for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> have subsequently turned up on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> mailing lists.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Imperialism</ENAMEX> vs. enlightenment. Even if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> isn't in bed with the religious right, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> predict that its
commitment to restore traditional morality will inevitably draw it into
right-wing politics. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s military culture plays into this indictment,
as do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCartney</ENAMEX>'s hideous sports metaphors. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>, he says, have "dropped
the ball." They need a "halftime" pep talk and a new "game plan." They must
defend morality "like offensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linemen</ENAMEX> protecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX>." Many of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> are prone to using <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> war metaphors:
"battleground," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of God," "civil war of values." This kind of talk spooks
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>.

            PK
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesmen</ENAMEX> emphatically deny a political agenda. They describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> as a
"revival movement" aimed at changing hearts, not a "reform movement" aimed at
changing laws. They point out that they postponed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> assembly from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996 to 1997</TIMEX> to avoid getting embroiled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s election. Unlike the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX>, they don't keep a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> list, and they expect to
disband when God decides that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX>'s revival mission is complete.

            In this dispute, tone matters more than content. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> needs
to show less of its macho side and more of its sensitive side. So its leaders
have begun to play down the war metaphors. They have turned the other cheek to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX>'s attacks. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, they asked the assembled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to pray for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> instead of judging them. They have also instructed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> to seek civic assignments from their local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pastors</ENAMEX>, not
from the movement's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>. "We stop short of prescribing what that agenda
should be, because it's beyond our competence," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>.

            By projecting this kind of
humility, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> puts its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> in the posture of aggressors. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX>'s
hair-trigger charges of intolerance have backfired, convincing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX> is intolerant. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> persistently denounces <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> for "excluding anyone who
is not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>"--roughly equivalent to denouncing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX> for confining
its membership to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX>'s objections to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> lifestyle have prompted some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> to question where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX> gets off second-guessing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who embrace
that lifestyle.

            By now, it's clear who has
won the war. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>, have expressed sympathy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> and an interest in
coaxing them toward gender equality rather than opposing them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX>'s vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, in retreat, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX> was only trying to "educate" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that PK
isn't purely benign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> complains that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesmen</ENAMEX> won the war because
they're "slick," like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX>. Actually, they won because they aren't. They
admit ignorance and error. They answer no-win questions. They listen to
criticism and openly contemplate changing their ways. If they were selling
anything but integrity, they'd be a disaster.

         
      
   
