
   
   
      
         
            Toy Story

            Not that long ago, in a
galaxy very, very close to home, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-largest toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> tied
its fortunes to the most popular film series in history. In a strange way, it's
been paying for that decision ever since.

            The toy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattel</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hasbro</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sky Dancers, My Pretty</ENAMEX>
Dollhouse, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> action figures, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micro Machines</ENAMEX>. The film
series, of course, is the Star Wars trilogy. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX> has
been making <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and action figures based on those films, and that
arrangement by itself catapulted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> into the ranks of major toy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> alone, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX> will sell <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$120 million</NUMEX> worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
Wars toys. And while sales <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> were obviously boosted by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-release of the trilogy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Lucas</ENAMEX>' creation has become a source of
perpetual revenue in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>. Since the first film came out, Star Wars
merchandise sales have totaled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $2.5 billion</NUMEX>.

            It's safe to say, in fact, that Star Wars
single-handedly created the film-merchandising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. While it had always
been possible to buy movie posters or souvenir plates (and God knows we're
thankful for the plates), the concept of creating a toy universe replicating
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in the film somehow eluded movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX> came along. This
isn't because Star Wars was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> movie that lent itself to action
figures and plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>. One could easily imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX> toys--as
there are now--or toys based on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Man From U.N.C.L.E</ENAMEX> . It's a classic
example of a company creating a market rather than responding to an existing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. No one knew how much <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> wanted action figures until they were offered
them.

            The
result, of course, has been a flood of toys based on everything from comic
books to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westerns</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX> is even in the process of hurriedly rushing to
market <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11 ½-inch</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> dolls, hoping to cash in on the frenzy before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> quintet end up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palookaville.</ENAMEX>) Nothing drives home the ephemeral
nature of popularity better, in fact, then wandering through the action-figure
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toys</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>" Us and seeing the deep discounts on toys from films that
were supposed to be hits but weren't. Ah, there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> from
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Action Hero</ENAMEX> ! There's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riddler</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman Forever</ENAMEX> and
Poison Ivy from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman & Robin</ENAMEX> ! And they're all yours for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX>
off.

            
The problem for toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> is that they need
to design and manufacture the toys for a movie without having any sense of how
popular that movie is going to be. You can easily end up making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX>
worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX> toys only to watch the orders dry up as the movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>. On the other hand, if the movie's popular and you don't have enough
product on hand to take advantage of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those few weeks</TIMEX> when your toys are hot,
you won't get the chance again.

            The one
exception to this short-life-expectancy rule is the film series that started
the whole exhausting merry-go-round. Star Wars toys did go through a
long slump, but since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> or so they have been consistent winners. As the
incredible box-office numbers for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trilogy</ENAMEX>'s re-release showed, there are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> upon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade or more</TIMEX> after Luke
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skywalker</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> appeared, who nonetheless see him as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>. This is
a phenomenon that could only have happened in the age of the videocassette
recorder, but even so it remains an anomaly in the world of pop culture. Where
almost everything else gets consumed and cast aside almost immediately, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
Wars has been able to remain somehow fashionable.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX>, as it happens, is not the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> of
Star Wars toys. That honor belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hasbro</ENAMEX>, which swallowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenner</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenner</ENAMEX> had been given the license to make Star Wars toys "in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perpetuity</ENAMEX>" back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, and was responsible for those little plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vader</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-3PO</ENAMEX> figures that now sell for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of dollars</NUMEX> at collectors
shows. But soon after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hasbro</ENAMEX> acquired the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, it made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the great
blunders in the history of merchandising, forgoing its licensing fee to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucasfilm</ENAMEX> because the sales of Star Wars toys were in a bad slump.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucasfilm</ENAMEX> turned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX>, which created an entire new line--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micro</ENAMEX>
Machines--of Star Wars toys. When those toys took off, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hasbro</ENAMEX> jumped
back into the fray, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX> was there to stay. Some have even suggested that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX>, by proving that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> still had legs, was indirectly
responsible for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s revival and for the prequel trilogy that will debut in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May of 1999</TIMEX>.

            This,
then, is a story to warm the heart of any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX>. Small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> sees big
opportunity, seizes it, and reaps the rewards forever after. The only problem
is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX> doesn't own the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucasfilm</ENAMEX> does. As a result of the
Star Wars deal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX> devoted more and more of its resources to that
line, shifting money out of internal development, staking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, in a
sense, on this product whose existence depended utterly on staying in the good
graces of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucasfilm</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX> found out exactly what dependence
means.

            
The Star Wars toy contracts were
scheduled to expire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, which sparked a bidding war <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattel</ENAMEX>
offered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> for a decadelong contract, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hasbro</ENAMEX> sought to expand its
current <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200-million</NUMEX>-a-year business. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX>, having less cash than either of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> big toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>, offered part of itself. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX> was able to
secure a license and guarantee its future, but in exchange it mortgaged the
farm. Beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucasfilm</ENAMEX> will receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$140 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in
advance-royalty payments, plus a set percentage of all toy sales. More
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strikingly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX> options to buy <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX> a
share, which at the time the deal was made was a bargain. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX>'s future is
solid--once the first film of the new trilogy comes out, sales of its toys
could reach <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $400 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. But more than ever, that future
will be tied very tightly to the desires of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucasfilm</ENAMEX>.

            As it happens, right now the
deal isn't looking as great for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucasfilm</ENAMEX> as it originally did. Announcement of
the terms sent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX>'s stock plummeting, so that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucasfilm</ENAMEX>'s options are now
out of the money. (It would be cheaper to buy the stock on the open market than
by using the options.) Still, the stock price will likely improve as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
nears. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucasfilm</ENAMEX> does hold all the cards.

            There's been a lot of
overdone talk in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX> about the transformation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> away from one based on manufacturing toward one based on ideas. But the
more interesting transformation signaled by the relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galoob</ENAMEX> and
Lucasfilm may be the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from an economy in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> design and make
products in-house toward an economy in which those functions are separated and
contracted out. And in this new world it's not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that owns the
assembly line that has real power. Instead, it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that owns the name
that dictates the terms. Anyone can make toys, apparently. But not anyone can
stamp the Star Wars tag on them.

             

         
      
   
