
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Airport</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better Than Disneyland</ENAMEX>
            

            E-shopping. Cell phones. You love all technology in any form, and what you
are glossing over is that this stuff is homogenizing the world. It's turning
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> into some sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, with its highly refined versions of
such Western paraphernalia as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nine West</ENAMEX> shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> everywhere. Of course
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> will shop on online. Why? Because it's there. And now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX> is even getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Disneyland</ENAMEX>, the last thing it needs, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2005</TIMEX>.
So in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, we'll be able to ask ourselves if we'd rather travel to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> ... and if we'd be able to tell the difference once we got
there. Oh wait, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> is the place with the palm <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, right? I can
understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> feels as if it needs a shot of something to revive its
flagging tourism industry. But really, the problem is not that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> lacks a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Magic Kingdom</ENAMEX>. This is simply not a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that screams "vacation destination."
Try instead: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>!" "More money!" "How about going up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX> and
making some money <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>?" Apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s decision a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX> to import the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Mulan</ENAMEX> unleashed a mighty appetite for all
things <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>. So we're going to get another of those infamous theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lantau Island</ENAMEX>--near the brand-new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Airport</ENAMEX>. While the last thing any
place in the world needs is a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Disneyland</ENAMEX>, I think there are special
circumstances here that make the incursion even more distasteful. Putting
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Disneyland</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lantau Island</ENAMEX> can only distract us from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> itself, which
seems to me to be the perfect iteration of a modern-day theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, with its
brilliantly modern design that effortlessly propels <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> to their gates,
their luggage, a brand-new rail link to downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> already offers everything that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> is promising: excellent
public restrooms. Theme <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> that serve dim sum. A lack of litter.
Harrowing rides (on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX>). It even has entertainment--in the form of
trendy shopping. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> houses an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outpost</ENAMEX> of the it's-cool-to-be-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shanghai Tang</ENAMEX> department store with its trademark teddy bears--which are far
cuter than any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> that I've come across while eating themed fast
food.) In fact, if I were running the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Tourism</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
government, I would bill the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> as a destination in itself.

         
      
   
