
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            Another nice week in the markets, especially the bond market, which rallied
strongly after a series of economic data suggesting that inflation, if not
dead, was at least still mild. The stock market was also helped by yet another
speech by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>, who talked about how rising house prices provided a
more consistent impetus to consumer spending than rising stock prices. The
broadcast version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s speech looked like it was coming off the Web,
giving him the disconcerting appearance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of a strange <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> sitting
at a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> in a crowded <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. But I may have been the only one who thought
this.

            In any case, it has been a powerful rally for the stock market in the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week and a half</TIMEX>, and all the talk now is of a revived bull market. But it still
all seems a bit odd, since the purported bear market lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few weeks</TIMEX>,
and was founded on nothing more than overwrought concerns about inflation and a
sudden advent of panic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about Y2K</TIMEX>. If you blinked, you missed the whole thing.
Which, from an investing perspective, means you should blink as often as you
can. And so, on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chat</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> recommended that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Atlantic</ENAMEX>'s application
to offer long-distance service to its local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> be denied, saying the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> had come close to opening its local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> sufficiently to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, but that its efforts fell <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just</NUMEX> short . An initial draft of
the memo was reportedly titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Only In Horseshoes and Hand Grenades</ENAMEX>.' "

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential candidate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> believes that commodity prices have been depressed because
'when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> tightened up the money supply <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who needed to raise cash did
so by selling commodities .' Can't you just hear it? 'Paw, the fed funds
rate just jumped again. Better go get some more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> out of the silo to dump on
the market.' "

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "After the Nasdaq toyed with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> level on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> before
closing just below it, technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> came out of the woodwork to say that
breaking through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> was going to be tough, because it was a 'resistance
level' for the index. Of course, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> raced past <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3000</TIMEX> ,
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> it stayed comfortably above it. So I guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> would now
say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> is a 'support level.' "

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Welch</ENAMEX> announced that he will retire after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s annual meeting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2001</TIMEX>, meaning that all eyes will be
focused on his succession . Early suggestions for ways of whittling down the
list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX> include: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">SEAL</ENAMEX> training (if you ring the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bell</ENAMEX>, you're out); a bake-off using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX>'s cool new photo-light oven; and a gala
tourney of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Win Ben Stein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money</ENAMEX> ."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in recent memory, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> is following the
release of its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourth-quarter</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX> results with a conference call
on which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX> will speak about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s performance and
answer questions from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>. It's just a coincidence that this new openness
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">investor community</ENAMEX> comes at a time when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s stock has treaded water
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "In its opening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX>, 
                  Being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX>
                averaged
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,495</NUMEX> per screen. That means if it had opened on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> screens--instead of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 25</TIMEX>-- it would have made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$127.5 million</NUMEX> . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX>! I bet the
studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> are really kicking themselves that they didn't book those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theaters</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Home Products</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX> announced a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70 billion</NUMEX>
merger that will create the world's largest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> . I bet they're
hoping those drug-price controls never make it out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
