
   
   
      
         
            Fact: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cell-Phone Users' Brains</ENAMEX> <i>Are</i> Damaged
            

            Of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cell Phone Haters Club</ENAMEX> has already convened an emergency
meeting to discuss these exciting <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>-related findings, which was the whole
reason I had to rush out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early this morning</TIMEX> instead of helping
you feed all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, round up lunch money, sign permission slips for
field trips to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bronx Zoo</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, pick a wad of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s hair
and hustle the older ones off to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> without jackets. The "dumb down"
feature that cell phones are offering rodent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> is no surprise to club
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, however. We noticed the same phenomenon in human cell-phone users
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and were just wondering how long it would take to make the species
leap to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>. If cell-phone use did not cloud one's judgment and impair memory,
then no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would ever use a cell phone a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time. The memory of the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> "incident"--the fuzzy, barely audible sound of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on the other
end of the line, interrupted by "break up," the need to scream insanely into
the phone, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRING HOME</ENAMEX> A QUART OF MILK I SAID" while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passersby</ENAMEX> stare
curiously--would be enough to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to throw away the damn things
immediately. If a cell-phone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> retained any memory at all of how it once
felt to have human dignity and not be enslaved to a ridiculous chirping machine
that can summon you anywhere anytime to talk about the most trivial things,
then that would be the end of an entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> of the customizable digital
gadget industry.

            Of course, cell-phone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, who don't remember what it felt like to live
without the threat of severe mental impairment hanging over them, will
rationalize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> news. At least until, as you suggest, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> do something
interesting in a vat of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. Don't forget, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been ignoring possible
health threats from cell phones for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time now</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last fall</TIMEX>, the venerable
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> department store <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barneys</ENAMEX> actually sold trench coats that had specially
lined pockets for cell phones. Put a cell phone into the pocket and no harmful
rays would waft through the fabric to attack your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. The coats sold well, I
was told.

            So if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> work holds up, we'll probably see cell phone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mittens</ENAMEX> next. And
special muffling ear muffs to block waves from entering the brain through the
unprotected ear canal route. And maybe nose plugs for good measure, because
those waves are sly. You'll know the cell-phone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> when you see them, that's
for sure.

            In other news, did you notice that a disgruntled office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>
drove to work and shot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>? And our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX> just
installed an electronic security system that makes it impossible to get into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> if you don't know a multi-digit security code.

         
      
   
