
   
   
      
         
            Microsurplus

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">218</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">211</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> passage of an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85 billion</NUMEX> spending
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> for health, education, and labor--a story off-leaded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and
run inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> promised a veto, citing a
Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget Office</ENAMEX> study concluding that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17 billion</NUMEX> over
the spending limit needed to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>--this despite the bill's
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.97</NUMEX> across-the-board spending cut. His negotiations with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> begin next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
unveiling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of sweeping privacy rules protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' medical records,
a story already broken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> (see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">USAT</ENAMEX> leads
with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> have transferred <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions of</NUMEX>
dollars to suspected terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sourced</ENAMEX> to anonymous intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who cite an internal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> audit of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, the story says that the transfers are protection
money to prevent bin Laden from attacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX>. The funds have
been used to finance several terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, including the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> also heads <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>--also under
investigation--and is represented by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>
( the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> doesn't say.) 

            Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s privacy rules any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> will have unrestricted access to
his own medical record and will have to approve of their release for purposes
not related to treatment or billing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> will be required to hire a privacy
"point <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , who will be trained to edit records for
release; currently, when an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> inquires about a job-related injury, for
example, he is usually given the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>'s entire record. The rules do not
need the approval of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, which in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> imposed on itself an (unmet)
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1999</TIMEX> deadline to pass legislation. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> did limit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
rules to cover only electronic records--even though the majority of records are
still on paper. And while the rules cover <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> and insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>,
they cannot cover the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> or pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> who consult for
them.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> stories on the privacy rules are well done, but there are
some lapses. For instance, in its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> paragraph the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> tells us,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">breathlessly</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> "have worked on [the rules] for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>"
(should we pat them on the back for that?). And the LAT inexplicably
devotes its entire <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> paragraph to an airy statement from the text of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">morning</ENAMEX>'s speech by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--a statement that does nothing to help explain the
proposal. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> did a better job detailing
the objections of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers front</ENAMEX> (and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reefers) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s astonishing
economic figures, which show an annual growth rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.8 percent</NUMEX> in the third
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>, up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.9 percent</NUMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. At the same time, an inflation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guage</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employment Cost</ENAMEX> Index, which measures wage pressure--was lower than
expected. (To read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moneybox</ENAMEX>'s take on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECI</ENAMEX>, click 
here.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX> also revised the way it measures GDP to
account for productivity in the tech sector; this revealed that growth this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decade</ENAMEX> was stronger than previously thought. The stock and bond markets soared.
Despite this miraculous news, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> says that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> expects a recession by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s elections--the highest percentage in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>--and that one in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> is not satisfied with the economy. (Question: If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> were to appear
before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and turn <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, what percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would
complain it was not <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">platinum</ENAMEX>?)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s second <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> debate, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanover</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>.
The debate included little sparring and much criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> for
not showing up. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Ballot Box</ENAMEX>'s dispatch from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanover</ENAMEX>, click 
here.)

            Writing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> commentery page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Cockburn</ENAMEX> alleges that the putative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> genocide of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar Albanians</ENAMEX> is
a myth. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, forensics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, have
turned up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>, not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX>, as has been
alleged. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> "were fighting a separatist movement, led by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberation Army</ENAMEX>, and behaving with the brutality typical of security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>."
But nothing they did before the West intervened justifies the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>
killed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s bombs.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> fronts a feature about ambivalence in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> over
the impending verdict in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial. (The preliminary findings will be
posted on a government web
site after the markets close on "a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>"--probably either <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> or a week
from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.) On the one hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">libertarian Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> dislike
government intervention. On the other, they hate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuits</ENAMEX> have
this concept of holy effrontery--in defending their cause it's okay to use any
means, including false statements," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>. "I'm not sure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s effrontery is that holy. It's certainly very shameless. But you've
got to admire it at some level." Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, which has been contributing heavily to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> since the anti-trust trial began, is making overtures to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> as well. Its group <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Raikes</ENAMEX>, has become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX>, and its top <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Krumholtz</ENAMEX>, sat next to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at a recent fund-raiser.

            So, you've lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> in the market--single-handedly bankrupting a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">233-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>--become an international fugitive, and spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> in
jail. What do you do now? Go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX>? No, but the lecture circuit is a
close <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Leeson</ENAMEX>, whose reckless derivatives trades sunk
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barings P.L.C.</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day in 1995</TIMEX>, got <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> to speak to a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX>
stock <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. It's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of a string of scheduled speaking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">engagements</ENAMEX>, product endorsements, and television roles. But unfortunately for
Leeson, his new career is not all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fantasy Island</ENAMEX>: His assets are frozen, and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sixty-five</NUMEX> percent of all his revenue goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barings</ENAMEX>, whom he owes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$164.4</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. He didn't see a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cent</NUMEX> from the book and movie rights he sold, and the
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> he can keep from his current media work must go either for medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> (he has colon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>) or into pension and mutual funds. 

         
      
   
