
   
   
      
         
            Was It Worth It?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>--

            I'm in a sudden panic, realizing that this is the last installment and we
have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few hundred</NUMEX> words to wrap up the argument and resolve the points left
hanging around. So I'll do it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX> style, with varied points connected
with ellipses (that's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> dots in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> ...).

            * One perspective that's gotten no hearing in this discussion is the
"immoral war" view--that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> was so corrupt, or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Vietnamese</ENAMEX> aims so admirably <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>colonial, that the effort to protect
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX> was wrong per se. That's because neither of us, nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lind</ENAMEX>, is in
this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. But we've suggested that the scope of argument is narrower than I
suspect it still remains in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> ...

            * What you, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lind</ENAMEX>, and I disagree about, in various forms, all has to do with
means and proportion. We agree that it would be better if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX> had not
been taken over by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX>--and that it was better that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, and others beat their insurgencies. The question is whether the fight
was worth it at several crucial junctures: when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> got
more seriously involved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963-64</TIMEX>; when it dramatically escalated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967-68</TIMEX>;
and when it began a prolonged withdrawal, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969 through the fall</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saigon</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> ...

            * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX> argues that the initial engagement was necessary , for the
"bandwagon" reasons of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> we have discussed previously. I view it as
understandable --for those same reasons--but ultimately unwise and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">destructive</ENAMEX>, for reasons that have been played out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> politics ever since.
And, much as I hate using this word, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s prolongation of the withdrawal
seems to me, well, criminal. (OK, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'60s</TIMEX>-style hyperbole, but you know what I
mean. Maybe "criminally unwise.") <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Tens of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds</NUMEX>
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>, died during the extended separation. Even assuming
there was some offsetting increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> credibility in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those years</TIMEX>, it could
not have been worthwhile ...

            * You ask about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> option--long-term partition, enforced by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. That might have been conceivable in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963 or 1964</TIMEX>, when the balance
between aims and costs was still more reasonable from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> perspective. By
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> everything about that balance had shifted. For reasons <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lind</ENAMEX> lays out very
clearly, domestic politics had powerfully and predictably turned against such a
costly war ...

            * You raise several times the claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Vietnamese</ENAMEX> were in some
sense "winning" by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>. Even assuming for purposes of argument that this is
true (which I dispute, but that's for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another day</TIMEX>), by that time it was
becoming irrelevant. The cost had exceeded a level that any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
politics thought this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would endure for such a symbolic struggle ...

            * Yes, it's odd that we should be struggling for the mantle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. But the balance of costs and goals is something he clearly understood.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX> also points out) is willing to pay financial costs,
like those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> defense spend-up. But we properly dislike sending
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to die for symbolic struggles when it's not really necessary--and that's
why My <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronnie</ENAMEX> got those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>. I am sure someone made the case
that this had become a symbolic stand, and he couldn't afford to look as if he
was running. That didn't stop him ...

            * My starting point was that, agree or disagree, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX>'s book. I end on that point too. But of course it's not the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> to
read. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Scott</ENAMEX>'s recent <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost Crusade</ENAMEX> , the memoir of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>
who trained <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mercenaries</ENAMEX>, is the most affecting book of any sort I've
read in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>. It was, by the way, recommended to me by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles McCarry</ENAMEX>, whose book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tears of Autumn</ENAMEX> stands with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greene</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Quiet American</ENAMEX> in conveying the climate of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s first
involvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX> ...

            * I've also just been reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fredrik Logevall</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Choosing War</ENAMEX> , a new
academic history that argues more or less the exact opposite of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX>'s case.
From <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1963 to early 1965</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logevall</ENAMEX> claims, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> faced
a deliberate choice about whether it should raise or lower the stakes in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>: Make it an all-out test of will, which it became, or look for an
excuse to leave--perhaps with the claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> had become
too ill-behaved to be worth further <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> support or lives. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Logevall</ENAMEX>'s evidence
is beyond my ability to introduce here. I'll simply say that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX> proves
that the decision to go to war was understandable, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Logevall</ENAMEX> provides the
argument for the "minimal realist" view that it was unnecessary and unwise. And
as he says in the final pages of his book:

            

               The certainty that this was an unnecessary war, not merely in hindsight but
in the context of that time, also makes the astronomical costs that resulted
from it during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965-1973</TIMEX> that much more difficult to contemplate. ...

            

         
      
   
