
   
   
      
         
            Flying Out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX>
            

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> rage against government taxes, others resent the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
are sucking dry our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> safety net even as they crankily vote down
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> budgets. Not me. I lie awake and worry about the national tragedy
that is the airline industry. I hate them all: the lackadaisical baggage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handlers</ENAMEX> who "accidentally" sent our luggage to a remote cargo <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">area</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, the surly steward(esse)s, the brazen caterers whose spongy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> in
brown <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goo</ENAMEX> so shamelessly denigrates the memory of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. But most of all, I
obsess over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose duty it is to de<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-ice wings</ENAMEX>, coax the cargo hold
not to explode, and fix any smoking engines before takeoff. So of course you
are right; "simple" mechanical failure is scarier than terrorism because it
connotes a level of indifference that is no less evil than overt terrorism but
far more insidious. And even worse, it epitomizes the attitude of most airline
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> toward their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are paying
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> or more--my ticket to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> topped <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>--for
the privilege of being herded like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> onto a death trap over which no one
seems to have much control. Stop citing those statistics that show air travel
is safer than automobiles. The big difference is that auto accidents are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">survivable</ENAMEX>. That's because auto accidents are, to some extent, controllable by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> who hears a car engine making a bad whompety noise
has a choice: Pull off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> or gut it out. The airplane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> who,
like me, hears a nasty whirrrrrsh on takeoff and feels the seat shimmy as if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">powered by Magic Fingers</ENAMEX> has no such choice. I must sit. And hope that the
pilot is better at his job than the baggage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handlers</ENAMEX> are at theirs.

            Despite the cultural leap that being an airplane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> requires--as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>, I have, after all, spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly four decades</TIMEX> constructing an
elaborate illusion of how I control my life--I continue to fly. So far the
gamble has paid off. I'm alive. You're alive. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> still have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>,
partly because we chose <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, as a destination. We even have our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">luggage</ENAMEX>. This time.

         
      
   
