
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Stand</ENAMEX>
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is the presidential debates--both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s jump to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> debate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>,
once too stiff, is now trying too hard to loosen up. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Haskell</ENAMEX>
energizer <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bunny</ENAMEX>" while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has the "insouciance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Martin</ENAMEX> and the
iciness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) thinks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s ideological similarity to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> helps him, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> will
focus on personal style rather than policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
attempts to distance himself from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "behavior" are
hypocritical, given his loyalty as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>--especially during the
impeachment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Slater</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press , reveals that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> camp is privately more worried about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">facing Bradley than Gore</ENAMEX> in a general election. But on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> appears relaxed and amiable. And on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kerry</ENAMEX> admits that he doesn't know if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s health-care numbers add up and says that neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> has been
intellectually honest about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> reform.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence O'Donnell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> )--think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was smart to stay out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> debate. But
many--some of them conservative, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> )--think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> hurt himself by not engaging his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> and may lose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> primary. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s absence helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
especially, say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> ), since he is the only other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> can
imagine being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Slater</ENAMEX>
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> camp has ruled out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> as running <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> has a good shot at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> nomination,
but not the presidency. Some--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brit Hume</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Barone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Donnell</ENAMEX>--think he has been too damaged by his recently published views on
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> political influence to make much of an impact. (Barone
notes that, even absent these views, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s core message goes counter to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s entire post-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">WW-II</ENAMEX> consensus on trade and foreign policy;
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> would have to fall into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Ocean</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> to become
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, he says.) Appearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> says he
will not backtrack from his pro-life views and says that this will be his last
campaign, if he loses. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> was scheduled to appear on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s Late
Edition , but the entire show is given over to news coverage of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s plane crash.

            
               
The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kmart" Myth</ENAMEX>
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> has fun with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign had been paying feminist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">celebrity Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> (laundered through a faceless consultant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>) to advise the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> on his wardrobe and on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oedipal</ENAMEX> relationship
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, among other things. "When you get somebody who has been some
exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> for the feminist psychobabble movement, who's trying to teach
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>] about 'alpha <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>' and 'beta <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>' stuff, you have to wonder if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
has any idea who he is," proclaims <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brit Hume</ENAMEX>. Asked about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> on This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> appears nervous but replies that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s pay has been cut and
that she has been working with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karenna</ENAMEX> on youth outreach.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept. of Self-Caricature</ENAMEX>
            

            "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>] sounded just like a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> to me. He started talking about
homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and all that. I don't need a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> to tell
me about that."

                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Last Word
            

            "I will say this into the camera: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are in my campaign. They
are welcome to this cause. They are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>. ... I am open to
appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>, to a vice presidential seat. They
are a tremendously able <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>, let me just say this: In
this heart, there is no malice or hatred of any individual. But you are looking
at someone who does enjoy fighting. And if that means fighting occasionally
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> like to fight occasionally with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX>, that does not make you an evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>."

                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
