
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Copycat Killer</ENAMEX>

            Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> lead with local election results. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> election round-up: Slugged "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> Take <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>," the story says
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> won control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time ever
(the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>) and is close to winning the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>
dispatches <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> show the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> won). But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> won
the mayoralty in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>-heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
legalized limited marijuana use and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> slashed car taxes.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times ' top nonlocal lead is the massacre of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> by a co-worker in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu</ENAMEX>, a
story off-leaded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with a widening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> probe into bribery in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> music business. The anonymously sourced story says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> will soon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prosecute</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> for taking payola from the large independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">label Fonovisa</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says the copier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">repairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byran Uyesuji</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>, had just been
laid off. He shot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, all of whom died immediately, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> shots
from a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9-millimeter</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX>. He drove a company <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> to a nature preserve and
gave himself up after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours</TIMEX> of negotiations. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uyesuji</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> registered in his name (a similar number
were found in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>) and was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of his high-school shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> note that according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu Star</ENAMEX>-Bulletin ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uyesuji</ENAMEX> had a gun permit turned down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> after an arrest for property
damage at work.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has the best detail on the shooting: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uyesuji</ENAMEX> is a "chunky figure" who wore
a blue-and-white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> shirt. A high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX> says he was "quiet and
not part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">in-crowd</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uyesuji</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , "I'm going
to bring him another <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> so he can shoot himself," and recalls that his son
received anger-management counseling after kicking an elevator door several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> has strict gun laws, requiring a
safety course, waiting period, and background check to get a permit. All the
papers note that there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 17</NUMEX> murders <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> puts this in perspective: In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">260</NUMEX> homicides among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">543,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uyesuji</ENAMEX>'s workplace shooting is one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
deadliest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s history. (To read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s take on quiet,
reclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> who snap, click here.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> fronts a new radar analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> Flight 990's last
moments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> fell <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 miles</NUMEX> a minute for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 40 seconds</TIMEX> and then turned
to the right before hitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, suggesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> began to break
up in the air. The straight initial drop also indicates that the problem was
likely not with the engines' thrust reversers, which would have caused the
plane to spin had they fired accidentally. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Transportation Safety</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> also reported that one of the thrust reversers had been deactivated on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>, a normal procedure that made their uncontrolled ignition less
likely. The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says that, in its final report on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean Airlines</ENAMEX> crash in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guam</ENAMEX> (released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> lambasted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Aviation</ENAMEX>
Administration for not regulating foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> enough. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
fronts a story detailing the improvements in victim
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consolation</ENAMEX> and in crash investigation since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> Flight 800 disaster. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">To</ENAMEX>
read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> on our irrational fear of flying, click here.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> will announce
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> a policy change on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> will end sanctions if the country
holds free elections. Previously, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> had required the removal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> to end sanctions. But a "senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>" undercuts
the sincerity of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> position when he tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>
cannot imagine, based on our analysis, that a genuinely free and fair election
would allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> to remain as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>."

On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> opinion page, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fellow Shibley Telhami</ENAMEX> presses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to announce a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> Doctrine asserting
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has "vital strategic" interests in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
has always maintained its "interest" in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> peace, but the "vital
strategic" moniker signals to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> that we are prepared to go to
war over that interest, if necessary. With current peace negotiations requiring
an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economic commitment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as February</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration needs to begin building support at home by redefining our
participation in the process as something more than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>.

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> weigh in on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's revelation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> had
been paying feminist celebrity <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> to advise him how to
be an "alpha male." "If Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> were more confident about his purpose in
running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, he would not need magical elixirs," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> write.
"The fact that his campaign sought to conceal payments to Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> suggests
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> knows this well." On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Dowd seconds</TIMEX> this opinion--albeit in her inimitably waggish way.
"You've got to respect a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who gets a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> to pay her a salary
higher than his own," she writes. "Of course, when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has to pony up a
fortune to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to teach him how to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, that definitely takes the edge
off his top-dogginess." But the top-dog <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX> goes to alpha satirist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Buckley</ENAMEX>, who recalls moments from his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi</ENAMEX>-therapy (in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ):

            "By the way [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>], that tie you're wearing, it's all wrong."


            "It's an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herm√</ENAMEX>®s tie, you ignorant shrew. It cost me almost as much as your
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> retainer."

            "Your anger is very alpha. But an orange tie with teensy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf clubs</ENAMEX> is
totally beta. In fact, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gamma</ENAMEX>. Lose it. And by the way, no more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf</ENAMEX>."

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s beta problem, click here.)

         
      
   
