
   
   
      
         
            Why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Wouldn't Hack It</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the curious things about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake Weisberg</ENAMEX> aptly calls the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do Dim Bulbs</ENAMEX>
Make <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Presidents?</ENAMEX>" question is that it's not a question anyone would
ask about corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>. On the contrary, it's conventional <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to hear that
having a really smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> is necessary to compete successfully, especially in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economy</ENAMEX>, and articles about company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> routinely include lines like
"He was the smartest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> I'd ever met." You would be very hard-pressed to find
someone who could argue with a straight face, pace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Brookhiser</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s future prospects, that it's precisely because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Welch</ENAMEX>
isn't that smart that he's done such a good job at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX>.

            It is true, of course, that the landscape of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> is dotted with
high-profile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> who never made it through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dell</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jobs</ENAMEX>. But the basic assumption about these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> is not
that they got tired of wrestling with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Introductory Calculus</ENAMEX> and quit, but that
they were too smart to waste their time in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. (A debatable assumption, to
be sure, but then I finished college, so I would say that.) The success of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>, in fact, is antithetical to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s educational career,
which looks like nothing more than a rote exercise in credentialism.

            The only reason this comparison really matters, incidentally, is that the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> that has leapt to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s defense has often been fond of saying in
the past that we should look to business as a model for the way we run
government. This was never as congenial an analogy to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> ideology as
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> thought it was--most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> borrow significant amounts of
money and take their time paying it back, and most invest heavily in the
future, rather than giving money back to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>--but an important
part of it was the idea that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> needs the same skills as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ross</ENAMEX>
Perot, too, was fond of this analogy, since he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>.)

            If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> needs the same skills as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>, then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> is out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">luck</ENAMEX>. Actually, he probably would have fit in pretty well with the corporate
chieftains of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1950s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1960s</TIMEX>, when there was no foreign and not
much domestic competition and the old-boy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> was in full effect. But
not-smartness doesn't count for much anymore, at least not in the business
world.

         
      
   
