
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoical Dawn Powell</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dear Lisa</ENAMEX>,

            I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawn Powell</ENAMEX> would be delighted to know that her
work means something to yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> with such a sharp, funny, and
clear-headed perspective on human dreams and human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foibles</ENAMEX>. And how appropriate
for us to be discussing a volume of letters in this format!

            You ask me how "solid" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> revival is. Gosh, I
wish I knew. I'd like to hope that she'll sell out edition after edition for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to come, but I'm an old-fashioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> and allergic to hype.
Moreover, I now have a vested interest in this matter--I've spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about seven</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> now--so I want to be objective in my prognostications.

            We may be certain of a few things, the most important
of which is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> will never be forgotten again. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> when I would
enter secondhand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, ask for one of her books, and have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietor</ENAMEX> tell
me that he'd "never heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Powell</ENAMEX>" are gone for good. (So, alas, are
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> when you would regularly run into <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX>'s novels at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">thrift</ENAMEX> sales and in
the dustiest corners of secondhand book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than a dollar</NUMEX> a
volume--which is how I build up most of my collection.)

            From this point on, anybody who undertakes any sort of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> literary history will have to come to terms with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">achievement--15</ENAMEX> more-or-less mature novels; close to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> plays, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of</NUMEX>
short stories, book reviews, and occasional pieces; a magnificent diary that
spans <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years</TIMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well over a thousand</NUMEX> letters. She's a part of our history
now, but also--in a manner that is quite unusual for an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> dead more than
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX>--part of our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life, too.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the best things about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> revival is that
it has been pretty much spontaneous--a sort of mass uprising of support. Her
books sold so poorly when they were originally issued that she is, in some
sense, brand new. We read her because she's good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> (the "death of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>" indeed!), and then we tell our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, who spread the word. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX>
needs no explication; rather, her wit makes us laugh, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are likely
to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we know (in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their late-20 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">incarnations</ENAMEX>), and her honesty and emotional courage
can take our mutual breath away. No rose-colored glasses for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.

            You mention her "optimism"; I would prefer the word
"cheer," for I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> was deeply pessimistic in many ways--in the grand
old Stoical manner--and that it was this pessimism that permitted her to throw
herself into life and living with such abandon.

            Do I make myself obscure? Then let me put it another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> was absolutely anti-utopian--skeptical of politics, indifferent to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX>, scornful of "happy endings" great and small, in marriages as in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revolutions</ENAMEX>. At bottom, her view of the world is bleak, blunt, unsparing, and
fundamentally tragic. She offers no great hopes, encourages no daydreams,
realizes that life is at best a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sisyphean</ENAMEX> effort for serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and that
most of us will never get that rock halfway up the hill to begin with. And so
she laughs (at least in part) because crying is a bore and a bring-down and
does nobody any good. How much more sane--how much more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> --to accept one's fate, get over it, buck up, and join the
party. It'll be closing time soon enough.

            Which book to read <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>? The generic answer is
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Time To Be Born</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>)--a dazzling and unsettling
evocation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> on the verge of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, which grabs and holds
from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Paragraph 1</ENAMEX>. Still, in many ways, I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turn</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Wheel</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>) is even more perfect--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX>-footed satire of literary
life and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity authors</ENAMEX> (namely <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest H.</ENAMEX>), and one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX>'s few
"modernist" books. Then there is Come Back to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorrento</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX>), a simple, direct, and achingly beautiful study of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> in a stultifying small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that cannot comprehend their
dreams and ambitions ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Come Back to Sorrento</ENAMEX> , by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, is one of the very few books written before the gay-lib movement that
features homosexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and is neither a soggy plea for understanding, a
mockery or hate tract, a clinical case study, or anything other than an
intricate and compassionate rendering of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> human beings).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>'s own favorite among her books was
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance Night</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX>), a grim slice of life set in a
small <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Home Is Far</ENAMEX>
Away is a thinly disguised autobiographical novel about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>'s
near-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dickensian</ENAMEX> childhood and unspeakably horrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stepmother</ENAMEX>--very moving.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Some day</TIMEX> it will make a great movie (indeed--shameless plug here--my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stevenson</ENAMEX> and I have finished a screenplay and are shopping it
around).

            Save The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Diaries of Dawn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>) for last. I think this is her greatest achievement--Petronius
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">meets Marcus Aurelius</ENAMEX> in mid-century <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>--but it is best appreciated after
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immersion</ENAMEX> in her life and work. My <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> will kill me if I don't
mention my own biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX>P., new in paperback from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry Holt Owl</ENAMEX>.

            But I've hardly begun to answer your questions! I'll
try to do better next time.

            Your pen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
