
   
   
      
         
            What, No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR Building</ENAMEX>?

            While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> wasn't paying attention, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Executive Office Building</ENAMEX>,
a grand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Empire</ENAMEX> pile that stands beside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> White
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> who aren't quite important enough to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in the executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mansion</ENAMEX>, was renamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight D. Eisenhower</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office Building</ENAMEX>. This
was apparently in tribute not to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> but to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Chafee</ENAMEX>, an
Eisenhowerish <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>, who had sponsored the bill
to rename the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEOB</ENAMEX>, as it's known, shortly before he died on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 26</TIMEX>. (To read
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story about all this, click here.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has no problem naming something else in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX>, a great general and a pretty good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--there's already a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theater</ENAMEX> named after him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Center</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Performing Arts</ENAMEX>--but what
about his erstwhile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> is reportedly getting
ready to name him <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>, and there seems to be general agreement
that he was the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> produced during the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. But--apart from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR Memorial</ENAMEX>, built <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few years ago</TIMEX>--no other
public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> can think of is named after him.
(The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roosevelt Bridge</ENAMEX> is named after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy</ENAMEX>.) Considering that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> built
much of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, this seems very unfair. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX> who want to set things
right are invited to get in touch with one another in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s
only request is that they not choose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Executive Office Building</ENAMEX>, just up
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEOB</ENAMEX>, because it's really ugly.

         
      
   
