
   
   
      
         
            Dawn of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Icon</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Tim</ENAMEX>,

            You're right. There is not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Dawn for All Seasons</ENAMEX>. If
novels were furniture, I would not try to sell her to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who insist on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shaker</ENAMEX>. To some, her work will feel too busy and gewgawed-up. A
smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> I know snarled, "Her stuff feels so dated." I didn't even bother
to rush to the defense. (By the way, that was one of my favorite letters--the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> complains about the challenge of working with timely material.
"When I started that book the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> could get a telephone call for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a nickel</NUMEX> ...
I would read over a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> and think of my vast teenage reading public saying,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'What</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a nickel</NUMEX>, mommy?'")

            Part of me, I admit, doesn't want to share her. It's
like having a newspaper broadcast the address of your favorite quiet little
restaurant. Hard not to wince at the notion of belonging to a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Mallon</ENAMEX>, who has written a book on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diaries</ENAMEX> and is working on a book about letters, e-mailed me: "I like <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>, though she's now one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> in the curious position of being
known more for her life than her work. I've read or browsed more of the letters
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diaries</ENAMEX> and biography than I have her books. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul Bowles</ENAMEX> is supposed to
have said about his rediscovery as an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>: 'It's too much too late.'" The
Bowles analogy is an interesting one. He was hipper than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippies</ENAMEX> who
embraced him, and the charm is that he got there first. Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> seems
to have understood things about the culture--about ambition, about sexual
politics--ahead of her time.

            I have mixed feelings about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s becoming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iconographic</ENAMEX> in this way. My first reaction is to fear it's the death of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> once he's in a position to do his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX> ads (what product does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irving</ENAMEX> model: Rolexes?). On the other hand, maybe it's a good thing, if it
eventually leads <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to the work. You lure college coeds in black with nose
rings to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plath</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Jar and the</ENAMEX>
hullabaloo over her marriage to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>, and sooner or later they're going to
actually confront the ferocious, complex poems. (And by the way, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plath</ENAMEX>, too, is
often funny. Almost typed "hysterically" funny; the etymology of that word
reminds us about the problems of being a witty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.)

            Generally, I'm not very interested in what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> are
"really" like. I know a slew of 'em, and can attest that there's no "irony" in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s being better--or at least different--on the page than in person. All
of us are. That's what motivates us to write, after all: the rifts between our
actual lives and the much richer imagined possibilities. So I don't generally
enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>' biographies. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>, who admitted that she probably knew
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dos Passos</ENAMEX> too intimately to evaluate his work, it often sours things for
me to have insider information about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s inspirations or source
material. Just as an example: I almost wish I didn't know that the inscription
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma Bovary</ENAMEX> put on the walking stick she gave to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rodolphe</ENAMEX>, was
stolen verbatim from a gift that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gustave Flaubert</ENAMEX> got himself, from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Colet</ENAMEX>. Gus was a boor and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hick</ENAMEX> and probably deserved his horrible
syphilitic death. Nevertheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madame Bovary</ENAMEX> is a
great book.

            My anti-biography bias confessed, I'd also say that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>'s life and art seem unusually seamless. You meet the same cleareyed,
jaunty, generous, doleful, complicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in many of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> that
she offers in person. Or at least as close to "in person" as letters and
diaries can get us. It's hard to say this without embarrassment, so Girl
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scout-y</ENAMEX> does it sound, but she's as close as I've found to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Role Model</ENAMEX>. (Must
be a common sentiment among her minions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Howard</ENAMEX> called his excellent
piece about her in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How Dawn Powell Can Save</ENAMEX>
Your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>.")

            I've really enjoyed talking to you. I would ask you to
fax me through a sample of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX>'s handwriting, so I could do some amateur
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">graphology</ENAMEX>. But maybe that's too hagiographic, too <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>- or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana-adoring</ENAMEX>, even for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anyhow</ENAMEX>, I know you're on the road, with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Louis Symphony Orchestra</ENAMEX>. How a music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> became this involved with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">novelist</ENAMEX> is a very intriguing question that we never got to here. But I trust
that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> status would have pleased her enormously.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Warmly,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
