
   
   
      
         
            The Bandwagon Defect
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>--

            Well, after our moment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">concord</ENAMEX>, let's give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> what it came for.
Are you ready to rummmmmmmmbbbbbllle??!!

            Actually, let's talk about concord a little more. Maybe the most surprising
thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lind</ENAMEX>'s book is what has not occurred. When I heard that it
was coming out, and what its title was, I thought: Oh, no, here we go again. I
was remembering the rancor that followed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> previous revisionist works on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>--by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Podhoretz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>, to say nothing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNamara</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>-years-after-the-fact revelation that he'd made a little mistake
back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>. Each of these books seemed to zoom us straight back in time
to all the anger of that era. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disclosure</ENAMEX>: I was really in a lather about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNamara</ENAMEX>'s book and did a very bitter denunciation of it on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX>. I said,
essentially, if you didn't speak up when it could have made a difference, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>, you should have the decency to remain silent now. Chances are I
attacked the other books too. Bonus disclosure: As is no secret, I was in the
antiwar protest movement in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> and avoided being drafted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> by
deliberately failing a physical.) In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX>'s book has received mainly
positive reviews, and not all from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> in the "stab in the back"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camp</ENAMEX>.

            It's conceivable that the calmer reception has to do strictly with the book
and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. These other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> were public figures during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the war</TIMEX>; Lind
was a schoolboy. They wrote as if they had scores to settle; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> often
settled scores right back. But factors like these can't be the whole
explanation. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the things I don't like in the book is a long chapter
debunking myths of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> (e.g., that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX> were OK until <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> drove them berserk). Many of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX>'s specific points are
reasonable, but it's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place where he has a categorically dismissive
rather than explanatory tone. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> were all dupes, so were the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lefties</ENAMEX>; this is a picture of the antiwar movement similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX>'
mental picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNamara</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rostow</ENAMEX>. That this hasn't yet created a
flap may mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> haven't noticed. Or it may mean that the emotional
steam has gone out of the whole subject. If so, I think the rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>
has a lot to do with it. Or it could just be actuarial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. The median age
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is just over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>, so most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have no personal memory
whatsoever of this episode.

            On to the disagreement. There is so much in this book that I'd like to go
into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> different themes that it raises. But one is most important--and it's
the main one where I disagree both with you and with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX>.

            To recap: The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> great axioms of the book are: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> constantly
test each other for dominance, and if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side shrinks from a fight, even a
symbolic one as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, its perceived "weakness" will cascade into real
weakness, as other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> classify it as a loser. But also <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> will stomach wars, other than total wars against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, only as long as
the casualty rate is low.

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">No. 1</ENAMEX>, for reasons we just don't have space for here, I think that Lind
presents the "bandwagon" effect of weakness in too sweeping and mechanistic a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>. But that's because I belong to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> he's specifically arguing against:
the "minimal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">realists</ENAMEX>," who think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> doesn't have to accept every
symbolic challenge. Lind presents <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 2</NUMEX> not as a failing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--as he
hardly could, having written before about the evils of an "overclass" that
avoids military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> and public obligations--but as a realistic factor to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bear</ENAMEX> in mind when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> makes commitments. (As an important corollary to
No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX> argues--unlike many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>--that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> couldn't
have fought <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really</TIMEX>, really casualty-sparing way, with all-out
attacks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX>, because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> would have backed
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Vietnam</ENAMEX> up.)

            When you put these together, you end up with the contention that it was
better to have gone in, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> and all, than to have avoided the fight
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX>. The clinching evidence is supposed to be that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX> is in
better shape than if we hadn't fought.

            Now, I love <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX>. I lived for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>--which beat
its own <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> uprising <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. But even accepting, for
purposes of argument, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s war spared <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invasion</ENAMEX>, it wasn't worth it. We are marveling at an end to rancor after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> , which shows how terrible the damage was within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>.

            The clinching argument on my side comes, you will be pleased to hear, from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>. Lind presents the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> as the time of a revived <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
War, which he endorses as a way to offset the bandwagon of weakness that
followed the collapse of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saigon</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was unbelievably conscious of the
need to avoid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> casualties. This was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who pulled out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>
after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> were bombed there. So he clearly found a way to project a
"bandwagon of strength" without putting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> on the line. Sounds like
effective "minimal realism" to me!

         
      
   
