
   
   
      
         
            Rainmakerman

            On a quiet news day, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with a scoop about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>'s concealment
of fuel tank problems similar to the ones that may have caused the crash of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>
Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> goes with the debate over the patient
privacy rules suggested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toshiba</ENAMEX>'s announcement of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> settlement in a
class-action suit over its laptops, a story also fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> knew about fuel tank
problems--probably related to the ones that caused the explosion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> Flight
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as 1980</TIMEX> but didn't tell safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> about the
findings until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this June</TIMEX>. Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> couldn't have prevented the tragedy,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> said that knowing about the fuel tank flaws would have led them
to realize much more quickly that the explosion resulted from mechanical
failure. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> threatened to use the report in
their <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion-dollar</NUMEX> lawsuits against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lead explains why some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> are
protesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s proposed rules on patient privacy (see
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s column for a rundown of the rules). Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> have said that the
rules--which ask only for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> notification and not consent--don't grant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> enough discretion over their medical records. And insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
are worried that the rules would make them responsible for privacy lapses by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> working together. As an example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says that an HMO
that directs a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> to a pharmacy could be liable if the pharmacy abuses
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s records.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that laptop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> sued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toshiba</ENAMEX>
over a flaw in the machines' floppy-disk controller that may cause data in
disks to be lost or corrupted. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toshiba</ENAMEX> has now agreed to incorporate new floppy
disk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controllers</ENAMEX> in PCs and provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> with coupons worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 to $225</NUMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s credit rating was immediately downgraded, and its share price
slipped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9 percent</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story is much sharper, naming the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5.5-million</NUMEX> laptop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>--and more importantly, the odd fact
that none of them seem to have actually suffered from the glitch. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toshiba</ENAMEX> seems
to have made the offer purely for its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> value, saying that it "wants to
continue to ensure its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toshiba</ENAMEX> brand name merits their
trust."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-lead is a terrific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exposé</ENAMEX> of the campaign that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schering-Plough</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> of the ubiquitous anti-allergy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Claritin</ENAMEX>, has waged
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in hope of being allowed to extend its wildly lucrative patent on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>. The lobbying effort has yielded a bill that, if passed, will let
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schering-Plough</ENAMEX> petition a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">review board</ENAMEX> to extend the patent for
another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>, thus preventing cheaper generic versions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> from
being sold. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Torricelli</ENAMEX> introduced the bill <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> (both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called the timing a coincidence). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>
scheduled a hearing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torricelli</ENAMEX> bill just after he was granted use of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schering-Plough Gulfstream</ENAMEX> for campaign travel. And after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schering-Plough</ENAMEX>
donated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> to former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon general</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Everett Koop</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koop</ENAMEX>
wrote letters to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> arguing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s behalf.
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schering-Plough</ENAMEX> argued that it needs its Claritin profits to pay for
groundbreaking, lifesaving drug research and development. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the
company netted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.8 billion</NUMEX> in profit, even after spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a billion</NUMEX> bucks on
said research.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">pager</NUMEX> describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rainwater</ENAMEX>
served as a financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Svengali</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, guiding him into a
stunningly successful series of investments. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> first sought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainwater</ENAMEX>'s help
in buying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rangers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> eventually made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14.9 million</NUMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> from a total investment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$606,000</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainwater</ENAMEX> began feeding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
opportunities in oil and gas, real estate, and a loan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> sold his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainwater</ENAMEX>-related investments when he began his presidential run, presumably to
avoid impropriety or the appearance thereof. The piece concedes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
doesn't seem to have done Rainwater any special favors as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, but
anticipates "more potential for conflict" if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> becomes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. This is
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainwater</ENAMEX> "is involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that are heavily regulated and have
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX> contracts." But <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>
would like to know how many recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> that
meet that description. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> adds that one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainwater</ENAMEX>'s many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>,
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> of psychiatric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, is being investigated for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> abuse
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> fraud but doesn't explain how a newly elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> could possibly
put a damper on the already-ongoing investigations. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s history with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainwater</ENAMEX> has already been much discussed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Richards</ENAMEX> once said that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainwater</ENAMEX> "owned" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dubya</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> seems to simply be recycling old
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> news for a national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metro</ENAMEX>" section story reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burkittsville</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>--home of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> in the eponymous film--are thoroughly spooked by
the onset of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX>. They have been profiteering off the film since its
release (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> sold the rocks from her backyard for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> each). But now
they fear that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> will bring violence from "copycat" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witches</ENAMEX> and
have enlisted protection from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Police</ENAMEX> and the county
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sheriff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burkittsville</ENAMEX> folk truly think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> will be
able to protect them at a time like this, then they haven't seen nearly enough
horror films.

         
      
   
