
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese Mini</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music and the Death of Irony</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Merrill</ENAMEX>,

            Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>! It's an honor to share breakfast conversation with one of the
few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the disgruntled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smartasses</ENAMEX> of my formless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> can genuinely
look up to as a formative influence. So, it was with particular pleasure that
today, as I do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, I padded across the floors of my suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Island</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in my color-coordinated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.L. Bean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slippers</ENAMEX>, pajamas, and bathrobe matching
set, sat down in my spacious breakfast nook over my customary <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> muffin
and marmalade, took a sip of this delightful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> blend my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I picked
up in the most adorable little catalogue we found, and began flipping through
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals</ENAMEX> in search of something pithy and clever to ruminate upon.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> did I find it! It looks like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> camp is really in a tizzy over
the latest ...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Er ... ah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHEM</ENAMEX>. OK. So I'm lying. I, uh, don't live a life anywhere
remotely near what I gather the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> of 
                  Slate
                must be
like. (No offense, everybody.) To be honest, I was up until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 4 or 5 a.m.</TIMEX>,
as I am almost every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Ghost</ENAMEX> cartoons in a drugged
haze, after seriously pissing off my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> by turning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>'s
Onion assignments really, really late. Since, like many self-hating
depressives, I don't normally even get out of bed until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least noon</TIMEX>, it sure
felt weird dragging myself into the corner store to buy the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> editions of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> (for some reason they
didn't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ) for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in, gee, um, oh,
say, my entire life (I generally do get around to reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , but
that's because I get paid to make fun of it) and wondering just how a longhair
dropout like myself somehow ended up, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this one week</TIMEX> anyway, being an actual
official <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> (of sorts) of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richest Guy</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freaking Universe</ENAMEX>.

            But I did find something wonderful, actually, and right on the front page of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> : the profile on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Takahito Sakurai</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> who
creates the music that announces the arrival and departure of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s commuter
trains. Because the schedule is so busy, each composition has to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only seven</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> long, but he still considers it his mandate to make each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them
True Art. Too cool. When you consider that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is also the center of
something called the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Osaka Noise Scene</ENAMEX>, a sort of hardcore punk based solely on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feedback</ENAMEX> and industrial sounds played at screeching, distorted levels, you get
a situation where the tie-wearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salarymen</ENAMEX> (a great word) are listening to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-second</TIMEX> music on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> and the punk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are listening in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> to
extended <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour-long</TIMEX> jams that sound exactly like a screeching, out-of-control
train. It's this sort of postmodern news story that I love the most, because
you're not sure if it makes you want to laugh or cry. (My favorite type of
found comedy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX>.)

            Also, I realize we're supposed to keep this current and newsy, and this is
definitely an old story by now, but I just have to ask what you think about the
whole <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of Irony</ENAMEX> debate that everybody was talking about a while back. As a
Master Ironist yourself, you must have had some thoughts about this character
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jedediah Purdy</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jed Clampett</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Joad</ENAMEX> or whatever his mame is. I myself
thought it'd be cool to take out a full-page ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">someplace</ENAMEX> as an "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open Letter</ENAMEX>"
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Onion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> saying "Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Purdy</ENAMEX>: We're sorry. We were
just trying to be funny. We only wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to like us. We promise not to do
it again," etc, but I can't afford a full page of the paper I work for, let
alone of a publication a sincere, earnest gentleman of his ilk would be likely
to read.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Regards,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
