
   
   
      
         
            What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fools These Mortals Be</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dear Lisa</ENAMEX>,

            Back for more! It's always fun to share favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>. Someone once said
that the world could be divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> categories--those who laughed at the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Stooges</ENAMEX> and those who wondered why. Not to stretch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dawn/Curly</ENAMEX> analogy
too far, but you know what I mean.

            As for my editing process, I've messed with the letters somewhat less than I
did with the diaries, for the simple reason that <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> had already edited the
letters before she sent them out. With the diaries, she was writing solely for
herself (at least in theory) and sometimes became a little sloppy or redundant,
as we will in purely personal jottings or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> drafts. Since I already felt a
little uncomfortable publishing the diaries--I'd never want that done to me!--I
thought it important to tidy her up here and there. (All of the words in the
published Diaries are <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX>'s own, but some of the external structures
are mine.)

            With the letters, I've trimmed them and occasionally deleted passages and
names, but otherwise they're pretty much as she wrote them. Although it's a
"reading edition," from the start I've always tried to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> purist. As
you know, when the marvelous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Steerforth</ENAMEX> press brought out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX>'s genuine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">masterpieces</ENAMEX>, originally released as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tenth Moon</ENAMEX> , I asked them to
call it Come Back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sorrento</ENAMEX> , for that was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>'s title--and we know
from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diaries</ENAMEX> that she was furious about the name her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> had
inflicted on her. Moreover, I've asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steerforth</ENAMEX> not to reissue Whither
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX>), which was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel that she published. It's not quite as bad as
she thought it was, but since she spent the rest of her life buying up any copy
she found and destroying it and never mentioned it in any lists of her work, I
think it ought to rest in peace, don't you?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Howard Lawson</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1894-1977</TIMEX>) was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted</ENAMEX> and original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX>.
Unfortunately, he was also a philanderer--what they used to call a "ladies
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>"--as well as a rigid <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stalinist</ENAMEX>. As such, he was hardly <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX>'s type--can you
imagine her mouthing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marxian</ENAMEX> jargon with any sort of straight face?--but he
seems to have been the great romantic love of her life, after her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, to
whom it should be remembered that she remained married for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42 years</TIMEX>. I believe
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Bride</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> (not one of her best but
very interesting for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX>), is deeply autobiographical. It was written
at the beginning of her probable affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawson</ENAMEX>, while she was also still
living at home with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, and it is wracked with private
haunting.

            And yes--I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> had a tough life, certainly a difficult one, but it
was also, as you say, a good life as well in its way. Her humor was the key, I
think; that, and her passion for work. It can safely be said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> lived
to write; her art, so rich in its laughter (even in some passages of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">saddest</ENAMEX> books), buoyed her up. How could she have stood all that she went
through otherwise--an impaired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, a difficult marriage, recurring health
problems, impoverishment, and what was essentially a period of homelessness
(<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this last</TIMEX> when she was in her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">60s</NUMEX>)? She was one strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, and humor was
her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shield</ENAMEX>.

            I agree with you that sexism likely played a part in her long
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underappreciation</ENAMEX>. On the other hand, I have found that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> actively
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">resent Powell</ENAMEX> for making fun of her gender as brilliantly as she made fun of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. I think the literary left was unhappy that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> were likely to be
as silly as her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>. I think social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> were unhappy with all of
those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> who drank too much, slept around, behaved foolishly,
and yet remained funny, agreeable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> was never an "uplifter." She
was an equal-opportunity satirist, and took her fun where she found it. She has
some of the bright, distanced amusement we find in the best comedies of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> antiquity.

            Or, if you prefer, she echoes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>--"What fools these mortals be!"
And we are. But she liked us anyway.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Yours</ENAMEX> till next time,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
