
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office Shooting du Jour</ENAMEX>
            

            Right, fragmented attention <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">spans</ENAMEX>. Very important ...

            I'd like to comment on that, but I'm watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> at the moment and can't
concentrate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> have just put out an APB for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> in the
office shooting du jour (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> dead so far, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two critical</TIMEX>, one stable). The
suspect, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of course, was wearing a brown hat, according to the police
account. And camouflage clothes. Aside from that, he looked pretty
average--average height, hair color, skin color (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> said he was either a
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a light-skinned</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>). Horribly, what he's done is starting
to sound pretty average, too: He went into an office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> (want to bet it's
his?) and opened fire. The television coverage is all too average as well: Lots
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX> on the spots, excitedly telling what they know "at this point" (not
much) and second-guessing themselves by telling TV Land which neighborhood the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> are searching, then showing the neighborhood from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX>, then
deciding that it was a boneheaded move to show where, exactly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hunting</ENAMEX> (let's not let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX> know where the cops are!). and zipping over
to another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX> on the spots who doesn't know much. At this point.

            Ah, is there anything that's at once so exhilarating and banal as breaking
news? I know that sounds callous and I apologize--someone is dead, perhaps
others will be too soon--but stories like this are far and away the worst thing
that we in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> do. Remember when we were both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior reporters</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> , doing far too much police news, knocking on the doors of the
dead and the near dead? And remember that time when that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady hissed</ENAMEX> at you?
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VULTURE</ENAMEX>," she hissed. We are vultures ... We feed off dead things and help the
overall process of decomposition. Why am I watching this broadcast? Why is it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> news? What good does it do? Where's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> need to know here?
Won't it just inspire another nut to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> down his officemates? Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolmates</ENAMEX>?
Then he can be on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, too.

            Oh, cool: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Video</ENAMEX> footage just came on showing the cops storming a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those SWAT shields. This is getting good. See you at dinner. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gotta</ENAMEX>
go.

         
      
   
