
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey Clubbed</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s earthquake in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, a story the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> fronts and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> slips inside. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead
announces that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has won the federal budget battles, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes with a scoop on the likely veto of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI-Sprint</ENAMEX> merger by
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> quake registered a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.2</NUMEX> on the
standard measuring scale (the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 17</TIMEX> one was a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.4</NUMEX>) and was closely centered
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bolu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>, halfway between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Istanbul</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX> (the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 17</TIMEX> one
hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bolu</ENAMEX>, but its impact spanned a much wider area). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> have been killed and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> injured; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> dead
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> injured. Even though this earthquake seems to have been less lethal
than the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> one, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is experiencing a horrible bout of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">déjà vu</ENAMEX>,
with reports of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> trapped under small mountains of rubble and widespread
frustration at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s ineffectual relief efforts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story
emphasizes that the quake came, inconveniently enough, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two days</TIMEX> before
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is supposed to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> summit (the trip
is still on).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> tallies the partisan wins and losses in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s federal
budget wars and declares <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the clear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">victor</ENAMEX>. The evidence: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have reluctantly loaded their bills with an extra <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 billion</NUMEX> in
spending and allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to pass his program for adding teachers
nationwide. That said, the story adds that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> could have done
worse, especially given their thin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>, inexperienced new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>,
low poll ratings, and internecine strife between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX>.
They managed to dedicate more money than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wanted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> and
military salaries and establish themselves as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protectors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
revenue. Now, says the story, they simply "want to go home."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead, sourced to "knowledgeable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX>," reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> will veto the merger between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI WorldCom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX>, on the grounds
that it would allow too few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to control too much of the long-distance
market. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> and the new mega-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WorldCom Inc.</ENAMEX> would control <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 80 percent</NUMEX>
of long-distance service. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WorldCom</ENAMEX> is spinning the deal as "the
single best hope for a strong and effective alternative to the mega-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bells</ENAMEX> and
the emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> alone fronts news of a terrorist attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
targets in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers planted explosives</ENAMEX> in parked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. Only a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were hurt in the blasts. No one has
claimed responsibility, but most suspect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>, which controls
most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> has denied involvement,
but the bombs are widely perceived as a message to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>, which is set to
impose sanctions against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> if it fails to expel or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extradite Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front the latest on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">990</NUMEX>
evidence of fire, loss of cabin pressure, or any other clear reason for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plane</ENAMEX>'s sharp descent. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> have found still-inconclusive evidence
that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> may have been thrusting the controls in opposite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directions</ENAMEX>, and surmise that they may have been fighting each other, struggling
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>, or simply panicking. "The dive was so violent that unbelted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> would have floated about the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP</ENAMEX> describes
dramatically.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Manes</ENAMEX>, who sold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX> Klebold
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Harris</ENAMEX> one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> they used in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> massacre, was
sentenced to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. The trial's biggest revelation was that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klebold</ENAMEX> had made a videotape outlining their plan, thanking those
who had helped them obtain the necessary <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, and assuring future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>
that they were acting alone without anyone else's knowledge. "Let me tell you
this much, they have no clue. So don't blame them and arrest them for what we
did," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klebold</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> quoted from the tape, but it was not released to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parkay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entenmann</ENAMEX>'s beware: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>
guidelines that, if accepted, would include a count of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">trans fatty acids</ENAMEX>--aka
"stealth fat"--on nutrition labels. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trans</ENAMEX> fatty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>, common in margarines and
baked goods, are unanimously thought by nutritionists to contribute to heart
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Foods</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than half</NUMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gram</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">trans fat</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a half gram</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">saturated fat</ENAMEX> per serving could proudly claim to be "trans fat free."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts the pomp-filled reinterrment of the
remains of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> whose graves were recently found under a
sports <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> puts the story inside). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> had originally been buried in an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mariners</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery</ENAMEX>, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citadel</ENAMEX> built a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> on the site without properly exhuming the graves,
which were finally discovered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> by a neo-Confederate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Volunteers</ENAMEX> spent most of the summer digging the site up, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil</ENAMEX>
War re-enactment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> gave them a full <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> burial, including a
rousing rendition of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dixie</ENAMEX>." The papers agree that the event epitomized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX>'s stubborn and controversial attachment to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederate</ENAMEX> symbols. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> is currently boycotting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> for flying the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> flag. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Hodges</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> to drop the boycott on the condition that
he push for a bill designating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX>'s birthday as a state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> is also the only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that still flies the flag and
doesn't celebrate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s birthday. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> "doesn't care about the flag,
they're just doing this to raise money," <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">State Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ravenel</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
