
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stocking Up</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with the Nasdaq composite index breaking the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> barrier,
a story topping the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business and Finance</ENAMEX>" box. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note that the
index has risen <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, buoyed by a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of weighted tech
stocks like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX> are cautiously optimistic, and
although a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> article says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> is unlikely to raise
interest rates again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, the other papers note that Wall Street will
wait for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>'s employment figures (to be released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>) before reaching a
conclusion. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> lawsuit against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> utility
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> for pollution violations, a story reefered by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> alleges that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> coal-powered plants
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> lack appropriate
pollution-control equipment. Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's story, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> 's story mentions prominently the probable cost increases for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> asserts, without attribution, that new
pollution controls will cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
mentions--at the end of its story--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s estimate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 million</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>.)

            The non-local lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>'s decision to make
the lifting of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> sanctions contingent on free elections, rather than on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s relinquishing power. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> broke this story
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>; see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>.) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's non-local lead is a report on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> civil war: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> have
become so well-stocked with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration is requesting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $2 billion</NUMEX> in aid to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX>
government over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three years</TIMEX> (compared to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$289 million</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'99</NUMEX>). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports inside that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>, who began peace talks with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 24</TIMEX>, have started kidnapping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> with increasing
frequency.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> workplace massacre is fronted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and reefered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX> wore fatigues to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shipyard</ENAMEX> and shot
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">9mm</NUMEX> handgun, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. He is still at large. (Note: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">online</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's story links to: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Discussion: Does</ENAMEX> media coverage of shooting sprees lead to copycat
crimes?" Furthermore: Does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> 's coverage of media coverage of
shooting sprees lead to copycat crimes?)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front the latest radar data from the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> crash.
After falling suddenly from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">33,000 feet to 16,000 feet</NUMEX> (and perhaps reaching
the speed of sound), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> rose like a roller coaster to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">24,000 feet</NUMEX> and
then dropped again to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10,000 feet</NUMEX>, at which point it was "no longer consistent

            The LAT fronts and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reefers (with an above-the-fold photo) stories on the aftermath of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cyclone</ENAMEX>, which left <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 3,000 to 5,000</NUMEX> dead. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> describe half-naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> boiling water amid flattened huts, with
bloated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>--both <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">livestock</ENAMEX> and human--being picked apart by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and crows.
"The winds have plucked off slabs of concrete and left the sidewalks
gap-toothed," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> correspondent writes. "Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s dead
have been discovered <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 miles</NUMEX> away, carried off in the raging cascades to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kujang</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> fronts, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reefer, the
conviction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron McKinney</ENAMEX> for second-degree murder, kidnapping, and robbery
in the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Shepard</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> is eligible for
the death penalty, the lack of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-degree-murder conviction and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>'s
historic reluctance to use the death penalty makes that sentence unlikely.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs a fascinating "where-are-they-now?" dispatch from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>
on the student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX> who stormed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Embassy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago today</TIMEX>.
Many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are now reformists pressing for open, secular
government. And although there will be government-sponsored anti-American
protests <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tehran</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> remembrances will take the form of muted
calls for "dialogue."  "Every revolution at first has special idealistic causes
and aims to change the world," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to organize the
takeover. "But in practice, after a while, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX> will come face
to face with some realities." Now shorn of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary beard</ENAMEX> and wearing
rimless Western spectacles, he says that "after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> of great difficulties,
including a war imposed on us and poor economy," he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> are
"confronting the demand of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to participate in politics." Meanwhile,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s supreme <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayatollah Ali</ENAMEX>
Khamenei, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> denounced pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">U.S. Iranians</ENAMEX> as "traitors" and "simpletons."
On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's opinion page, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> official
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Adelman</ENAMEX> writes a conventional remembrance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostage</ENAMEX> crisis: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> was weak and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> won <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this week</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> seasoned its editorial page with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">delightful</ENAMEX> collection of its best "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper</ENAMEX>" cartoons--a daily
gag-comic begun in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of these cartoons distill several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of
changes in business mores particularly well. In a cartoon from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX>, a
slightly paunchy middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, smoking a stogie under an umbrella on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">beach</ENAMEX>, tells his petite, bikini-clad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> sitting at his feet with her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">typewriter</ENAMEX>, "Take a postcard, Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hobbs</ENAMEX>." And in a cartoon from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>, a
natty, bespectacled young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in an ill-fitting suit says to a professional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> at a cocktail party, "I'm not one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX> who's made a fortune
with some kind of software. I'm just a nerd." From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> alpha to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> beta
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>--we've come a long way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
