
   
   
      
         
            Just the Facts

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Penfield Jackson</ENAMEX>, who is presiding over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> antitrust
trial, issued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">207</NUMEX>-page document that states the software giant
"enjoys monopoly power in the relevant market." The story, with accompanying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">analyses</ENAMEX>, leads at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's
top non-local, non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> story outlines <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s emergent
challenge to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> chronicles the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX>'s release
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> job statistics, which show that unemployment has dipped to its
lowest point in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX>.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> serves up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of several education stories:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seventy</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eighth graders</ENAMEX> failed a standardized
math exam and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65 percent</NUMEX> failed an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> test.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> delivers a powerful reproach to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, claiming that the company
stifled innovation, squeezed out competition, and impaired consumer choice. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conclusions</ENAMEX>, a precursor to the verdict expected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next year</TIMEX>, support the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">breadth of Justice Department</ENAMEX> allegations against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> (which publishes

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> ) and dismisses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s defense as
"specious." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> appeared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> at a press
conference and touted the findings as a victory for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> consumer. In a
videotaped statement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William H.</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">43rd Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>)
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respectfully</ENAMEX> disagreed" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> and defended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s integrity.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ends with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kicker</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> e-mailed his findings to attorneys
and the press in a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Word Perfect</ENAMEX> document--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corel Corp.</ENAMEX>'s alternative to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two-thirds</NUMEX> of the way through, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> cites experts
who say that the findings are hardly surprising (an opinion also expressed by

                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Moneybox</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that they cannot remember another antitrust trial
in which findings of fact were released before the actual verdict. This was
interpreted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> as a gesture intended to elicit a settlement. If
none is reached, appeals may drag on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> say.

            After holding at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.2</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.3 percent</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, the unemployment rate fell
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.1 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports on its front. (Each
percentage point equates to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly one million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.) The drop brought with
it only insignificant wage inflation, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1 percent</NUMEX>. The bright news put markets
in good shape before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> close, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> predict that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> will
be less inclined to raise interest rates when it meets <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 16</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s increasing visibility is attributed to the disappearance of half
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> campaign field, a floundering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, a best-selling memoir, and
the ability to draw in the politically disenchanted. The story emphasizes the
speed with which the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> campaign has ripened, but questions whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
can hold on with significantly less money than his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
mentions the outcome of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 14</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> straw poll, but doesn't say that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> thumbed his nose at it and trotted off to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> instead.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> revealed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
and the food stamp program, paid out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.1 billion</NUMEX> they shouldn't have during
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998 fiscal year</TIMEX>. Such payments sometimes come about through bad
information, accounting errors, or fraud, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> suggested that the wasted dollars could add up when retiring baby
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> put increased pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> coffers.

            Beyond their shock value, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s test scores made news because the
state is undergoing a high-profile tightening of educational standards. In
coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, statewide tests (with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> work and attendance) will determine
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> advance to the next grade. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that a sharply
divided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> to go forward with its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>-voucher
program until a definitive ruling is reached about whether the program violates
the separation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> attend parochial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> using public money. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> decided to suspend an injunction
preventing new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from joining the program. Finally, the LAT
fronts and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs inside official word of a change in leadership
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> split the difference on a story about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> drive for a missile-defense system. The latter highlights European
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>' "serious alarm" at the shield, which could damage military and
diplomatic ties across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>, and (somehow less likely) provoke an arms
race with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. This does not faze the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>, which writes
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> could unilaterally pull out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1972 Anti-Ballistic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Missile Treaty</ENAMEX>, despite what anyone thinks. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> spearheaded a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
protest vote, supported by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, that upheld the treaty's integrity.

            Just how tricky are things in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>? An inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead
details <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s reaction to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s "inability [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>] to name the leaders
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>. The latter,
however, isn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, but--as its ever-present <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homeric</ENAMEX> epithet indicates--a
"breakaway republic" of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. Perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>, which calls it a
"breakaway region" later on in the piece, was latently distracted by a blink in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> datelines. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three consecutive days</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early October</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
stories began "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GROZNY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GROZNY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>," and again "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GROZNY</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
