
   
   
      
         
            Hot Coca

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times fronts an accord to admit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX>--a story that broke too late to make the print editions of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> and too late for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> to change its print lead (a
feature story on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>'s signing ceremony (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>)--the culmination of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a decade</TIMEX> of intermittent negotiations
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>--comes after a week of intense, last-ditch
efforts by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoys</ENAMEX> to ink a deal by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 30</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> still needs the consent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> and several other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.) Neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story, nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>, nor online
stories by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> has any details about the agreement.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last evening</TIMEX>'s report by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> that the EgyptAir
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">990</NUMEX> cockpit voice recorder gives no evidence of a crime--a story that does not
make the early editions of the other papers. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> are talking "like
pals" when ''something happens," an anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>. "Alarms go
off. Both work to try to fix it. There is some kind of problem that they're
dealing with. It gets progressively worse. And the tape stops.'' The
Post leads with a profile of the new generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">smugglers</ENAMEX>. Unlike the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Medellin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cali</ENAMEX> cartels, these traffickers
maintain a low profile, do not commit terrorist acts, are tech-savvy, and
reduce their organizational structure by merging licit and illicit business and
by hiring outside smugglers on a per-job basis. They also cooperate with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insurgents</ENAMEX>, who control much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. As a result,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> expects to double or treble its estimate of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coca</ENAMEX> production. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with an update on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> invasion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX> in
which "chaos and violent death remain facts of life." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads
with fears among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> will lose
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control of the House of Representatives</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next fall</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officeholders</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains, have retired twice as
fast as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, fund-raising is below expectations, and to hedge their bets,
business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are uncharacteristically giving soft money equally to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> runs a similar piece lamenting the
explosion of partisanship and gridlock on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ,
however, fronts an article concluding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s budget victories are a
mixed blessing: He had defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> attacks, but launched no initiatives of his
own.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> off-leads <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British telecom Vodafone Airtouch</ENAMEX>'s failed friendly
takeover of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">behemoth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mannesmann A.G.</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$106.4 billion</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> expect
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>--including, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> notes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vodafone</ENAMEX>'s
cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Atlantic</ENAMEX>--to compete in a bidding war for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mannesmann</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> puts atop its "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwide</ENAMEX>" box--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reefers</ENAMEX>--the agreement reached by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> to pay back <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> dues. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> compromised on funding for international
family-planning programs--a stance <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> hinted at in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
lead (see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TP</ENAMEX>").

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> fronts--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reefers with an
above-the-fold picture--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s unusual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Square Garden</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fund-raiser</ENAMEX>, which netted, pardon the pun, nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,500</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attendees</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,000</NUMEX>), who paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $50 and $1,000</NUMEX>, got
to dribble an obstacle course and listen to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA Hall of Famers</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>) extol the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. "It was ironic," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes sourly in an otherwise glowing story, "that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
stopped watching <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>, who wouldn't do sports interviews, who wouldn't
even play a pickup game after his career ended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, would be the instigator
of such an occasion." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>' reactions to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s basketball bash.) Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>
reports that former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> will endorse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
and join his campaign. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s unique <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> experience.)

            On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Op-Ed</ENAMEX> page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon G. Chang</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for
an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> negotiations are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overhyped</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s claimed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.8 percent</NUMEX> growth is illusory, the writer
asserts--the economy is actually just barely expanding, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">debt-ridden</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> are unemployed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> or no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> will have to
reform its economy.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Chemical</ENAMEX> has revolutionized slime. Not
just any slime, mind you, but <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methyl cellulose</ENAMEX>--a wood pulp broken down by
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> into a tasteless, odorless, calorie-less goo. Unlike most <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methyl cellulose thickens</ENAMEX>, rather than thins, upon heating, and is safe to eat.
Unlike most starch-based food <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">additives</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methyl cellulose</ENAMEX> gives a buttery,
rather than pasty, flavor. Discovered accidentally in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, it was kept on
a shelf until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early this decade</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> decided to market it aggressively.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it is used for special effects in movies and for time-release <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX>,
as a grease-sponge in frozen dinners, as an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>-white substitute for vegans,
and as a thickener in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soups</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauces</ENAMEX>, and gravies. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> problem: getting food
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cellulose</ENAMEX> treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> is safe to eat.
To put his money where his mouth is--or, in this case, his mouth where his
money is--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> recently used an overhead transparency made of the
substance for a presentation in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. After he was done,
he proceeded to wolf down the transparent, ink-stained sheet.

         
      
   
