
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Etymology</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bumfuzzled</ENAMEX>"

            
               Note: Throughout this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX>, whenever the word "bumfuzzled" appears
in italics, the italics are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox's</ENAMEX>, not those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>.
            

            The lead story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> budget passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, which he
intends to veto, "totally bumfuzzled " <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> on the question of
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> funds would be tapped for current spending. Chatterbox
doesn't much care whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> funds are tapped for current
spending, but he knows the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are making a big show of caring about
that and therefore are being somewhat dishonest in pretending that they won't.
But what really interests <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s use of the word,
bumfuzzled , which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has never heard before.

            Here is precisely what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said (at an unrelated awards ceremony for
"blue ribbon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Hilton</ENAMEX>; interestingly, the transcription available on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> Web
site spells it "bum-fusseled," which is incorrect; Chatterbox here uses the
text supplied by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal News Service</ENAMEX>, which spelled bumfuzzled
correctly):

            
               [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]hey tried to say they weren't spending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
surplus--[chuckles]--and tried to blame us with wanting to, which is a miracle
how they got that done. [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Laughter</ENAMEX>.]
            

            And--but you need to know--and when you go back home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--I can imagine
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> must be totally bumfuzzled ; keep announcing
surpluses and we keep having budget fights. That's what's going on here.

            Chatterbox at first felt sure that bumfuzzled was a coinage of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s, like (but more colorful than) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Harding</ENAMEX>'s coinage of
"normalcy." The meaning, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> suspected, had to do with an intimate act
sometimes performed in the shower <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> of correctional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. In fact,
though, it's a real word. An <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 4</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> article about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Morris</ENAMEX>, a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rookie</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa Bay Devil Rays</ENAMEX>, quotes a baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout</ENAMEX> saying
he was "bumfuzzled " when he saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">98 mph</NUMEX> fastball. And a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 9</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Beason</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama Space Science Exhibit</ENAMEX>
Commission, saying, "I'm just bumfuzzled " that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Space and Rocket</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntsville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala.</ENAMEX>, might be for sale.

            Is bumfuzzled obscene? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authoritative sources</ENAMEX> suggest it isn't. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Heritage dictionary</ENAMEX> says that bumfuzzle , apparently used
chiefly in the southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, means "to confuse," and probably derives
from some combination of "bamboozle," "fuddle," and "fuzzy." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Unabridged dictionary</ENAMEX> says the term first came into use around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>
and agrees with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Heritage</ENAMEX> hypothesis about its derivation.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merriam-Webster Unabridged</ENAMEX> says bumfuzzle is an "alteration
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">dialect</ENAMEX>, 'dumfoozle' and 'dumfound.' "

            If there is an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> link, it's possible the link is somewhat racy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weiner</ENAMEX>, who wrote the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> piece, wonders whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bumfuzzled</ENAMEX> has
at least some associative link to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> slang term bumf , a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shortened</ENAMEX> version of "bumfodder ," or toilet paper. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bumf</ENAMEX> is
defined in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Shorter Oxford Dictionary</ENAMEX> as "toilet paper; worthless
literature; (usually derog. documents, official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>)." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bumf</ENAMEX> would, of
course, be an especially insulting way for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to refer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' budget, and it does seem plausible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> encountered the
word when he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weiner</ENAMEX> says he himself learned
the term bumf from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> .) On
reflection, though, this reading seems more entertaining than sound.

            Chatterbox was curious to see how bumfuzzled was used in the
traditional literature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">American South</ENAMEX>. To that end, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> searched
the online collection at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of North Carolina</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for the</ENAMEX>
Study of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">American South</ENAMEX> and found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> uses of the word. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> was
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Georgia Sketches</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Nathaniel Harben</ENAMEX>. Harben
was apparently a protégé of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Chandler Harris</ENAMEX>, who wrote the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Remus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stories; Northern Georgia Sketches</ENAMEX> is dedicated to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>, "in grateful
acknowledgement of the kindly encouragement which made this book possible."
Here is how "bumfuzzled" appears in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harben</ENAMEX>'s book (which was published in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>):

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, I'll be liter'ly bumfuzzled!" he exclaimed. "Ef it ain't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ericson</ENAMEX>! I knowed yore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was in the fight last night, an' I thought o'
you when I heerd the grape-shot a-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plinkin</ENAMEX>' out thar. But hang me, ef you don't
look sick ur half starved! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally</ENAMEX>, give 'im some'n' t' eat. They don't feed the
rebs much. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX>, she's been a-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pinin</ENAMEX>' fer you ever sence you enlisted, an'
last night <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">durin</ENAMEX>' the fight she mighty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nigh</ENAMEX> went distracted. She - "
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandpa</ENAMEX>, that's a lie!" cried the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, fiercely; but there were pink spots
in her cheeks as she retreated into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> and began to slam the pots and
pans on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone hearth</ENAMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> reference to bumfuzzled was in History
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wm</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mack Lee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Body Servant</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert E. Lee</ENAMEX>
Through the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> , published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1918</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>, a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> (and, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> presumes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s book
quotes at length a profile of himself that appeared in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bedford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>,
Bulletin . It is here that the word bumfuzzled appears. Chatterbox
will give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> (as quoted in the Bulletin 's profoundly
politically incorrect account) the last word:

            
               "The onliest time that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marse Robert</ENAMEX> ever scolded me," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Mack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>, "in de whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fo</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> dat I followed him through the wah, was, down in de
Wilderness--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven Pines</ENAMEX>--near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>. I remembah dat day jes lak it was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yestiday</ENAMEX>. Hit was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July the third, 1863</TIMEX>.
            

            "Whilst we was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Petersburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marse Robert</ENAMEX> had done got him a little black
hen from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and we named the little black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nellie</ENAMEX>. She was a good hen,
and laid mighty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nar</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. We <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kep</ENAMEX>' her in de ambulants, whar she had her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nest</ENAMEX>. ... On dat day--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>--we was all so hongry and I didn't have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nuffin</ENAMEX> in ter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX>, dat I was jes' plumb bumfuzzled . I didn't know what
to do. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marse Robert</ENAMEX>, he had gone and invited a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of ginerals to eat wid
him, an' I had ter git de vittles. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dar</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marse Stonewall Jackson</ENAMEX>, and Marse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. P. Hill</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marse D. H. Hill</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marse Wade Hampton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gineral Longstreet</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gineral Pickett</ENAMEX> and sum others.

            "I had done made some flanel cakes, a little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>, and some lemonade, but I
'lowed as how dat would not be enuff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fo</ENAMEX>' dem gemm'n. So I had to go out to de
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ambulants</ENAMEX> and cotch de little black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nellie</ENAMEX>.

            There was a tear in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Mack Lee</ENAMEX>'s voice, but in his eye I fancied that
I saw the happy light that always dances in the eyes of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> at the thought
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fowl</ENAMEX> for cooking.

            "I jes' had to go out and cotch little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nellie</ENAMEX>. I picked her good, and
stuffed her with breod stuffin, mixed wid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nellie</ENAMEX> had been gwine wid us
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, and I hated fer to lose her. We had been gettin' all our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nellie</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, sir, when I brung <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nellie inter de commissary</ENAMEX> tent and set her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fo</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marse Robert</ENAMEX> he turned to me right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fo</ENAMEX>' all dem gimmin and he says: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">'William,</ENAMEX>
now you have killed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nellie</ENAMEX>. What are we going to do for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>?"

            " 'I <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jes</ENAMEX>' had ter do it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marse Robert</ENAMEX>.' says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I.</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'No</ENAMEX>, you didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>; I'm going to write Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> about you. I'm going
to tell her you have killed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nellie</ENAMEX>.'

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Marse Robert kep</ENAMEX>' on scoldin' me mout dat hen. He never scolded 'bout
naything else. He tol' me I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> to kill de her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whut</ENAMEX> lay de golden <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>.
Hit made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marse Robert</ENAMEX> awful sad ter think of anything bein' killed, whedder der
'twas one of his soljers, or his little black hen."

         
      
   
