
   
   
      
         
            <i><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX></i>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Part II: Calling Willes' Bluff</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has experienced much frustration trying to figure out precisely
what's gone amiss at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . First it was reported (by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Barrs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Times L.A.</ENAMEX> ) that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> was sharing
advertising revenue from a special issue of its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> with the
subject of that special issue, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> sports <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX>. This
created a predictable (and justified) uproar at the paper, which caused the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Downing</ENAMEX>, to apologize and mumble some nonsense about how she
was unfamiliar with newspaper etiquette, which encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>
at the paper to push <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Parks</ENAMEX> to assign a story about the whole
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fiasco</ENAMEX>, which he eventually did (to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shaw</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer-</ENAMEX>winning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>). It also prompted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> to puzzle over the apparent financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">insanity</ENAMEX> of a deal in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> paid the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> 2
or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3 million dollars</NUMEX> in exchange for what seemed at best <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800,000</NUMEX> worth of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> wrote the earlier
item, he was unaware that even before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Times L.A.</ENAMEX> scoop, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Business Journal</ENAMEX> had broken another piece of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> story--namely, that the sports <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> had contacted "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, concessionaires and various corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX>" connected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> and asked them "to buy ads in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>; the ads themselves
were sold by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> 's advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>." (This story is not
available online.) Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is better informed, he still
suspects the deal was a ripoff for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> . Surely an aggressive
sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> for a virtual-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly newspaper</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> could shake
down these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> just as effectively. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> must admit that he
doesn't know what other goodies the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> may have extracted from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> also doesn't know how common it is for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> to enlist the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they write about to sell ads. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , after initially
covering the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> story quite aggressively, subsequently had to
admit that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> , which it owned then and continues
to own, ran a special section on its new downtown sports <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleet Center</ENAMEX>, which relied on ads procured by ... the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fleet Center</ENAMEX>. "We treated
them as a sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> and paid them a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> for ads that they sold,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gulla</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felicity Barringer</ENAMEX>.
"Will it happen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>? No."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> would love to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downing</ENAMEX> lose her job (and--this is probably too
much to hope for--see her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Mirror</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Willes</ENAMEX>, get canned,
too). Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> doesn't really think a ritual sacrifice will address
the basic underlying problem: When media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> strike secret business deals
with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are unable to evaluate whether these deals might
be compromising news coverage.

            This is not true of advertising, which--say what one will about its
corrupting effect on news coverage--always, by definition , discloses
potential conflicts to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. It would be wonderful if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> could now
be persuaded never to raise revenue by any means other than sales and
advertising, but that's probably impractical. (Newspaper circulation has, after
all, been declining for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>.) A much better step would be for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, Web sites, TV and radio news shows, etc., to
disclose to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, on a regular basis, whatever non-advertising
deals they have going. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX>, for example, could run a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> box
of agate type providing this information, with perhaps a longer summary
provided once or twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.

            Why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> didn't clamor for disclosure long ago, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
Times and elsewhere, is a bit of a mystery. Probably it reflected a
yearning to remain blissfully ignorant of trends in the news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> for as
long as was humanly possible. (Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> knows are more
interested in maintaining their virginity than in actually helping to maintain
the integrity of the business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> they belong to.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>'s cultlike attachment to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otis Chandler</ENAMEX>--the former publisher
and descendant of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> wrote a letter supporting the staff revolt--seems typical of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ineffectuality</ENAMEX>. Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> have (according to a report in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ) lately been
taping photocopied portraits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">newsroom</ENAMEX> walls, in silent protest
against what's being done to his legacy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> was indeed a heroic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> was a mediocre paper when he took it over, a great
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> when he stepped down--and it would be wonderful if he were reinstated or
allowed a say about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s fate. But by all accounts, he won't be; despite
owning more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> stock than anyone else, he's outgunned on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> by an assortment of younger, much more crass and stock-price-obsessed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> cousins.

            A more productive way for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX> would be
if they demanded to learn--and share with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>--comprehensive information
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s undisclosed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of income and labor. By doing so, they
would be endorsing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Willes</ENAMEX>' view that the wall between the news and
business sides of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> needs to be breached. But they would have the
satisfaction of knowing they were breaching it in a way that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX> and his ilk
would find unpleasant precisely to the extent that it exposed unpleasant
practices.

            Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thinks disclosure of non-advertising business revenue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> should be a news-industry norm, he will hereby do a little disclosing
of his own. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> mentions a book that is in print, he usually
provides a link to it at barnesandnoble.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. This is because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noble</ENAMEX>
pays 
                  Slate
                a sliver of the proceeds whenever someone buys through
a 
                  Slate
                link. Chatterbox, who has no ethical objections to this
arrangement, is free to say whatever he wants about the book in question
(frequently, he says the book is no good). He is under no pressure to mention
particular books, or indeed to mention any books at all, and does so only when
he thinks his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> might want to examine his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> material. (Chatterbox
does the same thing--bringing no financial benefit to 
                  Slate
               --with
the other various source links he provides.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of this column should
be under no illusion that it's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of finding the cheapest or
otherwise best online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> for particular books.

            OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC News</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> , and the rest of you: Your turn.

         
      
   
