
   
   
      
         
            Life on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX> and Off
            

            
               The simple honest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> believes in looking life straight in the TV
and no nonsense. There is less and less connection between what he's doing and
seeing and being and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Real Life</ENAMEX>," because what's really happening is the
lie.

               -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawn Powell</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Tim</ENAMEX>,

            Presumably, we have now taken care of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who the Hell Is Dawn Powell</ENAMEX>." Most of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of literary fiction still don't know, which is why the
articles and reviews all need to cover the identical ground--revealing how you
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heroically</ENAMEX> rescued her papers from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moldy basement</ENAMEX>--thus making it possible
for potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to weary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell Phenomenon</ENAMEX> before they even get to
her work. And since her ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are, I suspect, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> most
churlishly resistant to hype, I fear we may see the eensiest backlash soon.

            Let us admit that the Letters are not the best introduction to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>. Reading the letters of someone whose accomplishments you admire is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voyeuristic</ENAMEX> in the best sense (as opposed to reading a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>'s mail, which
is a peep-show). But for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, her letters are delicious. Such wonderful
balancing acts of literary bravura and homey friendship. They made me rue the
triumph of e-mail--a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>-rush, with no nutritional value. Hardly any of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> I know go to this much trouble online. In fact, I'm not sure you
can.

            Right from the beginning, from her first college letters home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> seemed
to be writing for posterity. She made sure that each bulletin from the front of
her life was whole, vivid, shimmering, and immediate, a perfect vignette. (Of
course, I don't know how much of that effect is due to your editing, but I
assume that, like a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hairdresser</ENAMEX>, you won't tell.) Not too perfect,
though--no grandstanding. Though we don't have the other side, we can tell that
she listened. The letters really make you feel as if you're settling down at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> with her and you're so excited to see each other that you start talking
right away, before the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> arrive, before you even take off your coats.

            After reading her great letters to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Wilson</ENAMEX>, I cracked out
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilson-Nabokov</ENAMEX> correspondence. Compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX>, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir</ENAMEX> feels
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">droning</ENAMEX> and nerdy. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Bunny</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nabokov</ENAMEX> wrote, "that was indeed funny--our
writing to each other on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> and both referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pushkin</ENAMEX>'s atheism."
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Har har.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> seemed to abhor pretension above practically anything. I love
her mocking eggheads at jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> ("I do enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intelligentsia</ENAMEX>'s pretending
they know a horn from a harp while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> pretend they know a book from
a bookie"). I love her mocking the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> ("I really dislike the pallid,
watery-eyed, churchly old-whore sentimentality of their limpid pastoral
novels").

            There's gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galore</ENAMEX> here, but I'm fascinated by how much she left out. You
feel these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> of mystery and secrecy in her. Hardly a word of complaint
about her travails with her autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. (A heartbreaking story, and I must
say, I bitch more about having to help my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> with his homework than she does
about narrowly saving her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> from an experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lobotomy</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins</ENAMEX>.)
Hardly a word about her courtship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Gousha</ENAMEX>--they meet offstage and
zip, they're off to marry--or about the nature of their subsequent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disagreements</ENAMEX>. And then, of course, there's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mystery of the Missing Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> with whom you claim she was hot-and-heavy and whom she
barely mentions (even to herself, in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diaries</ENAMEX>). You suggest they destroyed
all trace of the affair, by mutual decision.

            Do I wish we still had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>'s letters to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawson</ENAMEX>? Only partly. Partly I
admire that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> seemed to really understand the difference between
public and private life. Despite the mountains of verbiage, she had a
private life. I'm thinking, here, of that line in the documentary about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> snipes at her, "If the camera isn't running, do
you exist?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> most decidedly existed, off the page as well as on. And I
think she perceived--ahead of her time--the complicated ways in which most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't exist. They turn into their own ad campaigns.

            Who the hell is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawson</ENAMEX>, anyhow, and did he deserve this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s admiration?
It's fun that he has slunk back into history, while she has risen up. These
letters remind us that, although "underappreciated" in her own time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> was
hardly slaving away in monkish anonymity. She knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylan Thomas</ENAMEX>. She drank with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Beckett</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. She judged a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnard</ENAMEX> fiction
competition with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Bellow</ENAMEX>, and at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yaddo</ENAMEX>, when she had bad nosebleeds, it was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cheever</ENAMEX> who came to her rescue. During her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sojourn</ENAMEX>, she narrowly
missed doing the screenplay work on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wizard of Oz</ENAMEX> .

            It feels like a good life, actually. Far from perfect. But not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gogh</ENAMEX>, either. Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Proust</ENAMEX> in the cork-lined <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. "I am not afraid," she told
her diary, "of criticism or death or pain." That's what you feel most in her, I
think: her fearlessness.

            I had the same peculiar aching feeling finishing this book of letters that I
do at the end of her novels. That I don't want it to end. That I miss her. So I
can't even imagine how you feel, after shadow-dancing with her for so long. Any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biographer</ENAMEX>, of course, carries on a love affair with a ghost. But you were so
close--you just missed her!

            Yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
