
   
   
      
         
            What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is After-Hours Trading</ENAMEX>?
            

            When a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> ruled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> had abused its
monopoly power, many reports noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock price fell in
"after-hours trading." What is this?

            It is simply the trading of stock after the markets close. Traditional stock
trading takes place during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">business hours</TIMEX> because it involves a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">middleman</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">broker</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX>--who matches <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX>. (That's what all those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> shouting on the floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> do--but they only
work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekdays</TIMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9 to 4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eastern</ENAMEX> time.) In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> have
begun to make trades without a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">middleman</ENAMEX> by using electronic communications
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, or ECNs. With computers making the matches, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECNs</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Instinet</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MarketXT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Datek Island</ENAMEX> -- can extend their <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. Many allow trades as
late as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m. Eastern</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> plans to offer <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20-hour</TIMEX>-a-day trading
by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX>. Theoretically they could allow trading around the
clock.

            Because after-hours trading has yet to catch on with large numbers of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, the after-hours and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> markets can reflect different prices for
the same stock. A stock listed on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>--say, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX>--can be traded after-hours on any number
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECNs</ENAMEX>. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECNs</ENAMEX> are not linked to one another, a stock's price may vary
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> to exchange. And, because so few transactions occur, stock prices
are much more volatile in after-hours trading. To prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> from
getting badly burned, after-hours <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECNs</ENAMEX> accept only "limit orders" (bids in
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> names the highest price at which he'll buy or lowest price
at which he'll sell) instead of the "market orders" (in which the investor
accepts the prevailing market price) common during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. As trade volume
increases, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> expect that the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> and after-hours markets
will converge.

            Next question?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> thanks 
               Slate 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reader Steve Ruby</ENAMEX> for suggesting the topic .

         
      
   
