
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qaddafi</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> lead with a decision by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest managed-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UnitedHealth Group</ENAMEX>, to stop pre-screening
routine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' tests and minor surgereries. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> puts the HMO
announcement in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> spot of its "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business and Finance</ENAMEX>" box, giving top
billing to an anonymously sourced report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agro-drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>,
has been in merger talks with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agro-drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novartis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> explains, wants to separate its farming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> from its
drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> to boost its stock price. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> are trying to either
bisect the existing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or, more likely, merge with another agro-drug
conglomerate and then bisect the whole thing. (For more pharmaceuticals
mergers, see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UnitedHealth Group</ENAMEX>, which covers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14.5 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, will stop questioning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' decisions before treatment is given. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> has the most
concrete illustration of this change: Instead of questioning whether a heart
patient really needs a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac catheterization</ENAMEX>, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> will focus
instead on how to get the procedure done more quickly to reduce the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
stay. Besides the mounting pressure of class-action lawsuits and regulatory
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>'s motive was economic: It had determined that the
money saved through pre-screening was less than the cost of employing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pre-screeners.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will invest the savings in new ways to compare
treatment costs with patient outcomes, which it will share with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>. Only
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> credit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning</ENAMEX>
News --and after the jump, at that--with breaking this story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> tops its "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwide</ENAMEX>" box with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s dispatch of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> in a last-ditch effort to include <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in the World
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade Organization</ENAMEX> before the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> meeting on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 30</TIMEX>. One inauspicious
sign: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had to call <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time to
request an invitation for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emissaries</ENAMEX>, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> did not return his first
call.

            On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX>
writes that his company

            

               cannot compromise on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s demands that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> essentially
stop listening to the marketplace and cease innovating its products. The
current lawsuit would have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> ignore the most important recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> in computing--the Internet--by shipping a version of Windows that
omits the critical Internet capabilities.

            

            An analysis of the trial's fallout on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and</ENAMEX>
Policy" page concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s best bet is to curry favor with as many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> as possible; even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> were to drop its suit
under a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> writes, just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> could keep the case alive. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, by the way, publishes

                  Slate
               .)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts a news analysis predicting that the most likely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> breakup scenario would be along product lines: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would make
Windows, another would make application software such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Office</ENAMEX>, and
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> would handle Internet applications. Such a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">scenario</ENAMEX>--which Wall
Street prefers to a cross-product breakup--might even create more combined
shareholder value than current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> stock (which closed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.625</NUMEX> lower than
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s close--but rose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about three dollars</NUMEX> from its low point after the
decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes in a front-page analysis that
although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> dominates the software industry, it has been less successful
in the Internet market and especially in the interactive-cable-TV market. (For
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moneybox</ENAMEX>'s take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s brief, click here and
here;
for a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>," click here.)

            On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> opinion page, editorial-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sebastian Mallaby</ENAMEX>
predicts a partial rejuvenation of machine-style, get-out-the-vote electoral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizing</ENAMEX>. Where political ads on television and radio aim to disorient an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>'s base and suppress his turnout, machine-style organizing aims to
energize a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> and encourage turnout. The increasing political
activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unions</ENAMEX> accounts for much of this rejuvenation, of course, but the
phone-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>, door-to-door electioneering style of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> is being copied by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. In the information
age, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mallaby</ENAMEX> writes, even a brief personal recommendation at the water cooler
can sway a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> jaded by anonymous electronic campaigning.

            Quick! How many ways can you spell the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> manage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ,
it's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UnitedHealth Group</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>' default); at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , it's
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Health Group</ENAMEX>"; at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , it's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">UnitedHealthcare</ENAMEX>"; at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , it's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Healthcare</ENAMEX>"; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also throws in
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United HealthCare</ENAMEX>." (What? No "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unitedgrouphealth</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>"?) Only the LAT
explains that "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX>" is the parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Care</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> is reminded of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> skit featuring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> different ways to spell
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muammar al-Qaddafi</ENAMEX>--er, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kaddafi</ENAMEX>, er, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quadaffi</ENAMEX>, er ...

         
      
   
