
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Yent-a-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matic Speaks</ENAMEX>!

            
               An occasional feature in which kausfiles.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> suggests romantic
possibilities between public figures who may or may not know each other. This
one is so . . . well, inevitable, it just might work!:
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Torricelli</ENAMEX> --single (divorced) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jersey</ENAMEX> who has been linked to a series of glamorous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (e.g. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bianca Jagger</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Duff Medavoy Perelman</ENAMEX>)

            
               and
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX>-- glamorous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman writer</ENAMEX> and social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">climber</ENAMEX> who
divorced failed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huffington</ENAMEX>.

            Notes: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arianna</ENAMEX> --OK, he may be a bit conservative for you in your
current bleeding-heart <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">incarnation</ENAMEX>, but he's got what you want: a seat in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. You've put up with worse! You'll be back in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX> dinner
party/talk-show heaven! Tip: Don't call him "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Torch</ENAMEX>" to his face.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>-- True, there's that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult business</ENAMEX> in her background, but she's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">handsome</ENAMEX>, charming, and funny, and she's got what you want: a knack for
attracting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>! Play up her right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX> and you can spin it as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Romeo-Juliet/Carville-Matalin</ENAMEX> thing. Tip: You'll eventually have to do
something about her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> mama ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yaya</ENAMEX>") hanging around all the time, but better
be nice to her for now.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beltway Gossip Dump</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicos</ENAMEX> think the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode</ENAMEX>
Island <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Chafee</ENAMEX> means that: a) as has been reported, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> will appoint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chafee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>--who was
already running for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat from which his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was retiring--to
serve the remainder of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">term</TIMEX>; b) as only kausfiles
will tell you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Weygand</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, will decide to
stand for reelection to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> rather than run against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chafee</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, since the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chafee</ENAMEX> will be much tougher to beat as an
incumbent, even an appointed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>; c) with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weygand</ENAMEX> staying put, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will have to worry about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only four</NUMEX> open <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> seats in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2000</TIMEX>,
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> open seat total (counting resignations expected in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>) will soon go up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 20</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chafee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat, which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> thought they might capture, is now in the
probable-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> column. Bad news for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torch</ENAMEX>! (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torricelli</ENAMEX>, when
he's not dating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">glamourpusses</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Senatorial</ENAMEX>
Campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>); e) unless, that is, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torricelli</ENAMEX> can prevail on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Kennedy</ENAMEX> to run against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chafee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> has the name
and fundraising ability to win the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat, but right now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> needs him to raise money for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' campaign to retake the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House.</ENAMEX> ... Got all that? ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Cook</ENAMEX>, eat your heart out! ... Bonus
opinion item: On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s
This Week they could "rest assured" that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe v. Wade</ENAMEX> would be
safe in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>-appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said, he "would not use
a litmus test." Some questions: How can <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> be so sure his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX> will
support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> unless he uses a litmus test? And what's wrong with litmus
tests anyway? Wouldn't support of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Brown v. Board of Education</ENAMEX> be a
legitimate litmus test in picking a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> justice? If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> feels so
strongly about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> (which I think was wrongly decided) he should by all
means make it a litmus test. ...

         
      
   
