
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>, Stop <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Crazy Thing</ENAMEX>
            

            And another thing. It just hit me <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes ago</TIMEX> when I was in the study
repainting the red walls a redder red--a project that I estimate will take me
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> painting <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> since there also are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> bookshelves and the
back of each will need <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> coats since red paint <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streaks</ENAMEX> so badly--that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> we flit around from topic to topic here (and at our real breakfast table)
is indicative of a bigger problem in how we live our lives. We're so
fragmented. My attention, at any given moment, is divided among so many
competing thoughts that it makes my teeth ache. An example: This <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> after
you left for work, I was playing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> and she was
wiggling her fingers in the air in a way she considered menacing as she
shrieked, "I am the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROARRRRR</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX> is scaring Mommy!" This
was perhaps the cutest sight I have ever witnessed in my life. But even as I
was saying, "Help, save me from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX>," I was simultaneously thinking:
How am I going to wrap up that column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the kicker I have stinks; should I
roast a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> for dinner or not because it's not worth it unless I go get the
good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and that's at a butcher store <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX> away, and if waste <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> going to a butcher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, how many of those red shelves will I be able
to paint <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>; did I forget to give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zoe</ENAMEX> that permission slip she needed this
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>; is my skin starting to look old; do I hear the dog throwing up a sock
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>; maybe I should just end the piece by referring back to the
lead, but then I always do that so ...

            A certain percentage of these thoughts were perhaps valid. If I considered
them in an appropriate time and place. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> is only going to be this
cute and want to play <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 10 seconds</TIMEX> before she grows up enough
to get mean and criticize my hair like the others. So why am I wasting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">millisecond</ENAMEX>? This used to be called multi-tasking and be considered a skill.
Even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, it was called juggling. And I used to envy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who kept all
the balls in the air. I thought they got more out of life because they did
more. But now I don't know. It's been so long since I fully concentrated on one
idea or one task or one anything that my attention span has contracted to be
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> as long as ... well, as long as it takes to paint the backs of three
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bookshelves</ENAMEX>. And these, as you know, are not big bookshelves.

         
      
   
