
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petting Party</ENAMEX>
            

            The top issues are the foreign-policy "pop quiz" given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> by
a television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> and the ridiculousness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> advising <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>.
A close <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s victory in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> anti-trust trial.

            Interviewed briefly on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> will
choose their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> based on "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgment,</ENAMEX> vision, [and] philosophy" rather
than on factual knowledge. (The interview appears to be excerpted from a longer
interview for another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> program, though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> fails to make this
clear.) On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Blitzer</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, "At
least I didn't ask you who the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatia</ENAMEX> is"; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> snaps
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Franjo</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tudjman</ENAMEX>" before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blitzer</ENAMEX> can finish the sentence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> admits that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was entrapped, but reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> does not have his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s
curiosity about world affairs.

            Except for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ), most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>
think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> interview was--in the words of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> )--"gotcha journalism." Also, most admit to being as
clueless as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Will</ENAMEX> claims that he,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, knew only one name). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Barone</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> ) cracks
that the interview "tells you that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who just won all the money on
Jeopardy should be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> )--note that a more sophisticated candidate
would have refused to answer the questions or else launched into a deeper
discussion of foreign policy themes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour with Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> camp is pleased that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> kept his cool
under fire, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> says that anyway <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s main selling point is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">temperament</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s response to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> flap--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> announced he could have answered all the questions with no
problem--amounts to "waving your hand in class" and "almost makes you worry
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>]."

            Appearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> downplays the importance of her advice
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and defends her right to earn what male campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> make. Barone
notes that advice on gender issues is common in campaigns. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> warns that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s advocacy of "heavy petting" and "onanism" will not help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
popularity, though it might spice up his campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is on the
cusp of becoming "ridiculous," but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> looks more relaxed on the campaign trail
than ever. (For a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX>, click here; for an "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>," click
here.)

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Klein</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> verdict
will not require a "specific remedy," but will require "a remedy." On
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, says the decision demands "major changes in corporate policy" at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and that "it's not beyond the ken to see a breakup of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>."
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Feinstein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late</ENAMEX>
Edition ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Murray</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Juan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> )--predict that any punitive action will come after the
market has already broken up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> anyway. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hume</ENAMEX> argues that the
monopoly label is "a big leap" from the evidence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
strategy is to drag out its appeal until a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> wins the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> (and
presumably drops the lawsuit). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> illustrates its commentary on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> findings with a duel scene from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monty Python</ENAMEX> and the Holy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grail</ENAMEX> , in which one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knight</ENAMEX> says, "I move for no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>," then gets his limbs
chopped off, and then claims it's "just a flesh wound." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Moneybox</ENAMEX>'s take on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s findings, click here.)



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of Mirrors</ENAMEX>

Asked whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> flap will hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late</ENAMEX>
Edition ) says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> don't care if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> hires <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX>, but I do think
it reinforces an emerging perception for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, which is that he doesn't know
who he is." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> )
give similarly reasoned comments on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> "pop quiz" (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ie.</ENAMEX>, it doesn't really
matter, but it reinforces the perception that it matters, and therefore it
matters). (For a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s circular priorities, click
here.) 


And Now, a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Word From Our Sponsor</ENAMEX>

"This was a political attack on success. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> can't stand
is a successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> doesn't know anything about
antitrust--he's a liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>. ... So I think the idea of penalizing a
great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> with the use of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> statute is a suicide on this
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. ... This is relief for the losing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>--not for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ).


Last Word

"I am not a fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>. I do think it's a little sexist that that's
been blown into something it isn't. ... I took a cut in pay to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
[at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>]. I took another cut in pay to work for him [at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> a
month]--at a time where we're all tightening our belts."

                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX>
            

            
"My jacket is alpha-male brown."

                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Actually, I'm a delta male--<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi delta</ENAMEX>, that is."

                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
