
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi  Wolf</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> published an editorial about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> business that drew a contrast between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s uses of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> noted that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> for trendy gurus
peddling magical elixirs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> relies only on trusted long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>
("who think nothing of sharing hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> in order to save money").

            But as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> quite reasonably pointed out in TV appearances <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> too, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> by the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornel West</ENAMEX>. While
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> is not being paid by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> campaign, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> is by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign,
he plays an analogous role as affiliated intellectual. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> advises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
about how to score with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women voters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> is helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>.
And as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> case, the benefits of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>-West relationship are
clearly reciprocal. As a result of his association with a leading presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, West can expect to see his fame and his already formidable lecture
fees rise. I don't think he shares hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.

            I must admit to being poorly disposed toward West, mainly on the basis of a
devastating critique in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Wieseltier</ENAMEX> that
appeared in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 1995</TIMEX>. In a long review-essay, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wieseltier</ENAMEX> demolished West's
stature as a "public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>," portraying him as a pretentious egomaniac,
a mass of contradictions, and a superficial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX> who dresses up diluted
Marxism in incomprehensible phraseology. An obvious column idea suggested
itself: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> is much wackier than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s.

            Then I read some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>'s writings. While he certainly can be eccentric,
solipsistic, and turgid, at his best moments West is shrewd, courageous, and
inspirational. I remain ambivalent about his work, but it is certainly not, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wieseltier</ENAMEX> asserts "almost completely worthless." It doesn't trouble me at all
that West is advising <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. In fact, it makes me respect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, for openly
engaging a self-described socialist who may prove a big political liability to
his campaign, mainly because he finds him insightful and stimulating.

            Let's get some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>'s obvious faults out of the way. His vanity is indeed
considerable. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>'s picture invariably appears on the cover of his books, and
their interiors contain nearly as many self-references as those of that other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Moynihan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> goes on tremendous name-dropping riffs. The
just-published <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornel West Reader</ENAMEX> is dedicated to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Coltrane</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederico Garcia Lorca</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franz Kafka</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Celan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee Williams</ENAMEX>, Giacomo
Leopardi, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Beckett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Vaughn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muriel Rukeyser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Hardy</ENAMEX>, Nikos
Kazantzakis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX>, "and above all," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anton Chekhov</ENAMEX>. It's that "above
all" that really cinches it. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> has an unfortunate tendency to refer to his
utterances as "prophetic"--a judgment best left to others. But like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>'s
taste for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-piece suits (after another of his idols, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.E.B. DuBois</ENAMEX>), this
is a more a matter of style than of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>. West cultivates a distinctively
black mode of academic discourse, improvisational in tone and containing a
stronger element of showmanship and braggadocio than most of his white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> are comfortable with.

            Another annoyance is West's love affair with labels. In the early pages of
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornel West Reader</ENAMEX>, he describes himself "a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chekhovian Christian</ENAMEX>
with deep democratic commitments," "a Gramscian democratic socialist," a
"non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> socialist," and a "prophetic, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pragmatist</ENAMEX> freedom
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fighter</ENAMEX>." These stickers accumulate, as on a steamer trunk, without pointing to
any definitive destination. This habit, too, makes West easy to mock, but I
think it serves a purpose. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> wants to communicate the intensity of his
effort to reconcile his various influences: religious, political, philosophic,
and artistic. Wieseltier may be right that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>'s efforts at synthesis lack
rigor. But I don't think West's intention is so much to work out a system as it
is to put his own personal journey forward as an example. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> is self-made
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> who found <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kierkegaard</ENAMEX> in a bookmobile, was influenced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>
Panthers as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX>, and found his way to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Barth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dewey</ENAMEX>. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promiscuous</ENAMEX> use of slogans is a way of personalizing the philosophical, of
telling you where he's been.

            So what is it that I find appealing about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>? I think his main strengths
are his thoughtfulness about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s racial divide and his charismatic
enthusiasm about bridging it. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> has a reputation as something of an angry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revolutionary</ENAMEX>. I would describe him as a blunt-spoken moderate with a radical
self-image slightly at odds with the substance of his views. In Race
Matters , he blasts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> for trying to monopolize black political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and for lacking programmatic follow-through. He defends affirmative
action, but notes that it "is not the most important issue for black progress
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>." His basic stance is a rejection of both the conservative view that
racism is no longer a big problem and the liberal view that it's the whole
problem.

            Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> opts for a multi-causal explanation of black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
problems. He thinks racism remains pervasive and destructive, a truth that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> alone among <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX>'s presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> seems comfortable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uttering</ENAMEX>, and one that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> has helped him articulate more pointedly. Yet West
doesn't exonerate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of racism for irresponsibility or criminality
(something for which his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> on the conventional academic left, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adolph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>, can't forgive him). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> is blunt about what he calls black
"nihilism"--what he defines as "a numbing detachment from others and a
self-destructive disposition toward the world." West in fact takes a position
that is close to that of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> on the importance of family
structure and religious values. He is also a relentless and insightful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> of
black anti-Semitism, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homophobia</ENAMEX>, and anti-white racism. "The very ethical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the black freedom struggle largely depends on the open
condemnation by its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokespersons</ENAMEX> of any racist attitude or action," he
writes in Race Matters .

            Despite his emphasis on how bad things are, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> is hopeful--as opposed to
naively optimistic--about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s racial future. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> in what he
calls "politics of conversion," he considers no one beyond the possibility of
redemption and no problem utterly intractable. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> is among the toughest and
most trenchant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of black nationalism and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Afrocentrism</ENAMEX>. But he seldom
concludes a diatribe with a condemnation. His religious sensibility tells him
to try to find what is useful in views that he deplores, and to try to pull
moral reprobates in a more positive direction. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> is scathing on the subject
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX>. Yet he has embarked on a quixotic effort to engage
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> and change his mind.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>'s writing lacks the lucidity and panache of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> and
sometime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis Gates</ENAMEX>. He has said many things that I
wouldn't try to defend, and that I doubt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> would want to defend
either, such as his formulaic, p.c. denunciations of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> "imperialism."
Where he tries to lay out a policy agenda, as in his recent book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Future</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Progressivism</ENAMEX> (co-written with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto Mangabeira Unger</ENAMEX>), I
think he oscillates between dreary, conventional ideas (public financing of
campaigns, class-based rather race-based affirmative action, a consumption tax)
and utterly impractical ones (a modified parliamentary system, explicit
economic redistribution, mandatory voting). I'd be alarmed if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drafting Bradley</ENAMEX>'s policy positions. But for the role of spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> with a charisma deficit, he seems like just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
