
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blunt Instrument</ENAMEX>
            

            It's just an odd coincidence, but there did seem to be something telling
about the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What's News</ENAMEX>" section on the front page of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>, which listed as its first item the findings of fact in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> antitrust trial and as its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$74 billion</NUMEX> hostile bid
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX> is attempting to muscle out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Home Products</ENAMEX>,
which wants to have a friendly merger with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX>.)

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> item describes the results of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s relentless
pursuit of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> it argues--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> agrees--is a monopolist
engaged in anti-competitive behavior. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> item, by contrast, describes
the results of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s general indifference to the
anti-competitive implications of the huge wave of mergers that continues to
sweep across every sector of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy. And the logical question these
items raises is: What's the difference?

            To be sure, it's not entirely fair to say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade Commission</ENAMEX> have been asleep at the wheel when it comes to
pursuing antitrust cases. They have blocked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples-Office Depot</ENAMEX> merger and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed-Northrop Grumman</ENAMEX> deal, and threw a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> wrench (ill-advisedly,
but still) into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX>'s proposed acquisition of book distributor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingram</ENAMEX>. And in other cases, they've forced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to sell off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> or
make other changes before mergers would be approved.

            On the whole, though, the consolidation of industries ranging from financial
services to telecommunications to aerospace to the drug industry has proceeded
remarkably fast and with remarkably little interference. And what's perplexing
about this, particularly in light of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> case, is that mergers often
have an immediate anti-competitive impact, in the simplest sense that they
reduce the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in a market. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s default
position is that competition protects <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>--a sensible enough
position--then it's hard to see why the merger boom should not be scrutinized
more carefully than it has been.

            Of course, antitrust law is a very blunt instrument, and should be used only
when real harm can be discerned. But antitrust law is also much better suited
to preventing the formation of giant megacorporations--it is called
anti- trust law, after all--than to eradicating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX> that have
arisen by other means.

            Remember that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX> per se are not illegal. In fact, the
establishment of temporary monopolies--of taste, of technology, or of
distribution--is the only way that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are able to reap meaningful
economic profits, which otherwise would be immediately competed away. A
monopoly becomes illegal only when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> exercising it uses that monopoly
to shut out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> in other markets, either through coercion or by
subsidizing low, competition-killing prices in that market. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Again</ENAMEX>, many
academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> question whether this last tactic is really feasible, but
antitrust law depends on the assumption that it is.) And this, of course, is
exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s findings of fact say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> did.

            Oddly, though, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Klein</ENAMEX> appeared on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>, he seemed to be saying something more than
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> had acted in ways that were unacceptable for a monopolist. He
seemed to suggest that being a monopolist was itself unacceptable. "You know,
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> you have a choice," he said. "And if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gateway</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> or
Dell ... had a choice, they could go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and negotiate (or) they could
go to somebody else and negotiate. Here, everybody's got to go to one
place--that's what's hurting us."

            That's an audacious reading--or rather rewriting--of antitrust law, and
suggests that what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> wants is not just the breaking up of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> into
separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> but the breaking up of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s operating-system division
into competing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> (since otherwise there still wouldn't be choice of
different versions of Windows for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gateway</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX>). Maybe next we can
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block</ENAMEX> any further acquisitions by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX> and tell it that it has to set up
competing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to distribute different versions of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>, too.

         
      
   
