
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            Welcome to hard times. Oh, wait, that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks ago</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>,
we're looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamonds</ENAMEX> as big as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritz</ENAMEX>, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employment Cost</ENAMEX>
Index came in below expectations, which means that there's no wage pressure in
the economy, making it a good time for capital. Of course, the infinite
regression loop was in full effect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, although no one was following it
too far out. See, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECI</ENAMEX> was right, then that means that inflation is
pretty well under control, which helped lower interest rates and spur a lot of
buying in the stock market. But that makes most sense if the low <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECI</ENAMEX> is enough
to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> from raising interest rates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>. If it's
not, even if inflation is low, the stock market could be burned. So were we
judging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECI</ENAMEX>'s impact on inflation, or on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s feelings about
inflation?

            I have no idea. All I know is that when I woke up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, switched on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX>, and saw the stock market was up big, I knew without being told that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECI</ENAMEX> was lower than expected. (That's not a sentence that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX> I could
even have thought of, let alone imagined writing.) And so everything's good
again. Until the next big number comes out. On, then, to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s Cocktail
Chat.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "The major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> reported earnings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> , and
although, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reported, their bottom lines were
helped by higher oil prices, they were hurt by gasoline prices, which didn't
rise as fast. I know there is a logic in there somewhere, but if you're selling
oil and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX>, then aren't you buying from yourself? And if you're buying
from yourself, how can higher oil prices help you ?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "Shares in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> were pummeled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> after the company
said it was going to be spending very heavily on marketing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next quarter</TIMEX>
and that its losses could continue to grow. A number of brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>
downgraded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to 'near-term accumulate' or 'hold', although most
retained their 'long-term buy' ratings. That's always a good one. If you're
not supposed to buy it in the short term, how can you own it for the long
term? It's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zeno</ENAMEX>'s Paradox for investing."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "Offering a more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX>-congenial outlook for the future was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Priceline</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, which said it did better than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150 million</NUMEX> in revenue in the
latest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>. Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Priceline</ENAMEX> has the curious habit of reporting as
revenue the total value of the tickets and hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> that it 'sells' on its
site , even though the vast majority of that revenue goes to the airlines
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> supplying the seats and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Priceline</ENAMEX>'s actual revenue for
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> was, oh, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18 million</NUMEX>. It's a powerhouse, I tell you."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI WorldCom</ENAMEX> would be
responsible for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$550 million</NUMEX> in back taxes owed by a former state-owned
telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI WorldCom</ENAMEX> bought <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> admitted that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI WorldCom</ENAMEX> had been assured, in writing, that it would not be responsible for
the back taxes but said tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> had re-evaluated the situation. I guess
the original evaluation went something like this: 'If we lie, they buy the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. If we tell the truth, we're stuck with it. I say we lie.' "

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excite@Home</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $1 billion</NUMEX> to acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bluemountain</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, an
Internet greeting-card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> started by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippies</ENAMEX>--does 'hippies' always
have to have 'former' attached to it? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Mountain</ENAMEX> has next to no revenue
(again, it was started by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippies</ENAMEX> ), but lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. At this
rate, pretty soon you're not even going to be able to say to someone 'you
look like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX> bucks' without insulting him ."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "After news broke that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> is contemplating selling its drinks
in a temperature-sensitive vending machine , which will be able to raise
prices as it gets hotter outside, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>'s plans
would 'exploit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> who live in warm climates.' Yeah, what's up with that
whole supply-and-demand thing, anyway? Let's get a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five Year</TIMEX> Plan on soda
pricing, please."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employment Cost</ENAMEX> Index for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the most recent quarter</TIMEX> came in at just
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.8 percent</NUMEX>, below expectations, easing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> concerns about possible
inflation. This is the happy situation in which we find ourselves: the less
everyone makes, the better . Well, the better for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>, at
least."

         
      
   
