
   
   
      
         
            Unfriendly Skies

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> lead with the crash of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> flight carrying 217
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>. The plane plummeted into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>
shortly after takeoff. No one holds much hope for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>, though only the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> actually declares "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">217</NUMEX> killed" in its headline. Graphics
illustrating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>'s final <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> and articles detailing the grief the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and family accompany most of the stories. It is believed
that the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. The cause of the crash
remains unknown.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> was one of many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who stressed that there
was no evidence to suggest sabotage. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and some debris have been
found, none of it marked with signs of fire or explosion. Most of the papers
mention and dismiss a threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>- or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>-based flight
made to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Aviation Administration</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>. Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> explain why so little
is made of the threat: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> behind it is being held on a homicide charge
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and has made such claims falsely in the past.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> both hint at a manufacturing defect as
a potential cause. Another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">767</NUMEX>, produced at the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two weeks</TIMEX>
later, crashed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">217</NUMEX>. A faulty braking device was
blamed, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> issued retrofitting kits to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">767</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> after the accident. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> said it was "way too early" to look for a causal link
between the two tragedies. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> emphasizes the
10-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s clean bill of health and calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">767</ENAMEX> "a workhorse
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">trans-Atlantic</ENAMEX> travel."  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> points out a macabre, ironic
wrinkle to the story: the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> who disembarked in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> works as a
"grief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-pager puts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ore.</ENAMEX>, in the center of "a national
battle over the future of the Internet." City <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> decreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>
who use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>'s cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> must be allowed to choose their Internet
service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, effectively forcing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to share its wires with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> is suing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, arguing (along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>)
that government intervention will ultimately hurt consumer freedom more than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>'s potential dominance in the cable Internet market.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front page reports that the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RealJukebox</ENAMEX> computer
program surreptitiously sends its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">RealNetworks</ENAMEX>, information about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>'s computer, including the title of the CD in its CD-ROM drive.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RealNetworks</ENAMEX> doesn't mention this disclosure in its privacy agreement, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> could be in violation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer Fraud</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Abuse Act</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executives</ENAMEX>
give conflicting explanations about the purpose of the information collected:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RealNetworks</ENAMEX> is only recording aggregate information, while
another maintains that the data is used to identify "sophisticated" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> and
steer them toward the program's advanced features.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story explores a crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s educational system. Only
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> go to school, and the
dropouts rate is climbing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has undertaken a campaign for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> enrollment with some success, but no one's sure how much, because the
campaign has also caused eager-to-please <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> to fudge statistics. A
lack of funding has also caused many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, theoretically free, to charge
education fees that low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are increasingly unable or unwilling to
afford. Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> are no longer free, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> are no
longer assured a comfortable government job (the public sector is shrinking),
more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are deciding that educating their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> doesn't make
financial sense. What's missing from the article is context: What's the
enrollment rate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, or other comparable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>? 

            The WP fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s confirmation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX>
consults for his campaign. Previously, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign had funneled money
through other consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to conceal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s involvement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> was also an
unpaid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign, and had earned as much
as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> has engendered controversy with her
claims that teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> "sexual gradualism" techniques like masturbation and
oral sex is "as sensible as teaching them how to drive." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, at least,
seemed to take the advice to heart.

            
               None of the above: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT /CBS News</ENAMEX> poll shows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Guiliani</ENAMEX> in a dead heat in the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2000 New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Senate</ENAMEX> race, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 8 percent</NUMEX> of those responding indicating no
preference. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> believe that the election belongs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who can
identify and woo this mysterious swing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. The poll also has some alarming
news for the would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>: Even though neither has declared their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">candidacy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are already sick of them--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 40 percent</NUMEX> wish they had more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> from which to choose.

         
      
   
