
   
   
      
         
            Do <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dim Bulbs Make Better Presidents</ENAMEX>?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> reproduces a document that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>
wasn't eager to have published: his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> transcript, which includes his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>
scores (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">566 verbal, 640 math</ENAMEX>) and college grades (C average). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> doesn't want
to read too much into someone's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic</ENAMEX> records, which in this
case are mainly interesting as a reminder of how powerful the Ivy League's
affirmative-action program for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni brats</ENAMEX> used to be. But the data do tend to
substantiate what many have gleaned from listening to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
front-runner abuse the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English language</ENAMEX>: The sharpest tool in the shed he
ain't.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> article, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Mayer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexandra</ENAMEX>
Robbins, buttress their insult to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s privacy with a backhanded
compliment. "Historically, there is no correlation between academic achievement
and success in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>," they note. Many of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s highbrow
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>, go even farther, arguing that
thick-headedness is a positive advantage. In a recent column lauding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, Will
recalls the contest between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> book-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodrow Wilson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Howard Taft</ENAMEX>--noting that "such intellect
in politics is rare, and perhaps should be." The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookhiser</ENAMEX> recently made a version of the same case in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX> . "Perhaps the wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> should strive to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> on
tap and not be one himself," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brookhiser</ENAMEX> writes.

            The case against intellect in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is brilliantly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counterintuitive</ENAMEX>. If only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> had been able to grasp it, he might have
used it to great advantage in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>. But is it correct?
The argument rests mainly on some fairly compelling anecdotal evidence. The
list of less-than-brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> judged great by those making this argument
usually begins with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> and often includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin D. Roosevelt</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry S. Truman</ENAMEX> as well. The list of intellectually gifted but ineffectual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Hoover</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodrow</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>.

            Objection: The sample here is too small to be statistically meaningful. It
could just be a coincidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> happened to be both bright and inept,
and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was both disconnected and lovable. Another problem: The names
on the list are subject to extensive quibbling. Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> really a great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>? Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> a failure, just because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> rejected the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Versailles</ENAMEX>
treaty? Someday, someone will demolish the myth of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>'s alleged brilliance.
And was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>, who took gentleman <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cs</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, truly less than highly
intelligent? This supposition relies heavily on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Wendell Holmes</ENAMEX>'
oft-quoted observation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> was a "second-class intellect but a first
class temperament." There is a great deal of evidence to suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX>
was wrong about this and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>, unserious in college, had the supplest of
political wits about him.

            I can also provide some equally tendentious counterexamples. Highly capable
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> who were sharp as tacks include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> and--bring on the hate mail!--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jefferson Clinton</ENAMEX>. A list of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative dimwits</ENAMEX> who were lousy chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> might include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren G.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harding</ENAMEX> (who described himself, accurately, as too dumb to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald R. Ford</ENAMEX> (who played one too many games without a helmet, in the
memorable phrase of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon B. Johnson</ENAMEX>).

            Given that stupidity is not an advantage in any other profession, why would
it help a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>? I think the theory derives from the familiar prejudice
against intelligence, which holds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are too smart must be limited
in other ways. There's a popular notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who think too much can't
act--<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX> is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you want to run your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. And there's a
conservative, political version of this idea, which holds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>
are bound to be impractical, immoral, and too eager to impose their
rationalist, radical schemes on the rest of us. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William F. Buckley</ENAMEX> expressed
this view for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX> when he made his famous observation that he'd rather be
ruled by the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> names in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> phone book than by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University</ENAMEX>.

            But the dumb-is-better argument falls apart when you look more closely at
the personal qualities and corresponding successes and failures of just about
any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The ones who were dim but successful successfully compensated
for their dimness with other qualities. But the lack of intelligence still
harmed them. Take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>--please. I don't dispute that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> deserves
copious credit for bringing an early and glorious end to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
the ways he did this was by taking an unambiguous moral stand against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Communism</ENAMEX>, which gave powerful encouragement to the opposition in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern-bloc</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. But the moral certainty that caused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> to behave in this way
wasn't a tribute to his thickness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaclav Havel</ENAMEX> acted just as single-mindedly.
But an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> also needs to grasp more complex realities--and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> often couldn't. When it came to understanding something mildly
technical, such as the federal budget, he was baffled. As described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Stockman, he simply couldn't process the information that his contradictory
goals would produce a vast deficit, despite repeated attempts to spell it out
for him in words and pictures.

            Or look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s strong intelligence is the reason that
there is something on the plus side of his presidential ledger. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>
agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s most significant accomplishment--the opening of relations
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>--was the product of his own shrewd analysis of foreign policy, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>'s. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> himself wrote an article on the subject in Foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affairs</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> laying out the case for what he subsequently did. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> was
undone as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> not because he was too shrewd but because of something
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shrewdness</ENAMEX> didn't help him with: personal bitterness and lack of scruples.
Likewise with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has deployed his own formidable
brain, primarily in economic and some areas of domestic policy, he has largely
succeeded. Where he does his thinking with other organs, he has undermined
himself.

            In fact, I think the conservative case for presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupidity</ENAMEX> has it
exactly backwards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presidents</ENAMEX> get into the most trouble not when they behave
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> but when they delegate crucial brainwork to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>
on tap," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brookhiser</ENAMEX> calls them. A history of this sort of folly might start
with some of the failed schemes of the New Deal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> before describing
the way that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz kids</ENAMEX>" led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> astray on both the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> and the war
on poverty. It would touch on the bad advice <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Moynihan</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">welfare</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Magaziner</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> on health care. There is
probably no modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, smart or dumb, who hasn't landed himself in hot
water by hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> and then failing to second-guess them.

            To be sure, intelligence of the kind that might manifest itself in high <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>
scores isn't the most important quality in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leadership</ENAMEX>,
integrity, and determination are all more critical qualities. Dumb luck helps.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dumbness</ENAMEX> doesn't.

         
      
   
