
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wrong Stuff</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post leads with a federal budget compromise that will allocate nearly
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 billion</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> hiring--a central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">plank</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> policy. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> front this story.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> budget
story warns that there is still no agreement over environmental spending,
abortion, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> finances, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
are optimistic that a budget deal is around the corner (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> will try to wrap all remaining appropriations into a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$390 billion</NUMEX>
package to be voted on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as next week</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">release of EgyptAir 990</ENAMEX>'s data-recorder information, which shows that the plane
began its descent under apparent pilot control. This story is fronted by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes with a quasi-local lead:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s determination that the loss of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars Climate Orbiter</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> stemmed from gross mismanagement at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pasadena</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jet Propulsion Laboratory</ENAMEX>
and at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>. "These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> [at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JPL</ENAMEX>] could not manage their way out of a
Glad bag," pronounces a nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">watchdog group</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reefers this
story and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs it inside. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s private concern over <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> sales to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            Leaked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> arms-selling story notes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> recently sold a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 million</NUMEX> airborne radar system to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and plans to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> it several more. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Secretive Israeli</ENAMEX> arms deals with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> have long put the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> in a bind, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> explains: Since many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
weapons are jointly made with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> technology has likely
made its way to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, which uses it partly to threaten <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, which is
stocked with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> from ... the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            In its (reefered) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that the data
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recorder</ENAMEX> reveals no abrupt movements and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> maintained its compass
setting during the dive, which occurred <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight seconds</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">autopilot</ENAMEX> shut
off. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says an explosion is unlikely, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
insists that it is still a possibility. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> speculates on a loss
of cabin pressure (which the black box would not record), but USAT
notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> are taught to descend more slowly in such a situation. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LAT</ENAMEX> decides to focus on a possible hijacking or passenger rampage, and
for no apparent reason it fills several column inches with a detailed summary
of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">California crash</ENAMEX> caused by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX>. (Question: Did the LAT
reporter dwell on this particular crash because he happened to cover it
himself?) It is unknown whether the autopilot disengaged automatically or
manually; most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> merely note this fact in passing, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
oddly attributes this uncertainty to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> close to the investigation."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts--and the other papers stuff--the "indictment" of
kidnapping for his alleged refusal to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pervez Musharraf</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> land
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>--an event that triggered a military coup orchestrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Musharraf</ENAMEX>.
The general says his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only seven minutes</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> left when the
military commandeered the control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> and cleared the commercial airliner to
land. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharif</ENAMEX> could face the death penalty if convicted.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> off-leads, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> fronts, the decisions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wells Fargo</ENAMEX> bank to ban non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> from using its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATMs</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are reacting to a ban on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> fees passed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> front the
announcement that ramipril, an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-year-old</TIMEX> high-blood pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX>,
reduces the risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 percent</NUMEX> and significantly
reduces the risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>. The study of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 5 years</TIMEX> was
halted early because results were so encouraging.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is a textbook
example of how the media turn an alleged appearance of impropriety by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> into a "political problem" and therefore a story:

            

               On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> at least, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>, is
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> trip that has nothing to do with her probable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> candidacy in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. Her schedule ... [is] more or less standard fare for an
active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>'s visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Land</ENAMEX>. Neither the address she delivered
... <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> ... nor the speech ... she is to give <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>  ... is overtly
political. Yet with the election for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat she is expected to seek
less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> away, much of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> does is presumed to be political.
And whatever her intention, there was no escaping the buzz of partisan politics
audible even before her arrival.

            

            For a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" on this style of reporting, click here.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just Another Day</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>: Among the findings of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> investigation into the loss of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars Orbiter</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> is the following: "There was a widespread perception among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Climate Orbiter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that 'orbiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> is routine,' which caused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to
not pay enough attention to the risks of interplanetary spaceflight"
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ).

         
      
   
