
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folklore of the Antiwar Movement</ENAMEX>
            

            Our debate reminds me of that old story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston Churchill</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Shaw</ENAMEX> or whoever the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brit</ENAMEX> was who asks a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> if she'd sleep with him
for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one million pounds</NUMEX>. She is outraged. "How about for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 pence</NUMEX>?" he asks.
"Just who do you think I am, sir?" "We've already established that," he says.
"Now we're just haggling over price." In a sense, that's what we're arguing
over. We disagree on whether the price of keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>'s control was worth paying--or even if there was a price that might
have been politically acceptable in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1970s</TIMEX>.

            Let me try to make the case that the price was worth paying. First, look at
what happened as a result of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pullout. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intervention
have never come to grips with this. But a lot of horrible things did
happen. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One million</NUMEX> boat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, of whom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> died at sea. The
creation of a giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gulag</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> that was euphemistically referred to as
"re-education <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>." I've even heard <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> defend the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> as
legitimate educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. An oppressive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> over all of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. And the fall of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>, which fell all the way back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX>
Age, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that might not have fallen if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had
maintained a relatively small military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX> and provided
serious amounts of aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. My point is that all this was
a very high price to pay, though it wasn't paid by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.

            Now, what was the most explosive event of the war in terms of adverse
reaction at home? Clearly it was the incursion by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>. That led to protests all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, including the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at Kent
State in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> were shot to death by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guardsmen</ENAMEX>. But as
bad as the eruption was, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> weathered it. Anger didn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vanish</ENAMEX>, but it did die down. And I think there was still plenty of room for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> to maneuver. The trouble was he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> maneuvered
for the wrong thing. They got a peace settlement that left some North
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX>, but, ultimately, no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>.

            I know that "what-ifs" are pure speculation, but I'm not going to let that
stop me. So, what if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> had announced that he would leave a contingent of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX>. They wouldn't stay there in a front-line
combat role. That would be left to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, much improved by
this point in the war. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> would be there. At the very least, I
believe, their presence would have effectively deterred the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Vietnamese</ENAMEX>
from an all-out attack. It was such an invasion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>--and not anything the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viet Cong</ENAMEX> did--that caused the collapse of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX>. Sure, there would
have been protests and teach-ins. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rennie Davis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Dellinger</ENAMEX> would have
been mad. But I think fury would have subsided and the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> policy could
have been implemented successfully.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.K.</ENAMEX>, all this is hindsight. But we learn a lot from hindsight. You and I
agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Lind</ENAMEX>'s destruction of myths about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, or what he calls
"the folklore of the antiwar movement." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of those myths is championed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fredrik Logevall</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Choosing War</ENAMEX> . That's the idea of "missed
opportunities" for a peace settlement before the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> buildup in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>. As
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Lind</NUMEX> points out, this myth is a favorite of the left and always pops up in
connection with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> relations with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. It's classic
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Communist</ENAMEX>. But would any treaty have stopped <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ho Chi Minh</ENAMEX>, a convinced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalinist</ENAMEX>, from pursuing his goal of capturing all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> by any means
necessary? Of course not. He'd have achieved his goal a lot sooner.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>, I'd recommend a different book, one I've mentioned before. It's A
Better War by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Sorley</ENAMEX>, which explains how the war had been all but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">won</ENAMEX>, militarily, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 1970</TIMEX>. It hasn't gotten nearly the attention that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Lind</ENAMEX>'s book has, but A <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Better War</ENAMEX> deserves strong consideration by
anyone still interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. Yes, I was predisposed in favor of his
argument. Still, I think he made it especially well.

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, I'm not going to defend him. I've always wondered whether,
absent <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>, he'd have lived up to his promise to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thieu</ENAMEX> of
renewed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military intervention in the case of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Vietnamese</ENAMEX>
invasion. I doubt it. But, as you say, that's another story.

         
      
   
