
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRI</ENAMEX>'s Primary Primary

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> lead with partial results from the first-ever primary of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s ruling party, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRI</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Labastida</ENAMEX>, a seasoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>
favored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> bigwigs, clobbered his nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto Madrazo</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick governor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tobasco</ENAMEX> region. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, and ethicists have been toying with
the question of how a military invasion of a hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s information
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> might play out against the international "rules of war." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> talks with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> who spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> scratching their heads over how the findings of
fact in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial may affect stock markets. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs a
similar story inside.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> pushed deadlines back to wait for results from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>: With
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58 percent</NUMEX> of votes in, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Labastida</ENAMEX> was winning in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">272</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX>, compared
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madrazo</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> needs only a plurality of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX>. The election
is an important test for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRI</ENAMEX>, which has been in power longer than any other
party in the world; previously, the outgoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would simply knight his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, thereby guaranteeing him victory. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madrazo</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> argued throughout the campaign that the party apparatus had buoyed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labastida</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernesto Zedillo</ENAMEX> said he is neutral and expressed this
sentiment by checking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> names on his ballot. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRI</ENAMEX> should fare well in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s general election if it can remain less fractured than its
opposition.

            Halfway through the war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> legal eagles distributed to the
top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX> guidelines for conducting information warfare. They suggested that
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> avoid civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cyber targets</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>) as
carefully as they would if they were bombing brick-and-mortar sites, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports. Arbitrary cyber assaults with serious civilian
repercussions -- opening a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dam</ENAMEX>'s floodgates, releasing radioactivity -- would
be just as illegal under international law as if they were performed manually.
The article ends with a sample tactic dismissed during the war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>:
"to bombard the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> with faxes and other forms of harassment."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banner</ENAMEX> headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Milosevic To Withdraw From Kosovo: Says 'Aw, C'mon, Cut It</ENAMEX>
Out' ")
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> policy, still in development, would allow new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> on family leave to receive unemployment money, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> prohibited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> from using money for this
purpose, but new regulations may be on their way. At issue: for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60-plus</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>,
only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are involuntarily unemployed, eligible for work, and seeking it
have qualified for unemployment insurance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX> who take time off to care
for newborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> do so voluntarily, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> who disagree with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Objectors</ENAMEX> to the plan, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> first articulated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>,
also say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> shouldn't bleed the unemployment trust, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may need in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> leaner than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these</TIMEX>. As if anticipating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
story, a below-the-fold USAT piece summarizes a psychological study that
shows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> left at day care tend to have a weaker bond with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>,
which may have developmental consequences.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of change in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> has allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> to pursue a
string of civil rights-era violent crimes, including the racially-motivated
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> bombing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX> that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports. A combination of factors has pushed the cases forward:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX> hold more political power and have lobbied for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> to be tried;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> with heavy consciences can come forward without fear of speaking the
truth; and a feeling that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> must come to terms with past racism and
violence.

            Writing in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Industries</ENAMEX>" business section, media
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reporter Felicity Barringer</ENAMEX> asks questions posed by the recent rebellion among
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>'s agreement to share profits from a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> with the issue's subject. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> incident may make
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publishers</ENAMEX> more cautious about experimenting with revenue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, she writes,
but they will continue to do so as ad dollars flock Web-ward.

            Latest Y2K precaution-slash-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> bonus (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts, curiously):
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> will allow "the most anxious government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>" (as
well as the moderately worried, and those seeking a free trip home) in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
former-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> to return to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 or 30 days</TIMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>'s. The price tag for the exodus may run <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as high as $8 million</NUMEX>. Those who
stay don't expect a meltdown; without electricity and heating, however, there
may be a freeze-up. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Diplomats</ENAMEX> and embassy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belarus</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moldova</ENAMEX> qualify. No word on how the host <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> feel about this
vote of confidence in their technical know-how.

            In light of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 10th anniversary tomorrow</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin Wall</ENAMEX>'s demise, the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
takes a look at that rock, that pillar, that spectacular golden prism for
international political-economic constancy and hope: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Thurow</ENAMEX>, reflects on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> of blind luck, of
East-West rivalry, of booms and busts, of capitalism devouring communism, of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communists</ENAMEX> devouring cheeseburgers." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manfred</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brigitte Voigt</ENAMEX>, unassuming
store <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> who had never paid any attention to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>, were approached by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> and asked to open a pioneering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Germany</ENAMEX>.
Where will they spend this anniversary of the event that altered their lives
forever? <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
