
   
   
      
         
            Fallout From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Trial</ENAMEX>
            

            Some quickly jotted-down thoughts on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Penfield Jackson</ENAMEX>'s
findings of fact in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> antitrust trial, a ruling handed down about
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour ago</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> is treating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s chief conclusions--that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has
monopoly power in the PC-operating-systems market; that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has used that
power to harm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> in other markets; and that using its power in that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> has harmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>--as surprising. But the real surprise may be that
anyone's surprised, given <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s attitude and behavior throughout the case.
While the trial was going on, in fact, you would have been hard-pressed to find
a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> covering it who thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> was going to win. But
since the trial has ended, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> was apparently seized by the conviction
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> would be temperate in his decision. He wasn't.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. The stock market, on the other hand, seems to have been taking the
implications of this decision into account for some time. Even as the Nasdaq
has rallied strongly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of weeks</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s stock has been
treading <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. In fact, it's trading about where it was back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>. Now, in
the wake of the ruling, the stock did sell off a bit in after-hours trading,
but markets are all about anticipation, and the stock market appears to have
already anticipated something like the ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson</ENAMEX> produced.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. That's not to downplay the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-sidedness of the findings of fact.
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> did credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> with helping accelerate the expansion of
the Internet and with benefiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> via innovation in other cases, the
weight of his ruling is on the side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. In particular, his
ruling treats <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> as a textbook example of the idea that a monopolist can
use its control of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> market to give itself control over another, and that it
can use the profits--"immense profits," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> calls them--reaped as a result
of its monopoly to fund the domination of another.

            These happen to be ideas that many academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> are deeply skeptical
of, since if it makes long-term economic sense for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> to expand into,
say, browsers, it should also make long-term economic sense for someone else to
fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> is essentially saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
is too powerful--because of its control of the operating-system market--and too
profitable for anyone else to enter the fray against it. In fact, near the end
of his ruling, he explicitly says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s power has limited
technological investment that would otherwise have taken place.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Without sounding like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> shill here (and yes,

                  Slate
                is published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>), the findings of
fact do seem as if they're describing a world that doesn't quite exist anymore.
The advent of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Linux</ENAMEX>; the continued penetration of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Java</ENAMEX>; the merger between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netscape</ENAMEX>; and the rapid growth in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDAs</ENAMEX> and non-desktop applications: All of
these are phenomena that don't fit into the picture of a computing world in
which domination of the PC operating system translates into domination
elsewhere. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s ruling was, of necessity, backward-looking, since he had
to decide what had happened. But insofar as he remains guided by a PC-centric
definition of computing, it's not clear whatever remedies he suggests will
really conform to the way things are, rather than the way things were.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the odd things about the centrality of the browser war to the
antitrust trial, in fact, is that the browser itself now seems about as
important and distinctive as something like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wordpad</ENAMEX> (which is to say, not very
important at all). Once, it seemed like he who controlled the browser would
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> the Internet. Now, if anyone controls the Internet, it's the portals.
The unanswerable question, of course, is whether this would have happened had
there been no antitrust trial.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. As everyone is pointing out, the findings of fact do not tell us how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> will read the relevant laws in the case (that's Phase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) or what
remedies he may prescribe (Phase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). And it certainly seems possible that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> will reach a settlement. Some have even
suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s strong language was intended to spur just an
agreement, although one might have thought a more balanced opinion would have
had a better effect in that direction.

            Nonetheless, there is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> thing worth thinking about going forward.
You could read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s ruling as essentially implying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
monopoly over the PC operating system means that any expansion into other
contiguous markets--and most computing markets can still be construed as in
some way contiguous to the PC--is an unacceptable exercise of monopoly power,
then what kind of business can <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> legally pursue? Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> secretly
think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> shouldn't ever have been able to branch out into desktop
applications like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Word</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Excel</ENAMEX>? In other words, does control of the
operating-system market really preclude a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> from seeking to compete in
others? If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s answer to that last question is really yes (which would
be, I think, a startling answer), then we may in fact be talking about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> decision all over again. And that really would be a surprise. But
then, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> settled. And after this ruling, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> may decide it's better
off in the appellate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> after all.

         
      
   
