
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Cries Wolf</ENAMEX>

            Appearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>, controversial <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> argued against holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> responsible for the
views of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>, adding:

            

               
                  I was interested to see on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few nights ago</TIMEX>, Mr.
Press pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> have views that were much more, I
would say, disturbing, than mine, that were in fact, I would say,
racist.
               

            

            Who are these racist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>? A quick look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">transcript</ENAMEX> reveals only one allegation that comes close to fitting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s description, an example offered by "from-the-left" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
Press:

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRESS</ENAMEX>: I just want to follow up again. Because there's another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> by the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myron Magnet</ENAMEX>, who says there are lots of jobs out
there for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> just don't go after them. It reminds me of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meese</ENAMEX> saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX> by choice. Now is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s position?
               

               
                  [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNC Co</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chair Pat</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HARRISON</ENAMEX>: I have no idea who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myron</ENAMEX> is. Whatever he said
in that sense is ridiculous. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> does not believe that.
               

            

            I called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnet</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. He hadn't heard he'd been denounced as a racist
on national television. (This was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> angle so obscure only
kausfiles was on the case!) Like every other conservative intellectual
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magnet</ENAMEX> confessed that he was, indeed, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>. He'd gotten
the call from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> had told him that his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>
book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dream and the Nightmare</ENAMEX> had been a major influence. In
Dream , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnet</ENAMEX> is talking about the black "underclass"--not, as Press
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">implied</ENAMEX>, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">society</ENAMEX> in general. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnet</ENAMEX> says "only a minority of black
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>--perhaps one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>--belongs to the underclass.") One
dysfunctional feature of underclass society, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnet</ENAMEX> argues, is a failure to
take available jobs. "Of course there are jobs out there," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magnet</ENAMEX> told me,
sticking to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. "The success of welfare reform makes that abundantly
clear. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Folks</ENAMEX> didn't have trouble going out and finding jobs."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnet</ENAMEX>'s view is probably impolitic (though maybe less so than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> and
Press think). In important ways it may not be right. (If every able-bodied,
unemployed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in the black underclass tried to get a job back in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnet</ENAMEX>'s book came out, could the labor market have readily absorbed
them all? I doubt it.) But it's not "racist."

            It is, rather, a simplified, blame-the-'60s version of the standard "culture
of poverty" argument--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> good working definition of a "culture of poverty"
being a culture whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> do not take advantage of economic opportunities
when they present themselves. The argument is actually anti- racist in
the sense that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnet</ENAMEX> thinks the black-white economic gap is purely a "cultural
matter," the result of "bad messages coming from the larger culture [read:
those privileged, white hippies!] that have encouraged a weak family
structure." At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Institute</ENAMEX>, where he edits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Journal</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnet</ENAMEX> is known as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray-Richard Herrnstein</ENAMEX>
argument that genetics, not culture, is at the bottom of the black-white
divide.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> didn't return my phone calls.*  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> should know that I used
to work and play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shipley</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , who is a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. (How close a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> is he? Check
back with me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> on that! But regard for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shipley</ENAMEX>, I suspect, is giving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> a lot of protection when it comes to press coverage, though it might not
look that way.) If I were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, I'd want someone like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> around,
even if some of her ideas are quirky or wacky.

            But the "racism" charge isn't quirky or wacky--it's demagogy. It coarsens
and inflames dialogue in a way that tends to prevent exposure of which ideas
are right and which are wrong. ("It's just bullshit," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magnet</ENAMEX> says. "It means
'we don't even want to have an argument with you.' ") Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> was led astray
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX>' tendentious summary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnet</ENAMEX>'s views. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX> didn't call anyone a
racist. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> did. She should apologize.

            P.S.: Another distinction between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnet</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> didn't pay
Magnet anything for his advice, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> valued <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.P.S.: Kausfiles</ENAMEX> is having lunch with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnet</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>. If he blurts
out anything racist, you'll be notified immediately!

            
               * <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> did call after this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> was posted, but our conversation was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">off-the-record</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Page</ENAMEX>'s hack fact: 
            

            

               "The downside of the changing statistics, and indeed a new figure came out
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> showing unemployment down to--what?--around--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">around 4 percent</NUMEX>, the
lowest it's been since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, is that the poverty rate hasn't changed."

               -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Page</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 5</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
               

               "Continued economic growth led to a significant reduction in poverty in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, as the poverty rate declined to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.7 percent</NUMEX>."

               
                  --press release of the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy Priorities</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 30, 1999</TIMEX>. (The poverty rate has fallen from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15.1 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Census Bureau</ENAMEX>.)
               

            

            
               Pull-quote of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX>:
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sting</ENAMEX> really likes squash <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX>. He really enjoys <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soups</ENAMEX> that have been
smoothed out with no bits or pieces."

               
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Sponzo</ENAMEX>, family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sting</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, Trudie
Styler, quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX>.

            

         
      
   
