
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            Sometimes it's worth remembering that the everyday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of Wall Street,
even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these bull-market days</TIMEX>, is quite mundane. And I'm not talking just
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> who are still out there trying to hit that bid
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> shares at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX>. I'm also talking about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salomon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith Barney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> started coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> with a "hold"
recommendation. Think of it. Why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> right now? And starting it with
a hold? It's like a restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> who's forced to specialize in different
gradations of bland. Or a movie reviewer spending his time explaining why
Music of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and a half</NUMEX>. Or ... but I
prattle on.

            Anyway, the big news of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> was, of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> decision,
except that the big news was how little news the decision made on Wall Street,
at least in terms of moving the market as a whole or even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock,
which now stands only a point or so below where it was when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>
handed down his ruling. Actually, the decision did help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, including especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Linux</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Apparently something can
simultaneously be unimportant to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and incredibly important to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> it's competing against. It's the inscrutable wisdom of the market.
And so, on to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cocktail Chat</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "In a truly phenomenal decision , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delaware Chancery Court</ENAMEX>
ordered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer Associates</ENAMEX> to 
                  give back <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.5</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> shares of stock worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$558 million</NUMEX>. And 'I already spent it on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pokémon</ENAMEX> cards' will not be an acceptable defense."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Priceline</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> introduced its newest and most baffling innovation .
You can now offer bids on the price of groceries. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Airlines</ENAMEX> make seats available
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Priceline</ENAMEX> because they're perishable commodities--if no one uses them,
they're a total loss--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> do the same with empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>. So what items
are grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> going to make available? Day-old-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, batteries that
are about to expire, and mystery <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>? Well. This is going to be big. Really
big."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sci-Fi Channel</ENAMEX> announced that it will begin broadcasting a
weekday talk show with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Edward</ENAMEX>, who is 'known for his uncanny
ability to see dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> .' (Just like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sixth Sense</ENAMEX> .)
Variety said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sci-Fi</ENAMEX> was hoping to 'appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> who are not
necessarily <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX> of the occult.' Apparently only if the show featured
someone who could actually raise the dead would it appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX>
in the occult."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its opening day</TIMEX> of trading , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cobalt Networks</ENAMEX> saw its shares
better than quintuple, rising from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22 to $128</NUMEX> . In other
words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cobalt</ENAMEX> went from being a micro-cap stock to a mid-cap stock in the space
of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six hours</TIMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "In what was touted as a major vote of confidence by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> in the new
direction being taken by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$721</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in a successful stock rights offering that allowed current
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> to buy additional shares at a discount. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX> said <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99.3 percent</NUMEX> of
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> exercised their rights. Of course, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">89 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX>
is owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk Kerkorian</ENAMEX> , who exercised all his rights. So what
really happened is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerkorian</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX> another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$650 million</NUMEX> to play with.
But I suppose that is a vote of confidence of sorts."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "Citing attorney-client privilege, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> is refusing to turn over to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> a report by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skadden Arps</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s financial woes, despite
the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> has subpoenaed the information . Perhaps by the
time it surfaces, there will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18½</NUMEX> pages missing from it."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>'s stock rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 15 percent</NUMEX> after it announced
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that it would be holding a press conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to disclose major
new initiatives . Then it fell almost the same <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> after
it actually held the press conference. One wonders what would have happened if
at the press conference it had only announced that it would be holding another
press conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>."

         
      
   
