
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Keyes Loses It</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HANOVER</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>--The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> debate was enlivened by the presence of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hecklers</ENAMEX> who got inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dartmouth</ENAMEX> auditorium where the town hall-style
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forum</ENAMEX> was taking place. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, shouted that military spending
should be cut to provide better health care until she was ejected from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hall</ENAMEX>. The other, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>, ranted and raved about a variety of topics but was
allowed to remain.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX> is an intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, but <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> he seemed
truly deranged. In response to a question put to all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> about
whether they supported a flat tax, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyes</ENAMEX> declared that the income tax was both
socialism and slavery. "The income tax is a form of
tax that was advocated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX> because it cedes in principle to the
government control of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EVERY LAST DOLLAR</TIMEX> that is made or earned in income," he
bellowed, walking to the edge of the stage. "THINK ABOUT IT," he shouted at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. "If I have to give you a percentage of my income and you get to
determine the percentage, how much are you in control of? HOW MUCH? ANSWER
IT!!! ALL OF IT, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EVERY LAST</TIMEX> BIT OF IT."

            This assault left everyone a bit stunned, but it was
just a warm-up for his answer to a polite and intelligent question about
whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> ought to pay its back <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> dues. "If you want to
blame somebody for that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion-dollar</NUMEX> deficit, blame me!" he shrieked. "I was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> who helped to put together and
foster the policy that withheld our contributions from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> that takes our money--tosses it down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RATHOLE</ENAMEX>!" During these
screeds, someone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> editing room kept cutting to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience members</ENAMEX> who
were rolling their eyes, giggling, or trying to suppress gales of laugher.

            I'd say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step away from being hauled away
in a straitjacket. He, on the other hand, thought he was the hands-down winner.
As soon as the debate ended, he came upstairs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> where the press was
watching on a big-screen TV and offered to take questions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX>, pecking
out their stories on deadline, didn't immediately respond with any. At that
point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX> truly lost it, accusing the press of racism for ignoring him. I
think his tirade is worth recording in full:

            You know what's fascinating?
Can I make a statement here? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> debate that was held in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'96</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX>, they did the polling afterward. I actually won the debate in the eyes of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> polled. I OFTEN win these debates, and every time I stand before you
press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>, you have no questions. I find it kind of amazing. At some point,
you know, one has to start to wonder. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> have gotten
over their racial sickness. I don't know that you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> have. I think that
merit means nothing to you because you can't look past race. And I think I'm
deadly SICK of it. Every time I get in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, they
respond, just as it was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>, to the answers THAT I GIVE. But your response
is nothing because you don't represent those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. You apparently represent
the same money powers that are seeking to destroy the representative nature of
our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. I frankly think you all ought to be ashamed of yourselves. At
some point you ought to wake up to your responsibility not to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX> take
place in darkness and not to let virtue languish unnoticed. That's your job,
but you don't do it, DO YOU? Instead you <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PANDER</ENAMEX> to the money. But if you were
doing your job, we wouldn't have to worry about campaign-finance reform,
because there would be sufficient attention paid to every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in the race
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would know who they are and what they stand for
without the expenditure of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX>. But they don't know, because
you won't do your job. That's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SAD</ENAMEX>! And it's DESTROYING our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>.

            With that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyes</ENAMEX> stormed off the stage and departed the
room, leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> somewhat stunned. In fact, I think the racial factor
works mildly in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX>' favor. If he were a white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, and thus less of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">novelty</ENAMEX>, the press would portray him more directly as a fanatic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ignoring Keyes</ENAMEX>
is the kindest thing the press can do for him.

            The rest of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> was less exciting. If there was
a theme, it was turning up the heat on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> for not showing. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX> television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who interviewed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> before the debate asked if
he wasn't trying to get the job of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> without the job interview. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
took umbrage, saying he had to attend a dinner held in honor of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>, and that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> came first. The excuse is, of course, bogus, as was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> about having to attend a fund-raiser in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>. Several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> took shots at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> for his absence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> had the best line
about how to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to participate in the next debate. "If you call it a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fund-raiser</ENAMEX>, he might show up," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> quipped.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> launched the only direct attack on a fellow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, when he once again hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, this time on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>'s flat-tax
proposal, which exempts inheritance and capital gains. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> said that his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX> and that this wasn't fair. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> responded that people
should be "allowed to leave the world unmolested by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>." He even got off a
good line about  "no taxation without respiration" before dissolving into his
trademark crooked-grin guffaw. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> also took credit for the fact that all of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> present (with the exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX>) now support a flat tax.
This is indeed amazing.

            Perhaps the best answer of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s response to a question about whether the armed forces could be rebuilt
without restoring the draft. After explaining that he thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> didn't
need <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>, he turned to the issue of his temper, recently displayed in
response to a negative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> story that he
claimed was leaked by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> say that perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>
is angry. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, I get angry when we spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350 million</NUMEX> on carriers the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> doesn't want or need. ... And meanwhile, my dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX>
enlisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, brave young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, on food stamps. That's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disgrace</ENAMEX>. That's an outrage. I'm going to fix it as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>." To my ear, the applause <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX> topped out on that one.

            Unlike <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s performance, which ended abruptly,
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s format allowed for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20-second-long conclusions</TIMEX>, speed-speeches that
recalled the great <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monty Python "summarize Proust</ENAMEX>" contest. This was the most
interesting part of the event. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> declared that he supported a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Birth</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom</ENAMEX>," beginning with "the freedom to be born." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> decried what he
called the "virtue deficit." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> was in  "the worst moral
crisis it's ever faced." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> said he wanted to clean up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and
inspire young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, concluding the show, said that several
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> were getting old and that he wanted to pick their
replacements.

         
      
   
