
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Response to My Critics</ENAMEX>!

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kausfiles readers</ENAMEX> criticized the previous
item, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Ending of the Underclass, Part XVIII</ENAMEX>," as excessively
optimistic. The most common objection is, roughly:

            
               How do you get from a declining welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> to "the ending of the
underclass"? What if poor single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> on welfare just become poor single
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> working in low-wage jobs?
            

            My answer is: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Underclass</ENAMEX>" doesn't mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are poor, or even people
who are poor and live in neighborhoods with other poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. It means people
who are poor and live in poor neighborhoods isolated from the mainstream world
of work, where there are lots of single-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother households</ENAMEX> on welfare, few male
breadwinners, and an adversary culture (typically aggravated by race
differences). Although black poverty has been falling, let's assume, for
purposes of argument, that what is happening is poor single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> on welfare
have become poor single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> working in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and fast-food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX>. Can we
say the underclass is "ending"? I think so.

            We can say it because, by definition and in practice, working-poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>
aren't in the "underclass." A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> changing sheets in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marriott</ENAMEX> is no longer
cut off from the world of work. On the contrary, she's likely to be on the
lookout for job opportunities that pay more, or offer useful training. She's
eligible for raises and promotions (not to mention government subsidies like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX>). She can't afford to develop an attitude that
sets itself in opposition to the mainstream culture. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will grow up
knowing the discipline of a working <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, and they will have at least one
working "role model."

            We can also say it because a society of poor working single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> is
probably unstable in a good way. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> know they are not going to be
supported by welfare checks but are going to have to work, they are apt to ask
more of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in their lives--specifically, they are apt to ask that men
contribute by going to work. Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> will be less likely to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
out of wedlock, or at least partnership with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, precisely because being a
working single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> is a struggle. These trends are already starting to
appear--the percent of black births that are out of wedlock has finally stopped
growing, and the black teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">birthrate</ENAMEX> has dropped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26 percent</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, to its
lowest level since record-keeping began.

            Will such big, favorable long-term trends continue? Will others
materialize--in particular, will employment among poor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>
increase? I don't know--that's why I fudged and said the dependency drop
"suggests ... this problem may be on its way to being
radically ameliorated if not solved." (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> escape hatches in one
sentence should be enough!) But I am optimistic, because the logic behind the
favorable scenario seems so powerful. I hope more crack welfare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> will be on the lookout to see if this long-term
transformation is happening--i.e., if the ghettos are becoming different,
better <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX>--instead of just tracking down ex-welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moms</ENAMEX> who are now
working but are still struggling and not making much money.

            Yes, even if the underclass shrinks through assimilation, the problem of the
working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> will still be with us. But that's a different fight, and an easier
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to wage. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are working, it's not that hard to boost their incomes
through familiar means like income supplements (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX>), day-care subsidies,
health-care subsidies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, better training, etc. The peculiar horror of
the underclass has been, in part, that those remedies haven't been able to
crack an isolated subculture of non-working non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. Why can't we look
forward to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> when that has changed?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random</ENAMEX> endnotes: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, after bagging the endorsement
of the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teachers unions</ENAMEX>, has called for "tough future testing for new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>." Not just testing for "new" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, but "future " testing for
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>. Translation: I want to make it really, really clear that
incompetent current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> have nothing to worry about! ... <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>'s
worst example of the new, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-assed, semi-opinionated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
journalism? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Clymer</ENAMEX>, describing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s answer when asked for
examples of presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clymer</ENAMEX> wrote: "And in what may have been
the most thoughtful comment of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>] cited
the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>. He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail S. Gorbachev</ENAMEX> 'saw that
the world must change and had the courage to make that change.' " End of piece.
No explanation of why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s comment was "thoughtful," as opposed to, say,
stupid, given the ultimate pathetic failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>'s attempt to modify
Communism rather than replace it. Just a vague, free-floating, NPR-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bias</ENAMEX> that, well, anybody who mentions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> must be a classy, intellectual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clymer</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. He's not one of those "opinion" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX>! If he were he'd have to actually defend what he says ...

            
               [Note: The fiendishly clever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kausfiles</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> business plan calls for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, at about this point in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX>'s growth, of a snide
little item in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> that gives kausfiles
much-needed publicity. Sure enough, here it is, right on schedule! (Go to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> item.)]
            

         
      
   
