
   
   
      
         
            The <i><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX></i>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baffling Economics</ENAMEX>

            Yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> petition is circulating at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
concerning publisher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Downing</ENAMEX>'s idiotic decision to share advertising
revenue from the special issue of the Times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles</ENAMEX>' new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> arena with ... the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX>. (This novel
arrangement was made known <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks ago</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Times L.A.</ENAMEX> ) An earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> petition protested the
arrangement as a violation of journalistic ethics, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> prompted from
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Downing 1</ENAMEX>) a bizarre apology in which she admitted she didn't know much about
how newspapers work; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) a refusal to resign.

            The new petition, dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX> and addressed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> editor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Parks</ENAMEX> (who has said he didn't know of the financial relationship and
does not approve of it), urges <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX> to publish a lengthy investigation in the
paper of how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> fiasco occurred:

            

               
                  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most important steps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> can take is to publish
in its own pages a thorough examination of the events that led to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX>
deal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> owes nothing less to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> and to its
staff.
               

               Others have written about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> controversy and will continue to do
so. We need to do the definitive piece and do it first--not have it dribble out
in other places.

            

            The petition cites as the main precedent for such an investigation <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barlett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Steele</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> Inquirer investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreman</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foreman</ENAMEX> was a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inquirer</ENAMEX> who had an affair with a local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pol</ENAMEX> while covering local
politics for the paper.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> petition is signed by many important
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at the paper, including city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Boyarsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doyle McManus</ENAMEX>, and such prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and reporters
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Rosenberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Drogin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Fulwood</ENAMEX>. (Chatterbox
suspects other names have been added to the list since he acquired a copy.)

            The petitioners have a good idea, and not just because it might cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downing</ENAMEX>
(and maybe even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Captain Crunch</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willes</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Mirror</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> whose talk
of more cooperation between the business and news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> of the newspaper
probably led to this fiasco) their jobs. There remain many unanswered questions
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> deal, of which the "journalism ethics" question is only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>--and perhaps the least interesting. Why did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> think its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> deal was smart from a business perspective? According to the
sketchy information available (some of it from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> ' own
limited coverage; click here for the best piece), the deal was as follows: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
Times , which for all practical purposes enjoys monopoly status in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>, is paying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX>, which desperately needs publicity from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">somewhere between $2 million and $3 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>.
(The ad revenue from the special issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> handed over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> apparently was a down
payment on these dues.) In exchange, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> is getting a bunch
of ad signs posted inside and outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX>; the right to sell
copies of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX>; and its own "luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX>" (i.e.,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skybox</ENAMEX>). The right to sell copies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> is surely of negligible value. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> suspects the same is true of
the ad signs; but even if there's stupendous value in the TV exposure that
results, it's hard to see how the ads could be worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $500,000</NUMEX>. (In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Veterans Stadium</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">48-foot</NUMEX> ad over the center-field seats
currently costs at most <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> per season.) The skybox is probably necessary
to pamper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>; but if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> had simply rented its own like
most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, the annual cost would apparently have been at most <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rivenburg</ENAMEX>. This suggests that, instead of paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million to $3 million</NUMEX>
per year to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downing</ENAMEX> should be paying something under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>.

            An irony in all this is that the real way to make money off the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> would have been to pander to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> with a special issue of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> magazine (which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> did) and not
share the stupendous proceeds--reportedly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX>--with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX>,
but rather, to keep it all. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> doesn't expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Crunch</ENAMEX> and
his minions to understand journalism; but don't they understand how to make a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buck</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
