
   
   
      
         
            Drug<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">-Company Merger-Maniacs Need</ENAMEX> Sedation
            

            In the wake of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Home Products</ENAMEX>' friendly bid for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80 billion</NUMEX> (or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$74 billion</NUMEX>, depending on who's counting) hostile
counter-offer (click here to
read an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Explainer</ENAMEX>" on hostile takeovers), expectations are growing that we're
going to see a wave of mergers in the pharmaceutical industry. Novartis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glaxo</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schering-Plough</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merck</ENAMEX>: Everyone is either on the block or shopping.
Whether all this buying and selling makes economic sense seems somehow beside
the point. After all, they don't call it merger- mania for nothing.

            The most perplexing thing about the goings-on in the pharmaceutical
industry, though, is not that drug-company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> would rather run <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70 billion</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> rather than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Nor is it that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>'s
bid--which, remember, it could have made long before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Home Products</ENAMEX>
came a-courting--seems driven as much by the "if you want <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX>, then
I want <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX>" impulse as anything else. These, after all, are the
basic ingredients of many, if not most, mergers which has something to do with
the fact that most mergers destroy, and don't create, economic value.

            No, the most perplexing thing about all the merger talk is the reaction of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, who have driven up the prices of pharmaceutical stocks pretty much
across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. Since acquisitions almost universally occur at a price above
the current market price, and since bidding wars (of all kinds) tend to drive
prices far above fair value, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> have jumped into the drug stocks,
assuming that merger-mania has to be good for them.

            Here's the problem, though: There are no outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidders</ENAMEX> for these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. The only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that's going to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glaxo</ENAMEX> is another drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. So, there isn't any flood of outside capital coming into the drug
industry. If a wave of mergers gets touched off, all that's going to happen is
that capital will be redistributed from certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> to
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>. But the total amount of value in the industry as
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a whole</TIMEX> will remain the same.

            In bidding up the prices of all these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are
essentially saying that if you divide a pie up into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> slices, it's more
valuable than if you divide it up into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> slices. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX> is the very
same size. It just looks different.

            It's true that it's better--all other things being equal--to own one of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> slices rather than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>. But all other things aren't equal,
since for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX> to become a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, it's going to have to spend
huge amounts of money to acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX>. The possibility of a merger
wave may make the stock of the potential acquirees more valuable. But it should
make the stock of the potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">acquirers</ENAMEX> equally less valuable.

            The other possibility is that there really will be synergies in the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that will make them more profitable together than they are
apart. But it is hard to see what these are, and empirically, synergies are
next to impossible to realize.

            What that means is that the determinants of value for the industry as a
whole--free cash flow, return on invested capital, and future growth
prospects--will remain unchanged after the merger wave is done. And that means
the stock price of the industry as a whole--if there were such a thing--should
remain the same.

         
      
   
