
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>, Folklorist

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> gave a speech on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX> advocating "moral education." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> agrees
that "values" should play a larger role in educating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, which is why he
supports well-regulated programs requiring high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to perform
volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of some kind. A danger of injecting "values" more fully into
school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curricula</ENAMEX>, however, is that if it isn't done thoughtfully, it will end
up presenting certain pious and erroneous sentiments as fact. This is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oft-</ENAMEX>noted weakness of some of the liberal "values" teaching that already goes
on in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>--a lot of silly misinformation about the environment and ancient
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilizations</ENAMEX>, for example, routinely ends up being passed along by
bumfuzzled
elementary-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>. This drives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> (and even many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">batty</ENAMEX>. Increasingly, something similar seems to be happening when
"conservative" values (like a literal belief in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>) get taught at the
expense of evolutionary science. If moral lessons are to be taught more
forthrightly in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, it's important that the distinction between knowledge
and folklore be maintained.

            In his speech, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> himself seems to have stumbled over that
distinction. In a litany of examples in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> have shown "character
and courage beyond measure," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> cited the following:

            

               
                  When a gun is aimed at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventeen-year-old</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>--and she is shot
for refusing to betray her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            This refers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassie Bernall</ENAMEX>, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> shot by their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classmates Dylan Klebold</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Harris</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last April</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine High School</ENAMEX>
massacre. Shortly after the shooting, the horrifying story spread that before
she was shot, one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> asked her if she believed in God. She said
yes, and the gun was fired. The anecdote became the basis for cover stories in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> and Christianity <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and for a best-selling
book<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, She Said Yes: The Unlikely Martyrdom of Cassie</ENAMEX>
Bernall , written by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Misty Bernall</ENAMEX>. But as was reported
somewhat tentatively on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 25</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> and subsequently confirmed elsewhere, the story
almost certainly isn't true. "We strongly doubt that conversation ever
occurred," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Davis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jefferson County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanna Rosin</ENAMEX>.

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> now believe really happened is that another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valeen Schnurr</ENAMEX>, was shot in both <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and then asked if she
believed in God. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schnurr</ENAMEX> said yes and, for whatever reason, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assailant</ENAMEX>
wandered off without harming her further. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Schnurr</ENAMEX> recovered and is now a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Northern Colorado</ENAMEX>.) She Said Yes
acknowledges this in a backhanded way, with the caveat that "the exact details
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassie</ENAMEX>'s death ... may never be known." In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> piece, which
appeared on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 14</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosin</ENAMEX> explained that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schnurr</ENAMEX> is not going out of her way
to tell her story, because whenever she does it's interpreted as a betrayal of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernall</ENAMEX>. "You will never change the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassie</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernalls</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pastor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave McPherson</ENAMEX>, told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosin</ENAMEX>:

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> is going to stick to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX> story. It's the story they
heard <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, and circulated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> uncontested. You can say it didn't
happen that way, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> won't accept it. To the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassie</ENAMEX> will
always say yes, period.
               

            

            What goes for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> apparently goes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> too. It's
inconceivable that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> don't know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernall</ENAMEX> story has been
discredited; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s speechwriter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Gerson</ENAMEX>, was until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> , for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>'s sake. (A very good one; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> used to work
with him at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> .) At the risk of sounding judgmental--and meaning,
of course, no disrespect to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassie Bernall</ENAMEX> and her tragic murder--Chatterbox
concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s decision to use the story anyway is something a little
worse than exploitative. It's immoral.

         
      
   
