
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawn Powell</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> Act
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Tim</ENAMEX>,

            I'm thrilled to speak to the undisputed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn Powell Fan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>. We <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawnites</ENAMEX> ought to stick together. Sometimes a passion for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> can
still feel eccentric, like owning a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hairless cat</ENAMEX>. When a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-edition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX>
book goes up for auction on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX>, the same <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> of us bid; I've often
thought we should join forces for some harmless price-fixing. Yet I've been
told that thanks to you, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn Powell</ENAMEX> revival is officially a done deal, her
place at the table of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Lit</ENAMEX> all nicely set.

            So my first question for you: How solid is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> revival? I
certainly didn't see anyone reading her at the beach <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>. Nor do many
of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic colleagues</ENAMEX> know her work. They've heard of her, though. "Which
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> should I read?" they ask suspiciously.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX>'s problems, as she griped herself, is that she wrote so damn
much. She failed to produce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perfect Little Novel--a Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatsby</ENAMEX> --that college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> could plunk on their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greatest Books</ENAMEX> lists. Her
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> novels give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX> a run for her money as social satire, but then
there are the elegaic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> books. For a while, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> tried to belittle her
as a "regionalist" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">à la Flannery O'Connor</ENAMEX>.

            Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> is incomparable, we're already mired in comparisons. You must
get mighty sick of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Parker</ENAMEX> analogy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> like the idea of Dotty
and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> mud-wrestling for the title of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funniest Woman</ENAMEX>. But I notice that in
both the biography and your prefaces, you shy away from any feminist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indignation on Powell</ENAMEX>'s behalf. May I do so, just for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sec</ENAMEX>?

            The otherwise admiring review of the Letters in the daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times complained that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> failed to speak enough about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> world
wars she lived through. Same dart that was aimed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austen</ENAMEX>, who penned slight
little "parlor room dramas" instead of addressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Napoleonic Wars</ENAMEX>! Aside
from the fact that the accusation is simply false--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> strikes me as
downright visionary about politics, portraying the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> involvement in
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Time To Be Born</ENAMEX> as a media war much like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grenada</ENAMEX>--it
is yet another time-honored way of dismissing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s work.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ammo</ENAMEX>, as we all know, is important. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diapers</ENAMEX> and dresses are not. How I love
listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell mock Hemingway</ENAMEX>, in her Letters :

            

               There was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>' conference with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H.</ENAMEX> pumping all the way up from
Bimini on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> wings. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest</ENAMEX> gave a good speech if that's what you like
and his sum total was war was pretty nice and a lot better than sitting around
a hot <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> ought to all go to war and get killed and if they didn't
they were a big sissy. Then he went over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stork Club</ENAMEX>, followed by a pack
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">foxes</ENAMEX>.

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX> lived large for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. But our myths of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman artists</ENAMEX>
encourage living real small. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvia Plath</ENAMEX>, as we all know, had to wake up at
dawn to pen her verse before tending to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austen, O'Connor</ENAMEX>, and Emily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickinson</ENAMEX> were classic spinsters. They were so sexless, they were as good as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. (Or, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> would put it about a brilliant acquaintance, "She doesn't
know she is female, and if she should glance down in the shower and see a set
of balls she would only think, Dear, dear, how dusty things get in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.
THIS DOES NOT MEAN I DO NOT <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ADMIRE HER MIND</ENAMEX>.")

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, had a marriage, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> (male and
female), loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. She actually did live--and not just for the cameras.
She had illness and struggle too, in spades, but what amazes me is the
hardiness of her optimism, her resilience, her delight in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of
ideas, and her unshakable confidence in her own worth.

            The feminist issues weren't her only hurdle. There is the simple fact of her
wit. Nobody loves a wise-ass. As we know from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX>, it's the
sanctimonious stuff that gets rewarded. Furthermore she wrote, scathingly,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have never liked to hear about class.

            All of the above? None of the above<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "The terrifying thing," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> noted,
"is that it's the wind and the time and the tide that decide your luck." Do you
think it is that arbitrary? A different turn of the magic wheel and it'd be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawn Powell</ENAMEX> novel having sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50 million</NUMEX> copies in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">385</NUMEX> languages including
Swahili, instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Old Man</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea</ENAMEX> ?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> may be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron saint</ENAMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> laboring in obscurity. That's
partly what makes her revival so romantic. Aside from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathaniel West</ENAMEX> and The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Day of the Locust</ENAMEX> , though, this is it, right? You're the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th -Century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rediscovery Guy</ENAMEX>! I wonder if you think this kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archaeology</ENAMEX> could happen again--to one of us nice mid-list novelists in, say,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2039</TIMEX>--or whether that possibility has been blockbustered,
conglomerized, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX>'d right out of existence.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
