
   
   
      
         
            It Takes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Destroying a Village To Save the World</ENAMEX>?
            

            Greetings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>; greetings to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Club</ENAMEX> community.

            This book was a huge surprise for me. But first, let's have a little talk
about the unspoken psychology of book reviewing.

            It seems to me that there is a basic question about a book that's often the
real question in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">reviewer</ENAMEX>'s mind but that rarely gets laid out directly in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX>: Do you hope other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> actually read the book? We can all think of
books that we read as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> (because we have to), and whose achievement and
message we applaud but that we'd never urge our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to take the time to
read themselves. Similarly, other books may have big logical holes, or messages
we find unconvincing, but are nonetheless a ton of fun to read.

            So let me start by saying: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> should read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lind</ENAMEX>'s new book. You
and I, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>, will no doubt find things we disagree about in the book's message.
I will try to explain in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few days</TIMEX> why I am unconvinced by the most
fundamental point the book tries to make. But I will be satisfied if people
take from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Club</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point only, which is that they should get hold of
this book. There is much more richness and subtlety to its content and argument
than we can cover here.

            I know and respect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lind</ENAMEX>. He is productive, versatile, and above all,
utterly fearless. He writes with a kamikaze spirit (in the admirable
sense)--taking his argument as far as he can and not seeming to care about who
might be mad at him as a result. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who write as fearlessly as Lind
does are often tempted to be contrarian just for the hell of it. Think of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX>' debunking of ... Mother <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Theresa</ENAMEX>. And I was afraid that
this would be my main reaction to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX>'s new book. He would start by finding
the event that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> consider to have been a disaster, and by sheer
virtuosity try to show that actually it was a good idea and a big success.

            But the tone I feared, of being contrarian for its own sake, turns up only a
little bit, as we'll discuss later on, in sections arguing that more or less
everyone was wrong in assessments of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> at the time, and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lind</ENAMEX>'s
proposal of a new regional-psychology explanation of why the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> goes
to war. But the book as a whole is a calm, well-researched, carefully reasoned,
gracefully written development of an argument that I finally disagree with but
that cannot at all be laughed off. By the end of our installments here, I will
have tried to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Club</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">members</ENAMEX> that this book has the wrong title. It
should have been called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Understandable War</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX> does a
very impressive job of showing why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who weren't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX> and weren't war
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> made decisions that turned out so badly through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>. He does
not convince me that it was "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Necessary</ENAMEX>," in the sense that policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> had no better options.

            But that's for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> installments. Let me wrap up this one, and suggest some
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> for discussion and disagreement, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> ways.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) What the book basically says. The heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX>'s argument is that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> was a real war, "the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">world war</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twentieth century</TIMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and its pawns and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> really wanted to expand their
ideological, military, and territorial influence, and they really were engaged
in a winner-take-all contest with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supremacy</ENAMEX>. Because of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>
could not afford to do what great rival empires would previously have done: go
to war over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> that really mattered to them, in this case <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. Instead they tested each other constantly in proxy wars,
for instance, and over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>. These proxy fights mattered because real fights
were too dangerous.

            In all of these other cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lind</ENAMEX> says, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> understood the
importance of winning or at least contesting the proxy fight: mounting an
airlift to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>, arming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, fighting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, making clear that it would
resist any further push on these frontiers. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had not done
so, he says, then its world position would have fundamentally changed, with
serious consequences for it and the world. No one would have believed in its
will to fight. There would have been a "bandwagon" effect against it. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>,
in his view, was not an exception to this pattern, but a logical--"necessary,"
as he puts it--continuation.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) What's interesting about his argument. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX> means to debunk
"minimal realism," the argument that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should do only those
things in the world that it really has to do, because the great evils it must
avoid are overextension and overcommitment. As applied to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, this would
mean staying out of a fight that was likely to go bad. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lind</ENAMEX> comes up with a
memo claiming that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Kennan</ENAMEX> had made the same argument--about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>! There was really no way to preserve it from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> in the long
run, so it would be better to look the other way if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
tried to take over. ("A period of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> domination, while undesirable, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preferable</ENAMEX> to continued [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>] involvement in that unhappy area.") Assuming
that the memo is presented in context, it is interesting, to say the least.
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of similar discoveries.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Where I think he has not made the sale. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lind</ENAMEX> recognizes that a
"necessary" defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX> would have cost many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>
lives--because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Vietnamese</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> had so much
at stake in the conflict. Because of the casualties, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lind</ENAMEX> says, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> would eventually have had to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> anyway. The (quite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">understandable</ENAMEX>) nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics is that support for a war falls
when casualties rise.

            Nonetheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lind</ENAMEX> says, the strategy of "maximal realism" means it would
have been better to have started the defense, and continued it until the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">casualties</ENAMEX> became too high for domestic politics to bear, than to have taken
the "minimal realism" course of not starting the fight.

            This really is the crux of the "necessary" argument: better to have fought
and withdrawn than never to have fought at all. This is where I disagree with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lind</ENAMEX>--and with you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>, I'm guessing. Reading this book helped me see
that I am a "minimal realist." Here's a place we might start. Do you agree with
this characterization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX>'s argument? And do you agree with him that it was
worth having made the start, even if the end was likely to be bad?

         
      
   
