
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veep Veep Beta Veep</ENAMEX>

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> except the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> lead with the recovery of a large piece of
wreckage from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">990</NUMEX> and the discovery of an electronic beacon
possibly emitted by its cockpit voice or data recorder (this story also tops
the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwide</ENAMEX>" box).  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts this story but leads with a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s order to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> to restore funding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>, a story fronted by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . Citing <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> violations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> issued a temporary
injunction against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, which said it will appeal and also fight the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX>'s efforts to make the injunction permanent.

Many air crash stories are filled with airy nothings. "The large questions ...
remained unanswered," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> informs us. "Like many aspects of the early investigation,
numerous facts begged for interpretation and elaboration ... but no immediate
conclusions were forthcoming from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. ... In an inquiry that will
undoubtedly produce many leads, an intriguing one surfaced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>" about a
possible suitcase tampering. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> paragraphs later, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> "were not attaching much significance to the lead." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> does note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">767</ENAMEX> has an excellent safety
record.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-leads the behind-the-scenes maneuvering by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration to admit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 30</TIMEX>,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> hosts a world trade meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> walked
away from a similar deal in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> but restarted negotiations with a call to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> "late on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 16</TIMEX>." The
"secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX>" since then are intended to consummate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
efforts to include <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATT</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> (which sets the
terms for world trade). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> fronts a story chronicling the preparations
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> expected to protest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">separate Post</ENAMEX> story notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> put off voting on a bill to strengthen
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military relations in deference to the negotiations with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            The LAT fronts--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> reefer--the death
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Payton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payton</ENAMEX>, who had bile duct <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, was
his legendary training regimen and brute strength, packed into a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">10</ENAMEX>'',
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">204-pound</NUMEX> frame. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 23</TIMEX> he rushed for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">275 yards</NUMEX> in a game, a league record,
and received the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MVP</ENAMEX> awards.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> fronts a long history of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>.
Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> did not nurture a strong political opposition to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> (eventually he grew cautiously opposed). Also unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> soberly accepted his duty to serve by enlisting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
Reserves. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says he secured an extremely rare reservist
position (they numbered in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>)--one which allowed him to tailor his
military schedule to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knicks</ENAMEX> games. Although he discovered the position through
tips from military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
application did not get special treatment from military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> and that he
specifically asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knicks</ENAMEX> not to lobby on his behalf. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s choices,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes, "display characteristics that recurred often in his
public life: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">foresight</ENAMEX>, circumspection, and skill at finding advantage while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">adhering</ENAMEX> strictly to the rules."

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> opinion pages run critiques of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s rush to judgment on airline disasters. "An event with a
one-in-a-million chance of happening to any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> on any given day will, in
fact, occur <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">260</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," notes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mathematician John Allen Paulos</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ), who argues that the EgyptAir
crash was almost certainly a random event. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read Paulos</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>"
dispatches here.)
And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Glassner</ENAMEX> writes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> that most differences in
safety records between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> have been shown to be statistically
insignificant. Nevertheless, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs a story detailing the (mixed) accident history of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX>. (To read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> on our irrational fear of flying, click
here.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Cohen</ENAMEX> predicts the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Version 2.0</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpha Male</ENAMEX>.
"Do not be surprised if, someday soon, you hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> growl. Do not be surprised
if, at some <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rose Garden</ENAMEX> event, he bares his teeth at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> or--in a suit
selected by [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>--sniffs him. He may even come up to him and challenge
him to arm wrestle. No one has ever done that to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> before--not in an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">olive</ENAMEX> green suit, anyway. This will surely win <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> the respect, admiration,
and sighs of countless <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
