
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Planes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trains</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget Appeals</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with an anonymously sourced report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> has urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to compromise with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> on
abortion in order to repay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> dues, and she has volunteered to take the flack
from pro-choice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with a look at the many deals being
given to lobby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> during the frenetic, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last-minute</TIMEX> budget negotiations on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the emergence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s growing privacy-rights
movement and says that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> will file for a proposed ballot
initiative giving protections to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of identity fraud. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s assertion, in an interview, that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> offered to help him join the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was struggling with his decision to enlist or
possibly be drafted (he ultimately enlisted). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> did not take his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> up
on the offer, he says, "because a lot of those decisions were made with
political influence ... it did not feel right." (Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> used [perfectly legal] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider contacts</ENAMEX> to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force Reserve</ENAMEX>, respectively, during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> published an excellent examination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s draft
dilemma [see also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TP</ENAMEX>"]; on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 15</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> did the same of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s choices [requires free registration, use <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and Serrano
as keywords; see also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TP</ENAMEX>"].

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> wants to give in to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> demands that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> funds
not subsidize abortions provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>--the last major sticking point in
budget negotiations with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> leak, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX>, helps prepare pro-choice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> for the impending compromise and puts
pressure on wavering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quotes a pro-choice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>'s reaction to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> strategy, but not a pro-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s.) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's story on special-interest budget feeding notes that
7-Eleven managed to get repealed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil War-era</ENAMEX> tax on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> selling
liquor--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> gift to compensate for a likely forthcoming hike in the minimum
wage.

            A separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> roundup of the budget talks (run inside) notes that despite
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX> promises from both parties, almost nothing has been done to reform
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>' pledges to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> largely
amount to accounting gimmicks.  The LAT fronts a story emphasizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s victories on most budget
issues. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year</TIMEX> that began with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> trying to drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> ended with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> agreeing to much of his wish list," it notes.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
focuses on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' anger at their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> for taking
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> off rather than finishing the budget.

            The LAT fronts, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs inside, the results of a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pew Research Center</ENAMEX>
poll on political and economic attitudes. The findings are no surprise:
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are moderate and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">centrist</ENAMEX> "from virtually every angle"
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ). The poll largely replicates the results of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT /CBS News</ENAMEX> poll (see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TP</ENAMEX>"): The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> is extraordinarily unpopular, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s popularity; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
will be hard pressed to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s high approval rating;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are happier with their finances and more tolerant of government
intervention than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> identifies a group of swing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pew</ENAMEX> calls the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Prosperity Independents</ENAMEX>." They are young,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">well-educated</ENAMEX>, secular, and libertarian (but pro-gun control). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> they
gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a slight edge over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> they prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to either
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 to 40</NUMEX> points. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
popularity papers over an extremely fractured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">base</ENAMEX>, which stems not from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment so much as from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>.

            On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> opinion page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James DeLong</ENAMEX>, general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Legal Center</ENAMEX>, writes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Penfield Jackson</ENAMEX>'s findings of fact offer
much proof that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> deals rough with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, but virtually none that
these hardball tactics harm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. "This case is not about antitrust," he
writes:

            

               which involves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> getting together to raise prices and restrict
output. This case is about how business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> deal with each other. It raises
issues that go under such names as property rights, contracts, commercial law,
and business <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">torts</ENAMEX>. These are important and useful legal domains. ... [But]
they are not antitrust questions.

            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts a summary of the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s reaction to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s findings. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s conclusions are "mostly solid," the
Times writes, his conclusion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s integration of its
browser into Windows provides no technical efficiency or consumer benefit is
weak--especially because it flies in the face of an appeals court ruling last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, by the way, publishes 
                  Slate
               .)

            
               It's a jungle out there: These are trying times for yuppie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dads</ENAMEX> and moms. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> has been
replacing its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crystal salt</ENAMEX> and pepper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shakers</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and business class with
tubular paper sachets. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> often condenses in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shaker</ENAMEX>, but victimized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> aren't buying this explanation. As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> harried
frequent flyer laments, "If the airplane hits a bump, you have all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> on
the wrong spot." As if that weren't enough, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger Kings</ENAMEX> across the land are running out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pokemon</ENAMEX> toys to go with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kiddie meals</ENAMEX>. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchises</ENAMEX> with toys left have
lines of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">minivans</ENAMEX> wrapped around the block at the drive-thru; a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BK</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> tries to calm the panic by reassuring distraught moms and tots that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is "working around the clock to move toys [to out-of-stock
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">franchises</ENAMEX>]. We have toys making their way by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX>, and automobiles
as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>." But what will this do to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BK</ENAMEX> stock? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> asks a
"restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>": "In the short run, this clearly hurts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger King</ENAMEX>," he
says. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> can't afford to have an unlimited number [of toys] on hand so
they just do the best they can and kind of regroup after the disaster."

         
      
   
