
   
   
      
         
            Front-Runners Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Non-Candidates</ENAMEX>
            

            "What part of 'no' don't you understand?" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX> Gov.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> asked a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> at a lunch in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. The
erstwhile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro wrestler</ENAMEX> wasn't showing off his excellent grasp of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
language--no, he was executing a rhetorical flourish to underscore his
commitment to not running for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> presidency.
"I am not a candidate for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>," he said. "I do not want the job." Indeed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX>, who recently admitted he wanted to be reincarnated as a bra, told his
lunch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX> that he could never be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> because the job is simply too
restrictive. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the free world, but he probably
has the least freedom of anyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> said. "I've lost my
freedom a great deal being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>." Jeez, he's never going to be happy as a
brassiere with that kind of thinking. Boxer shorts, perhaps.

            While I'd rather be discussing your superb piece in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">morning</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> on the limits of online grocery
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shopping</ENAMEX> (so that's why we didn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb shanks</ENAMEX> for dinner ...), I can
imagine the flames and charges of nepotism and conflict of interest. So
instead, I'd like to discuss all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who aren't running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--a
list, I might point out, that's always far more interesting than the jokers and
sad sacks who are running for the highest office in
the land. Remember how exciting it was when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Cuomo</ENAMEX> wasn't running for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>? Now, that was a non-race. Or that lovely general, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>, is
he not running again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>? I haven't heard that he's not running, so I
suppose I have to assume he isn't not running, which would be a shame since he
was such a great non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> ...

            Here's my current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>. He's been
doing a fabulous job of not throwing his hat in the ring yet. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> ran a clip of
him <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, in fact, speaking at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> I believe), in which
he says that if he were really running, he'd be a lot more organized, but he's
not. He said all he's doing, in fact, is reminding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of bedrock liberal
positions that seem to have been forgotten along the way. Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> still
not running? Who cares? Remember how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Kennedy</ENAMEX> always used to not run? Kind
of sad that he no longer doesn't. One thing I'm looking forward to: more
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> getting into the whole non-candidacy thing. Don't you think that
our old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Barksdale</ENAMEX> would make a spectacular non-presidential
hopeful?

         
      
   
