
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Waging War</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times ' top non-local story is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT /CBS News</ENAMEX> poll showing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
have a significantly higher approval rating than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> on most election
issues. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ' top non-local story is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55-44</NUMEX> passage of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
minimum-wage hike--a bill that has not passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and would likely be
vetoed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for the tax breaks it gives to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reefers this story.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads
with the revelation that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> has rated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> divisions
as unready for war, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> has received such a designation
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>. This "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-4</ENAMEX>" rating means that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in question--based in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>--need more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, equipment, and training to
participate in a regional conflict. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says this is partly an
appeal for more money. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , which credits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ,
runs this story inside. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with a Y2K
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scoop</ENAMEX>: Nearly <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of local <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> emergency services--such as
fire, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ambulance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX>--are not Y2K <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">compliant</ENAMEX>. This statistic comes
from the final report of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year 2000 Conversion Council</ENAMEX>, to
be released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> also says that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of health-care
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are unprepared; however, the federal
government, the telecom industry, the financial sector, transportation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>, and the oil and gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> are over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> ready.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> poll finds that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dems</ENAMEX> have a greater-than-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-point</NUMEX> electoral
advantage on health care, education, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> lead
on military readiness, but this issue holds little weight with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, the poll
finds.) Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7-percent</NUMEX>-higher approval
rating than Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>; if this holds, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says it
would ensure a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> holds a significant but
shrinking lead--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10</NUMEX> points--over both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> (the
difference between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in a race with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was not statistically
significant). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> led <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> points in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> points in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>.
Both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> have a greater-than-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-point lead over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>,
however.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2 million</NUMEX> shares
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> leading up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>'s hostile takeover bid for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX>. Since the bid was announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX> shares have
dropped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9 percent</NUMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> opinion piece describes why there have been so many pharmaceutical mergers
recently. Scientific breakthroughs tend to produce small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">start-ups firms</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pioneer</ENAMEX> new methods of research and secure valuable patents. Soon, the
establishment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> realize they need the new research technology and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">patents</ENAMEX>, and the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> realize they need economies of scale to keep
producing successful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. Thus the antibiotic revolution produced a spate of
mergers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '40s and '50s</TIMEX>, breakthroughs in heart and digestive drugs
produced mergers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>, and the genetic revolution is producing mergers
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>. Also, the move in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to create new prescription coverage
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> threatens to lower <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> prices, which in turn pushes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to produce newer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> with higher margins, which requires more research
money and new technology.

            On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Op-Ed</ENAMEX> page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Wills</ENAMEX> argues
that the true test of a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is not temperament or virtue but
the shrewd ability to communicate with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX>.

            

               What disqualifies a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> is the kind of flaw that would turn away
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>. By that measure, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s anger is not what a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pastor</ENAMEX> would
encourage for the good of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>, but it makes little difference at all
in his ability to attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>.

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s problem, therefore, is not that he is a "beta" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice presidents</ENAMEX>--even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>--must be) or that he is reserved (so was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>), but that
hiring a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> hanger-on like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> and trying to hide it shows a
"stunning lapse in intelligence," a daft inability to perceive what will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mobilize</ENAMEX> and what will alienate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>.

            On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> opinion page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX> asks his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>,

            

               Why does everyone loathe us so? Because, my little preciouses, we are so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">loathable</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> like to picture themselves as independent thinkers. In
truth, with the exception of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, there is no social subspecies
more slavish to fashion, more terrified of originality and more devoted to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>-think.

            

             To this, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> readily, wholeheartedly, and unconditionally
agrees.

         
      
   
