
   
   
      
         
            <i><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX></i>, Part III: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Willes Speaks</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times-Mirror</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> "cereal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> wrote a lengthy
memo to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> essentially pleading for a cease-fire in the ongoing war
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' editorial and business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX>. (To get up
to speed on the controversy, click here and
here to
read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s previous items about it.) The key passage in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX>' memo is
headed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Complexities</ENAMEX>." Here it is:

            

               
                  It is important to realize that as we go forward, there are no easy
solutions to complex problems. Inferences from recent events must be drawn
carefully so that decisions can be made that meet all critical and important
requirements. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> mistake has been ascribed to the
fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Publisher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Mirror</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> both lack extensive years of
newspaper experience. Yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> had the courage to report
that it had an equally awkward arrangement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fleet Center</ENAMEX> when it opened
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> had newspaper experience. In fact his
family had run the paper for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 100 years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> is owned by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Company</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> translation : This is where running a family-owned
newspaper along classy principles gets you: Somebody comes along and buys you
out. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L'affaire Fleet Center</ENAMEX> occurred after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> family
sold the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .)

            

               
                  Bad decisions can and are made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with all kinds of backgrounds in
the best kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. The key is to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> make the best
decisions they can. And when they make a bad call, to quickly acknowledge it,
learn from it, and move forward.
               

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> translation : A "bad call" is one that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> find out
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>. So <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from now</TIMEX> on, keep your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yaps</ENAMEX> shut!

            

               
                  Other newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> have business ties that raise important
journalistic questions with which they successfully grapple <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. For
example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona Republic</ENAMEX> must cover sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in which their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have
direct ownership positions. I mention these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> examples simply to indicate
that as we go forward we must meet our simultaneous responsibilities to our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. This requires sensitivity to
all of the relevant issues in a brutally competitive and complex world. We are
               

            

            
               Chatterbox translates : A word to the wise for other news
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>: Flay us for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> deal and we'll flay you right
back. Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX> should write a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-part series!

            [<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Correction 11/12</ENAMEX>: An <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> version of this item ended on the triumphalist
note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> should do penance by giving up tobacco
advertising, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> just announced it will do. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A Times</ENAMEX> staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Hiltzik</ENAMEX>, who finds most coverage of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A Times</ENAMEX> fiasco "ludicrously uninformed," informs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> banned tobacco ads as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whoops</ENAMEX>.]

         
      
   
