
   
   
      
         
            Making Money at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Mint</ENAMEX>
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Mint</ENAMEX> just released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another new quarter</TIMEX> and announced plans for a
new dollar coin in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 2000</TIMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ventures</ENAMEX> are anticipated to be highly
profitable for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mint</ENAMEX>. Why all the new coins? And how does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Mint</ENAMEX> make
money?

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Commemorative Coin Program Act</ENAMEX>, which mandated
that each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> be honored with a new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999-2008</TIMEX>). New <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX> on the front and a state
design on the back, are being released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every 10 weeks</TIMEX> in the order that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> ratified <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Constitution</ENAMEX> (click here for the
release dates). The new <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> coin will honor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacagawea</ENAMEX> (click here for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> article on how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Mint</ENAMEX>
plans to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacagawea</ENAMEX> dollar more successful than its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan B. Anthony</ENAMEX> coin).

            In passing the law, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> cited the coins' educational value, saying the
new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX> would "promote the diffusion of knowledge among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> about the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Collectors</ENAMEX> also lobbied for the
change, since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> coin design had changed little in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX>. But the major
advantage was the potential profit.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Mint</ENAMEX> is in a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>: It can cut and stamp a piece of metal
and sell it for the face value of the coin. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A quarter</TIMEX>, for example, costs the
Mint <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five cents</NUMEX> to make, but sells for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 cents</NUMEX>--an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> profit margin.
These profits, called "seigniorage," go into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s general fund and
are budgeted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> just like tax revenue. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX> coins can also be
exchanged for new ones, but this accounts for only a small portion of the coins
manufactured <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>.)

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> teaches us that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Bank</ENAMEX> uses "money
supply" as a tool to stimulate the economy and control inflation, this does not
mean that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> regulates the supply of bills and coins. New coins and bills
are an insignificant percentage of the total money supply, which--depending on
the definition--also includes checking and savings accounts, money market
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holdings</ENAMEX>, mutual funds, and other financial instruments. (Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> buys
and sells securities, changes interest rates, and adjusts the required reserve
ratio--the amount of hard money <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are required to have on hand--to carry
out monetary policies.) So, coins (and bills) are simply supplied as demanded
in the marketplace.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a typical year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mint</ENAMEX> makes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5 billion</NUMEX> quarters. But it estimates
that upwards of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are collecting the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> commemorative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quarters</ENAMEX>, which is creating an unprecedented demand. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX> are now
being produced at a rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5.5 billion</NUMEX> per year, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mint</ENAMEX> estimates that
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarters</TIMEX> series will generate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $6 billion</NUMEX> in profit.

            Next question?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> thanks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Mint</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>
Bank.
            

         
      
   
