
   
   
      
         
            Worst of the <i><ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX></i>
            

            I love that story! Especially how that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> went <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>! Ah, local politics ...

            But for sheer, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX>-spirit drama, you just can't beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Otis Chandler</ENAMEX>
Story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. I was practically weeping--weeping, I tell you--when I read the
excerpt from the letter the former, great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times wrote, castigating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark H. Willes, chairman and chief executive</ENAMEX> of
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror Co.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for the sheer, unmitigated crap (my paraphrasing
here) the ex-cereal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX> has been pulling since he took over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> hapless
paper. The letter was read aloud to a cheering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">newsroom</ENAMEX> on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, and I like to imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Willes</ENAMEX> cowering in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">office</ENAMEX> seriously
stroking his greased mustaches <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">à la Snidely Whiplash</ENAMEX>. (Note: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX> does not,
as far as I know, have a mustache; this is how my brain works, as you
know.)

            In any event, for those of you not following along at home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lion</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> journalism who during his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year</TIMEX> tenure remade the
Times from a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> to one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> every
thinking human ought to read <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> (quick: Name the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>!). Sadly,
he was forced to retire from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Mirror Co.</ENAMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> when he turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX>. And even sadder, he was the last thing that stood
between the paper and calamity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has steadily lost its place
among the great rags, thanks mainly to the laughingstock way in which it has
has been "reinvented." How?

            Let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> summarize:

            

               I am well aware of the ill-advised steps that have been taken by the current
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> ... such as the unrealistic and impossible goal of adding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX>
circulation, which was announced when Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willes</ENAMEX> came in. Many of these new
marketing programs that were first announced by Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willes</ENAMEX> have been tried and
appear to be unsuccessful. For example, he suggested that the breaking down of
the traditional editorial/business <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> and appointing of business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> was
going to result in new growth to the paper in terms of additional advertising
volume, possible circulation growth, and increased profitability. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willes</ENAMEX>
was quoted at the time in many national media stories as saying he was going to
reinvent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, inferring that the traditional system was outdated and was
in effect a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX> concept.

            

            Oh dear. The letter goes on like that for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX> glorious, Frank
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capra</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">esque</NUMEX> pages. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> everywhere ought to frame it. There ought to be
a parade in honor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dummies</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX> burned in effigy. Ah, but
the marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> would never allow it, would they? Last words from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>, my pet; it's been great e-mailing you. See you at supper:

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> cannot successfully run a great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX>, both of whom have no
newspaper experience at any level. Successfully running a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> is not like
any other business.

            

         
      
   
