
   
   
      
         
            Caucasian Killers

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> all lead with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">271</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">156</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> vote to
prohibit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>-assisted suicide--an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Medical Association</ENAMEX>-supported
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> intended to overturn an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> law. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> have approved the
suicide measure twice, with majorities of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51 percent and 60 percent</NUMEX>.) The bill
has strong support in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> is threatening to filibuster. It is unknown
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would sign it if passed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' top
non-local lead is the assassination of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Armenian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>--including
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>--inside the parliament <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>. This story tops the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's
"Worldwide" box, off-leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , goes below-the-fold at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> (which runs a dramatic video-still of the assassination attempt),
and gets reefered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> .  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-leads the serious, gentlemanly debate between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, a story fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and reefered
(with front-page pictures) by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Armenian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassins shot Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vazgen Sarkisian</ENAMEX> and much
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Cabinet</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">close</NUMEX> range, then took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Armenian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kocharian</ENAMEX>, negotiated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 10 hours</TIMEX>
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunmen</ENAMEX>--apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX> angry at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>'s
land-for-peace negotiations with neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Azerbaijan</ENAMEX>--gave themselves up.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamic Azerbaijan</ENAMEX> lost control of the mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nagorno-Karabakh</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Armenia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this decade</TIMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarkisian</ENAMEX>'s murder came just
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> after seeing off <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strobe Talbott</ENAMEX> (a
sometime 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contributor</ENAMEX>), who was mediating the peace
talks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Armenia</ENAMEX> is one of the highest per-capita
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign aid, and the negotiations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Azerbaijan</ENAMEX> are a
special project of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore-Bradley</ENAMEX> debate as an amicable affair.
Wearing a brown jacket and maroon tie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was more aggressive than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>,
taking questions from the audience <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX> before the cameras rolled and
charging that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s health-care plan would eat the entire <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 trillion</NUMEX> (over
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>) surplus. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> brushed aside most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s criticisms at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>,
then disputed then calmly later on. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX> passed up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">questioner</ENAMEX>'s invitation to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attack Gore</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign-finance abuses. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Ballot Box</ENAMEX>'s take on the
debate, click here.)

            On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. Nitze</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> should unilaterally destroy its nuclear
weapons. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Retaliatory</ENAMEX> nuclear strikes are never justified, he argues, because
they would kill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innocents</ENAMEX>. Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> should use its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pinpoint</ENAMEX> conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> to make both pre-emptive and retaliatory strikes
against nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> and rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John H. Fund</ENAMEX> opines that many of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>--many of them now <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less-than-adoring</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>--could have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predicted McCain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nixonian</ENAMEX> reaction to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s mildly critical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
story (he accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> of "planting" the story in the
Times to smear him; see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>). Fund
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s hypersensitivity should give pause to his acolytes in the
national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has "courage and candor," Fund writes. "But a president
can't rule by heroic example alone; he must build and lead a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. In light of
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s record and reputation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> [as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">temperamental</ENAMEX>], one must ask
how effective a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lone Ranger</ENAMEX> like him would be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports on the latest hot Internet startup: a llama
auction
site. Run by a computer techie at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> who moonlights as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breeder</ENAMEX> at the
"Llamarada" <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Llamaweb</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> lets you search for your woolly pet
by gender and personality type, and even offers a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>herd discount" for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> sales. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> has taken a liking to "PHL
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gem Dandy</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female</ENAMEX> with the cute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inky-black</ENAMEX> face, described as
"suitable for use as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX>" and "very docile/willing." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> will have to
ask his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> before bidding, though. (He might have to settle for the
cashmere goat.)

         
      
   
