
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next Intellectuals</ENAMEX>

            Should there be a Ph.D. program for public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>? The response to
the news that one has been created has been knee-jerk and mocking.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> called it a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hot Air Doctorate"</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camille Paglia</ENAMEX> declared in last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Education</ENAMEX> , "They're going to groom
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--what? To be me? That's not the way to do it." It's true that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intellectuals Program</ENAMEX>--didn't anyone notice that the acronym is PIP?--offers
its own butt up for the kicking. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> for its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> could have
been ripped out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Language Association</ENAMEX> catalog, circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>: There are
classes on feminism, "new spiritualities," environmentalism, postcolonialism,
gender, race, media, dissidence, and, of course, pop culture. The host
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Atlantic University</ENAMEX>, an undistinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boca Raton</ENAMEX> evidently looking for an excuse to lure name-brand talent to its
campus--and who would refuse a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> gig, especially if they make it in, say,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> is name-brand--among the stars scheduled to shine there
briefly at some point in the future are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornel West</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">philosopher Anthony Appiah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parisian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">semiotician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Kristeva</ENAMEX>, feminist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychoanalytic critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juliet Mitchell</ENAMEX>, and even, interestingly, that elegist of
public intellectualism lost, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Jacoby</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Intellectuals</ENAMEX> --but all of them are of a political inclination (leftish)
that has been losing the culture wars on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> of late. You can't help
wondering whether its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>, trained in such ephemera as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhetoric</ENAMEX> and
Principle," as one of the core <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> is called, will be able to hold their
own in the substantially more conservative--and possibly more
substantive--public arena. "If we roll our eyes," wrote the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inquirer</ENAMEX> 's book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlin Romano</ENAMEX> in an essay in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> ,

            
               it's because we suspect that [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F.A.U.</ENAMEX>'s] freshly minted public
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> will find themselves cerebrally all dressed up with no place to
go. Can you imagine 'the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boca Raton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>' exercising cultural clout in
the national media, with profiles about them to follow in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ?
Don't hold your breath.
            

            But it's not as if there's anything wrong per se with a doctoral
training program for public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>. At its best, it would be an
interesting graduate program of general studies.

            The main problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F.A.U.</ENAMEX> program, it strikes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>, is the
name. It's pretty presumptuous for any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> to declare his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
"public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>"; you would much rather they got their certification as
such from someone else. Otherwise, the whole thing sounds harmless. For <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
thing, contrary to the popular wisdom, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F.A.U.</ENAMEX> does not intend to turn out baby
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paglias</ENAMEX>. The program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Kirsch</ENAMEX>, claims, at least, that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
aren't looking for fame: "They are looking for some engagement with the
public." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirsch</ENAMEX> is using code, but what he means is that what he's training his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to be are behind-the-scenes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX>--what Italian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marxist Antonio Gramsci</ENAMEX> called organic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gramsci</ENAMEX> believed that
everybody, no matter what he does, participates in some kind of intellectual
activity--is a philosopher or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of taste, has a unique
conception of the world and line of moral conduct, and therefore generates new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> of thinking. The job of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who actually call themselves intellectuals
is to articulate such situational thought and put it to use for change. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Said</ENAMEX>
put it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some 1994</TIMEX> lectures on the subject:

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s advertising or public relations <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> ... would be
considered an organic intellectual according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramsci</ENAMEX>, someone who in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> society tries to gain the consent of potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, win
approval, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marshal consumer</ENAMEX> or voter opinion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gramsci</ENAMEX> believed that organic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> are actively involved in society, that is, they constantly
struggle to change minds and expand markets ... are always on the move, on the
make.
            

            In short, you could view the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Atlantic</ENAMEX> program as a version of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy School of Government</ENAMEX>, except it's for left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>
rather than centrist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>.

            Moreover, the ideal of the public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> is no newfangled fad.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organic</ENAMEX> intellectual" is not strictly identical with "public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>," of
course, and one wonders whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Jacoby</ENAMEX> understands who exactly he's
signed up to teach, given his understanding of the term "public intellectual"
(in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Intellectuals</ENAMEX> he defines it as one who writes with "vigor
and clarity," not as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> or left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>). But the notion of the
public intellectual is much older than that of, say, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen-scholar</ENAMEX>,
whom no one sneers at, except perhaps organic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>. Almost every
philosophy or political tendency worth mentioning, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plato</ENAMEX> on, has held in
special esteem its version of the active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX> who puts his principles across
well and thereby commands a wider <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>. We might think the idea is newer
because of the phrase, which gained currency in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> mainly because of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacoby</ENAMEX>. In his book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacoby</ENAMEX> deplores what he characterizes as a sort of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX>,
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edenic</ENAMEX> condition of what he calls "classical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>"
born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the turn of the century</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Mumford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight Macdonald</ENAMEX>, and,
inevitably, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Wilson</ENAMEX>--to the generation born after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>, he claims, have all retreated into academia, where they have
lost themselves in a thicket of specialized professional jargon.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> doesn't exactly buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacoby</ENAMEX>'s argument that there are no public
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> left. If anything, there are too many--every bright young thing
graduating from college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> feels compelled to publish his or her
particular social critique, whether readable or not, and there is a small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">platoon</ENAMEX> of quasi-subsidized publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Press</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Books</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Affairs Press</ENAMEX>, etc.) ready to print them. On the other hand, why should
there be any limit to the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby public intellectuals</ENAMEX> out there? And
why shouldn't they be left-wing? Quite a few of the aforementioned junior
pundits get money and support from right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tanks</ENAMEX>, which are the moral
and intellectual equivalent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Atlantic Public Intellectuals</ENAMEX>
Program, if that. So, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> says: Let <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers bloom</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
