
   
   
      
         
            How <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> Could <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Have Been Saved</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>:

            Hmmm, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s on your side and not mine? I don't think so. He was
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> who declared in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s intervention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> was a
"noble cause"--and the press trumpeted the comment as a gaffe. This didn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bother Reagan</ENAMEX>, who was used to such treatment, and it didn't affect his
position on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. He not only supported the war; he often voiced the
conservative argument that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> had prevented the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> from pursuing a winning strategy. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX> rejects this view, and so do
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX>) As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was willing to commit <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, but he didn't
need to. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> doctrine of backing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX> around the
world worked. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> pulled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> both because of the
bombing that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> of them and because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> didn't have a mission
there in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. This doesn't make him a minimal realist. The truth
is, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> should never have been sent in.

            I think we disagree over what constitutes revisionism. The kind I'd been
looking for would bring fresh analysis and a new interpretation of events. The
late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Braestrup</ENAMEX> did that in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Story</ENAMEX> , which showed how badly the
press had misreported the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tet Offensive</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> and repercussions it caused.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNamara</ENAMEX> didn't do that; he simply embraced the left's contention that the war
was unwinnable and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> shouldn't have intervened. I have to plead amnesia
on what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Podhoretz</ENAMEX> said exactly. I read their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> books, but I
don't remember them. Must be old age.

            The problem with so much that's been written about the war is that it stops
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>. At the time, things did not look good for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX>, despite the
utter failure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Viet Cong</ENAMEX> to achieve what they wanted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tet</ENAMEX>
Offensive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was still tied to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westmoreland</ENAMEX> strategy of
staging big battles. But post-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westmoreland</ENAMEX>, things did get better, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> scarcely noticed. To cite <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> example, in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Bright Shining Lie</ENAMEX> ,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most riveting books about the war, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Sheehan</ENAMEX> doesn't take
evidence that the war was finally being won by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> seriously. Nor do most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> who covered the war. They're frozen in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, I think, and that time was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>. By the way, I know of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who wrote about the war critically and then lamented the outcome
and what they'd written. They are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shawcross</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Lacouture</ENAMEX>.

            Casualties. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> definitely are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualty-sensitive</ENAMEX>. I'm reminded of
this every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning and night</TIMEX> when my commute takes me past the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial</ENAMEX>. There's always a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> there. I think it's partly because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> haven't got a fair shake from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, etc.
Anyway, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX> is right that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> had stayed at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> level, there
would have been a huge political price to pay at home, far bigger than the one
that was actually paid. But they didn't stay at that level. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>
began bringing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> home in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>. Nonetheless, the war went better.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Vietnamese</ENAMEX> fought better. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Viet Cong</ENAMEX> were driven away from the
outskirts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saigon</ENAMEX> and isolated in pockets. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> had the
upper hand. And some have claimed the war was essentially won. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time I
heard this argument was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> when I took a course on the military at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>. It
was taught by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prof.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kauffman</ENAMEX>, who used to write the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s annual
posture statement. I didn't believe him at the time. But more recently the case
has been made strongly by the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Colby</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost Victory and</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just this year</TIMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Sorley</ENAMEX> in A <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Better War</ENAMEX> .

            All this leads to a question I'd like you to answer. It's about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>
model. What if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had not pulled all its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>,
but left, say, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> behind and kept up military and economic aid?
Might <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX> have been--you won't like this word--saved? I think so. Of
course, I'm rewriting history here. In reality, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> allowed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Vietnamese</ENAMEX> to keep <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX> when he
negotiated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1972</TIMEX> peace settlement, and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> came home, and
all aid was cut off in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>.

            Lind mentions the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> model, but doesn't really pursue this point. What's
your view, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
