
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limits of E-Commerce</ENAMEX>
            

            Air travel is a horror. But still, how amazing! I mean, to get on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> at
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">22 hours later</TIMEX>, hop off in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX>--where it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 a.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, I'm sorry, call me <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amish</ENAMEX>, but how
cool is that! I've been thinking a lot about our trip and the amazing Place of
the Future that is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> ...

            The thing that I think will totally mess up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businesspeople</ENAMEX> when they
consider <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> and, to a different degree, the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, is the extent
to which e-commerce--and the Net--will catch on. It's the classic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>'s trap
that every businessperson from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Marco Polo</ENAMEX> on has made when considering the
gigantic potential market of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            Again, it's easy to leap to the wrong conclusions when you wander around
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> and see how wired everyone is. So many cell phones! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Groups</ENAMEX> of people
out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, and rather than talking to each other, each was engaged in a
cell-phone conversation with someone else. It seemed like we were never more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> paces away from a street-side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stall</ENAMEX> selling cell phones, service, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accouterments</ENAMEX>. I've never seen such customizing of digitalia: It made me want
to buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (since you made me get rid of our old, useless one!) just so I could
"personalize" it with one of those translucent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antennas</ENAMEX> with the lightning bolt
inside. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> customize their phones in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>
personalize their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fringe</ENAMEX>, medallions, blinking lights.
Remember the teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> talking into phones that were buried inside Winnie
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooh</ENAMEX> covers?

            Now, imagine when all those cell-phoners start browsing the Web through
their smart phones ...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> is the culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, and add the Net to it, you figure, and
you've got a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillion-dollar</NUMEX> opportunity--but you'd be wrong. The thing about
shopping here is it's a social activity, a reason to get out of your tiny
apartment. Didn't we hear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HK</ENAMEX> is the most crowded place on the planet?
That's why e-commerce will never catch on: It provides a "solution" to a
nonexistent problem. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> want to leave their desks and their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>,
indeed, they have to if they want to see each other. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net</ENAMEX> will never catch
on there the way it has here.

         
      
   
