
   
   
      
         
            Do <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">These Glasses Make Me Look Ugly</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Merrill</ENAMEX>--

            I also came across the terrible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moesha</ENAMEX> news, and it's truly tragic, not only
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moesha</ENAMEX> (oops, sorry, I meant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Brandy</ENAMEX>. I always just think her as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moesha</ENAMEX>,
even though that's obviously not her name, kind of the way <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of people
around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> still think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dean Anderson</ENAMEX>'s name is "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGuyver</ENAMEX>"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, it must drive the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> absolutely nuts, wouldn't you
think?), but for our entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. On top of the the pain and suffering Moesha
(er, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brandy</ENAMEX>) must be going through herself on a personal level (I once saw a
Lifetime original movie about coping with dehydration, and believe me, it was
more than a docudrama, it was the powerful story of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s courage in the
face of acute moisture-shortage), there is also the larger tragedy of a whole
consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> having to go without new episodes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moesha</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>
until, somehow, a cure can be found.

            As a comedy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, I'm sure you must be familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moesha's</ENAMEX> (there I go
again) sitcom work. Did you ever happen to see the one where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moesha</ENAMEX> has to get
glasses, except she refuses to wear them because she thinks they make her look
ugly, and so she spends the entire episode bumping into things and getting into
all sorts of crazy mixed-up situations because she, you know, can't see
anything?

            I didn't, but I did see a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-sentence capsule plot summary for it in the TV
listings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one time a couple of years ago</TIMEX>, and I gotta tell you, I laughed my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">friggin</ENAMEX>' ass off. Just imagine how much even funnier it would've been if I'd
actually seen the entire <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half-hour</TIMEX> episode! Until such comedy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> is back on
the airwaves once again, the theme-song lyrics "Everybody! In the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>! Say
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo-eeeeeeeeeeeeee-sha</ENAMEX>!" will have taken on a grim new tone for us all, becoming
not an anthem of celebration and joy but a somber dirge of melancholy and
despair across the land.

            The bit about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide</ENAMEX> summary is a true story, and here's
another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>: An entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> here at the paper attended a press
junket with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moesha</ENAMEX> (I mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brandy</ENAMEX>) once, and he got to interview her along with
the rest of the teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psycho-murderer</ENAMEX> horror flick she was in, called,
I think, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Still Know What You Did Two Summers Ago</ENAMEX> , or something like
that. I still have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moesha</ENAMEX> promotional hat he gave me from his trip. Since
they were all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>, he sarcastically asked them if they had any advice for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Youth</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, and Moesha literally replied that if they believed in
themselves, they could make their dreams come true.

            But get this: That's not the funny part. To illustrate her point, she said
"Look at me ... sometimes I worry that I'm not pretty enough, but I work hard,
and put on makeup, and try to overcome my weaknesses." (!?!?!?!?)

            She didn't say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sometimes</ENAMEX> I worry that I'm not a good enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>," or
sitcom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>, or movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, or whatever. She was worried that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't
think she was pretty enough. And I wonder what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> (and really, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> now? Doesn't this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> know his life already parallels the plot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Citizen Kane</ENAMEX> enough as it is? I mean, hasn't he even ever seen it?)
would have to say about that? And maybe all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s aspiring
submarine-crew <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> would finally get to fulfill their dreams of supervising,
and, in the event of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War III</ENAMEX>, actually launching thermonuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>,
if only they just believed that they were pretty enough, huh?

            More later,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
