
   
   
      
         
            Dream Trips
            

            For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days</TIMEX> since we've
returned from our lovely junket to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, I was able to sleep more or less
normally last night. As you and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto</ENAMEX> (the dog) know from my frequent nocturnal
mumblings, trips to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>, and shufflings around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>, the jet
lag of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week</TIMEX> has been miserable. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Every night</TIMEX>, a roiling marathon of
travel dreams has played inside my head. You know the genre: I'm in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">airport</ENAMEX>, with too much luggage, trying to catch a plane home and/or use a pay
phone with improper currency. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> I made it until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dawn</TIMEX> before having a
single, ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> dream. The dream: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX> (the Goldbergs!) convinced us to
use their tickets home from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> on a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on which
we already were booked. The horrible part about this wasn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Anxiety</ENAMEX> of
Uncertainty (would the airline honor the tickets?), it was how reality impinged
upon the dream: Shortly after our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> took off, it began a slow-motion plunge
into the drink. The icy <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>. Near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nantucket</ENAMEX>, where we vacation every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>. Yes, somewhere over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doomed</ENAMEX> EgyptAir Flight 990 collided
with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>-lag dreams, and as I sit here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, the nightmare of air
travel permeates my waking.

            This should be no surprise since the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> crash
permeated my waking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. What a bizarre day. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> getting into
their ghoulish costumes to celebrate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX>, the neighborhood teeming with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> dressed up as Death ... and everywhere around us the ghoulish news of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">217</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> perished at sea.

            Still, I am surprised at the degree to which it's truly
unsettling old hard-bitten cynical me. I am not someone who fears flying
(that's your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, right?), but I'm am definitely starting to have second
thoughts. I've always been something of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> for technology and have
typically enjoyed an unreasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> in all machinery except pay phones. In
fact, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> crashed into the ocean not far from where we slept, I was
sure it couldn't have been mechanical error. I figured it had to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>.
We even talked about cranking out another lesser thriller, remember? Prologue:
A case of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stingers</ENAMEX> disappears from the back of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military transport.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 1</ENAMEX>: We watch as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>, sitting on their trawler off the coast of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, sight in on a jumbo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>, ready, aim, and fire one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stingers</ENAMEX>,
blowing the silver tube of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> out of the sky. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 2</ENAMEX>: Troubled, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Transportation Safety Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s beeper goes off
assigning him and, later, gorgeous, straight-arrow, divorcee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Agent</ENAMEX> Delores
Dunray, to the case ...

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA 800</ENAMEX> appears to have suffered from a design
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flaw</ENAMEX>, a fatal crack in its technology. Was it a technical glitch that caused
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> crash of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payne Stewart</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>? Too soon to say. Will it
also be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">culprit</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> crash? I much prefer the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terrorists</ENAMEX>-taking-out-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an</NUMEX>-airplane scenario to human error or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bad Technology</ENAMEX>.
Don't you?

         
      
   
