
   
   
      
         
            Style of the <I>Times</I>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the problems plaguing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s anti-missile defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>, a legacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star</ENAMEX>
Wars" dream. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead exposes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s gross
underestimation of the flow of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>-producing
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Revised estimates on global drug-trafficking are expected to shake
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> drug policy for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to come. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with the unexpected
decline in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> spending.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP</ENAMEX> describes a "stinging" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>-page report, submitted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
by a independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> appointed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX>, that criticizes the
government for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-optimism about its ability to develop interceptors, or
"kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>," that would destroy incoming ballistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> by colliding
with them at supersonic speed. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the program is
fraught with technical challenges and political pressures. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration and congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, less gung-ho about the program than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, have reluctantly acknowledged that a "limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>" might be
necessary sooner rather than later to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> from such
"rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>" as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. But is the multi-billion-dollar effort
still a pie-in-the-sky dream? Perhaps. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> points out that despite a
successful interception <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, there has been no integrated test of the
program's component parts: the kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>, radars, and controlling computer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>. And it remains to be seen whether the kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> will be able to
withstand the shock loads of the booster <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> being designed to carry them
into space.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> drug-intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have admitted
that their methods for measuring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> production might be "seriously flawed."
According to those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s estimates are likely to "skyrocket."
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> unnamed government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> suggested to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> that estimates of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> production in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX> alone could triple. Where is all that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>
going? Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> think it's going to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>; others think it's coming here
and that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are using more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> than previously feared. Not everyone
agrees, of course: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Policy Analysis Program</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX> is
a cynical, outside dissenter. "More <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>? Hard to believe," he
said. "Where are all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX>?" Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> think the estimates are little
more than "guesswork" used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> to get more money out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> spending has declined by one percent
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX>, from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$213.6 to $212 billion</NUMEX>. The slight drop is attributed to
congressional cuts, low inflation, and efforts to weed out fraud. "The decline
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> spending is a phenomenal development," said a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget Office</ENAMEX>, which, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports, had predicted
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19 billion</NUMEX> more on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> than it
actually did.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front stories on the violence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs an Op-Ed written by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story details <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> and
highlights the plight of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>.It reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> estimate
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> have been killed. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> admits that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> cannot
be checked independently.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , on the other hand, focuses on the
growing tension between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and the West and on nationalist support for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> military's operations. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Op-Ed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>
appeals to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and denies that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is targeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> tell us that ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> are suffering, that our
military tactics may increase that suffering. The very opposite is true. ...
Our land and air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> strive to target only opposing armed forces." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">;</ENAMEX>

            The WP fronts the likely mobilization of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> and business
lobbies to push <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to adopt the legislation necessary to open trade with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, should the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> strike a deal that would bring China
into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> stuffs a related story on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.-China WTO</ENAMEX> negotiations, which had stagnated before the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> intervened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. The LAT fronts a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, the
site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> meeting, where the trade debate is already heating
up. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> would like to get <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>--one of the world's fastest growing jet
markets--into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> are opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s entry until it
allows independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> and improves general working conditions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">;</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts the discovery that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> is trying to develop
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">longer-range</ENAMEX> ballistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, prompting concern over a possible arms race
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North and South Korea</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, which provides <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seoul</ENAMEX> the
military assistance it needs for strategic deterrence against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>, has
been pressing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> to restrain its missile program. (After all, our
anti-missile defense program might be on the rocks. See above.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX>;

            
               "low" and behold : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> laments <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of an era</TIMEX> in his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On</ENAMEX>
Language" column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Magazine</ENAMEX> . In the latest edition of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Manual of Style</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usage</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of the lauded paper, the capital letter has been taken down a peg.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> explains: "We are guided: 'It is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamm</ENAMEX> (without a given name)
in the first reference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.' Note: not 'the
current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>,' with a capital P." Also losing caps are "founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>"
and "the king," in "God save the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> might not feel the
immediate effects of the new rule, but with trickle-down style there's sure to
be a sea change on the way.

         
      
   
