
   
   
      
         
            Is <I>The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New New Thing</ENAMEX></I> Copyrighted?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>' just published book, The 
               New <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Thing</ENAMEX> , lists a copyright date
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here
to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Nocera</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Strouse</ENAMEX>'s discussion of the book.) Does this mean
it is not legally protected until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>?

            No. A book's reported copyright date is essentially
meaningless. Copyright protection is granted automatically to a work
immediately upon its creation (which, in the case of a book, means the moment
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> first puts his pen to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> or fingers to the keyboard).
Publication of the work or registration with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Copyright Office</ENAMEX> is not
required. Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> had to publicly declare a claim
of copyright on published works for it to be legally binding. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, the
use of a copyright notice was made optional; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> must now presume that a work
is copyrighted even if it does not directly say so.

            If a work is copyrighted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, the protection
lasts until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 years</TIMEX> after his or her death. If it is copyrighted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>
party (e.g., a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>), it is protected for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95 years</TIMEX> after publication or
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">120 years</TIMEX> from creation, whichever is shorter. Thus, there is little legal
consequence to post-dating a copyright claim. So, why do it? Typically, a
book's scheduled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">release date</TIMEX> changes multiple times before publication.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX> often use the latest of the potential publishing dates in order to
ensure that a new new book doesn't look old too soon.

             

            Next question?

         
      
   
