
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eine Klein Critique</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kausfiles</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> went away for a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, and missed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Klein</ENAMEX> swoon. This time over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>. Actually, it
was more of a swoonlet; as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> makes clear in a contribution to

                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Fray</ENAMEX>,
he's just really happy with several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>. (Is he allowed to swoon for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> at a time? Isn't that
some sort of antitrust violation?)

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>'s piece is perfectly OK. But one expects a lot of him, since he was once
(and may again be) the best in the business. So:

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Why discover <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> so late? Most of the press told us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX> about the
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s "artful languor," his "aloof anti-charismatic messianism," his
emphasis on "substance, not style." You can see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>'s failure to obey the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>'s quasi-menstraul cycle (which dictates that this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Comeback</ENAMEX>
moment) as stubborn, heroic individualism. Or you can say <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> seems to think its high-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> aren't very well
informed--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, maybe, with no time to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>--and they can use a
sort of remedial course on what's been happening in politics over the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. They need a classy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> to tell them that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has "run an
extremely effective campaign" but that "The race is about to intensify." Did
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> write sentences like that when he was at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ? I don't remember them. (A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>
theory: Maybe it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> who are isolated and not very well-informed.)

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) In the course of mildly hyping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
proposed an "extremely controversial" solution to each of the problems he has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tackled</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> poverty. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> poverty speech was a
bunch of sensible incremental proposals that practically everyone
to the left of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rector</ENAMEX> might endorse (and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rector</ENAMEX> might go for some of them). To show <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s extreme controversiality
on poverty, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> "has remained opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">welfare</ENAMEX> initiative." But it is hardly controversial if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> doesn't renounce
his own recorded vote against the bill. What's significant is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>
doesn't call for repealing any significant part of the law--which would be controversial. What seems to have
happened is that after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> got burned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>' sniping at the cost of
his health plan, he got a bit cautious, and hasn't proposed anything dramatic
since. But that's not the sort of complication you can get into if you're
giving a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">remedial</ENAMEX> lecture to time-pressed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDs</ENAMEX>.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>'s other generalities are sometimes a little off. He says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
antipoverty plan had a "big price tag--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9.8 billion</NUMEX>." If that's a big price
tag, we really have gone a long way down the incrementalist <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> also
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">praises Bradley</ENAMEX> for giving "speeches on issues that are less prominent on most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX>' radar screens," citing, as his first example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s speech on
"gun control." But if ever there was a "hot button" issue that is big on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX>' radar screens but relatively unimportant in reality, it's
gun control. As others have said: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> has fact-checkers; it needs some thought-checkers.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> is just spending his time doing something else, like writing his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next</TIMEX> novel. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, Kausfiles
doesn't have that excuse!

            
 
            

            

               So he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucasian</ENAMEX> guilt thing going, is that it?
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ickes</ENAMEX>, a White <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy chief of staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
re-election, steadfastly has denied breaking any fund-raising laws."

            

                --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct. 27</TIMEX>, describing the efforts of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX> on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson Jr.</ENAMEX>'s campaign for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
