
   
   
      
         
            Those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wild 'n' Crazy Supply</ENAMEX>-Siders
            

            The single-mindedness--OK, fanaticism--of the supply-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siders</ENAMEX> who helped
orchestrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> tax cuts of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX> never fails to astonish. These
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> really are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s equivalents of what we used to call vulgar <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marxists</ENAMEX>,
only instead of explaining everything that happens as a product of the class
structure, they explain everything that happens as a product of tax rates, and
they are unwavering in their insistence that the lower taxes are, the better
everything will be. By this point, they can be fazed neither by
experience--like the performance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1993</TIMEX> tax
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hike</ENAMEX>--nor by theory.

            There's an excellent demonstration of this ability to avoid the real world
in the latest issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> , which features <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different
columns on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Mundell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Memorial Prize</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics</ENAMEX> (which
our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> recently dissected). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Barro</ENAMEX>, a conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>
to be sure--and one who has no love of taxes (or of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, for that
matter), but also someone with a firm grasp on reality. His column is therefore
a fond tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mundell</ENAMEX>'s work in international macroeconomics, a field he
practically invented, and to his influence on current thinking about exchange
rates and monetary policy. This is, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barro</ENAMEX> notes, the work for which Mundell
won the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX>.

            Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mundell</ENAMEX> also went on to work on--or speculate on--the supply-side
effects of tax cuts, and this work was obviously important to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Reaganauts</ENAMEX>.
But as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barro</ENAMEX> himself writes, "Whatever the merits of supply-side economics and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganomics</ENAMEX>--and I would say there are many--these ideas had nothing to do with
the work that resulted in a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> prize."

            And yet just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, in the very same issue, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Craig Roberts</ENAMEX>,
among the truest of the supply-side <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cadre</ENAMEX>'s true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX>, begins his column
with these words: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert A. Mundell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> has deprived supply-side
economics of its voodoo status." Of course, he doesn't then go on to actually
offer any evidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> was impressed by or even interested
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mundell</ENAMEX>'s supply-side work. (He can't because there is no evidence.) He just
retells the story of how a "handful of supply siders ... gained control of
policy" and saved the world.

            Oh, actually he does one other interesting thing, arguing that supply-siders
deserve credit for a great unrecognized feat: "the integration of micro- and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macroeconomics</ENAMEX>." Before them, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> saw that there might be links
between the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and industries behave and the way national and
international economies behave. This is, needless to say, an announcement that
will come as quite a surprise to most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>.

            The problem with the supply-siders isn't, of course, that tax cuts are
always a bad idea, or that emphasizing the effects of tax cuts on supply as
well as demand was a mistake. It's that their faith in supply-side economics is
a religion. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX> cannot be questioned, let alone refuted, and even
things to which it's irrelevant--like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mundell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> prize--have to be
understood in its light. The odd thing is that this approach makes it
impossible to take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> seriously, which raises the obvious
question: why does he keep writing?

            On the other hand, I keep reading. So maybe that's an answer.

         
      
   
