
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of Tabloid Objectivity</ENAMEX>

            I am sitting here attempting in vain to find something to disagree with in
your brilliant last posting, my darling, but cannot. OK, allow me this one
quibble: As you know, I'm of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are only good for
one thing: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX> value. The good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> figured that out
before the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and we're just now catching up. (Unless we
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">count Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>.) And by that measure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> would be the better
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. Still, I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pro Elephant Dung</ENAMEX>. And I vote. Sometimes.

            However, I'd like to squander my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> here with something I find far more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">riveting</ENAMEX>, and infinitely more disturbing: I'm referring, of course, to the
announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Media Inc.</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that owns the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly World News</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> --is
buying the publisher of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> and the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examiner</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$105 million</NUMEX>. You probably remember that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Media</ENAMEX> was
purchased in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 million</NUMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> headed by
former Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Altman</ENAMEX>, so maybe you aren't surprised by
this hubris. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Pecker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Media</ENAMEX>, the
combined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will be "one of the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> of celebrity-driven
content in the world." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX>? I hope not.

            I couldn't believe this when I read it. I'd be terrified if I thought that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will let this one get by without its usual far-sighted scrutiny. I
mean really: How could any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> let such a deal go
through? I don't know about you, but I look to my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> for unbiased, even-handed
reporting of alien <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">abductions</ENAMEX>, miracle pet rescues, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity drunks</ENAMEX> and
their sudden-onset obesity. But imagine, if you will, a world in which all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid media</ENAMEX> is consolidated under one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>. Where will we go for the truth?
TV? If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly World News</ENAMEX> asserts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> is going to blow up
on such and such a day, will the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> ever dispute it? Even if it
knows that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWN</ENAMEX> is out to lunch on this one? The fact that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> would even have to ask such questions should put the stamp of death on
this deal at once. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX>, if only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> already ...

         
      
   
