
   
   
      
         
            What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is a Hostile Takeover</ENAMEX>?
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Home Products</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX>
agreed to a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$72 billion</NUMEX> merger. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Hours</TIMEX> later, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>, another drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>,
launched an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$82 billion</NUMEX> hostile takeover bid for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX>. What makes
some takeovers hostile? And how do they work?

            In a friendly takeover, the management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of the acquiring and target
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> negotiate the terms of the deal--covering issues such as how shares
in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will be divided--and then both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> approve it.

            A takeover is deemed hostile when the target <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> to
the deal. (This is the case with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX>, which quickly rejected
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>'s takeover bid. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX> has since filed suit to block the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHP-Warner</ENAMEX>
merger.) In a hostile takeover, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">acquirer</ENAMEX> can take control of the target
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s management one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways: a tender offer or a proxy fight.

            In a tender offer , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">acquirer</ENAMEX> offers to buy shares of the target
for more than the market price. Individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> then decide whether to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> their holdings; if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">acquirer</ENAMEX> doesn't win a controlling stake, the offer
is rescinded and the shares returned. In a proxy fight , the acquiring
company asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> for their "proxies"--that is, the right to vote in
their stead in management elections. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">acquirer</ENAMEX> promises to replace the board
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> that rejected the merger with one that would approve it. As in a
tender offer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> are guaranteed profit--either through cash payments
or more shares in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>--if the takeover is successful.

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX> has not officially made a tender offer or begun a proxy
fight, it has made clear to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> that they would benefit
financially from the deal: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX> would offer them <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> more per share
than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHP</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read

                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moneybox</ENAMEX>" on why these mergers don't usually
create the value <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> expect.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> have tried to prevent
such an offer from ever reaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> by including a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX> breakup
fee in their agreement. This provision requires any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that thwarts the
marriage by acquiring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> to pay the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX> is challenging the breakup fee in court, arguing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>'
boards neglected their obligation to pursue the best interests of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> by undermining attempts at a hostile takeover.

            Next question?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> thanks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prof.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Pritchard</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Michigan Law</ENAMEX>
School.
            

         
      
   
