
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Winnable War</ENAMEX>
            

            Hi, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>,

            Maybe the sting is finally out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> debate. Your comments were
so reasonable, it's hard to believe the subject was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. When I look back
now at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam</ENAMEX> era and recall what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (including me) thought and said,
I think a dark cloud must have passed over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Passions were so great
on both sides of the debate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>--I was antiwar at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>--that few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have honestly reconsidered their views or taken a fresh
look at the war and its results.

            With all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> books pouring out, I'd been looking for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> for a
revisionist take, one that didn't accept either of the liberal explanations
(the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> missed opportunities for a settlement; the war was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unwinnable</ENAMEX>) or the conservative <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> tied the hands of the
military). But serious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> revisionism barely existed--until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lind</ENAMEX>'s
book came along. I know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>, but only slightly, and I haven't read any of his
earlier books. I was excited when I read <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Necessary War</ENAMEX> , and
I think it's an enormously important book.

            Let me start with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> points:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Yes, I basically agree with your characterization of the theme of the
book. And I agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX> that even an ultimately unsuccessful intervention
was better than none at all. I'm not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to make the point that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia</ENAMEX>
would probably be quite different <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (and far worse off) if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> had pulled out in, say, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963 or 1964</TIMEX>. Then, the dominoes might really
have fallen; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> did anyway (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Kann</ENAMEX> of the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> has written that a breathing spell was needed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> to
allow free markets and political freedoms to grow. And, boy, did they grow
during that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year period</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965 to 1975</TIMEX> while the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> staved off
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Vietnamese</ENAMEX>. Would <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> be a free <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> absent that? I
doubt it. Would <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> be independent?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lind</ENAMEX> may overstate the bandwagon effect in world affairs, but there's
certainly something to it. The proof is what happened post-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> did bug out. Then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> was emboldened and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
was demoralized. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> were soon on the move in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>) were all but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paralyzed</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> was dead set against intervening anywhere. The defeat
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and the rest of the world the message that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> was out of the game for a while. And this was an accurate
message. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lind</ENAMEX>'s contention is that things would have even worse if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> had simply taken a pass on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. A more damaging message would have
been sent and a bigger bandwagon effect touched off. As for minimal realism,
it's an excuse for neo-isolationism, for an ever-shrinking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> role
in international affairs. It could have been invoked to let the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Koreans</ENAMEX>
take the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese Communists</ENAMEX> seize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> guerillas
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">conquer Malaysia</ENAMEX>. I'm glad it wasn't.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. There's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> area where I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lind</ENAMEX> comes up short. He thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, given the way the war was being fought, should have pulled out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>,
if only to avert the subsequent casualties that, he argues, wound up weakening
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s determination to combat <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> communism. He's right
about the way the war was fought under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Westmoreland</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX> to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wrongheaded</ENAMEX> is a mild way of characterizing it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westmoreland</ENAMEX> tried to
lure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> into big battles and stressed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> counts. Meanwhile, most of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX> was falling under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> control. But everything changed when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westmoreland</ENAMEX> left. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Creighton Abrams</ENAMEX>, adopted a new
strategy, stopped fighting major battles, and began piecemeal seizure of land
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>. His pacification program brought security and a better
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> to rural areas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> program wiped out the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Viet Cong</ENAMEX>'s
infrastructure. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, the war was won militarily--or almost won. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> had become a capable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. All that was needed to save <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> was what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> did in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>: leave a couple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
divisions and provide military and other support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The truth
is, the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> was winnable.

         
      
   
