
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shattering Glass-Steagall</ENAMEX>, Redux

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> lead with a joint anti-urban-poverty initiative between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hastert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, to be announced
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The plan will dovetail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> ideas, such as tax credits for banks
that lend to poor neighborhoods, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> ideas, such as the elimination
of capital gains taxes on property sales in these "renewal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
runs this story inside, and says the plan is vague and will yield little
until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is out of office. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the life-without-parole
sentence given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron McKinney</ENAMEX>, who on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> was convicted of the
(second-degree) murder of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Shepard</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reefers
this story with an above-the-fold photograph (the same used by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, who argued against the death penalty. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads with congressional approval of a landmark <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>-overhaul by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">362-57</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90-8</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is expected to sign the financial-services legislation, which
reverses the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Glass-Steagall Act</ENAMEX> by allowing commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, securities
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, and insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to expand into each other's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>, creating
one-stop financial shopping for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. (See the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 23</TIMEX> TP, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shattering</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glass-Steagall</ENAMEX>.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's story focuses almost entirely on what
it sees as the lenient consumer-privacy provisions in the bill. The
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
notes that, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX>, a sentence was inserted in the legislation
exempting the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-biggest credit-card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">issuer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE Capital</ENAMEX>, from even these
privacy provisions. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> opinion page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX> predicts
that the deregulation will cause another savings-and-loan-type debacle.

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-leads  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>'s hostile takeover bid of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$82.4 billion</NUMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX>, which had just announced a friendly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$72 billion</NUMEX> merger with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Home Products</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's story, run inside, does the best
job of contextualizing: The pharmaceutical industry is fragmented, with
inefficiencies in research and few new products; it also fears that that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> may start to cover prescription drugs, which could lower prices. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's online edition reports that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early this morning</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX>--which already makes the anti-cholesterol <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lipton</ENAMEX> in
partnership with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>--opposed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX> bid. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> seems to
think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX> will attempt to fend off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, but
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner-Lambert</ENAMEX>'s anti-takeover defenses are
weak: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Shareholders</ENAMEX>, through a spontaneous mail-in election, can dismiss the
entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> at any time. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> waits until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">31st</NUMEX> paragraph
to mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> sits on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s parent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s poor performance in a
foreign-policy pop quiz. Asked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WHDH-TV</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> to name the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of
Chechnya, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> could name only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Teng</ENAMEX>-hui.

On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> opinion page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selig Harrison</ENAMEX>, a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Foundation</ENAMEX>, argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> should formally end the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean War</ENAMEX> as
part of a missile-limitation treaty with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> signed an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">armistice</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX> but pledged to reunite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> in the future--and so did not
sign a peace treaty.) In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pyongyang</ENAMEX> offered to let the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> monitor its
long-range <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> as long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> takes a neutral role in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">peninsula</ENAMEX>--that is, guarantees peace regardless of whether it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> or
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX> that invades the other. A report released by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisory group</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> made no mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> offer. 

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Rosenthal</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50-year</TIMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX>, got fired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. In his last column, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX>
touches on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his days</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' strong-fisted executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s and '80s</TIMEX>. "When you finish a story, I would say, read it, substitute
your name for the subject's," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX> relates. "If you say, Well, it would
make me miserable, make my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> cry, but it has no innuendo, no unattributed
pejorative remarks, no slap in the face for joy of slapping, it is news, not
gutter gossip, and as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> I know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> was fair, then give it to
the copy desk." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX> was the last of the old
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bulls</ENAMEX>, who included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Baker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Reston</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that the rumors circulating about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
advising are not true. She never advised him about clothes, she says, and she
mentioned "alpha" and "beta" only in passing, in one memo. As for her
exorbitant fee, she says, "I have written a whole book about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> should
not have to apologize for making the same fees <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> make. Also, I'm a reasonably
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, and I had to close down my whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>" to write memos for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. She concedes that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> who wanted the payments concealed. In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" section, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Gerhart</ENAMEX> explores the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX>'s fascination
with theWolf story. Why, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhart</ENAMEX> asks, has no one risen to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX>? "Is it
because she's radical? Is it because she's ambitious? Is it because she's not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">card-carrying</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the political consultancy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>?
Because of the money? Because she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>? Because she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who writes
about sex all the time?"

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reports that an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> staple is making a comeback:
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ketchup</ENAMEX>. Under a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwesterner</ENAMEX> and former football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heinz</ENAMEX> has
transformed its marketing, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ketchup</ENAMEX> sales bested those of salsa,
which had been first for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> running. Where it used to pitch its tomato
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paste</ENAMEX> to moms, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heinz</ENAMEX> now pitches it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. It is airing existential TV
commercials, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> philosophizing about the "moodiness" of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ketchup</ENAMEX> that
refuses to leave the bottle; forthcoming ads will teach the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">under-12</NUMEX> set that
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ketchup</ENAMEX> can be "fun" (a campaign sure to draw the appreciation of moms and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">day-care workers</ENAMEX> everywhere). Nationwide food fights among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX>: Lets see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricky Martin</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taco Bell Chihuahua</ENAMEX> top that .

         
      
   
