
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ending of the Black Underclass, Part XVIII</ENAMEX>

            According to tabulations obtained exclusively by kausfiles from
sources deep within the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, the percentage of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> on welfare is at its lowest level in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 15</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and probably its lowest level since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1970s</TIMEX>. This "dependency
rate" (or "recipiency rate," for the PC-inclined) was calculated by comparing
the number of welfare cases with the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 15-49</TIMEX>) in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. Here are the numbers for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>:

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year           Dependency</TIMEX> rate* 
            

            


               

                  

                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>

                  

                  

                     9.7

                  

               

               

                  

                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>

                  

                  

                     9.3

                  

               

               

                  

                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>

                  

                  

                     10.4

                  

               

               

                  

                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>

                  

                  

                     10.2

                  

               

               

                  

                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>

                  

                  

                     9.7

                  

               

               

                  

                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>

                  

                  

                     9.7

                  

               

               

                  

                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>

                  

                  

                     10.2

                  

               

               

                  

                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>

                  

                  

                     11.0

                  

               

               

                  

                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>

                  

                  

                     11.5

                  

               

               

                  

                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>

                  

                  

                     11.3

                  

               

               

                  

                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>

                  

                  

                     11.1

                  

               

               

                  

                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>

                  

                  

                     10.9

                  

               

               

                  

                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>

                  

                  

                     10.6

                  

               

               

                  

                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>

                  

                  

                     9.7

                  

               

               

                  

                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>

                  

                  

                     8.4

                  

               

               

                  

                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>

                  

                  

                     7.0

                  

               


            

            You get the picture. Welfare dependency among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> remained at a high
level until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> before the welfare system was radically reformed
(when there was already a lot of talk of reform in the air). Since then, the
African-American dependency rate has plummeted <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34 percent</NUMEX>. There's no reason to
think the drop stopped in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.

            Is the black dependency rate the lowest ever? Probably not, for the simple
reason that before the "welfare explosion" of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1960s</TIMEX>, many poor blacks
were blocked or discouraged from receiving welfare. It's hard to know for
sure--due to a change in record-keeping practices, there aren't strictly
comparable numbers from before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>. But a very crude back-of-envelope
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">calculation</ENAMEX> suggests that the black dependency rate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> was somewhere
around <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX>, and that it then more than doubled, to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">around 12 percent</NUMEX>, by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, when the welfare caseload stabilized. That would make the current rate
the lowest since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX> or even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '60s</TIMEX>.

            Politically sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, including those in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration, may not want to publicize these encouraging statistics, because
they also show that the black dependency rate, even at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX>, remains far
higher than the white rate (which is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.1 percent</NUMEX>). But so what? The black
dependency rate has always been much higher than the white rate, at least since
the welfare explosion. This is one reason why the "underclass," as measured by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Julius Wilson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabel Sawhill</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Mincy</ENAMEX>, has been
a majority-black problem.

            And that's the point. The existence of a largely black, welfare-dependent
"underclass"--and the way it reinforces stereotypes about all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poisons</ENAMEX> race relations--has been <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s greatest social problem. What the
plunging dependency rate suggests is that this problem may be on its way to
being radically ameliorated, if not solved. A smaller portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> on
welfare means not only a smaller underclass; it means more working and
middle-class role models. It means there is a much greater chance that the
latter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> will eventually swamp and assimilate the former. (Might the
drop in black dependency just record <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are being pushed off welfare
into poverty? It could, but it almost certainly doesn't. Black poverty and
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> poverty have been falling. Click here for more on this
issue.)

            Can a favorable "tipping point" be far away? Things seem to be finally
getting better very fast.

            [* Methodological fine print: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welfare</ENAMEX>" means Aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dependent Children</ENAMEX> (AFDC) or its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Temporary Assistance</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Needy Families</ENAMEX> (TANF). For various technical reasons, it is difficult to
exactly compare the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>) on welfare with the
total <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> (including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>) over time. As noted, the
table above instead compares the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> welfare "cases"
with the adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. Typically there is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> per welfare
"case," but not always--for example, under some conditions, two-parent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
qualify for welfare. There may be also be one, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, or more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in a
single "case." The "case" numbers also include cases in which technically only
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> receives welfare--although typically there is also an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> in the
household. ]

         
      
   
