
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net Election</ENAMEX>
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>--both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s failure to quickly denounce an assertion by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> had used poison <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> take to the airwaves to praise their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave DeBusschere</ENAMEX>, tells <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>) that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> was "very quiet, actually. But a
wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>--a lot of fun to sit and discuss different things with." On
the same program, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celtic Bob Cousy</ENAMEX> acknowledges that "old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX> don't
know a lot about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> solutions or campaign finance
reform." Interviewed courtside at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Square Garden</ENAMEX> (the site of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fundraiser</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> tells Late Edition (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>) that his new
campaign slogan is, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It Can Happen</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are mildly surprised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s increasing lead over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> (both of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Newshour With Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> ), among others, conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has "stopped the hemorrhaging"
in his campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> will soon be
helped by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s negative ratings, which are sure to rise as the candidate
becomes better known. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Klein</ENAMEX> says that when he
asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> why he feels so strongly about distancing himself from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> referred to his struggle to break free of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s shadow
when running in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> race for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Schneider</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late</ENAMEX>
Edition ) says the smartest thing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> to do is simply ignore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
not criticize him and risk alienating his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are encouraged by a new poll showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, the media
favorite, nearly neck-and-neck with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. Brit Hume
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) thinks this puts more pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to perform
well in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>'s debate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Birnbaum</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> ), who
notes that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> poll is just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> poll, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gang</ENAMEX> ), who says it's much easier for a polarizing figure such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
(or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'96</NUMEX>) to win <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> than to win the nomination. However,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> support in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> (the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">state</ENAMEX>) is broad but skin deep; if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> wins New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX>, he predicts, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> might give the veteran
another look. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Will</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) proposes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert E. Lee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> Grant (who won by attrition). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> counters
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> might be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George McClellan</ENAMEX> instead (who did not).

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> criticize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> for her silence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>
Bank--especially for her comment afterwards that denouncing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> on
stage would have hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX> peace process. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> defend her, however, arguing
that she was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX> on a diplomatic mission as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Lady</ENAMEX>, not as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> senatorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is further ridiculed for a new
soft-money-funded "issue advocacy" TV ad created by the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>
and featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> )
argues that every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> exploits these campaign-finance loopholes, but
Stephanopoulos, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carney</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Barone</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> ) conclude that
the ad will hurt her more than help her. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Klein</ENAMEX> notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> vote
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is actually <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> votes: the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> superliberal" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and the
"outer-borough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superconservative</ENAMEX>" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Et Cetera</ENAMEX>
            

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michel McQueen</ENAMEX> notes that there
has been a tremendous surge in Internet fundraising in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five weeks</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has now raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one million dollars</NUMEX> online; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox Softball Sunday</ENAMEX>
            

            Some of the questions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 24</TIMEX>:

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two months ago</TIMEX> the headlines: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Starr Expects To Issue Report On Clintons By</ENAMEX>
Fall Of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>." You've now resigned, not completing your report. What
happened?

               Do you believe the public lost confidence in you?

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> are already saying that [your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> was hired by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> in the southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time; therefore, anything that he concludes about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will be tainted because of his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>.

               You lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> trials. Do you believe that those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">juries were</ENAMEX>, in effect, influenced by the perception of you in the impeachment
process against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>?

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 50 million</NUMEX>--why so long? Why so much money?

               Some would suggest that if you had not been practicing private law while
being independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, the process would have moved along more quickly. In
hindsight, should you have stopped all private law practice?

               Let me show you how the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the end viewed your performance
as independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. Put it on the screen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>, favorable, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>;
unfavorable, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX>. The exact opposite of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. What happened to
you?

            

            Some of the questions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Snow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday last weekend</TIMEX>:

            

               Was it the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was trying to save [as he alleged to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>]?

               You mentioned that [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lies] would be grounds for removal of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>.
Isn't it also grounds for disbarment?

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>], I'm wondering what you think about the famous moment on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Lawn</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of the impeachment when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> stepped to the lectern and said that history would remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, in his view, as one of the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> we've ever had. Does
that tell you anything about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s judgment?

               Apart from the oddness of the [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>'s] statement--granted it was
odd--what does it show you about the the judgment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who made that
statement, if anything?

               What's your sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Freeh</ENAMEX>?

            

         
      
   
