
   
   
      
         
            Losing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Cookies</ENAMEX>
            

            I have never knowingly clicked on an online ad. Never. I
did it a couple of times accidentally <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years ago</TIMEX>, when I was still
confused about how search engines worked and couldn't figure out which juicy
inviting button near the top of the screen to hit. But each time, as soon as I
realized I was going to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX>'s page, I recoiled as if a spider had landed
in my hair. "No! No! No! No!" I shrieked in horror, jerking my modem's cord out
of the wall. Also I delete all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> on my hard drive once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> because
I have some vague belief that this diversionary tactic will confuse the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marketers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> the next time I go to a site.

            Also, I always lie on any surveys. Either I say our
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> household income is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $10,000</NUMEX> or I say it is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $200,000</NUMEX>.
I never wanted to admit any of this to you, but now that you are no longer
directly involved in running any Internet sites, I think you can take the
truth.

            This is not an anti-Internet stance, per se. I just hate
having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pester me to buy stuff I don't need. My own brain is already
working <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overtime</TIMEX> pestering me to do same.

            For that reason, I have never willingly watched a
commercial on TV either, with the exception of that e-trading commercial that
you love so much and wake me up to see every time it comes on. "This is the
funny part," you shriek, elbowing me. I am proud to say that although the ad's
plot line is vivid in my mind--young <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">upstart</ENAMEX> with vaguely threatening hairstyle
shows that old geezer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> a thing or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>--I could not for the life of me tell
you exactly which e-trading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is paying the bill. Am I the only person
whose brain simply will not hold onto brand names? I know what I like, I just
don't know if it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> or an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adidas</ENAMEX> or some other model of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. I like the
ones with the shiny <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chrome fenders</ENAMEX> and bench seats. But I don't think you can
buy them anymore. Here are the attributes of consumer goods that appeal to me
far more than brand name: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Color</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weight</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Whether it feels comfy enough
to fall asleep in while you're reading. None of these features can be properly
conveyed online. Trust me; I spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my days</TIMEX> shopping on the Internet.

         
      
   
