
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=350300619-12101999><SPAN class=350300619-12101999>The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ascent of Mann</ENAMEX></SPAN></SPAN>

            
               Movies

            

            

               
                  The Insider
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are shocked: They
actually like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Mann</ENAMEX>'s film about the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX>
interview with a tobacco industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whistle-blower</ENAMEX>, which was canned when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>
caved to corporate pressure. "The Insider shouldn't be the
edge-of-your-seat, gut-churning thriller that it is. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">… Mann</ENAMEX> could probably make
a movie about needlepoint riveting" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>
Crowe shines as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Wigand</ENAMEX> (the whistle-blower); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Pacino</ENAMEX> hams it up as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">moralizing 60 Minutes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Plummer</ENAMEX> does a mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>. 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> writes, "It's a terrific
muckraking melodrama--it will get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fuming." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read the rest of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review.)

            

               
                  Dogma
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions Gate Films Inc.</ENAMEX>). Despite protests from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Smith</ENAMEX>'s latest is "a
tortured testament from a true believer" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). What's
more, this "obviously devout, enlightened parable" about a pair of rebellious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">angels</ENAMEX> (played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Damon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Affleck</ENAMEX>) is "mercilessly funny" and
"gratifyingly cynicism free" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock, Salma Hayek</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Rickman</ENAMEX> round out the cast as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
apostle, a muse, and a messenger from God. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to check out the film's
official site and here to see what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic League</ENAMEX> has to say about
it.)

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bone Collector</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">So-so</ENAMEX> reviews for this
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> rip-off starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denzel Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angelina Jolie</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
plays a recently paralyzed forensics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> who uses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jolie</ENAMEX>, a rookie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>, as
his proxy to investigate a series of exceptionally grisly murders. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>
(the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ) pans the film, saying it has "one of those plots
where a depraved serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> leads everyone in a find-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX> version of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Where</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waldo</ENAMEX>?' " Most everyone agrees, calling the film formulaic and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gore</ENAMEX> overly mannered. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> positive comment: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jolie</ENAMEX> have
surprisingly good chemistry. (Visit the official site.)

            
               Music

            

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX> of Los
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rage</ENAMEX> Against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epic</ENAMEX>). Has <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rage</ENAMEX> Against the
Machine finally struck a balance between political preaching and guitar-heavy
rap-rock fusion? Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say yes, praising the "resonant, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>-slamming
riffs that will leave you shuddering" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Sciaretto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMJ</ENAMEX> ) and the fact
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>'s lyrics "make a case that there are still some things worth
fighting for" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Hermes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). A few are not
impressed: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Derogatis</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> calls lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Rocha</ENAMEX> "insufferable" and his lyrics "addlepated," and compares his
contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>'s otherwise excellent music to "rodent droppings at a
gourmet dinner." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> 's cover story on the
band.)

         
      
   
