
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=630250921-01071999>Pok&<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#233</NUMEX>;mon: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Menace</ENAMEX> </SPAN>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
20
            

            The
cover editorial heralds the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> trade deal as
"a momentous agreement that will vastly improve [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s] economic landscape."
The cover story explains the deal: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> will open its
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> to foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, telecommunications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, carmakers, and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. Ensuing competitive pressures will reshape <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s domestic
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Ä¶ A</ENAMEX> column argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pok√©mania</ENAMEX> proves globalization is
not a euphemism for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americanization</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' embrace of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pikachu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teletubbies</ENAMEX> demonstrates that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">globalization</ENAMEX> is a two-way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec. 6</ENAMEX>
            

            The
cover story explains the race controversy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Decatur</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>: The expulsion of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> (for fighting at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> game)
that has outraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> is viewed as an attempt to halt the white
flight that has undercut the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s tax base. ‚Ä¶ An editorial favors <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>-tolerance school rules such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Decatur's</ENAMEX>: The rules "effectively combat the greatest crisis in public
education <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> ‚Ä¶ the crisis of violence."‚Ä¶ An article explains the "constitutional etiquette" of the vice
presidency. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veeps</ENAMEX> should never malign or crudely distance themselves from their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX>. In case of assassination or impeachment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> needs a
smooth transition of power to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-in-line.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1999</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> tells the strange story of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Miranda Grosvenor</ENAMEX>. The homely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman ensnared</ENAMEX> numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> into obsessive telephone affairs during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>. Stars such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gere</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Joel</ENAMEX> fell for her
out-of-the-blue phone calls, gossip, and flattery. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> asked to meet her
she stood them up or sent photos of a blonde <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>. Some of the relationships
lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quincy Jones</ENAMEX> invited her to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel</ENAMEX> considered
writing a musical about her.

            
               
                  Talk, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> exposes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's mob origins. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> was
bankrolled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> loans in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> leaned on newsstand
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> who refused to sell it. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> realized real news wasn't
profitable, he turned it into a scandal sheet. ‚Ä¶ An item pokes
fun at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s newest excess: "pity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX>." Talent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> now offer
"conscience <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>," helping their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity clients</ENAMEX> pick philanthropic
causes that boost their image and ego.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
29
            

            A
great cover story stunt exposes the impossibility of electronic
privacy. Given a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s name, a Web-based "information <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broker</ENAMEX>" tracked down
his "base identifiers"--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> number, birth date, and address--in
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">snoop</ENAMEX> had discovered his unlisted phone
numbers, bank balances, stock holdings, and salary, as well as the phone
numbers of everyone he calls. To protect your privacy, ask your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> to
restrict access to your records and beg your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for legislative
protections.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
22
            

            An item skewers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>'s Scrooge-like philanthropic record. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1994 to 1998</TIMEX>, the
multi-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> gave away <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $475,642</NUMEX>. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gambino</ENAMEX> crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> gives
more to local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX>.




                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 21</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story profiles a day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX> who learns his financial fundamentals from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> and trusts his "feel" for stocks. If his luck holds (as it doesn't for
most day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>), he could net <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. He feels liberated but
"looks like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> hugging a slot machine." ‚Ä¶ An article
surveys the exploding--er, growing--private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> industry. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> is advocating
an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Interstate Sky Way</ENAMEX>" to ease traffic jams. A pair of inventing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> is
building a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model-T</ENAMEX> for the air--a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$179,400</NUMEX> plane with simplified controls and a
giant parachute for safer crash landings. ‚Ä¶ An essay explains
why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> always view <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> "through a dehumanizing prism."
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Visceral loathing</ENAMEX>" is the only attitude acceptable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> press
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corps</ENAMEX>. Sympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>--see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>--are ostracized. The author
says he has stopped writing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> because he has become
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wired ,</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1999</TIMEX>
            

            An article marvels at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multibillion-dollar</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>-goods" industry. To boost business, All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nippon Airways</ENAMEX> painted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pok√</ENAMEX>©mons on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its 747s</TIMEX> and hands out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pikachus</ENAMEX> to its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>. Icons such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello Kitty</ENAMEX> adorn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> cards, cell phones, and even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">condoms</ENAMEX>. The omnipresence of cute is a symptom of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s fetish for childhood.
‚Ä¶ An article explains why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> lost the allegiance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> promoted the growth of the Internet more than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> in
public life, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> spent his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sabbatical</ENAMEX> courting venture
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">capitalists</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> is mobilizing libertarian-leaning e-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veep's</ENAMEX> on visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> campus.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 22</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pok√©mania</ENAMEX> calls Pok√©mon a "pestilential Ponzi
scheme" that stokes acquisitiveness and encourages <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to fight. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pok√©mon</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> introvert and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">ex- Space Invaders</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obsessively</ENAMEX> collected beetles as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>. (For 
                  Slate
               's more kindly
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pok√©mon assessment</ENAMEX> click .) ‚Ä¶ An article says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are increasingly angry about the
soaring price of prescription drugs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Seniors</ENAMEX> are mobilizing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is
advertising his opposition to "price gouging," and drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are filling
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airways</ENAMEX> with attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> plans to extend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> coverage to
prescriptions. ‚Ä¶ In an interview , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> vows he will attempt to settle the
antitrust case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> but insists that he will not give up the right
to bundle programs with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
22
            

            The
cover story puzzles over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">dyslexia</TIMEX>. Dyslexics have
difficulty reading because they are unable to break words into their
constituent parts. Research indicates that dyslexia is an inherited
neurological problem. Early intervention and phonics can help dyslexics catch
up. ‚Ä¶ In an interview , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> begins to lay out his foreign
policy vision: "[The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>] should not retreat" but should "be humble
in its leadership." ‚Ä¶ The illustration for an essay on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> (or lack of it)? A picture of him reading his own recently
published book.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 22</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story claims there is a "cheating epidemic."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Three-quarters</ENAMEX> of college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of high-school "high
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">achievers</ENAMEX>" admit cheating. Online term-paper <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX> and other high-tech scams
(sending answers by pager) make cheating easier than ever. Character education
could help. ‚Ä¶ An article follows the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wild Yak Brigade</ENAMEX>, a vigilante <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that
patrols the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> plateau to protect the rare <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chiru antelope</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poachers</ENAMEX>.
The chiru is hunted for its hair, which is woven into high-priced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shawls</ENAMEX> and
sold to very rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--often <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX>. ‚Ä¶ A piece describes cost-effective office perks designed to
retain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gymboree</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> get a recess for hopscotch and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies-</ENAMEX>and-milk break. Other innovative benefits include: nap <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX>, corporate
concierges, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camps for office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 22</TIMEX>
            

            The
cartoon issue. A piece explains that the primary purpose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>
cartoons is to caricature the human condition. Proof: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s archives
contain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">381</NUMEX> cartoons of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on psychoanalysts' couches. ‚Ä¶ An article
argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is his own worst <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s best argument for his
candidacy is his formidable experience, yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> refuses to run on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
record. ‚Ä¶ A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Biological Diversity</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kier√</ENAMEX>°n
Suckling details his successful environmental extremism, founded oddly on
abstruse lit-crit theory. As an adherent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deconstruction</ENAMEX>'s "absolute
relativism," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suckling</ENAMEX> believes in undoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s dominion over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. Using
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Endangered Species</ENAMEX> Act, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suckling</ENAMEX> has sued to halt logging, ranching, cattle
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grazing</ENAMEX>, and construction throughout wide swaths of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
29
            

            The
cover story decries the concentration in media ownership.
Deregulation, privatization, and new technologies allow <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> transnational
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T/Liberty Media</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bertelsmann</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Electric</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>--to dominate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conglomeration</ENAMEX> encourages cultural homogenization and consumerism. ‚Ä¶ An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> examines how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> is behaving abroad.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> used American-style lobbying to bully <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX> into reversing
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarian</ENAMEX> TV's content quotas. ‚Ä¶ A piece explains how to sustain independent journalism. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pluralism</ENAMEX> is vital to democracy. Using the Web, alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> can
exchange content with international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 22</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story describes the implosion at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillsdale</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s premier conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>. Headed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Roche</ENAMEX>, Hillsdale
positioned itself as a bastion of traditional values. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche</ENAMEX> resigned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> learned that he had been having an affair with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">daughter-in-law</ENAMEX>--a fact that came to light after she committed suicide on
campus. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche</ENAMEX>'s resignation statement read: "We have proven that integrity,
values, and courage can still triumph in a corrupt world." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> refuses
to repudiate its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-president</ENAMEX>. ‚Ä¶ An article calls for an overhaul of antitrust law. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> case demonstrates that antitrust statutes punish dominant market
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and should be more laissez-fare. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> 
                  Slate
               's "" on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> case.)

         
      
   
