
   
   
      
         
            How <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> Resists the Web

            The
simplest way the Internet can enhance democracy is by making buried information
easily available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. By putting documents of all kinds online,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> let in disinfecting sunlight and make themselves accountable to the
public. By and large, the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has made impressive strides toward
making itself Web-accessible. But there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big exception: the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is ostensibly fascinated with cyberspace. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fifty</ENAMEX> Web-related bills and
resolutions are pending on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>. Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
participate in an Internet caucus. Yet, when it comes to posting basic
information about its inner workings, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has been shamefully slow. The
result is that it protects the privileged status of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> and
insulates back-room deals from public scrutiny while fencing out concerned and
engaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>.

            Let's
say you want to find out something about the latest draft of a bill. You might
try the home pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> , which link to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> tourism tips and member
home pages. But these sites provide scattershot coverage of legislation
revisions. Nor are the pages of the legislation's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> likely to help. Most
of these are filled with promotional dross. Biographical information, press
releases, and lengthy legislative accomplishment lists are complemented by
intern solicitations and flag request forms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch McConnell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>,
includes his recipe for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chocolate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nut Pie</ENAMEX> .

            You
may get closer to what you're looking for at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPO Access</ENAMEX> , a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Printing Office</ENAMEX> site where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> can download legislation and
search Congressional Record archives. The clumsy and confusing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">THOMAS</ENAMEX> --a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> site--duplicates some of this information. It contains bills,
roll-call votes, and links to congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> sites. But neither of
these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> gives you the up-to-date information that might enable you to
understand how a bill is working its way through the legislative process.

            "There
is much more information online about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> than at any time in history,"
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Poblete</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Administration Committee</ENAMEX>.
That is undoubtedly true, but it's hardly a meaningful statement. There is far
less information about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> online than there should and easily could be.
Here is what's missing and why:

            

               Working <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Drafts of Bills and Amendments</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Citizens</ENAMEX> can access
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX>, but working drafts are rarely posted. That's because under current
policy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">THOMAS</ENAMEX> cannot post an update until the text is processed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Printing Office</ENAMEX>. The delay guarantees that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> have time to
get drafts and influence the process before the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> knows what's
happening. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Thierer</ENAMEX>, Internet policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX>,
says that "the messy nature of the legislative process makes it difficult to
keep a site <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to date</TIMEX>." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Ruskin</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Accountability</ENAMEX>
Project, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that watches <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, asserts that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairmen</ENAMEX> squelch the posting of drafts because, "If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> figured
out what was in some of these bills, there would be public outcry against
them."

            

               Hearing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Transcripts and Statements</ENAMEX>. To find out about
congressional hearings, the curious must locate the appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> site.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> post opening remarks and transcripts, but the coverage is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scattershot</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">THOMAS</ENAMEX> publishes hearing testimony, but it often takes months
before the transcripts are "processed." While the public waits, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>
purchase uncorrected transcripts from pricey transcription <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Poblete
counsels patience and claims that all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> will offer video archives of
hearings someday. In the meantime, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> could make all its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>'
hearings available with the help of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few $200</NUMEX> scanners.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Research Service Reports</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> spends over
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$64 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> on a research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> that analyzes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of issues,
from abortion to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zambia</ENAMEX>. The reports, which are often excellent, are public
documents that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> can't easily get its hands on. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Daschle</ENAMEX>,
D-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.D.</ENAMEX>, posts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRS</ENAMEX> reports on his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> give
them away in response to specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituent</ENAMEX> requests. Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> often
have to wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> for research that a congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> can download in
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>. As a result, commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> are able to make money selling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bootleg</ENAMEX> copies. Penny
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill Press</ENAMEX> , for instance, peddles CRS reports for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$49</NUMEX> per order. Why
not put these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> out of business? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruskin</ENAMEX> contends that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> hoards the
reports because "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> see CRS as their own fiefdom and they like the ability
to give reports as a favor to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>." A congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX> is
"considering" making all CRS reports public. It is supposed to report its
conclusions by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voting Records</ENAMEX>. To find out how a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> voted on a particular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> must comb through archives of roll-call votes, which are
categorized by bill number and searchable by topic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Constituents</ENAMEX> can't search
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> name, at least at any official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> site. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruskin</ENAMEX> argues
that "easily searchable voting records are essential to democratic
accountability." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poblete</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is considering how to make voting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> easier to access.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lobbyist Disclosure Reports</ENAMEX>. These reports detail how much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> are paid to work on a particular issue and in theory what, who, and
how they lobby. They can make for very interesting reading, but to get them you
have to go in person to a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruskin</ENAMEX> argues that
posting the reports would allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to trace patterns of influence.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Citizens</ENAMEX> are not able to access these reports online, even though they are
electronically stored. Poblete claims that the reports will be posted as soon
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> resolves "technical hurdles."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personal Financial Disclosure Reports</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> must report how they spend their "representational allowances" and have
to file personal financial disclosure reports. The disclosures can be used to
ferret out wrongdoing and conflicts of interest. The data are computerized, but
for "policy reasons" the reports are not available online. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is
"reconsidering" whether to post them, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poblete</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years ago</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker-</ENAMEX>elect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> promised to make important information available
online "at the same moment that it is available to the highest-paid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX>." That did happen, but only once--when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> instantaneously
published the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> Report . When it comes to its own dirty laundry,
there seems to be no such hurry.

         
      
   
