
   
   
      
         
            Lessons of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO Summit</ENAMEX>

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> press has grown a little smug since the collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> trade
talks and the victory of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss</ENAMEX> World
competition in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that the "big revelation" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> conference was that, perhaps for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, developing
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> insisted on being heard. It also noted "an incredibly sloppy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organisation</ENAMEX> in one of the wealthiest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in the world's richest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,"
which it said "bordered on the ludicrous. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ministers</ENAMEX> of some of the smaller
developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> were denied entry to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> where closed talks between the
larger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> were on. When they did manage to get past security they found
no chairs for them. And senior government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> complained that as the
negotiations stretched early into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, there was no drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>
available either." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> small developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> was a lesson in humility to a group of developed
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> which thinks it owns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>."

            In an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> about the crowning of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yukta Mookhey</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zoology</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mumbai</ENAMEX>, as Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World 1999</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX> said it
was not her achievement alone. "That <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> produces such beauty--physical and
intellectual--is entirely due to the fantastic genetic pool it draws upon and
the cross fertilisation of ideas it swears by," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "While taking
to modernity with great gusto, we have made this otherwise terrifying monster
in our own image. While other civilisations, with their 'insect origins,'
fumble with such ideas as the timeless and ethereal qualities of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s
beauty, our beginnings attest to these ideals from time immemorial. … The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> achievement is a combination of lightness and gravitas, of bridging the
gap between the highbrow and the middlebrow, and rediscovering for itself the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inextricable</ENAMEX> link between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, mind and soul." The paper contains much
more in this self-congratulatory vein.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> called the collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> talks a "disaster" and a "calamity" for
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> were mostly to blame. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>
is not some alien <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX>, but their own creation," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
in an editorial. "They must now save it from the consequences of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cowardice</ENAMEX> and folly." Otherwise, the rule of law in world trade would be
replaced by the law of the jungle. Papers around the world struggled to
identify the lessons of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> called it a victory for "a new idea"--that
"the world is not for sale." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, it said in an
editorial, were pleading for "a new world order, one of an open world but of a
world which isn't, under any circumstances, reduced to mere merchandise."

            
Writing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Post of Canada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Frum</ENAMEX> said that the demonstrations were symptoms of an "ever-worsening
global problem-shortage." He wrote, "With peace and prosperity blanketing ever
larger stretches of the globe--with nuclear weapons being decommissioned and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unionists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nationalists</ENAMEX> entering into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> together in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>--we are in danger of reaching a state of affairs where there is nothing
left to protest." An editorial in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> said it was the failure
among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to put the common good above vested interests, and not
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> demonstrations, that caused the collapse of the conference. "To
ignore this in favour of viewing the resulting impasse as a victory of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of light (ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or at least their self-appointed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>) over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of darkness (that is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> of free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX>) is to create a false, misleading, and ultimately harmful dichotomy," the
paper said.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> said
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> riots proved "that the prediction of the end of history was
premature." An editorial in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, "The ideological struggles of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twentieth century</TIMEX> may have culminated over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX> with the
unquestionable triumph of capitalism over socialism, but that has not meant
that strong--and strongly felt--differences of opinion over what our capitalist
future will look like do not abound." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that the failure of the talks had damaged the
credibility of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> and given the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> "a black eye." The paper
said it is clear that one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s greatest challenges is to
convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> of the advantages of freer trade but that the conference
could not have come at a worse time: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> lacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in painting
a future for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>, and its conference was void of passion and vision."

            Following the death after
an attempted robbery in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monaco</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmond J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safra</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> praised his work for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sephardim</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sephardi Education Foundation</ENAMEX>, of which he was the chief benefactor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Levy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Sephardi Federation</ENAMEX>, described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safra</ENAMEX> as "devoted to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> life in the world." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safra</ENAMEX>'s largess also included chairs at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, synagogues, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holocaust Museum</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute for Sephardic Studies</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeshiva University</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years ago</TIMEX>, he donated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Einstein</ENAMEX>'s earliest
manuscript on the theory of relativity to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel Museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
