
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sweet Spot</ENAMEX>

            There are a lot of amazing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> in the world, but with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Penn</ENAMEX>, each performance is amazing in a
different way. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmet Ray</ENAMEX>, the fictional 1940s jazz guitarist in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s unexpectedly delectable 
                  Sweet and Lowdown
               , he
lifts his voice about an octave and wears a small waxed mustache as if it were
a fancy hood ornament. Only the mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Django Reinhardt</ENAMEX>--the great gypsy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guitarist</ENAMEX>--pops his bubble of self-worship, sending him into sweats and, in
some cases, unconsciousness. The rest of the time he's a preening cock, fond of
quoting (without irony) a rapturous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>: "I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">meee -rac-ulous</ENAMEX>." When
he plays, he folds himself intimately over his guitar and silently moves his
lips, as if whispering sweet nothings to it; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX>'s expression of stewed
soulfulness parodies this twerpy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">egotist</ENAMEX> and exalts him at the same time.
Actually, it's the music that exalts him: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> does the intricate finger-work
himself, while on the soundtrack, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Alden</ENAMEX> gives the solos a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reinhardt</ENAMEX>-like
mix of limpidness and bite. The idea of a jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guitarist</ENAMEX> who's also a textbook
Freudian hysteric--loose and yet focused when he's onstage, an anxious buffoon
when he's off--has comic poetry built into it, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> has radar for both the
comedy and the poetry. It's the way he blends them, though, that is uncanny:
He's like a great jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmet Ray</ENAMEX> is the
protagonist of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>'s dreams: a narcissistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shit</ENAMEX> who's also an artistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">titan</ENAMEX>. The conceit works better here than in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deconstructing Harry</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>), where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>--a cross between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip Roth</ENAMEX>--screwed up his
own and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives but was let off the hook because he brought so
much meaning into the world through his books. Frankly, it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s place
to forgive himself for all the bad things he has done--or, for that matter, to
assess his own talents. With <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sweet and Lowdown</ENAMEX> , he has made the tension
between an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s work and life more archetypal--and more funny. In
mock-documentary fashion, the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emmet</ENAMEX> is relayed by jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>--among them <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Duncan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nat Hentoff</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> himself--who set the
scene for hilarious anecdotes about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guitarist</ENAMEX>'s unreliability, profligacy,
and terror of encountering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Django Reinhardt</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emmet</ENAMEX> has an infantile
indifference to everyone and everything except his own needs. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who fall
for him he spews such unprocessed bilge as, "I gotta be free; I'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>."
But just when you think you've had enough of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emmet</ENAMEX>'s whining,
self-aggrandizement, and emotional cowardice, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> plays a trump card: that
beautiful music.

            Maybe it's wishful thinking on my part, but <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sweet</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowdown</ENAMEX> feels like penance for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Kopple</ENAMEX>'s bleak documentary <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man Blues</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>), which chronicled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> tour with his New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orleans</ENAMEX>-style jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX>. When he watched himself perform in those vast, tony
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theaters</ENAMEX>, did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> think what the rest of us were thinking--that this isn't
how jazz is meant to be heard? The way he shoots the music here is tender and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uninsistent</ENAMEX>; the camera floats past the tables of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX> until it comes to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emmet</ENAMEX> and his wonderfully pickled look of concentration. The note of satire in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX>'s performance is a hedge against the reverence that dampened such jazz
sagas as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertrand Tavernier</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'Round Midnight</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>), while the
gorgeousness of the playing is a hedge against the satire.

            The story takes a
moralistic turn: Emmet pays both an artistic and a personal price for not
risking more of himself emotionally. But the film doesn't bog down in loathing
(self- or otherwise) the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s last work, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Celebrity</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>), did.
He adores this milieu too much--he probably wishes he'd been born into it. And
he's in the buoyant, tall-tale mode of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Purple Rose</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>).
With cinematographer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhao Fei</ENAMEX>, production <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santo Loquasto</ENAMEX>, and costume
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">designer Laura Cunningham Bauer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> re-creates the world of urban supper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clubs</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> mingle with jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and high-society vamps and where
the music itself seems to smooth over class distinctions. Early on, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emmet</ENAMEX> picks
up the tab for a table of tuxedo-clad <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX>, then goes
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with them to drink and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">jam</ENAMEX>. He stumbles back to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> via the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dump</ENAMEX>,
where he shoots the breeze with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hobos</ENAMEX> and indulges in his favorite form of
recreation: picking off <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> with his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.45</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> has never made a movie where
the jokes seemed so offhand yet so precise--so beat-perfect. He must have
wanted to freshen his approach this time out. Why else would this famously
settled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> pick both a mainland <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> cinematographer (who reportedly
came with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of translators) and a different kind of lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>--one who
wouldn't mimic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s diction like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mia Farrow in Purple Rose</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Branagh</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Celebrity</ENAMEX> ?

            Of course, there are aspects of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sweet</ENAMEX> and Lowdown
that don't seem so fresh when you're out from under its spell. The conception
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, for instance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> still thinks along the same lines as in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>), where the open and inarticulate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX> stood for purity, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s hope of salvation, while such overeducated,
older types as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Keaton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX> (the lesbian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>) were like
sucking swamps of neurosis and infidelity. The purity here is embodied by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hattie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Morton</ENAMEX>), a mute laundress whom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emmet</ENAMEX> picks up on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boardwalk</ENAMEX>. The other extreme is represented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanche</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uma Thurman</ENAMEX>), a sleek
and edgy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sophisticate</ENAMEX> who has affairs with lowlifes as research for novels.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> is clearly letting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emmet</ENAMEX> have a taste of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>--Blanche
doesn't say, "I've gotta be free; I'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>," but that's the implication.
The problem is that he can't bring himself to give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blanche</ENAMEX> any soul. And what a
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>, making the feminine ideal a mute (who does laundry--always a big
plus)!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> struck <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> when he cast <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX>, however. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> known for her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Eyre</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>) and an incendiary
turn in the little-seen Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skin</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>), she has a dimpled
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-smile, a slightly bobbing walk, and the manner of a pixilated silent movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ragamuffin</ENAMEX>. The part is all mugging--pulling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harpo</ENAMEX>-like faces--but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX> turns
it into a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">delicious tease</ENAMEX>, always seeming on the verge of speech, of
saying something naughty or funny or caustic. She appears not to talk because
she just thinks better of it. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hattie</ENAMEX> gazes serenely on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emmet</ENAMEX> after their
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> coupling, he keeps up both ends of the conversation--"Did ya' like that?
I knew you would. … I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> when I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> had sex …" She worships him and sees
right through him, and a part that might have seemed a sentimental contrivance
becomes the source of comic bliss.

            
               Sweet and Lowdown
is a "small" comedy--it's monaural, not stereo, and purposefully distant. But
it has a touch of magic. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> gives you several versions of the
same climactic scene (it varies according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>), and the effect of
all those farcical possibilities is elating: a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rashomon</ENAMEX> -like sequence
where you don't give a damn what actually happened. Each variation is more
entertainingly outlandish, and in the last, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmet</ENAMEX> finally sees Django
Reinhardt, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> caps it with one of the great movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">swoons</ENAMEX>. Everything he does
hits the sweet spot.

            The best of many good reasons to see

                  Tumbleweeds
                is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet McTeer</ENAMEX>, who plays a hopeful <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>-ish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> who
bounces from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>--and state to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>--with her cynical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescent daughter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly J. Brown</ENAMEX>) in tow. McTeer, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> who
won a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tony</ENAMEX> award for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Doll's House</ENAMEX> , gives a
performance that is so gorgeously modulated you'll think she has been in movies
all her life. It helps that her character, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Jo</ENAMEX>, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX>. Fixing breakfast,
she dances around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and sticks her tongue out at her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>, as if
razzing her own domesticity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> uses her whole slinky frame--lots of
leg and lots of cleavage--to show how this busting-out babe is too alive for
the blue-collar he-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> she takes up with. It's no wonder that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ava</ENAMEX>--who has the heavy spirit of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> forced to be more farsighted than her
parent--gravitates to theater, where one's exhibitionism can be harnessed. It's
maybe also no wonder that--given where her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s feminine instincts have
led--she takes the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romeo instead of Juliet</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gavin O'Connor</ENAMEX> plays the dull-witted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trucker</ENAMEX> who's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Jo</ENAMEX>'s latest conquest, and he also directed the movie and co-wrote the
screenplay with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela Shelton</ENAMEX>. (The story is based on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelton</ENAMEX>'s "childhood
memoirs.") Beat by dramatic beat, these are some of the most nuanced scenes in
a film <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Connor</ENAMEX> is a fabulous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. Maybe too fabulous.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> appear to be entertaining themselves so much that some of the
tension dissipates, and the ease with which the movie goes down ends up working
against it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tumbleweeds</ENAMEX> could use some dissonances. I'm a little fuzzy,
for instance, on this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s finances. They don't want for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> or a roof
over their heads, and they end up--with no visible means of support--on a nice
little block in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, which isn't the cheapest housing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. I
miss the rawness that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillian Armstrong</ENAMEX> brought to another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
story, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Tide</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX> here are just a little too
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sturdy; Tumbleweeds</ENAMEX> seems on the brink of tumbling into a TV series.

         
      
   
