
   
   
      
         
            Family Styles

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> confirmed her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> candidacy. Responding to
a question at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>' union meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, she said she would make
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next year</TIMEX>. Everyone has assumed that she's
running since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>. She also confirmed that she will move to the house
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chappaqua</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, that she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> recently purchased (but did
not confirm that he will). She said the announcement came in response to
public "excitement" about her candidacy and her need to
address the issues "vigorously." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skepics</ENAMEX> said it was an effort to bounce back
from recent public missteps and to prevent further erosion of
support.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX> proposed new workplace ergonomic
regulations. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Roughly 27 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> would
be affected. The regulations focus on repetitive-motion injuries and require
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) identify and inform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> of musculoskeletal risks; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
eliminate hazards after a single incident; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) pay injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' wages
and benefits during recuperation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>'s spin: The protections are long
overdue. Business' spin: The costly
regulations are excessive.

            

               Fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> are made up of married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX> study found that this type of
household declined from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent to 26 percent</NUMEX> of the total <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1972</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Fifty-one percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> now live with their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, down from
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>. The changes were attributed to: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) increased cohabitation;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) later marriages; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) greater acceptance of divorce; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX>
with "empty nests." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> said the statistics signaled the decline of
marriage and "traditional" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> . But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
are increasingly recognizing that these "modern"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> can work.

            

               A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> was appointed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> lawsuit. Both sides
agreed to let federal appeals court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Posner</ENAMEX> oversee settlement
talks. The negotiations must adhere to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Penfield Jackson</ENAMEX>'s recent
"findings of fact," which ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> was a monopoly and had used its
power to harm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX> agreed that the appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX>, who
has long opposed aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> intervention in antitrust cases, was
good news for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> called the selection
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">astute</ENAMEX> , saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX>'s sterling reputation and conservative
credentials would increase the chances of settlement and decrease the
likelihood that a resolution would be overturned on appeal. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read an
assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX> in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas A&M University</ENAMEX> is investigating the fatal collapse of a log
pile. The collapse of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40-foot</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramid</ENAMEX>, which was being set up for
an annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bonfire</ENAMEX>, killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> and injured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>. Underclassmen were working high on
the pile-- contrary to safety procedures --but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> don't yet know
whether this contributed to the collapse. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aggies</ENAMEX> called it an unfortunate tragedy , but argued that the tradition was
too important to abandon. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Outsiders</ENAMEX> said the mishap was predictable and the tradition should be scrapped.

            

               Serious crimes decreased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half of 1999</TIMEX>.
An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> survey, which tabulated violent and property crimes reported to police,
showed declines in every category in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> of every size. Crime has now
declined for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven and a half years</TIMEX>. The reduction was variously attributed to:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) more policing; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) harsher prison terms; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
sustained economic growth. The optimistic take: The drop is "astounding … enormous and
encouraging ." The pessimistic take: Then why do we feel less safe than ever ?

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> for leaking information on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> Flight 990. He said some leaks were false--including reports
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-pilot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gamil al-Batouti</ENAMEX> said, "I've made my decision now" before
switching off the autopilot--but he refused to say what was on the cockpit
voice recorder. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> had planned to relinquish the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> investigation into whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Batouti</ENAMEX> intentionally downed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>,
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> requested more time to analyze the recordings.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Batouti</ENAMEX> is suspected because: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) he uttered a prayer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> times as the
plane dived; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) his controls were in the "nose down" position, while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">captain's</ENAMEX> were in "nose up"; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> pleaded with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Batouti</ENAMEX> to help
him pull the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> out of its dive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> are
rushing to judgment based on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Muslim</ENAMEX> bias. The American
spin: There's still no evidence of any other cause.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. C. United</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Major League Soccer Championship</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-0
victory over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Galaxy</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> title in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year</TIMEX> existence. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> hailed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>'s "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and only dynasty ." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> must
vastly improve marketing, telecasts, and the level of play
before anyone else will care.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> approved a final budget bill. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$385 billion</NUMEX>
compromise measure, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has agreed to sign, passed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">296</NUMEX>-135
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74-24</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> gained: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) additional funding for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) environmental protections; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) money for
international relief and foreign relations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> won: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.38</NUMEX>
percent across-the-board budget cut; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) increased spending on defense and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">veterans</ENAMEX>' health; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the ability to claim to have protected the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security surplus. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Optimists</ENAMEX> hailed it as a restrained and
responsible measure that "limits
spending in a booming economy." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> called it a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>-ridden
sham, based on bookkeeping gimmicks.

            

               A federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> suspended <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> restrictions on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> fees.
The temporary injunction will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX> to
continue charging non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> for ATM use until a trial takes place. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wells Fargo</ENAMEX> barred non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> cash machines in response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s ban on ATM surcharges. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX>'
spin: We're winning in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. Consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>' spin: But you've already
lost in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of public opinion.

         
      
   
