
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devolution Day</ENAMEX>

            "Hand
of history touches Ulster" was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX>'s main headline <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, echoing a
remark by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> that "the hand of history is at
last lifting the burden of terror and violence and shaping the future of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> on both sides of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Sea</ENAMEX> agreed
that the meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ever all-inclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was a momentous event. They called it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Devolution Day</TIMEX>, and they
labeled it historic. Among mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>,
which has always been skeptical about the peace process, led with the headline
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Extremists</ENAMEX> could still wreck new Ulster <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dawn</TIMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>
noted in its lead story that the signs that things have changed "for ever" with
the transfer of power from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX> came in small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>. "An anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> picketed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Buildings</ENAMEX>, evidence that
politics were coming home at last," it said.

            The
Times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> said in an editorial that the peace process would not have been possible
"without an extraordinary transformation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> politics, economics, society
and culture" during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two decades</TIMEX>. Cursed by emigration since the potato
famine of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1840s</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> ached to present itself as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s 'victim,'
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> invariably cast as the villain of the piece. The complete
story was never this simple: but the image had adhesive quality." But "[o]ver
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> both the underlying facts and popular perception have altered
dramatically" through a process of "economic modernisation, social liberalism,
reconciliation with the north, and an outreach to the wider world," the paper
said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendan Behan</ENAMEX> wrote with confidence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five decades ago</TIMEX> that 'other people
have a nationality, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> have a psychosis.' Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Behan</ENAMEX> has proved a better
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> than a political prophet."

            A
much-used photograph in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press was of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> with a camera to his eye, snapping the media at the opening ceremony for
the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Mirror</ENAMEX> surrounded this with the smiling faces of the
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in the peace settlement under the headline
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Smile</ENAMEX>! We've <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Made History</ENAMEX>." For once, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s biggest-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> , cleared its front page of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> scandal to make way
for a huge headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peace: Let's All Pray It Lasts</ENAMEX>." "In one way or another,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> have been at war for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in a
front-page editorial. "Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, peace was given a
chance."

            
Writing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertie Ahern</ENAMEX> said: "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North and South</ENAMEX>, we can now say with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">certainty</ENAMEX>, it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are sovereign. We have, all of us,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nationalists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unionists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republicans</ENAMEX> and loyalists, gained from this
certainty." Praising the contributions of "some extraordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Mitchell</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahern</ENAMEX> said that if anybody
tried "to wreck the agreement through violence, we will confront them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">…</ENAMEX> [A]s
we have shown in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, we can overcome all of the obstacles
to achieving a lasting peace." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> was pictured on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s
front page signing away <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>'s territorial claims to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">north</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
Independent fronted a photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth II</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary McAleese</ENAMEX> celebrating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Devolution Day</TIMEX> with a private lunch at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buckingham Palace</ENAMEX>. It said plans were afoot for the queen to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> to cement the new relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>. This will
be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ever visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">monarch</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also
quoted the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Irish Nobel</ENAMEX> Prize-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seamus Heaney</ENAMEX> welcoming the agreement
with a quotation from the epic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anglo-Saxon</ENAMEX> poem "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beowulf</ENAMEX>": "A light appeared
and the whole place became brightened the way the sky does when heaven's candle
is shining brightly."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Protestant Belfast Telegraph</ENAMEX>
said in an editorial that it would be hard to exaggerate the significance of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX>, which will be included among the greatest events of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> history. It
stressed the importance of the contributions "of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>--and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in particular--repaying their debt to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> by an unremitting commitment to the peace process." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish News</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> paper based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX>, led with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX>'s appointment of a go-between to discuss arms
decommissioning with an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> headed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chastelain</ENAMEX>. The IRA's statement did not name its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>, made no
promise to give up its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, and expressed concern at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> First
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Trimble</ENAMEX>'s insistence on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next February</TIMEX> as the deadline for
disarmament to begin. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> is
widely thought to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Padraig Wilson</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of IRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maze</ENAMEX>
prison in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said that, according to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> new security
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assessment</ENAMEX>, the IRA possesses <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> handguns, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> heavy
machine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,600 kilograms</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Semtex</ENAMEX> high explosive.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX> conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
with divisions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> over its negotiating stance toward the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. It said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>--have accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX> of going
beyond its mandate by proposing a compromise that would allow discussion of
genetically modified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX>. This is something to which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in particular is
vehemently opposed.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Vidal</ENAMEX> infiltrated one of the closed working party
meetings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> because it issued him with the wrong accreditation--a blue
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">delegate</ENAMEX>'s pass instead of a green press badge. He gives an amusing front-page
account of the opening of a debate in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX>" on whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> should include investments and competition in the
next round of negotiations. "In theory the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> is now an official
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">delegate</ENAMEX> to the talks, can deliver speeches, introduce policies, and make
political trade-offs," he explains. The issue pits the rich <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> against
the poor ones, and no progress is made. "The pace, after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">40 minutes</TIMEX>, is
telling," he writes. "Several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are visibly suffering. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> are pretending to be asleep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> is reclining
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alarmingly</ENAMEX>. The only sign of life is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> could well be in love with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>. Her eyes flash. They lean
together and cannot stop whispering."

         
      
   
