
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Posner</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Posner</ENAMEX> is a far more distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Thomas Penfield Jackson</ENAMEX>, who chose him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> to mediate--or attempt to
mediate--a settlement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> case. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> is a well-regarded
district court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX> is chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seventh Circuit Court of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appeals</ENAMEX> and the most prominent legal philosopher currently on the federal
bench, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>.

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s choice is a gracious <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, but an odd
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX> is the high prophet of "law and economics," a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of thought
that derives legal principles from economic analysis, typically pointing at
some established legal doctrine and declaring it nonsense. No area of the law
has been more affected by law and economics than antitrust. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX> believes
that "predatory pricing" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolist</ENAMEX>'s act of cutting prices to kill
competition, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is alleged to have done by giving away its Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> browser) can almost never exist. He has argued for only the narrowest
kinds of antitrust remedies in only the narrowest kinds of antitrust cases.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asking Posner</ENAMEX> to mediate between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> is a bit
like asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> to oversee elections in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX> cannot be
pigeonholed as an anti-government obsessive. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, he has other
obsessions too. As a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lecturer</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago Law School</ENAMEX>,
he teaches <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> seemingly irreconcilable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law and Economics</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Law</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Literature</ENAMEX>." He has authored <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,500</NUMEX> judicial decisions, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
of articles, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two dozen</NUMEX> books, including Sex and Reason ,
Law and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Literature</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aging</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Age</ENAMEX> and, most recently, An
Affair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investigation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Impeachment</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trial of President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). His take on the official report: "a splendid libretto by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chorus</ENAMEX> of television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> ‚Ä<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">¶</ENAMEX> hapless walk-ons,
clandestine comings and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goings ‚Ä¶</ENAMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May-December</TIMEX> romance."

            Some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX>'s greatest intellectual disdain is reserved
for the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">internationalists</ENAMEX>, multiculturalists, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX>, [and]
sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vegetarians</ENAMEX>" on the academic left. He has little time for those who
"pity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> (and penguins, and sea otters, and harp seals) more than
fetuses." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX>'s early r√©sum√© reads more like that of a vegetarian than a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">libertarian</ENAMEX>. He clerked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Brennan</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> at the height of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> activism and later worked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Solicitor General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurgood Marshall</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX>'s explanation for
his change in perspective is disappointingly conventional: He says he was put
off by the picketing, sit-ins, and violence he witnessed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> while
teaching there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '60s</TIMEX>. In the spirit of law and economics, we should
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit</ENAMEX> and/or tar him with motives that are more intellectual and/or
self-interested than that. Whatever the cause, the transition was complete by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX> published his seminal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Analysis of Law</ENAMEX> ,
shining the light of cost-benefit analysis into every dark corner of the law,
from antitrust to racial discrimination to--of course--sex. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reading Posner</ENAMEX> on
any of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> makes it difficult to shake off the mental image of the
bemused libertarian rooted to the sticky floor of his local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safeway</ENAMEX>, fiendishly
applying his cost-benefit quadratics to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charmin</ENAMEX> in one hand and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Cloud</ENAMEX>
in the other--while myriad little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posners</ENAMEX> hop around at home, praying for his
return.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Seventh Circuit</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, and he started producing opinions like one in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> declaring that an
injunction should be granted "if <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P x H[p</ENAMEX>] > (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-P</ENAMEX>) x H[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">d</ENAMEX>]." Not surprisingly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX>'s jurisprudence bloodless and ultimately cruel, chasing the
logic of free-market capitalism right off the edge of a cliff. A notorious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> suggested making it legal for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to auction off their unwanted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> to the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidders</ENAMEX>. An essay on rape reads almost like a parody of
the substitution of economic for moral reasoning. ("[A]llowing rape would lead
to heavy expenditures on protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, as well as expenditures on
overcoming those protections. The expenditures would be offsetting, and to that
extent socially wasted.")

            A more appealing aspect
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX>'s philosophy is his belief that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> base their opinions on
"guesses" and personal ideology, while hiding behind a veil of precedent. He
seeks, as did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Wendell Holmes</ENAMEX>, to "demystify" what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> actually do. It
is judicial humility--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> have no access to transcendent moral truth--that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">leads Posner</ENAMEX> to economics as a way to cut through legal indeterminacy. Choosing
not to feel anyone's pain, he has quite literally found safety in numbers
because they are, in his view, morally neutral where pain is not.

            In practice, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX> is not so humble. His appellate
opinions contain long expository "asides" when he disagrees with the law as
handed down by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> opinion in which he felt forced to
apply an antitrust doctrine he disliked includes the snide observation: "[i]f
this is what the [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> believes--and it does appear to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s
current position, though not one that is easy to defend in terms of economic
theory or antitrust policy ..." His expository aside was adopted as the law of
the land by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.

            An odd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and an odd
choice, but possibly an inspired one as well. After all, the rights and wrongs
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> case are purely economic. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> made none of the
sociological arguments against large and powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> that are
sometimes part of the antitrust debate. Has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s behavior harmed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> economically by taking too much of their money or slowing the pace of
innovation? Is there a remedy that will do more good than harm?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX> cannot retry the facts or impose a result as a
matter of law. But who better to rationally and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coldly</ENAMEX> lay out the costs and
benefits of settlement for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>? If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tells Microsoft</ENAMEX> that, on this occasion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has a point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
will be hard put to disagree. And if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that whatever
tortures it has in mind will do more harm than good, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will have
to listen hard.

            Who better to strip away the hubris and slippery
moralizing of both sides in this case than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who really can distill
consumer harm down to a decimal point? Like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> bookmaker or a seasoned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">actuary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX> will spit out a number at the end of these negotiations and,
like a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pentium</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">processor</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX>'s number will be right. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> can choose to listen to his advice or disregard it. But they won't be
able to say they weren't helped with their math homework by the very best.

         
      
   
