
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiener Whining</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Super</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>

            It is a well-known fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> Avenger
keeps a special place in his heart for the downtrodden and the outcast,
including, but not limited to, the poor, the indigent, the day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blind</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> sees the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of rampant capitalism
manhandling an unfortunate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>, he will fly to the rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">straightaway</ENAMEX>, unless
he's busy leading anarchists into battle on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">napping</ENAMEX>.

            But there is one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> whose persecution will
instantaneously get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> into superhero mode, and that is:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wiener dogs</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> loves <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wiener dogs</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> loves all <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, but he especially loves <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> that have
no discernible legs.

            So when Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gale Hogsten</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> wrote to
complain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Super 8</ENAMEX> motel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> abused her <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wiener dog</ENAMEX>, along with the
rest of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> donned his codpiece and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">cape</ENAMEX> and
superhero tights--though not necessarily in that order--and launched himself
into battle. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Super 8</ENAMEX> is a major motel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>--it is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> better than <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Motel 6</ENAMEX>--but
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> showed no fear.

            But first, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> will let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gale</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hogsten</ENAMEX> tell the story.

            "As <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Floyd</ENAMEX> was coming our way, I booked a
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, so we could get the heck out of here," the aggrieved Ms.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hogsten</ENAMEX> writes. "What <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Super 8</ENAMEX> did was to call <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Floyd</ENAMEX> a 'special
event,' hence they were able to charge any damn price they wanted to. Our
family got the regular rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$48</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, however others in the hotel
started getting ripped off, being charged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $125</NUMEX>
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">third night</TIMEX>. Nothing like the feeling of being homeless and being screwed
in the process." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> endorses the previous statement
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wholeheartedly</ENAMEX>.

            "Like most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, I was traveling with a pet and
when I read about this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Super 8</ENAMEX>, it did say (still does) that small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are allowed. We have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wiener dog</ENAMEX>, a corgi, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>. Somehow the
idiot at the desk heard we had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and decided to charge us an extra <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
bucks. What are you going to do, not pay?"

            Not pay, indeed.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hogsten</ENAMEX> writes,
"they never gave us any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> service for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> made contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hogsten</ENAMEX> via e-mail
and learned that her <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wiener dog</ENAMEX>, whose name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rusty</ENAMEX>, was traumatized by these
events, though not as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hogsten</ENAMEX> was traumatized by these events. "What
pissed me off personally was charging <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> bucks for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wiener dog</ENAMEX>," she stated,
emphatically.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> right away made contact with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Super 8</ENAMEX> executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Super 8</ENAMEX>, it turns out, is owned by the Cendant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX>, which owns <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">every</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> and motel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and is therefore the
sort of unfeeling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> that would rob <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fleeing a hurricane. Except
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> who was assigned the difficult task of dealing with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>, one <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Nemeth</ENAMEX>, did a provisionally satisfactory job of
making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> happy.

            "I hear you," she said by way of introduction. "We
heard that some of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">franchises</ENAMEX> were doing this sort of thing, and we get
angry when we hear about them doing it." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nemeth</ENAMEX> maintained that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Super 8</ENAMEX> does
not discriminate against short-legged <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>. "We get a lot of letters saying,
'Thanks for letting us bring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fluffy</ENAMEX>,' that sort of thing."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fluffy</ENAMEX>? Who ever heard of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wiener dog</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fluffy</ENAMEX>?
But that's not the point.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nemeth</ENAMEX> promised to
investigate the motel in question. She promised to apologize, on behalf of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Super 8</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rusty the wiener dog</ENAMEX>, and she promised free <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Super 8</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hogsten</ENAMEX>'s choice. Wait till next episode to learn if <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Super 8</ENAMEX> keeps its
promises.

            Now let us contrast the open attitude of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Super 8</ENAMEX> with that
of, oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>'s bête noire . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> Avenger
is quite positive that, as long as he is reachable via e-mail at
Shoppingavenger@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each month</TIMEX> will bring him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 or 20</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> complaints
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>. (Little-known fact: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>," spelled backward in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aramaic</ENAMEX>, is
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ponzi</ENAMEX>.")

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>'s new favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> story
comes from one <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Brangham</ENAMEX>, who states: "I've resisted writing because you
no doubt have received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of complaints about this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and I
thought, 'Why pile on?' But after reading the other complaints you've received
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>, I think it's fair to say that I've got the topper--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>-Haul almost
killed me."

            Do tell, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brangham</ENAMEX>.

            "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> was moving from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>.
When we picked the truck up (they did honor the reservation) a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> brought the
vehicle out, parked it out front, and then reached behind the front seat and
brought out a bottle of fluid. He opened the hood, poured some of it somewhere
in the engine, closed the hood, put the bottle back, and handed me the keys. I
asked him what he'd done, and he said, 'Oh, just topping up some stuff.'"

            If you're thinking "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yikes</ENAMEX>," you're right.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brangham</ENAMEX> continues: "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> was in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">driver</ENAMEX>'s seat and she literally couldn't move the wheel <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six inches</NUMEX> in either
direction. I got in there and could do little more. ... Then we realized the
fluid that had been topped off was power steering fluid. There was a pool of it
gathering on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. I went behind the seat to find <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> empty bottles of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fluid</ENAMEX>, plus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> a cup left. It sure seemed like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">knowingly</ENAMEX> rented me a faulty truck."

            But it gets worse. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brangham</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> "customer
service," which, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>'s estimation, is probably a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> in a phone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX>. After waiting a considerable period of time, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>
mechanic showed up, taped up a leaky hose, and left. "It's dark, but we still
have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stop</ENAMEX> across the river in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hoboken</ENAMEX>. ... I'm driving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>. In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">middle of the Holland Tunnel</ENAMEX>, doing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 30 mph</NUMEX>, the steering wheel
drastically stiffens. It's now so hard to steer this huge truck that I have to
put my foot up on the dash or on the door to tug the wheel in the direction I
need it to go. I'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6'3</NUMEX>" and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">195</NUMEX> lbs. and it took <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">every ounce</NUMEX> of strength I had
to stop from smashing into oncoming traffic in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX>. If my
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-foot-something, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">115</NUMEX>-lbs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> had been driving, there's absolutely
no way she could have controlled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>."

            Horrible, yes? It gets still worse. "I bought power
steering fluid like it was cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>, topped off, and away we went." He topped
off <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">every few miles</NUMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>, they drove the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX>.
"Upon arrival, they keep us waiting for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half</TIMEX> because 'the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mechanic</ENAMEX>'s not in yet like we told him.' When he finally arrives, he proceeds
to tell us incessant stories about how drunk he got the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> before and how
his hangover is killing him."

            The mechanic eventually inspected the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>.
"You've got a busted hose," he told them. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brangham</ENAMEX> writes: "The first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanic</ENAMEX> had patched the hole on the hose with electrical tape.
Apparently, this is a very foolish thing to do. ... Even in his groggy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>,
[the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mechanic</ENAMEX>] couldn't believe a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanic</ENAMEX> would pull such a
stunt."

            Suffice it to say that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brangham</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> made it to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> and asked for a refund because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> nearly
killed them. But, he reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> didn't even offer an apology.

            Any of you loyal deputy
Avengers out there have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX> story that can top this one? You know where to write.

            In the previous episode, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> promised to
explain to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Airlines</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>'s favorite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> will keep his promise:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Very tasty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanuts</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southwest</ENAMEX> tries, at least most of the time, to
keep its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> happy. This is in marked contrast to every other airline
ever flown by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>, but particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Airlines</ENAMEX>, for which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> has very hard feelings at the moment, for reasons that will be
explained in the next episode.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> does have its drawbacks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
Avenger, when he was just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avenger</ENAMEX>, worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one summer</TIMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Big Boy</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> learned very quickly that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Big Boy</ENAMEX> is a restaurant
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't know how to eat in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. The same holds true for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>: It is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't know proper airline etiquette.
On his last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> flight, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>, the seat next to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> was filled by a gentleman whose first words were, "Bring on
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Heinekens</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> had a very long flight.

            But this, of course, is
not <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>'s fault, except insofar as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> makes its seats so cheap
that even drunken assholes can fly across this great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of ours.

            Recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> went to bat for one of his
loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss M.</ENAMEX>, who had an actual, valid complaint about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.</ENAMEX>'s luggage, , was left sitting for an hour in the rain--on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tarmac</ENAMEX>. When she got to her destination, she discovered that her clothing was
ruined. She got very little satisfaction when she approached <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> through
the normal channels, so she turned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX> for justice.

            After some initial backing-and-forthing, in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> made noises that sounded very much like the noises made by such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> when they do something wrong, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> came around and
offered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> travel vouchers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.</ENAMEX> considered this a satisfactory
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX>, and thus so did the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Avenger</ENAMEX>, who is nothing if not loyal
to the wishes of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> knows how to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> happy, which
is very unusual in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> business <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next month</TIMEX>: Why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-Haul</ENAMEX>
is a key part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX>'s plan for world domination.

            
               Got a consumer
score you want settled? Send e-mail to shoppingavenger@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .
                  
               
            

         
      
   
