
   
   
      
         
             Reduce, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuse, Re-Quote</ENAMEX>

            With the tabloids once again brimming with news of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">celebs</ENAMEX>' shrinking waistlines, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX> almost skipped right over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> 's recent declaration that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s quest for thinness is "really
getting out of hand." "Just ask ultra-lean <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Frasier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Leeves</ENAMEX>,"
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> suggested knowingly. Why ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leeves</ENAMEX>? Because according to the
Star , she's so "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sick</ENAMEX> of being added to the ever-expanding list of bony
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> that she's forced to eat 'more than I want' in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
'because I'm afraid that somebody's watching me.' " But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX> didn't
need to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leeves</ENAMEX> for her thoughts on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tinseltown</ENAMEX> thin parade, because she
already had--in an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> that appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">USA</ENAMEX>
Weekend just before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsstands</ENAMEX>. Queried about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>'s criticism of her weight, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leeves</ENAMEX> said, "I've been thin my whole life. I
do now find myself in a restaurant eating more than I want to because I'm
afraid that somebody's watching me, which is ridiculous." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the rest of the interview.)

            This is not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX> has caught
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the tabs with its hand in the proverbial cookie jar. While their most
compelling assets are those memorable pieces of journalism that certainly won't
appear anywhere else--such as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> "Then!" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Now</ENAMEX>!"
photos of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s varicose veins--when it comes to filling the rest of
their pages, the tabs are ruthless recyclers. Of course, mainstream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX> have been known to borrow a quotation or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, but they usually
give a nod to the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. The tabs, on the other hand, have managed to
turn the brazen, uncredited filch into an art form unto itself.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , for example, trumpeted that it had snagged "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> fun facts" about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Love Hewitt</ENAMEX> "that might surprise you." The surprise, however,
would only be for those who hadn't <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> read those same <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> facts--with the
corresponding identical quotes--in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Abele</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> 
                  Maxim cover story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>. And
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> item about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie O'Donnell</ENAMEX> opening her home to
trick-or-treaters seemed awfully familiar, maybe because it had appeared in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks earlier</TIMEX>. (Unless, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Donnell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spokeswoman Jennifer Glaisek</ENAMEX> managed to remember and repeat to the
Star --virtually verbatim--everything she told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> .)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> 's regular "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Style</ENAMEX>" feature is
frequently written in a breezily intimate manner that could fool the
unsuspecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> into thinking that the celebs have actually cozied up,
pajama-party style, and dished with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> about their beauty,
fashion, and health secrets. But the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> it would appear the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> has cozied up to is its research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarian</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s column,
for example, featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felicity</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keri Russell</ENAMEX>, the vast majority of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>'s musings were cribbed word for word from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May People</ENAMEX> magazine
story and an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> InStyle feature. Credit for those charming quotes
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>'s fondness for mangoes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eggo</ENAMEX> waffles and the fact that she
once had bangs "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> tiers high," for example, should go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> ,
while it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">InStyle</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Simpson</ENAMEX> who reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>, an avid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">walker</ENAMEX>, says she has "big, huge, happy endorphins" flowing through her
body.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> runs a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-page "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star</ENAMEX>
Style Special" cover story ("Shania: I'm not beautiful") that claims to have
all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> on country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shania Twain</ENAMEX>'s "secret flaws" and what she's
doing "to make herself perfect," including using a skin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ointment</ENAMEX> meant for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">softening cows</ENAMEX>' udders. It didn't take long to trace the sudden interest in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twain</ENAMEX>'s bovine toilette to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX> edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London's Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Callahan</ENAMEX> was apparently so enamored of
the interview <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twain</ENAMEX> gave to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> that she tried to replicate it
exactly: The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> quotes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twain</ENAMEX> in her piece are identical to those
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Woods</ENAMEX>' original, although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> are
never mentioned. Surely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Callahan</ENAMEX> just forgot in the rush of her scoop.

            While we're on the subject of editorial déjà
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vu</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX> has become strangely attached to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tilton Talk</ENAMEX>," the part
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlene Tilton</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> gossip column in which the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> spouts off about whatever strikes her fancy, with ellipses
separating her insights from one another. Recent entries have begun "What's
with all this millennium hysteria<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" and "How about those new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target</ENAMEX> ads?"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reading Tilton</ENAMEX> Talk always left Keeping Tabs with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unmistakably</ENAMEX> familiar
feeling, until it finally came to her: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tilton</ENAMEX> has clearly been paying homage to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX>- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of column writing. And why not?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Imitation</ENAMEX>, after all, is the sincerest form of flattery.

         
      
   
