
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> on the Web

            At
long last, there's a cure for the intractable problem of the "undecided" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX>.
Thanks to a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selector</ENAMEX> , the Web can
actually tell you who you should vote for. Simply type in your opinions on a
range of issues, and the site tells you which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> agrees with you
most.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selector</ENAMEX> is one of several Web tools offered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SelectSmart</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> , a company
that produces Web sites to help with all sorts of complicated decisions (its
slogan is, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Before You Decide"</ENAMEX>). In addition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential Candidate</ENAMEX>
Selector, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> offers a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lawn Grass Selector</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pet Selector</ENAMEX>, a Hair
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Products Selector</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contraception Selector</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> will be matched
with your pro-life, creationist views the same way <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leave-In Conditioning Spray</ENAMEX>
will be recommended for your dry, frizzy hair.

            Here's
how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selector</ENAMEX> works: The site asks your positions on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> issues,
from abortion to defense spending to free trade, and also asks you to choose
whether you feel "strongly" or "somewhat strongly" about each of those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX>.
You can also answer "no preference" to any of the questions. When you're done,
the program spits out a list of all the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, ranked and
scored in order of how closely their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX> match your views.

            The
tool claims moderate accuracy. According to a poll on the site, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for whom they intend to vote appeared at the top
of their list. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Another 19 percent</NUMEX> found their top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> place.
The poll doesn't ask the far more interesting question of how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> might
change their votes because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SelectSmart</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> results.

            I
asked a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> with disparate political views to test-drive the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selector</ENAMEX>. They ended up with funhouse-mirror versions of their actual
preferences--accurate in some places, comically distorted in others. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">selector</ENAMEX> placed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, respectively, on ""
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX>'s list--wrong order, he says, but not bad. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy</ENAMEX>'s list got less
accurate as it continued: It placed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Socialist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David McReynolds</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural Law</ENAMEX>
Party's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hagelin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> (who is not even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>) before
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy</ENAMEX>'s real-life <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> choice, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>. He observes that "the only
accurate score is for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>, who I would indeed rank dead last."
Meanwhile, the site told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX>, who writes for the conservative
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , to vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>--"the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for whom I have
the most contempt," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> says--while awarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> place, behind
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Browne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Phillips</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>. "Do they have a drunk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> doing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">rankings?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> asks.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Curt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>, the site's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>, sounded sober on the phone, but he has certainly
crafted some sloppy questions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> about whether they advocate
teaching evolution or creationism in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. This is not exactly an issue for
the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, but in any case, giving it the same weight as such topics
as health care or taxes seems preposterous. Even when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> does hit on
major issues--crime prevention, environmental protection, foreign policy--his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phrasing</ENAMEX> is without nuance and sometimes without sense. For example, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selector</ENAMEX> asks, "Would you prefer your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> promise to protect or reform
(or even abolish) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>?" This question is impossible to answer from
the choices provided. The distinction between protecting and reforming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security is anything but clear: Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> suggest
that the best way to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> is to reform it , while even
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who advocate preserving the current system--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>--advocate some significant changes . "Reform" could mean any number of
things, from minor tweaks (the addition of individual savings accounts) to more
radical fixes (replacing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> taxes with privately managed
individual accounts). Even if the site asked the question more precisely--say,
by asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> if they prefer government-managed savings or private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX>--it would reduce an issue of agonizing actuarial detail to a flippant
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">liner</ENAMEX>.

            The
options for answers are just as clumsy as the questions. The "somewhat" button
is ambiguous--if I tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selector</ENAMEX> that I am "somewhat" pro-choice, I might
be saying that I want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who is generally pro-choice but who opposes
partial-birth abortions. Or I might simply be expressing that abortion is a
less urgent issue for me than others. Indeed, the site doesn't allow you to
designate which issues are most important to you. You may care about gun
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> far more than you do about anything else, but unless you leave the
other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> questions blank, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> list won't reflect your
priorities.

            The
biggest problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential Selector</ENAMEX>, though, is that it reflects an
utterly unrealistic sense of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> choose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. It undermines itself
with its own idealism: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> boasts that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selector</ENAMEX> screens out
superficial factors such as advertising, hype, and image, and allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to
base their choices solely on the issues. But few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> make up their minds on
the basis of positions alone. The site does not try to measure intangibles like
integrity, experience, passion, and electability that do--and should--matter to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>.

            Right
now, the site is most helpful to the minor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, whom it gives the same
weight as the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. It helps them find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>'s Web site
now links to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selector</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libertarian Harry Browne</ENAMEX> says that a
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who found themselves matched to him have become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>.

            If the questions and
answers were formulated more precisely, the site could make for a fascinating
exercise. It would allow you to see how closely you line up with the candidate
for whom you intend to vote, and thereby tell you whether your attraction is
based on a congruence of views or a more ephemeral sense of goodwill. The
technology might usefully be applied in local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX>, in which it's hard to sort
out the platform of every potential state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> board
official, and city council <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>. But for now, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selector</ENAMEX> is no
more than a terrific party game--the election-year equivalent of having your
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">palm</ENAMEX> read.

         
      
   
