
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joke</ENAMEX>'s on You

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> had great sport with the gaffes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>. You remember the jokes: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> misspelled "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato</ENAMEX>,"
botched the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Negro College Fund</ENAMEX> slogan ("What a waste it is to lose one's
mind"), etc. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few months ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> turned this tactic on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, mocking
his suggestion that he had helped "create the Internet." Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is applying
the same derision to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> episodes illustrate an important
principle of negative campaigning: If you don't have something nice to say
about someone, say it with humor.

            In a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> asserted, "During my service in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">States Congress</ENAMEX>, I took the initiative in creating the Internet." <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A day</TIMEX> later,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> he had
"cracked up" over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s claim: "If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> created the Internet,
then I created the interstate highway system." In a satirical press release,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Sensenbrenner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>, exclaimed, "I had no idea my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
created the Internet." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Leadership Council</ENAMEX> aired TV ads linking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s Internet claim to similar assertions that he "lived on a farm" and
"undertook the task to reinvent the Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>." The ad accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> of
"trying to reinvent reality."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> jokes, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> jokes, poisoned their target without projecting
malice. They seized on a single misstatement, exaggerated it, and inflated it
into a comprehensive critique of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. In each case, the statement was
useful to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> because it touched on a weakness that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) was
similarly reflected in other comments by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) directly
undermined his campaign rationale. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>'s case, the rationale was national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX>, and the weakness was stupidity. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s case, the rationale is
economic progress, and the weakness is taking undue credit.

            If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> had called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> would have looked mean, and swing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>,
being suspicious, would have doubted the charge. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> had called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>," these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> would have assumed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armey</ENAMEX> was lying about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to slip the accusation past this barrier of incredulity is to pose the idea
indirectly, through satire--to savage your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> with a smile. Once the idea is
planted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX>'s head this way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> thinks it was his idea to begin
with--and he begins to embellish it. The next time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> makes a mistake, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">voter</ENAMEX> thinks to himself, "There goes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> again. What a moron."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
has gradually applied this lesson to his criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. In his campaign
kickoff speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last June</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was too heavy-handed: "Some in this
administration think they invented [prosperity]. But they did not invent
prosperity, any more than they invented the Internet." By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, however,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> had lightened his touch: "If [what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> have done] is
reinventing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, it makes you wonder how this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> was ever
skilled enough and efficient enough to create the Internet."

            This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> returned the favor. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, radio talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Imus</ENAMEX>
asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> should "have been able to identify the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>" when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was quizzed about those
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week ago</TIMEX>. In the quiz, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> had failed to name <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and had asserted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> who had
overthrown the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, recently "took over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> … is
going to bring stability to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and I think that's good news for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subcontinent</ENAMEX>." Here's how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> answered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imus</ENAMEX>' question:

            "I
sympathize with those who say that that's not really a fair test. I think that
it is troubling that he didn't know [that] it's important to stand up for
democracy, and that a military coup overthrowing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> is not good news.
And I think it's important <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">…</ENAMEX> and troubling that he didn't know it's in our
interests to stop the spread of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Comprehensive Test Ban</ENAMEX>
Treaty. I mean, this is a part of the world where it's probably most likely
that you're going to see serious problems in the future unless something's
done."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
went on: "But not knowing the names … I think that's kind of understandable. I
mean, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> I was talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Otkir Sultonov</ENAMEX>. You know, the prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uzbekistan</ENAMEX>. And he asked me, 'Did you send a birthday card to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamed</ENAMEX>?' That's of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamed Karoui</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tunisia</ENAMEX>. I had
just been talking about him with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ion Sturza</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moldova</ENAMEX>.
We're old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. We actually met through a mutual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lennart Meri</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Estonia</ENAMEX>, of course."

            Imus
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ribbed Gore</ENAMEX> over the joke, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have been playing with it ever since.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WITH TONGUE IN CHEEK</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">GORES</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BUSH</ENAMEX>," roared the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> . "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GORE</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">THROWS IMUS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A RADIO FUNNY BONE</ENAMEX>," agreed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
joke may look funny, but as a political kidney punch, it's dead serious. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
campaign rationale is that he'll keep <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> strong and make <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> proud.
His weakness is that he's ignorant of world affairs ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grecians</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosovians</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>) and has a track record as a bad and indifferent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>. By criticizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s answers to the world affairs quiz, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is trying to inflate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
weakness and discredit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s rationale. And by following up his serious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accusation</ENAMEX> (i.e., that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> showed indifference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> coup and
ignorance of the region's nuclear importance) with a lighthearted recitation of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is sugarcoating his indictment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX> will laugh, swallow, and absorb it.

            It's true that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cynically oversimplified Quayle</ENAMEX>'s blunders. It's equally true that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cynically oversimplified Gore</ENAMEX>'s statement about the Internet. And it's true
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is now doing the same to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. But it's also true that in every case,
these cynical charges have stuck. You call this tactic outrageous? <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">C'mon,</ENAMEX>
lighten up.

         
      
   
