
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates Crashing</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject: Don't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condescend</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO Protesters</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: "" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 1</TIMEX>)

            
               From: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Perry</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed Dec 1</TIMEX>

            It's not just interesting that the major media
coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO/Seattle</ENAMEX>, this piece included, has been dismissive and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">condescending</ENAMEX>--it's telling. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' front-page piece, which
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX> quotes, refers to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>' "sentiments"; the smug
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brainless</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>" headline in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TP</ENAMEX>" betrays a similar willful
ostrich-pose.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>' main victory lies in making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>
front-page news in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> is a non-democratic (unless
you want to stretch the definition of "democratic" to absurd proportions)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> with great power to affect, well, everyone . It is
symptomatic of the decay of accountability and legitimacy in ostensibly
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>-centered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            This is a major issue, and it's not going to get
play if a few loud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> don't make noise and force corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> to at
least take note, even as they reel out the tired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>-esque line that a
global economy is both inevitable and the best of all possible worlds, so get
used to it, take your medicine, shut up and get back to work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX> in black
masks smashing Starbucks windows make easy targets, sure. It's a lot harder to
actually look beneath the surface and think through the present and potential
effects of the incredibly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>--and in many ways dangerous--phenomenon of
globalization.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject: Don't Pick
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skip Gates</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: "" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 1</TIMEX>)

            
               From: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Imhoff</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed Dec 1</TIMEX>

            Yes and no to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Early</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicolson's</ENAMEX> reviews. Yes, the book as a whole is insufferably smug (with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornel</ENAMEX>
West at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the smirking line) and politically correct. Yes, its
choices are trendy and will date it badly and quickly. In this, it is very much
like another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> product, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Encarta Dictionary</ENAMEX> . The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictionary</ENAMEX> and its style guide would make Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grundy</ENAMEX> proud. They cite as
"objectionable" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as many words as any other dictionary, damning
every word that any small political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> anywhere has ever criticized. (The
style guide suggests not using "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX>," although it gives no usable
alternative; it labels "<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>" as offensive, and recommends "patient
with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>" as the proper phrasing.)

            However, the personal criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry Louis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is, in my opinion, overdone. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> wants to, and has, succeeded in his
profession. That isn't a bad thing. He has done so by hard work, by doing a lot
of worthy editing and literary criticism. He wants to read and know everything,
much like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diderot</ENAMEX>, to whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Early</ENAMEX> compares him. That's admirable, not a
weakness. Sheath the claws.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
Plagiarized Obits

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: "" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>)

            
               From: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Hobson</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mon Nov</ENAMEX>
29

            Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX>'s comment on plagiarized
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> obituaries: When I worked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Bedford</ENAMEX> Standard
Times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX> it was common to lift obits from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> word for word.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
Plagiarized Obits

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: "" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>)

            
               From: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Riley</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mon Nov</ENAMEX>
29

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times obituaries of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> containing an identical paragraph:
Doesn't that probably just mean that the paragraph came from a wire service
that both papers subscribe to (probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>)? If so, that's
not plagiarism--while I don't know this, my guess is that agreements between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> or other wire services let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> do pretty much
whatever they want with the wire copy. The episode involving a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, does sound more like plagiarism, so I
don't see that the cases are alike.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: How Big Is</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Windows Source Code</ENAMEX>? Don't Ask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               From: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dan</ENAMEX> kloke
            

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed Dec 1</TIMEX>

            Aaaargh! Explainer was humming along just great,
hitting the nails on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, until the last sentence: "And a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">browser</ENAMEX>'s source
code is only a fraction of the size of that of an operating system."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ewww</ENAMEX>. That is only true if you accept the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
premise that welding a graphical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user interface</ENAMEX> (GUI) onto an operating system
leaves you with a bigger, better operating system (OS)--a proposal which is
not universally accepted by the computer programming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> at large.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">browser</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> is small because it uses the functions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GUI</ENAMEX>. In
UNIX/Linux, the OS isn't tightly bound to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GUI</ENAMEX>, hence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX>'s greater
configurability for specific tasks, as well as its potential for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GUI</ENAMEX>. This is the real problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows</ENAMEX>: It's much more than an operating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, it's an OS (DOS or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NT</ENAMEX>) inextricably meshed with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GUI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MS-Windows</ENAMEX>).
Most of the "size" of the Windows basic installation software are details for
add-on services to the OS, many of which go unused.

            An OS is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GUI</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GUI</ENAMEX> is not an OS, even
when their coding is intertwined. The size of the OS, in the context of code
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> or object), is the size essential to execute files. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows</ENAMEX>, that
amounts to a DOS layer (the minimum required for complete, if not pretty,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 400k</NUMEX> of object code on disk. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Linux</ENAMEX>, it's a kernel with
enough support to maintain a command console, something around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">120k</TIMEX>. (Remember:
Both of these OS's can boot from floppies!)

            Browsers, as mentioned, don't have to be very big
either if they have a rich set of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GUI</ENAMEX> features to draw from. It's the dressy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows GUI</ENAMEX> that takes up all the space on your disk. Yes you have it, yes you
installed it "with" the OS--but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GUI</ENAMEX> isn't the OS! Even at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GUI</ENAMEX> and the OS are coded by separate, different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deftly</ENAMEX> and flawlessly unraveling the (deliberately
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convoluted</ENAMEX>) intricacies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> situation may be too much for the
valiant 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>, already caught in the middle (twixt truth and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fealty</ENAMEX>) as they are. The OS/GUI distinction is among those at the core of the
government's antitrust case. I hate to be nit-picky, but this distinction is
the nit ! If you don't get how important the distinction is, would you at
least credit the vehemence with which the computer software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX> argues
this issue? The article's closing sentence manages to gloss it right over.

            (To reply, click here .)

         
      
   
