
   
   
      
         
             Hsing-Hsing 

            Hsing-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hsing</ENAMEX> and I grew up together. I arrived in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1970</TIMEX> as a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-month-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX>. He came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Zoo</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year later</TIMEX> as a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">-month-old cub</ENAMEX>. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, I took more field trips
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> outings to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hsing-Hsing</ENAMEX> and cellmate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ling-Ling</ENAMEX> than I can
count. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past six years</TIMEX> I have lived next door to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX>, and hardly a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> passes when I don't jog or stroll through its grounds. I watched
Hsing-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hsing</ENAMEX> grow from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cub</ENAMEX> into giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">panda</ENAMEX> and meticulously followed his
efforts to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ling-Ling</ENAMEX>. I knew this panda. So I speak from the
heart when I say: Good riddance to the semi-bear.

            Hsing-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hsing</ENAMEX>, who died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ling-Ling</ENAMEX>, who
died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, drove otherwise reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> barking mad. At the time of his
death, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hsing-Hsing</ENAMEX> was the most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> in the world. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 60</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had visited him during his life sentence at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Zoo</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pandaphilia</ENAMEX> turned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX>'s own propaganda
rag. According to obituaries, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hsing</ENAMEX>-Hsing "enchanted" and "enthralled"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. He was a wonderful "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX>" between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. He
was "sweet-natured"--the most "cuddly" and adorable of all creatures. "The
world needs all the teddy bears it can get," mourned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memorial</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Schaller</ENAMEX>, a
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panda biologist</ENAMEX>, describes giant pandas as perfectly symbolic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.
With their lovely fur, clumsy movements, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goofy</ENAMEX> faces, they seem the
embodiment of innocence, childishness, and vulnerability. This is also the
public image so carefully cultivated for them by endangered-species <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>.
But behind the pretty face lurks, well, a bore. If we're going to
anthropomorphize pandas, let's be realistic about it. The idea that pandas are
sweet and genial is ridiculous. Pandas are not ill-natured. They are worse:
They are no-natured. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Drearier animals</ENAMEX> you cannot imagine. They are highly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-social</ENAMEX>, detesting interaction with other pandas and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. In all my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treks</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pandas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> and yard, I never once saw them be playful or
affectionate or active or even violent. Compared to almost any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX>--apes, big <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>, seals, prairie <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX>--the pandas were a drag.
They led a life of unparalleled tedium. Pandas are Mother Nature's couch
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX>. They are staggeringly lazy, so slothful they avoid climbing trees
because it's too tiring. Their entire lives are spent eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bamboo</ENAMEX> and
sleeping. (Not that there is anything wrong with eating and sleeping--I would
like to spend my own life that way--just don't call it endearing.)

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hsing-Hsing</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ling-Ling</ENAMEX> were not simply dull. They
were also unpleasant. Confinement depresses zoo <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, and the pandas were no
exception, behaving more like kooks than teddy bears. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ling-Ling</ENAMEX>, unprovoked,
assaulted one of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">keepers</ENAMEX> and gnawed on his ankle. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>' decadelong
attempt to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> was played as comic opera, but it was much darker. At first
Hsing-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hsing</ENAMEX> failed to inseminate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ling-Ling</ENAMEX> because he tried to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> with her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ear</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>. (He may have been inept because he never learned about mating
in the wild.) Then the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> imported a male panda from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Zoo</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ling-Ling</ENAMEX>. He mauled her instead. (So much for panda comity.) Eventually
Hsing-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hsing</ENAMEX> got it right, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1983 and 1989</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ling-Ling</ENAMEX> bore <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cubs</ENAMEX>. All of them died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within days</TIMEX>. One <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cub</ENAMEX> perished after <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ling-Ling</ENAMEX> sat on it.
Another seems to have been killed by a urinary tract infection acquired from
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ling-Ling</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Keepers</ENAMEX> believe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ling-Ling</ENAMEX> infected herself by sticking bamboo and
carrots up her urinary tract, surely neurotic behavior.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Zoo</ENAMEX> is pleading with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to replace
its dead pandas. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Tse-tung</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hsing-Hsing</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ling-Ling</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> as a gift, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s free-market <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is savvier. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> pandas in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zoos</ENAMEX> are here on long-term loans, at a going rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> per
pair per year. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has offered a discount to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Zoo</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 million</NUMEX> for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> has countered with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5 million</NUMEX>. I say keep the money, leave
the pandas in the wild, and buy a few more seals instead. After all, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian</ENAMEX> just announced plans to stuff <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hsing-Hsing</ENAMEX> and exhibit him. They
could just stick some bamboo in his paws, return him to his old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX>, and claim
they had received a new panda. No one would notice the difference.

         
      
   
