
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">336</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three for All</ENAMEX>"

            
               Planned
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Parenthood, the Museum of Natural History</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>--what's the
connection?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 335</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wall Nuts":</ENAMEX>
               
            

            

               In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> anniversary of the fall of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin Wall</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> reminisced about some bad advice he
received <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>: "In my view, that would have been an open provocation,
tantamount to sticking our fingers in the eyes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> military." Who
advised him to do what?
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>, who is stupid, advised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to do something stupid to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>,
because, you see, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> is not very smart, in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> is
stupid."<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Wellesley Wild</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> advised his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> to 'Get tough on that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. General
something. Wears that funny looking hat.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Narver</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Whatever it was, it couldn't have been worse than sending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Joel</ENAMEX> to play
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Petrosky</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "Barb
wanted to flash her black sports bra as she went through Checkpoint
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Fitzpatrick</ENAMEX>
            

            "An
Oktoberfestively drunk <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> egged him on to use the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stiff corpse</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX> to chip off a hunk of wall."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            It's sad to see a great
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> reduced to a tattered geriatric remnant of its former self. But
enough about me. Let's consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s nostalgic invocation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> military. It seems like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only yesterday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhukov</ENAMEX> rallied the
indomitable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of that mighty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> to stop the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> outside
the gates of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> and left them to die by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> in the snow. The good
times, they're over so quickly. Today, alas, what comes to mind is a couple of
bad baritones from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Army Chorus</ENAMEX>, drunk on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antifreeze</ENAMEX>, trying to convince
some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that their music stands are made of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plutonium</ENAMEX> and worth a few
bucks. It's sad, really. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> . Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX>'s original face.
Or the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Drifters</ENAMEX>" on tour, singing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volga Boatman</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">halftime</TIMEX> during a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX> game. Of course, the shape I'm in, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> I'll have
forgotten the entire episode.

            
               Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fault</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            "Some of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> suggested that I come over here to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin Wall</ENAMEX> and dance on
the wall," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. "Without wearing underwear," he did not add.
"As if I ever wear underwear!" he then went on not to conclude.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Dickinson</ENAMEX>'s
True<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-Life Baptist Adventures Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Did you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preachers</ENAMEX> wear waders?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> who baptized me wore waders while I
got real wet. "You're gonna stay down there a while [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">glub-glubby</ENAMEX>] 'cause you're
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SINNER</ENAMEX>!"

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>, I was summarily
dismissed as a troublemaker for asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seditiously</ENAMEX>, "What's with all those
footballs, basketballs, tetherballs, and volleyballs, why do we have to play
'duck-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck-goose</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>?"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech Talk Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Recent problems with the

                  Slate
                mail server have meant that many responses arrived too late
to appear in the quiz. These were, without a doubt, the funniest answers each
of you has ever written, and they would certainly have run on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> page.
It may be some comfort to you, as it is for me, that this is something we can,
with a clear conscience, blame entirely on others.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moe</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
