
   
   
      
         
            A "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad Visit</ENAMEX>" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with official <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> denials that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airborne</ENAMEX> radar system <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> plans to build for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> contains any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
technology. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said the deal, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is trying quash,
could be worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $2 billion</NUMEX> and represents "the zenith of transactions
conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Ministry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> since the start of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> began after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> took delivery last
month of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ilyushin</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX> transport <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> in order to install a radar
system before handing it over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, it said. Defense establishment
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> that there's nothing new about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> building a
radar system for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. They speculated that pressure has levied on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel Aircraft</ENAMEX>
Industries in foreign sales of intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. "Those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> could argue
that while they are barred from selling to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has no control
over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s military industries," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said.

            The
paper published a front-page photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Clinton</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Wall</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. An article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> by its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> said, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">obody</ENAMEX> takes seriously <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s claim that
her visit [to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>] <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> was strictly a personal trip." The article said
that winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> vote is critical for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. But it quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference of Presidents of Major Jewish</ENAMEX>
Organisations, as saying that the seemingly disordered manner in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
arranged her trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> "is evidence of the fact that she's not quite tuned
into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> here yet, doesn't understand its nuances and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">complexities</ENAMEX>, and is perhaps getting some bad advice."

            The
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, in a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
visit, said that she "did not pass the test" at the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wall</ENAMEX> because
"security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> desecrated the women's section of the
Wall by barging through those at prayer." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem Judaic</ENAMEX> school winced when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entourage</ENAMEX> turned their backs on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wall</ENAMEX> as they left (you're supposed to back away from it). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of them told
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , he plans to vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. "She came here for political reasons, not to pray. It's in bad taste," he
said. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> were dominated by a new crisis in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> peace negotiations chaired by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Mitchell</ENAMEX>. "Ulster
talks in dire trouble" was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> 's front-page headline.

            
Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>'s decision in a referendum to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth II</ENAMEX> as its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head of state</ENAMEX>, the controversy about her constitutional role continued in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> press. Before the referendum, the monarchist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX>, decided not to ask her to open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic Games</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>,
saying he would do the job himself. But he has since bowed out and said that,
to ensure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Games</ENAMEX> would be "a great unifying national occasion," he will
invite the queen's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor-general</ENAMEX> Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deane</ENAMEX>, to perform the opening ceremony. Whoever is tapped for the job, it still
won't be the queen.

            In an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>-supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> noted
that, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympic Charter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Games</ENAMEX> "shall be proclaimed open by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of state of the host <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logically</ENAMEX>, therefore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> should
do the honors, but "political practicalities" dictated otherwise. "If, for
whatever reason, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen</ENAMEX> is not considered to be the appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to
open the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Games</ENAMEX>, and thus to represent the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> on such an important occasion
to the world, what is she doing as head of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place?" the paper
asked. "The whole issue demonstrates the continuing absurdity of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>
retaining its constitutional links to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> monarchy."

            In an
editorial, the Straits Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> dwelt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> on the threat of
further secessions from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> following the independence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. It
praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdurrahman Wahid</ENAMEX>, who is currently in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, for
promising another referendum for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Aceh</ENAMEX> region. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> warned of big
problems: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesians</ENAMEX> "fear that if the logic of secession is not checked,
there will be no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> left for them to call home"; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s refusal
to contemplate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aceh</ENAMEX>'s departure, saying it would be unconstitutional; and the
region's economic role as a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s natural gas, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>, pepper, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rubber</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">timber</ENAMEX>. "What will a sudden break do to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s economy, particularly at a time when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is clawing its way
back to growth after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> crisis?" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> asked. "In the circumstances,
it is perhaps best for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX> to wait for the economic and political situation
to stabilize before taking a decision on a referendum."

            At a
rare press conference--reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>--to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mark</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> anniversary of his accession to the throne of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emperor Akihito</ENAMEX> said it weighed on his conscience that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> should be
celebrating the occasion "under the present stringent economic circumstances."
He was nevertheless "deeply moved" to think he had been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> for 10 years
and "deeply grateful for the good wishes extended to me." Asked what events
have made the deepest impression on him since his accession, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>
said walking through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Brandenburg Gate</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> "remains with me as an
unforgettable memory." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hirohito</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> faced "numerous difficulties" at the
moment, but added: "As I recall the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and how in its past so
much hardship and distress have been overcome, I firmly believe that the wisdom
of each and every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> and co-operation from international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> will
tide us over in fine style."

            
Following the death of the last <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ocean Park</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Morning Post</ENAMEX> called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> for an end to using marine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mammals</ENAMEX> for
popular entertainment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney</ENAMEX>, a "false killer <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX>," died of a bacterial
infection <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> in a concrete tank at the theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. His jumps through
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hoops</ENAMEX> had been one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>'s main attractions. In an editorial, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barney</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 16</TIMEX>, was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">th whale</ENAMEX> or
dolphin to die at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 20 years</TIMEX>. The arguments for keeping
such <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> in captivity did not work any more, it said: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Children</ENAMEX> are not
educated by watching a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphin</ENAMEX> walking on its tail or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX> carrying human
riders on its back."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> ran an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> on the reported return of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rickshaw</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> after a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40-year</TIMEX> ban. "Nothing can be a greater symbol of
feudalism than the hand-drawn rickshaw," it said. "It is blatantly
exploitative, smacks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">'coolie</ENAMEX> culture,' and is a terrible affront to
human dignity. It should evoke a sense of revulsion in any sensitive human
being, and has no place in a civil society."

         
      
   
