
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exorcising Arnold</ENAMEX>

            
               Movies

            

            

               
                  End of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Days</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX>'s apocalyptic action thriller gets spanked by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. The
plot: The devil has come to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Time</ENAMEX>) as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> turns over, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arnold</ENAMEX> must stop him or the
world will end. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call it preposterous and filled with baffling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inconsistencies</ENAMEX>, or as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> writes, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ovies</ENAMEX> like this are particularly
vulnerable to logic" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). Words such as "ridiculous"
and "absurd" pepper the reviews: It's "fire-and-brimstone bunk, a tired
compendium of involuntary crucifixions, grim messages carved into human flesh,
fly buzzings, ominous choral chants on the soundtrack and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> head
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">twisting"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desson Howe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to find out how religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> persuaded the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filmmakers</ENAMEX> to change the story's ending.)

            

               
                  Toy Story 2
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). A rare verdict on
the sequel to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toy Story</ENAMEX> : It's better than the original. Why? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">animation</ENAMEX> has improved noticeably in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> since the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> came
out, with more detailed surfaces and more nuanced facial expressions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The
plot is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>: A toy must chose between eternal life in a collectibles
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX> and the more dangerous life at home with his beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, who may
abandon him as he grows up. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) It is a vivid reminder of the "love, pity and
guilt that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> feels for a favorite toy" that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> have probably not
thought about in quite a while (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ).
(Visit the film's official site.)

            

               
                  Flawless
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Writer-director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Schumacher</ENAMEX>'s
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman Forever</ENAMEX> ) tale of a gruff, homophobic ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX>) who
ends up bonding with his drag <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen neighbor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Seymour Hoffman</ENAMEX>)
exasperates the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flawless</ENAMEX> is so awful it just might put an end
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s hypocritical infatuation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in drag as symbols of its own
supposedly liberated sexual attitudes" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call it corny, predictable, and packed with gay
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stereotypes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Clark</ENAMEX> looks at the film's chilly reception
and points out that "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> that this atypically 'little' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumacher</ENAMEX>
movie might get better reviews if it were a starless, low-budget indie that
could catch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> by surprise" and adds that "though formulaic, [it] plays
better than other equally contrived genre <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hybrids</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to visit an unofficial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Niro</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan page</ENAMEX>.)

            
               Books

            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tupperware: The Promise of Plastic in 1950s America</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian Institution Press</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> design <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>
delivers a "heavily academic cultural critique of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tupperware</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Hartigan</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ), but all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> can talk about is the story of
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brownie Wise</ENAMEX>, a struggling single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, turned the languishing line of
plastic containers into a booming success via <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> simple idea: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tupperware</ENAMEX>
Party. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inventor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Tupper</ENAMEX> came up with the idea, but it wasn't until he
handed over control of sales to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wise</ENAMEX> (the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> ever to appear on the
cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> ) that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> took off. The book tells how
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> isolated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950s</TIMEX> suburbs gain a social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, as
well as providing them with an acceptable way of earning income. When critics
do get around to talking about the quality of the book, they praise its "wit
and erudition" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Shapiro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tupperware Corp.</ENAMEX>'s home page
includes information on its products as well as how to give a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tupperware</ENAMEX>
party.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annie Leibovitz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sontag</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leibovitz</ENAMEX>'s book of photographs (which includes the works in her current show
of the same title at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Corcoran Gallery</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>) is described by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> as both slickly commercial and annoyingly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">didactic</TIMEX>. The idea of the
book, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sontag</ENAMEX> explains in her opening essay, is to demonstrate the
amazing diversity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. But as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Stevenson</ENAMEX> notes in the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> , the point "feels a bit tired by now," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sontag</ENAMEX>'s preface fails
in its attempt to "wrest Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leibovitz</ENAMEX>'s photographs back from the magazine
pages where they help sell movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX>'s." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Lehmann</ENAMEX>-Haupt
departs from the critical pack, declaring that "this mesmerizing book shows
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in such astonishing variety that no cliché or generalization about the
sex will ever again suffice" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">View</ENAMEX> a collection of
the photographs here.)

            

               Art
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Rockwell</ENAMEX>:
Pictures for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockwell</ENAMEX>'s transformation from lowbrow illustrator to classic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>
is now complete: A documentary on his life and works has aired on public
television, a traveling exhibition of his work is making stops at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corcoran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX> and, what's more, his work is being
tentatively embraced by postmodern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kimmelman</ENAMEX> glows in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">useums</ENAMEX> are full of pictures by old masters like Hals
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greuze</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boilly</ENAMEX> that, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockwell</ENAMEX>'s pictures, show everyday scenes. On
top of which there is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockwell</ENAMEX>'s subterranean complexity: the buried allusions
he made to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Isaiah …</ENAMEX> or to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mondrian</ENAMEX>'s grids." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> runs
an article on the exhibition titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"America's Vermeer?</ENAMEX>" that revels in the
irony of a sentimental illustrator, so long contemptuously dismissed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, being installed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> artistic pantheon. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norman Rockwell Museum</ENAMEX>'s
Web page lists future dates and locations for the traveling exhibit.)

         
      
   
