
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">347</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chillin'</ENAMEX> "

            
               Complete this
expression of amazement from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Collins</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of</ENAMEX>
Health, "I don't often pick up a scientific paper and find myself getting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chills</ENAMEX>, as I did when I saw _______________."
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to news_quiz@hotmail.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 346</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solid Goldberg</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               
                  While introducing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> dinner
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoopi Goldberg</ENAMEX> recalled a disturbing question one of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">granddaughters</ENAMEX> recently asked. "This was kind of chilling, because it wasn't
even like I could say, 'No, no, it's not going to happen.' " What was the
question?
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>,
Grandma, how the fuck did you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Nichols</ENAMEX> so badly?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
Amoros
            

            "Are
you going to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Dick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-sit for us again?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Bonin</ENAMEX>
            

            "Are
rampaging anarchists ever going to ransack our neighborhood
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Starbucks?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX>
            

            "Could
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Vilanch</ENAMEX> write even more musical numbers into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscars?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amoros</ENAMEX> had
similar answers.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramma</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> say that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy of Motion Picture</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts and Sciences</ENAMEX> is going to come to your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and demand the return of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> (TM) you won for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghost</ENAMEX> , citing the poor quality of your
performances in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eddie</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Associate , Boys on the Side</ENAMEX>
and, to be perfectly honest here, Ghost . Is that true?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Retribution in Lieu</ENAMEX> of an Actual Wrap-Up
            

            Because

                  Slate
               's worthless e-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> is displaying its
characteristic incompetence (surely not treachery--that would suggest paranoia
on my part and determination and skill on theirs--not likely), I received no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> responses to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s quiz, except a few that slipped through enemy
lines, and those using a back channel I'd rather not discuss. (I can
say that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> are pretty annoyed at the pebbles inadvertently flung at
their windows.) However, I have been given the usual meaningless reassurances
that this problem will be corrected shortly. Complaints can be sent directly to
Critical <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Path</ENAMEX>. But not by e-mail.

            
               Gold <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush</ENAMEX> to
Judgment Answer
            

            The granddaughter asked if she might get killed at
school.

            Presumably this was an inquiry into the
possibilities of gun violence and not a request for the sweet release that
death can bring from irksome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoopi</ENAMEX> told this moving personal anecdote at an
event marking the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> anniversary of the Brady Bill. In his after-dinner
remarks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said: "Screw it. Go on and shoot each other if you
want to. What the hell do I care? I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame duck</ENAMEX>. With a big butt." No, no, of
course he didn't. That's just the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum cake</ENAMEX> talking. If there was <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum cake</ENAMEX>. How
should I know? I wasn't there. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dweezil Zappa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Peck</ENAMEX>. What the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> said was, "No one believes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> is as safe as it should be or can
be. Or as tidy, I am not adding."

            "We should not ... be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">speechless</ENAMEX> when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> say, 'Am I going to make it to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>?' " said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>. "We should give them an honest answer: not if you keep asking these
phony-baloney movie-of-the-week questions," she untidily failed to add.

            
               Ought To Biography
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> were asked
for the title of a much needed but unwritten autobiography of any national
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Seven Years in</ENAMEX>
Tibetia , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I've Finally Made Up</ENAMEX>
My Mind To <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Cuomo</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Salzman</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s Yes, I
Can: My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>! "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amoros</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s The
Good <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Days</ENAMEX> , a memoir of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.7</NUMEX> ailment-free <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>
Fee
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s
Shoulda, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woulda, Coulda</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Rubin</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX> With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rest of the Week With Mom</ENAMEX>, Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> Was off
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hanging Out With His 'Motorcycle Club'</ENAMEX>) , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Bonin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster Wallace</ENAMEX> collection
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Infinite Jest</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>

            
               Brief <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Interviews With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hideous Men</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl With Curious</ENAMEX>
Hair , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broom</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">System</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>

            
               A
Supposedly <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fun Thing</ENAMEX> I'll <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never Do Again</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William J. Clinton</ENAMEX>

            Click
for more books.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exasperation with Critical Path,</ENAMEX>

                  Slate
               's worthless e-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
