
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">344</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Futurific</ENAMEX>"

            
               "If I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
it won't happen for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>. If I'm not, it will happen immediately." Who
said this about what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 343</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Be</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>":
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           You are making up the front page of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>
Times (online edition) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Nov. 24</TIMEX>. What is the headline for
your lead story?
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Clooney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where's Our Gold?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Petrosky</ENAMEX>
had a similar answer.)

            
"Insider: What the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX> Merger Means to Your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolls-Royce</ENAMEX>
Collection."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Petrosky</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thanksgiving Miracle: Children Starving</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mac Thomason</ENAMEX>
            

            "G.W.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush Arrives</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Impromptu Friendship Visit: Shalom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwaiters</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwaitresses</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michele Siegel</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Plummer</ENAMEX> )

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Firm</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scowcroft</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sununu Wins Another Big New Government Contract:</ENAMEX>
'We'll <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Forever Owe 'Em,' Official Explains</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael C Doyle</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            The greatest scene in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX>'s best movie about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>, (which is,
incidentally, a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX> category thanks to a generous contribution from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil-Exxon</ENAMEX>), comes at the end, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Clooney</ENAMEX> hand
over all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX>--right at the border! The camera goes in
tight to show the complex emotions and various facial tics playing across
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clooney</ENAMEX>'s handsome mug, and we hear a fusillade of gunfire--it seems to go on
forever!--announcing the cynicism and greed and callousness that underlie the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> are slaughtered. OK. That was the ending they didn't
shoot. And, for all I know, didn't write. But the one that actually ended the
movie was good too, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clooney</ENAMEX> finally proposes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Pfeiffer</ENAMEX> right in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomingdale's</ENAMEX> for gosh sakes, and all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> applaud and
applaud--it seems to go on forever--announcing the cynicism and greed and
callousness that underlie <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas shopping</TIMEX> or marriage or movies or
something. And then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> blast the hell out of the menswear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. Cool!

            
               Respect for Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Repressive Religions Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Seventh Money Show Opens: Complete Kuwaiti Support</ENAMEX>
to Foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX>"

            I, for one, breathe easier knowing that a favorable
investment climate prevails in our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> story on the page, behind "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Helping Hand</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Families of Convicts" and "Campaign Against Drugs to Continue</ENAMEX>," is the only
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> story to make most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> papers: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Parliament Agrees To Discuss</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Urgent</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Replacement Bill, Women's Decree Fails, 'Rights' Remain Alive</ENAMEX>."

            What is more delightful, the sarcastic quotation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX> around "urgent" or the snide quotation marks around "rights"? Either way,
some savvy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editorializing</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> rejected by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41-21</NUMEX> a decree by
who say they support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights say they voted no out of principle: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">emir's</ENAMEX> decree undermined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>'s authority. Interesting principle.

            

               Scores
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> attended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s session, sitting in a reserved section of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> applauded when the result of the vote was announced.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fundamentalist Ahmed Baqer</ENAMEX> also drew applause from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> when he screamed,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't want (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights)! Why do you want to force it on
them?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberal lawmaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sami Al-Munayes</ENAMEX> accused many of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> of
hiding behind the constitutional excuse, while in their hearts they wanted "to
deny <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the society the right to live."

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Autobio Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Match the presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> with his campaign autobiography.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidates</ENAMEX>:
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Books</ENAMEX>:
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Life on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Fathers</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Cash of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Father</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Birth of Freedom</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Birth of Freedom in My Millionaire</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s Pants
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Charge to Keep</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Charge Account Provided by My Millionaire</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cronies</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Charge of Drunk and Disorderly</ENAMEX>, but I Was
Just a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Boy</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Earth in the Balance
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Chicken in the Basket
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Present</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> Past
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Future</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Other Thing</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Answers</ENAMEX>:
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> in the Balance.
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> wrote both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Present</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> Past .

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> of My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fathers</ENAMEX> .

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A New Birth of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom</ENAMEX> , which is not a tell-all book about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s sexual liberation
and which contains no confusing pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Taylor</ENAMEX> standing beside a
hot air <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> wrote
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Charge to Keep</ENAMEX> , in the sense that his communications <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> wrote it, but he put his name on it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s "restoring dignity and
integrity to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>" is another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s lying. (In his defense, it must
be said that he may have read it.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ongoing Autobio</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to submit the title of an
as yet unwritten but badly needed autobiography of any other national political
figure.

            Answers to run
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> not a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
