
   
   
      
         
            Family Matters

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               How does one "get
over" a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>'s affair? How long does it take for the hurt to lessen?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX> From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Sus</ENAMEX>,

            As with bleeding,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">healing</ENAMEX> takes different amounts of time for different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, some people
bleed to death. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> wishes you peace of mind, wherever you may find it. Give
yourself some time to see how things play out and see how you're feeling about
things ... well, about him. If you can't get over it, get out of it.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, understandingly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I am having an
ongoing ordeal over whether my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> should refer to her
stepfather as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stepdad</ENAMEX>," or by his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name. I've been remarried for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> to my present <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, and he insists that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> should refer
to him as either "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>" or "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giles</ENAMEX>" when addressing him. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> calls my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> by his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name, which infuriates him because he believes it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disrespectful</ENAMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> insists he doesn't deserve to be called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>" and
now only makes reference to "him" when mentioning her stepfather to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>. Please advise about what would be the most appropriate way to handle
the situation.
            

            

               --Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giles</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear Mrs,

            "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giles</ENAMEX>" sounds like
a real beaut. The form of address, you understand, is merely the battleground
for the simmering war between them. Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> won't call him "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>," which
he wants; and he won't permit a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-name address (which is perfectly
acceptable), which is what she wants. And for whatever it's worth, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has
never heard of anyone saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stepdad</ENAMEX>, please pass the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX>," so forget that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Someone, maybe a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX>, needs to deal with the alienation the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">youngster</ENAMEX> feels and the hostility harbored by your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>. If you can find a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to deal with and improve their relationship, what she calls him will become
a moot point. Reading between the lines, it may be that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s biological
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>-situation are part of the equation.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, worriedly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.,</ENAMEX>
               
            

            
               Tell me if I'm overreacting. I was having lunch
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle</ENAMEX>, who works in hospital billings, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX>. Just in
passing, I mentioned that I never received a thank-you note for my (small)
wedding gift. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle</ENAMEX> insisted I was wrong and to prove it took me to her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> where she pulled out this "book of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>." In it she had a page for
each of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> was listed what I gave her and the date she
wrote a thank-you note! What was troubling was not so much that, but the other
entries--including, "how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> responded to death of (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">her</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>," i.e.,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, card, etc.
            

            
               I think her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accountant</ENAMEX>'s mind has gone too far. I mean, you can't measure everything, and
keeping a ledger on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> is odd. I told her this, and she said that in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> tradition they believe "all your actions are inscribed in the book,"
and she is doing just that. What do you think?
            

            

               --Unsure
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Un</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks this woman
is one sandwich shy of a picnic. What she is referring to is God's accounting,
not hers. The poor dear must have been reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marvel comics</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> when
they talked about this. It is true that the humanistic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> view holds that
the substance of one's life is created by good deeds, but a ledger toting up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and cards does not figure in. Her misunderstanding reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> who asked a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> what gear she was in at the moment her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> hit
another. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gucci</ENAMEX> sweats and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reeboks</ENAMEX>," she said.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, rationally

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I am a 20-year-old
female, and I have been married for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> and have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> with my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>. He works a lot, and our marriage hasn't been on track for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months now</TIMEX>, and we seem to be more like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">roommates</ENAMEX> than a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>. I
don't know if he's cheating on me, but he has been acting strangely. He's been
coming home at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 a.m.</TIMEX> when he gets out of work at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:30 in the morning</TIMEX>. He tells
me it's because he goes to have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> after they close the store
where he works. I don't know whether my marriage is over and whether to talk to
him about all this and ask if we can work things out. One thing I do know is
that if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is cheating, I wouldn't be able to stay with him.
            

            

               --Confused
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Con</ENAMEX>,

            My dear, if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> really is drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>
from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:30 to 6 a.m.</TIMEX> he would need to wear Depends. If you suspect he is taking
an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">after-work</TIMEX> breather with someone other than his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>, you could call the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and ask. He may, however, not level with you. In any case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool parlor</ENAMEX>, you must get the problem out in the open.

            When you state your age,
and the age of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, it sounds like you are in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romeo and Juliet</ENAMEX>
territory. If this is not a typo, you are far too young to be dealing with all
the factors you mention. Confront your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> with both your suspicions and
your awareness that things have gone off track. See where the conversation
goes. If he has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> complaints, consider counseling (if he's willing) or
separate maintenance. You cannot live like this and needn't tolerate his
in-your-face behavior.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, proactively

         
      
   
