
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Panda Debate</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject: Plotz the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panda</ENAMEX> Poacher

            
               From: THesse

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed Dec 1</TIMEX>

            You are a poor excuse for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>. While I
understand (and respect) the meaning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1 st Amendment</ENAMEX>, I think
you take it to an unacceptable level. You see, my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> read your
"article" and could not fathom how (or why) a supposed intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> could
possibly say those things. It upset her greatly. She has never seen a panda in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, and while they are not the liveliest <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, I know her eyes would
light up and her smile would be from ear to ear at being able to view one for
herself. I believe you need to grow up and start looking at the positive things
in the world. You have got to be the saddest thing I have ever encountered.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject: Fluffiness
Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fur Deep</ENAMEX>

            
               From: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Munson</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec 1</ENAMEX>

            Good for you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Humans</ENAMEX> have the most annoying
tendency to ascribe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cutesy</ENAMEX> attributes to wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX>, even the
fluffy ones, really don't care if the whole human race lives or dies. They'd
press the nuclear launch button if it got them a chunk of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herring</ENAMEX> for
a reward. They're not good or evil, they are just mindless slaves to instinct
and the food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>. By all means enjoy them, just stop once in a while to
explain to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Care Bears</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flipper</ENAMEX> aren't the real thing.

            Get real, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>. You've all got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in your
lives who need your attention a whole lot more than pandas do. And the
difference is, they'd appreciate it.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s
Rosebud

            
               From: Tearful

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed Dec 1</TIMEX>

            Admit it, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plotz</ENAMEX>, you still harbor resentment from
when your mommy threw your teddy bear out, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age16</TIMEX>.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobson's Choice</ENAMEX>

            
               From: 
               Itrucks
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: Mon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec 6</TIMEX>

            One wonders where the moral problem is here. Does
it lie with the developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> who tolerate less than ideal environmental
standards and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>/forced/sweatshop labor, the multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that
take advantage of those conditions, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> who happily buy the
merchandise despite its questionable origin?

            My college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> developed a problem for an ethics
class that revolved around a wrenchingly poor "fictional" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that proposed
to enable slavery in return for economic development. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would allow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> for labor as long as they provided decent housing,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and medical treatment. In return, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would enforce the property
rights with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s police power. Since famine was endemic in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, it is probable that the slaves would have a higher standard of living
than would be available to them in the "free" sector. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> would
have the advantage of a stable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> that could be trained and experienced
with no threat of the employee jumping to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>.

            Would your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> take such a deal? Would you buy
products produced under such a system?

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AmeriCorps</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Let Charities Call the Shots</ENAMEX>

            
               From:

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Lenkowsky</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: "

            
               Date: Mon
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec 6</ENAMEX>

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Bandow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris Wofford</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
And I both serve on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of the Corporation</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Service</ENAMEX> and have
been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of government involvement with non-profits for longer than I care
to remember. So, what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> should I take in this interesting dialogue?

            To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX>, I'd say that most of the largest
non-profits have long since signed on to the Federal gravy train. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About a third</NUMEX>
of their revenues (on average) now come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Treasury</ENAMEX> (or its state
equivalents), along with lots of strings that significantly compromise their
independence. And I have not run across any of them that would prefer an end to
these arrangements. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> now even finds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX> proposing
to expand them under the headings of "charitable choice" and "school
vouchers."

            So, the real issue is not whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AmeriCorps</ENAMEX>
somehow violates the integrity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>, but
whether it offers any advantages over our current ways of doing so. I think it
does. On balance, I'd rather offer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do their
bidding than grants to do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s bidding. That's probably cheaper
too.

            To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>, I would say that large numbers of
AmeriCorps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> do not a successful program make. Nor do the records of
their "accomplishments," which the Corporation scrupulously collects, since
such studies do not usually reveal if these results might have occurred anyway
(i.e., through other sources of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>) or how valuable or long-lasting
they are. And while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> is undoubtedly sincere in saying the Corporation
tries to be the "junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>" in its relationship with its grantees, long
experience watching non-profits pursue government support makes me more than a
little skeptical.

            I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AmeriCorps</ENAMEX> is valuable because it offers
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--especially our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--an opportunity to devote an
intensive period of their lives to giving something back to their society and
learning the civic skills upon which our voluntary tradition relies. Even with
volunteering at record levels (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> say they are so engaged,
according to the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX> survey), I think we have to take steps to ensure
that the spirit upon which it (and much else that's worthwhile) depends is
transmitted from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AmeriCorps</ENAMEX> is one way of doing this
(and by no means the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX>) and can be redesigned so that both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> would feel more comfortable that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, are really
calling the shots.

            (To reply, click
here .) 

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aussies Ain't Gents</ENAMEX>

            
               From: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Thomson</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: Mon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec 6</TIMEX>

            As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Thomson</ENAMEX> mentioned in your
McLaughlin tidbit, I would like to make clear that I am not a "courtly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brit</ENAMEX>" but an uncouth <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX>. Under normal circumstances, being referred to
as an "honorable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX>" would be considered flattery but, where I come
from, it's an insult.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            [ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Thomson</ENAMEX> is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX>.]

         
      
   
