
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">335</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wall Nuts</ENAMEX>" 

            
               In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> reminisced about some bad advice he received <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>: "In my view, that would have been an open provocation, tantamount to
sticking our fingers in the eyes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> military." Who advised him to do
what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">334</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Paige Proofs":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Fill in the blank as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paige Patterson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baptist Convention</ENAMEX>, responds to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Show me</ENAMEX> a single case where a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Baptist</ENAMEX> has ____________, and I will do my best to see it never
happens again."
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fun</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Werthmann</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Rodriguez</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
Asplund , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Murphy</ENAMEX> had similar
answers.)

            
"Gotten <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800s</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SATs</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Evolved from some other form of life."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LeRoy Tabb</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wellesley</ENAMEX>
Wild
            

            "Named
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paige</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Welch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Stock</ENAMEX> )

            
"Professed belief in some ridiculous half-man <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-god who performs miracles
and can be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and one</NUMEX> at the same time and lives forever."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale</ENAMEX>
Shuger
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Many responses were
built on the assumption that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Baptists</ENAMEX> are bad in bed. Certainly, some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religious groups</ENAMEX> associate sex with sin, which can either be inhibiting or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inspiring</ENAMEX>, depending on your point of view (and whether or not you own your own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vestments</ENAMEX>). Still other faiths forbid specific erotic acts, such as getting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undressed</ENAMEX> or smiling. Of course, sexual pleasure is not experienced in groups
(unless you are very lucky), but between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of whom
should be awake at the time, praying for forgiveness). And so there is no proof
that any particular religion is sexier than any other. There is, however, some
evidence that sexual satisfaction correlates with educational attainment; for
instance, those who completed graduate school express greater sexual happiness
than those who dropped out of high school. You'd think this sort of thing would
show up in more educational reform plans. But not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>'s. (Praise the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX>.)

            
               Entirely Aboveboard
Answer
            

            "Show me a single case where a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern Baptist</ENAMEX> has
acted deceptively ."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rev. Patterson</ENAMEX> was commenting on a letter from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Community Relations Council</ENAMEX>, an umbrella <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 60</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, protesting his denomination's use of "deceptive" tactics to
convert <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX>, including--in a rare show of unity--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seminaries</ENAMEX>, are particularly vexed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baptists</ENAMEX>'
use of tallis and yarmulke in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>.

            "Our quarrel with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Baptist Convention</ENAMEX>
is not over its right to proselytize," said the letter. "Rather, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> is deeply offended that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.B.C.</ENAMEX> has formally embraced a strategy
that attempts to deceive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> into believing that one can be both a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>."

            That <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.B.C.</ENAMEX> employs a
very different conversion tactic than the straightforward hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead enema</ENAMEX> used
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inquisition</ENAMEX> to convert <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, sometimes turning them into "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maranos</ENAMEX>," or
secret <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, other times into "pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>," or dead <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>.

            
               Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leftovers</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mental Health</ENAMEX>: "I am personally shocked--shocked!--when something like this
happens."--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX> discovers that the deinstitutionalized
mentally ill do things that harm others; he proposes to change the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
policy on forced deinstitutionalization. Sincerity check: In his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in office, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX> financed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> new housing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>; there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10,000</NUMEX>
homeless mentally ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> alone. Honesty check: I added the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> "shocked."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mental Health 2</ENAMEX>: "This is serious wacko stuff."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> comments on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>'s tax plan. This is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX> refer to as "the pot
calling the kettle, like, some kind of pot" or what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wildman Fisher</ENAMEX> calls
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> vs. donkey."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theological Health</ENAMEX>: "A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX> has introduced a bill to prevent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">circumcision</ENAMEX> after death."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Sontag</ENAMEX> writes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>.
Or after heavy drinking, she does not add.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yuck</ENAMEX> "<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha-ha</NUMEX>"? Or yuck "blecchhh"? Health: "There's a big yuck factor to
reusing devices."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Kessler</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> comments on "single use"
medical devices being cleaned and reused. He does not refer to foreskins.

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shocking</ENAMEX> (and delightfully so) religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intolerance</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
