
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">343</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Be the Editor</ENAMEX>"

            
               You are making up
the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwait Times</ENAMEX> (online edition) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Nov. 24</TIMEX>.
What is the headline for your lead story?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               
                  
                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 342</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A and Q":</ENAMEX>
                  
               
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        The answer, from G.W. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, responding to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Russert on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> : "I really don't. I will if I'm the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." What is the question? 
                     
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On</ENAMEX>
execution <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, do you ever pick up a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX> and head down to the pen, to
taunt the condemned and mock them when they beg for clemency?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
Evanson
            

            "Do
you think I'm better-looking than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cokie?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michele Siegel</ENAMEX>
            

            "Would
you like to have sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX>
            

            "Do
you ever, just for fun, say, 'No <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Taxes'</ENAMEX> in front of a mirror<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Germain</ENAMEX>
            

            "Is it
true you have no penis?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Sepmeier</ENAMEX> had a
similar answer.)

            Click 
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Most responses assume
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.W.</ENAMEX> is a stupid, hollow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> kept afloat by his own vanity and the
self-interest of his rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>. So why hasn't stupidity torpedoed him the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> it did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>? And can this be explained without resorting to the
phrase "dumbing down" or alluding to the questions on that Who Wants a Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bucket of Money</ENAMEX> quiz show being multiple choice about the Brady
Bunch , not like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX>, when quiz show questions were so hard that
you had to cheat to win, and presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> all spoke in full
sentences, in iambic pentameter, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>, while wearing complicated wigs and
fancy hats and several layers of underwear with fastenings so elaborate you had
to be like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> just to undress for one of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naked Fireside Chats</ENAMEX> from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aero White House</ENAMEX>, a giant dirigible moored to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelda Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>. I guess
what I'm saying is that maybe times haven't changed all that much and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid people</ENAMEX> are the same all over the world. And if they're not, why hasn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> done <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those marvelous trend-spotting covers on The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New New Stupidity Stupidity</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Answer … er …</ENAMEX>
Question , No, Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX>: Do you have
any opinion of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>, a possible successor to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>?

            

               Some <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Other Meet the Press Moments*</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.R.</ENAMEX>: Would you accept an
invitation to meet with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Log Cabin Republicans</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>?

            G.W.:
All that does is create a huge political, you know, nightmare for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. I'd
rather meet with the least tolerant, most reactionary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the party <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">…</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, of course.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.R.</ENAMEX>: Do you support
adoption by gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>?

            G.W.:
I believe that society ought to aim for the ideal. And the ideal is for a man
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to adopt a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. They should beat it regularly with a stick, educate
it in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX> so it won't get confused by, you know, learning, then
throw it on the barbecue and eat it, and then we can all get high again, like
when we were young and … is this thing on?

            *Final
sentence added by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker Cartoon Contest</ENAMEX> Follow-Up
            

            Another suggested caption for that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeigler</ENAMEX> drawing
of a weary suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atlas</ENAMEX> arriving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with the world on his shoulders:

            "Holy fucking shit! A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">globe</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX>
Follow-Up
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three Days of the</ENAMEX>
Condor , the film, was adapted from the novel <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Six Days of the Condor</ENAMEX> .
I had been a fan of the book before they made the movie, and, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exceptional</ENAMEX>, I always did miss those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> extra <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven O.</ENAMEX>
Newberger
            

            
               Schedule
Note
            

            There will be no quiz on
Thanksgiving while we recover from the effects of that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX> that
makes you so sleepy. What do you call it? <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Heroin</ENAMEX>. Bless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> and her
unconventional stuffing. News Quiz resumes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Sex <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, stupidity <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, drugs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>--a reverse
of the usual order on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. (This "common denominator" sponsored by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnership for a Drug Free America</ENAMEX>.)

         
      
   
