
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">342</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A and Q</ENAMEX>"

            
               The answer, from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.W. Bush</ENAMEX>, responding to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> : "I really don't.
I will if I'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." What is the question?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               
                  
                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 341</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beat the Press</ENAMEX>":
                  
               
            

            

               
                  
                     The headline in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Mirror</ENAMEX> is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX>."
What is the lead?
                  
               
            

            "Gen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> to be cut up and divided among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that want a piece of
him."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mac Thomason</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grumpy</ENAMEX>'s death has caused the dwarfs to pull together as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Mannella</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            
"Despite another <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX>-place division finish, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit Tigers</ENAMEX> ex-manager Sparky
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> is quick to assure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is not disappointed. 'We are a
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, we're not feeling any pressure to outperform <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, we have
great chemistry, and our shortstop bakes the best <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lemon bars</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major League</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Baseball</ENAMEX>, that's for damn sure!' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Shuger</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford Street</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> was the scene of 'Pedophiles on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parade</ENAMEX>,' a joyous
celebration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yesterday</ENAMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> ate a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half-dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kippers</ENAMEX> for breakfast, and he loved
them all."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal Pollack</ENAMEX>
            

            Click 
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Among the single digits,
no number is less evocative than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>. Consider movie titles. Run up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
and you'll find that every other number has better films-- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Flew Over the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cuckoo's Nest , Two for the Road , Three Days of the Condor</ENAMEX>
(and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three Brave Men</ENAMEX> , based on a book about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Abe</ENAMEX>, who's played
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Borgnine</ENAMEX>--straight stuff--you can imagine how we felt), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feathers</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Five</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Easy Pieces</ENAMEX> , and--no kidding, this is as good as it
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">gets-- Six Lessons From Madame La Zonga</ENAMEX> , with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lupe Velez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Errol</ENAMEX>.
It's not that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> is too big a number; climb <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more and you get to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samurai</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six</TIMEX> is simply uninspired, suggesting nothing. It's enough to make
you turn to drink. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Beer</ENAMEX>. With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borgnine</ENAMEX>. An entire <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX>.

            
               The Best-Laid
Family <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planning Oft Goes Astray Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cherie Blair</ENAMEX>'s a picture of happiness yesterday
after news that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> will soon be extended--to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX>
left rivals floundering <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> when we broke the news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Premier</ENAMEX> and
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> are expecting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>."

            The story continues:

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookies</ENAMEX> entered into the spirit of things by
jokingly offering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500-to-1</NUMEX> odds against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> being
named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX> and being born on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s birthday.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Congratulations to the Blairs</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Euan</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicky</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn</ENAMEX>--poured in from around
the world.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hours</ENAMEX> after our stunning scoop, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mrs Blair</ENAMEX> accepted
a bouquet from our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. She paused outside <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">10 Downing Street</ENAMEX>, and smiled:
'Thank you, I'm very well thank you.'

            "Of her reaction to the
pregnancy, she said: 'It was a real surprise.' <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX> killjoys struck a sour note
by calling the timing of the announcement a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labour</ENAMEX> stunt."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Spiegel</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riding Derails Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            "After reading your
wrap-up I've come to the conclusion that you don't ride <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> very much and
that you're getting your train perceptions from old movies. Or you do ride
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX>--just not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> I'm always on. You see on 'My <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX>' (sort of like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cosby</ENAMEX>'s 'My <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>'), if it's 'only' <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">35 minutes</TIMEX> late, hey, we're
making good time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>!"

            I was thinking of those
high-speed maglev <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> that whisk you swiftly and safely to your destination
while you have intense encounters with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Davis</ENAMEX>. Are you saying they're still
on the drawing board?-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker Cartoon Contest Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            The "Back Page" of the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cartoon</ENAMEX>" issue features a wacky contest: Write a caption for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Ziegler</ENAMEX>
drawing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> on her front porch shouting something about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the
suit struggling up the path with a huge globe on his shoulders. (For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
who have never seen a cartoon and don't know how a caption works, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>
explain that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> forgot the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX>!" would be one possibility.)

            Here are some nearly
winning entries:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> forgot the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pokémon</ENAMEX> cards!

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> forgot the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> book!

               Looks like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> gave the wrong final answer!

               OK, maybe the world is enough.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mom</ENAMEX>, this probably isn't <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Seinfeld</ENAMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mom</ENAMEX>, look what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> bought on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX>!

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mom</ENAMEX>, a homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> threw a huge globe at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>!

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>'s home! I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dads.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> replaced the continents with poorly rendered squiggly shapes.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mom</ENAMEX>, why is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> stealing contest ideas from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickelodeon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>?

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Test: The Secret History of the American Meritocracy</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lemann</ENAMEX>. Oh, wait, that's my entry for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s other contest.

               I don't care how much funnier your caption is, we're using <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX>'s
entry and that's final.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>'s really gonna need a blow job tonight!

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pol resigns</ENAMEX> after sex scandal.

         
      
   
