
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Empty Jocks</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> of history's greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> headlined a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Square Garden</ENAMEX> fund-raiser for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Knicks</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teammates Dick Barnett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave DeBusschere</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt Frazier</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Lucas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monroe</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis Reed</ENAMEX> sang <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s praises, as did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kareem Abdul-Jabbar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
Cousy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius Erving</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Havlicek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses Malone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Robertson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Walton</ENAMEX>. The event, complete with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheerleaders</ENAMEX>, movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>,
and lights and music reminiscent of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> game, enthralled the press. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Throws Garden Party</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scores</ENAMEX>," whooped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has pitched himself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> in a world corrupted by
glitz. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> put it at the gala, "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> of spin control, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is one of the most honest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I've ever met." So it's worth asking
whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX>' media blitz for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, punctuated by their full-court
press on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s political talk shows, conveyed anything of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>. The
question posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX>--"Why do former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX>
support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>?"--raises a prior question: Why should we
care?

            On the
talk shows, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> testified that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is "intelligent,"
"knowledgeable," "well-rounded," "compassionate," "concerned," "wonderful," "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>," "a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listener</ENAMEX>," and "a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>." They applauded his
"honesty," "integrity," "respect," and "quiet strength." They recalled that he
"played very hard," "played by the rules," and "was always interested in the
needs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." They asserted that he "loves his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>" and seeks "the good
of as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as possible."

            These
platitudes are probably true. But why did they dominate the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>? What light do they shed on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s presidential
competence or agenda? On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeBusschere</ENAMEX> argued that the
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> "know [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>] as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>" and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> should "listen to what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> have to say about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that they all respect and have known very
well." That explanation, however, turns out not to be true of many of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erving</ENAMEX> conceded that he had never played
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and knew little about him until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cousy</ENAMEX> told the same
story: "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I jumped on board the minute the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> called. … I didn't
have a personal relationship."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX> who knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> failed to name anything he had
accomplished in politics. Nevertheless, they praised his political career.
"He's had good leadership qualities as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX>. DeBusschere
agreed: "He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. He was when he <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> came into the political scene. …
He was going to study and learn … and I think he's done that." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> added,
"He's had some experience in national politics. And then he got away for a
while … which is sometimes very helpful." Again, how do the assertions of
former <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> clarify this question? Unable to produce evidence,
they extrapolated from sports to politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> believed in "passing and
getting other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved in the game," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX> argued on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> .
"That's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s about, and what he'd do in his politics: getting everybody
involved in the game."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX> were plainly ignorant of the issues. "Old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX> don't know a lot about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> solutions or campaign-finance reform and all,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confessed Cousy</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Schieffer</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erving</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J</ENAMEX>, since you're the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> here, I guess I ought to ask you about health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>." The question sounded like a joke, but it wasn't, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erving</ENAMEX> answered it.
"I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s position," he replied, citing "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s health care
plan, which I got a chance to read <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s campaign has been long on sentiment and short on solutions. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>' testimonials did nothing to remedy that deficit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">DeBusschere</ENAMEX> praised
him for "caring and going out and saying things and doing things about" race
relations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> called for racial "enlightenment" and predicted, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> will try
to make that happen." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Los Angeles Lakers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Jackson</ENAMEX> observed, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Skin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX> is an immediate reaction to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and this is something that we have to
overcome. This is something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> sees." Cousy boasted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> "makes human
rights a cornerstone, really, in terms of his priorities … All those problems
stem, obviously, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s inhumanity to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. … So I'm happy to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
focusing on, you know, just getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to get along together on a domestic
and a worldwide level."

            Cousy
argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock advocates</ENAMEX> should be taken seriously because they're
"concerned about issues" and unencumbered by the "baggage" of immorality that
disqualifies many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity athletes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley "</ENAMEX>has been very selective in terms
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> that he has asked to jump on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cousy</ENAMEX>. "If we're
all pretty good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and we've lived our lives properly, then, hey, why don't
you listen to us in this case and vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>?" No doubt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cousy</ENAMEX> has
lived his life properly. So have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. And they don't get on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX> .

            
Stripped of their rationalizations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX> fall back on the argument
that their opinions are important simply because they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>. "Look at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is all about," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX> argued. "Basketball is
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s game. … <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> come to games to see these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> play. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Stars</ENAMEX> have such
influence on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. And it's just apropos for me to be here to say
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who can generalize all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> together." On
Late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edition</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> said of his basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pals</ENAMEX>, "Why wouldn't you
reach out to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>? … I'd be stupid if I didn't do that."

            If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX> don't know why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> should be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, why are they endorsing him?
Because they think their association with him helps their image as well as his.
"Not too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhodes Scholars</ENAMEX>," observed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cousy</ENAMEX>, arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>
"personifies" the virtues of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> sports. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty years ago</TIMEX>, everybody was a
dumb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock</ENAMEX> who played sports," sniffed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeBusschere</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, I think, has proven …
that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> are very intelligent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and that type of stigma attached to you is not worthy."

            But
are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX> serving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> well? At best, they're helping him exploit the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">superficial</ENAMEX>, elitist politics he claims to be campaigning against. That's what
happened on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russert</ENAMEX>, after hosting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX>
for much of the show, explained the absence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> representative by
reporting, "We asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> campaign to provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> who would
support him. They declined."

            At worst, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hurting Bradley</ENAMEX> by failing to comprehend and refute misrepresentations of his
agenda. That's what happened on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> , where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Brazile</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> of endangering "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> and all
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>" by trying to "eliminate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>." What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
needed was a policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> who could block <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brazile</ENAMEX>'s cheap shot. Instead, the
task of defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> fell to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erving</ENAMEX>, who shrugged that "it's probably a
debatable issue, but knowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, he is, you know, the type of
individual who has always been fair." With that response, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erving</ENAMEX> negated his
layup for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> by yielding a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-pointer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brazile</ENAMEX>. That's the problem
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. They can score, but they can't play D.

         
      
   
