
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">339</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bird in Hand</ENAMEX>" 

            
               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 6</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> opened crates and pulled out pheasants, then, holding them
by the legs, spun the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> around to make them dizzy; this is one feature of a
program whose uneasy combination of private and state funding is drawing
increasing criticism nationwide. What is the program called?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">338</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super</ENAMEX>-standard":
            

            

               In part to accommodate older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, federal standards now mandate that
new ones be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 inches</NUMEX> tall--2 inches taller than the old ones. New
what?
            

            "The
type size of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kervorkian</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX> number in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellow Pages</ENAMEX> ad."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Koegel
            

            "The
wheelchair ramp that leads directly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Nicole Smith</ENAMEX>'s bed."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotchkiss</ENAMEX> (You see, she likes old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiny</ENAMEX>,
yapping <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Dickinson</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Curbs</ENAMEX>. Oh, the fun we'll have watching geezers struggle to get out of the
street before the light changes!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Hammett</ENAMEX>
            

            "Those
old <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4-inch</NUMEX> magic elves were completely useless for anything except making
shoes."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Among many native
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peoples</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> are cherished and respected for their funny smell. That's
what I learned in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthropology</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> who had to be at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110</NUMEX>,
kept on the job by tenure and a network of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teflon</ENAMEX> tubing that functioned much
like an actual large intestine. Who can blame him for lying to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gullible</ENAMEX>
young? He had every reason to be angry: Old age is an unforgivable insult.
Consider the sex lives of older <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. (As did most quiz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, with
disturbing vividness.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> are damned if they do and damned if they
don't; damned and mocked if they can't; and damned, mocked, and pointed out by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> if they can but only with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pharmacological aids</ENAMEX> or an elaborate
arrangement of winches and pulleys. The sad fact of an extended life span is
that you get those extra <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> tacked on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the end</TIMEX>, extending your frailty and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">neglect</ENAMEX>, not added to your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20s</TIMEX>, extending your time in ersatz anthropology
classes. The other horrifying consequence of a greatly extended life
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">span</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX>'s ass. Thank you! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> to be back!

            
               Big Answer
            

            New standards specify <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6-inch</NUMEX> letters on street
signs so elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> can read them.

            "They're just a lot easier to see," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerard</ENAMEX>, highway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superintendent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifton Park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, where they've begun
switching to the new signs at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> a pop each time an old one must be

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Highway</ENAMEX>
Administration predicts that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2020</TIMEX>--and I know a cheap joke when I see it,
especially from some smarty-pants highway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX>--one out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 or older</TIMEX>. And damn mad about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday Shopping</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Every commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> makes assumptions about
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. Judging by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WIRELESS</ENAMEX> , a catalog for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of
public radio, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> can quit worrying. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX> are bland, white,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Midwestern</ENAMEX>, and very, very old--more likely to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> than to man
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">barricades</ENAMEX>. (Assuming that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">at least 6 inches</NUMEX> high.) Below, some
actual sample products.

            

               RADIO-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONTROL MOUSE</ENAMEX>: "gets even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">laziest cat</ENAMEX> on the prowl."-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">At last</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX> has taken the drudgery out of playing with your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">kitty</ENAMEX> and reduced the
risk of breaking your hip.
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HANDY GIFT FOR</ENAMEX> A HANDYMAN: "a collection of reproduction nails and the
history behind them."-- The energy you save by not playing with your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>, you
can save all over again with these pre-collected nails.
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BASS FISHING MONOPOLY; GOLF MONOPOLY</ENAMEX>-- coming soon, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Substandard Nursing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Monopoly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constant Joint Pain Monopoly</ENAMEX>, Gradual Loss of Memory
Monopoly.
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SHIRTS WITH FUNNY SLOGANS</ENAMEX>-- the greatest affront of all to the dignity of
older <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, including the following:
When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Did My Wild Oats Turn Into Shredded Wheat</ENAMEX>
In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dog Years</ENAMEX>, I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead</ENAMEX>
As Bad as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kids</ENAMEX>
This <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shirt Condescends to Me</ENAMEX>
Please <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Treat Me Like an Enfeebled Old</ENAMEX> Drooler
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Above Two Don't Actually Exist</ENAMEX>
Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Does That One or This</ENAMEX>


               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BERNADETTE PETERS IN CONCERT VIDEO</ENAMEX>: "sings, sashays, and shimmers through
her favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> songs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">…This</ENAMEX> is your chance to experience her famed pig
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> rendition of 'We're in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money</ENAMEX>.' "-- as good an argument as you'll
ever see for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Right To Die</ENAMEX>. Ustjay ootay utecay orfay ordsway.
               

            

            Read more about it at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wirelesstoo</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
if you dare.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Cloutier</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Right-On</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chant Against Submarine Service Sexism Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            (See you all at the big demo.)

            Foggo

            Froggo

            Hoggo

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gog</ENAMEX> and Magoggo

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foggo Foggo</ENAMEX>, looks like a Doggo!

            Leggo my Foggo

            Troggolodyte

            Faggo

            Fucko

            Groggo Noggin

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            That crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>. It's wild. And funny. Like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chaucer</ENAMEX>. And his enormous yet embarrassing penis.

         
      
   
