
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fireless Chat</ENAMEX>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WASHINGTON</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>--History records that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> telephone conversation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1876</TIMEX>
was an urgent request for an in-person meeting. "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watson</ENAMEX>, come here, I want
you," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Graham Bell</ENAMEX> is supposed to have said to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> in the
next <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> participated in what was billed as the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> presidential Internet chat, an event intended to showcase another
epoch-making technology in a larval stage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was more patient than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>.
He resisted the urge to say what must have been on the mind of nearly everyone
present at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the 90-minute</TIMEX> demonstration: Why don't we turn this damn thing off
and have a real conversation?

            The
idea for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Town Hall</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chat</ENAMEX>, co-sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Leadership Council</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excite</ENAMEX>, was to
demonstrate how the Net enables new forms of democratic communication. Here's
how it worked: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sat onstage in a small auditorium at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX>
University accompanied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al From</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DLC</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From</ENAMEX>
had a screen in front of them. From read aloud questions sent in by e-mail, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> answered. Also wired in to the session were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> other government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in remote locations around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Andreessen</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>. In theory, virtual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> could watch streaming
video of the event, listen to an audio simulcast, or watch a scrolling text
transcription, all over the Internet.

            In
practice, the technology was pretty clunky. Due to "network congestion," the
voices of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> didn't come through at all, and others were
either time-delayed or so distorted as to be barely audible. At times, the town
hall dissolved into a series of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hello Watson</ENAMEX>, can you hear me?" exchanges.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> read his prepared opening remarks (in which he compared the event to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>'s fireside chats) from a teleprompter. If you were watching this on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>, the herky-jerky streaming video of his head and torso represented a
giant leap backward from the straightforward TV broadcast on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX>. And the
scrolling text, which was transcribed not by voice-recognition software but by
human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX>, was hardly a high-tech marvel. The overall effect was that
of primitive video-conferencing. In a way, it made you marvel at how far we
haven't come since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>'s day.

            When
the technology did work as intended, it merely made you wonder what good it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anyhow</ENAMEX>. Having a meeting over the Internet is still like walking to the mailbox
in a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spacesuit</ENAMEX>. That it can be done--impressive. But why do it at all,
given that the quality of the interaction is so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX>? As in all Internet
"events" I've ever seen or participated in, the time lags and unfamiliarity of
the basic structure sucked any spontaneity and most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> from the
room.

            Part
of the fault was not technical but human and political. In theory, the Internet
allows for a vast range of queries from far and wide. In practice, questions
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> were so carefully vetted as to be far narrower in range than
what he might have encountered from a small, homogenous, and friendly audience
like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>. The questions were in fact, triple-screened: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, which weeded out anything with the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica</ENAMEX>" in it, then
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DLC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, with a bias toward <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>, and finally by From, who choose
from among those culled for him. The messages that got passed on to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
were wonky and sincere, dealing in an unchallenging way with matters like free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> and health care. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the few sparks of interest was a question about
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, if he didn't live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, would put aside <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for
a possible Y2K catastrophe. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> said he wouldn't, because he doesn't
anticipate any serious problems.

            Before
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was pointing at questions drifting by on his screen, begging for
more difficult ones. The event might have worked slightly better if he had been
given a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> to flag questions he wanted to answer or a keyboard to send
messages back to the control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. But this too would have risked
embarrassment, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is an acknowledged computer illiterate and can't
type. Nonetheless, he does appear to have gained a sense of how the Internet
might someday be democratically useful. In his closing remarks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made a
point about how isolated a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> can become from the public despite his
best intentions to keep in touch and how the new technology might help. Then he
thanked everyone for coming to his "press conference."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is right that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, , will have a real tool to maintain
contact with ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. It's too late for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> himself. He could have
learned how to use a computer, of course, but I don't think electronic politics
holds any appeal for him. You can't seduce a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> in an e-mail message. To
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the political is the interpersonal: the hand on the shoulder, the
intent gaze, the fleck of spittle in the eye. Even on television, he can
provide a simulacrum of this human experience. But on the Internet,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> is far more abstract. E-mail bores him--and it showed. The most
interesting part of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s event was what happened after it ended, when
you got to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> doing what he does like no one else, schmoozing live
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. I eavesdropped as he massaged the ego of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Jermoluk</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excite</ENAMEX>. "I know this may have cost you arm and a leg, but I think you may have
revolutionized politics," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> confided to him.

            At the end of unsuccessful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cyber</ENAMEX>-events, everyone always praises them as "historic." Perhaps so, though I
think history will remember them as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fumbling</ENAMEX> experiments that pointed in a
different direction. At this point, they testify mainly to the capacity of the
Internet to take something interesting--like a discussion with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--and make it unbearably dull. But be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years or so</TIMEX>,
advances in technology may get us to the point where an Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Town Meeting</ENAMEX>
is almost as interesting as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Town Meeting</ENAMEX> without the Internet.

         
      
   
