
   
   
      
         
            Can the Net <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Save McCain</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>?

            NEW
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">YORK</ENAMEX>--Judging from recent opinion polls, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, is a
significant threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> in
the crucial first primary state of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s standing in opinion polls is, at the moment,
irrelevant--because it's not clear that he will be on the ballot for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 7</TIMEX> primary. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> faces an uphill battle in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire State</ENAMEX> for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> important reasons: Getting on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s ballot is a notoriously difficult
and time-consuming task requiring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of petition signatures from all
over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and the bulk of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> is backing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> campaign is betting that it has a secret weapon: the
Internet. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net</ENAMEX> is playing a big role in mobilizing our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> around the
state," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry O'Brien</ENAMEX>, political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s New York
campaign.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> campaign has actually had an active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> for only a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, and it is in the relatively isolated location of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Staten Island</ENAMEX>, the
smallest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> boroughs. Nonetheless, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">national</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
campaign has been organizing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> via the
Internet.

            
Perhaps alone among the major presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s campaign has a
multi-site strategy. The national campaign has a main Web site, and there is
also an "interactive" site. The latter features <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> targeted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>,
although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> campaign says it will "go national" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> for now it
aims at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>.

            
Residents of those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> can sign up with the campaign based on a map of
congressional districts, as well as get daily information about campaign
appearances in their area. (Clicking on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 2</TIMEX>, for example,
shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> will be appearing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Hampton Town Hall</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX>
and will then be at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WMUR Presidential Forum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manchester</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>)
Allowing potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> to register by congressional district gives the
local campaigns very targeted databases.

            The
interactive campaign site was designed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">VirtualSprockets</ENAMEX>. They
use the programming language <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ColdFusion</ENAMEX>, which is known for e-mail integration.
The campaign paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few thousand dollars</NUMEX> for the initial setup fee and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX>
per tailored-state setup. The low cost is important for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s effort,
because the campaign is focusing the bulk of its advertising dollars on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">do-or-die New Hampshire</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 1</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19</TIMEX>) primaries.

            "In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, presidential Web sites were more or less Web billboards," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Fose</ENAMEX>,
who runs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s national Web site. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, we are not only allowing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to find out about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> but trying to push <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to be
involved."

            Hence,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Brien</ENAMEX> says, when he set up shop in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> from the national campaign, he
received a database of "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple thousand</NUMEX>" e-mail addresses. That was crucial
because, with the regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, the New York
campaign needed to reach out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've not necessarily been <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
petition-gatherers before--and thus aren't on anyone's mailing or phone
lists.

            "We've
had to reach out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX>, college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, and civic types," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Brien</ENAMEX>.
"The Internet has been a tremendous asset to us, the overwhelming majority of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that will end up being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> [from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>] came to us
through the Internet."

            Will they succeed? Well,
the time allotted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> for gathering petition signatures runs between
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 30 and Jan. 6</TIMEX>. "We already qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay Ridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, and Staten
Island in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Brien</ENAMEX> hopefully.

         
      
   
