
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">348</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Whose Deal?</ENAMEX>"

            
               "These are the big
cards we still have to play. Beyond that, I think that, frankly, the likelihood
of success is quite small." Who said this about what desperate effort to save
what precarious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX>?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 347</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chillin' ":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Complete this expression of amazement from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Collins</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health</ENAMEX>, "I don't often pick up a scientific paper and
find myself getting chills, as I did when I saw _______________."
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matilda Krim</ENAMEX>'s semi-nude 'Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX>' photo spread."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
Amoros
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EEG</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Dickinson</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Booty Call</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Werthmann</ENAMEX>
            

            "Two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lab animals</ENAMEX> copulating frenziedly, unaware of the death that awaited
them."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Gerber</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mailer Daemon</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Critical Path</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Staples</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            To thoughtful quiz
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> (thoughtful in the sense of "acutely thinking," not in the sense
of "considerately sending a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> gift to the quiz wrangler whose shirt size
is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15/34</NUMEX> and whose liquor size is one liter), chills can be induced by both
fear and joy, particularly erotic joy. That the first sort of chill is easily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transmuted</ENAMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> may explain why scary movies are popular date-night
entertainment: To be scared is a short step from being sexually aroused. (Hold
me!) This theory goes a long way to explain vampire movies, which are both; and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX> movies about inspirational music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, which are neither. It
may also be that any intense emotion can be transformed into any other, which
is why the best part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breakin</ENAMEX>' up can indeed be makin' up, and why a
passionate quarrel can culminate in a yet more passionate reconciliation. It
may also explain the expression "scared stiff" (in the sense of tumescent, not
in the sense of immobilized by drunken overindulgence in a gift bottle of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bourbon</ENAMEX> that one never received). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happy Hanukkah</ENAMEX>, everybody!

            
               Golly Genome
Answer
            

            "I don't often pick up a scientific paper and find
myself getting chills, as I did when I saw this whole chromosomal
landscape ."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> was reacting to an account of the first
sequencing of a human chromosome, No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>, described in the current issue of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>.

            An international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> of university centers
took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> to achieve this milestone in the human genome project, whose goal
is to decipher all human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. Although it is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> smallest of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> pairs of human chromosomes, No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43 million</NUMEX> units of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, of
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> have decoded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33.5 million</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> has identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">535</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000 or so</NUMEX> thought to be on No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>. The total number of human genes is
estimated at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 60,000 and 120,000</NUMEX>.

            The genome sequence is
posted at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genome</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ou</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">edu/Chr22.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">html</ENAMEX>.

            
               Left <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Over Ought To Be</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biographies Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were asked for the title of
a much-needed but unwritten autobiography of any national political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>.
Unfortunately, a series of foul-ups from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shining Path,</ENAMEX> 
                  Slate
               's
worthless e-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>, prevented many replies from getting through. Near as
I can tell, e-mail service to the quiz remains shaky, but many amusing
responses about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> and that attack rabbit are just now trickling
in, so look for those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>. In the meantime, a few more campaign bios:

            

               "Being There: The autobiography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Faith of My Political Handlers</ENAMEX> , also by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W."</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dearest</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris Jackson</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, ghostwritten by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX>, titled<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, Bitch Set Me</ENAMEX>
Up! "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J. Basial</ENAMEX>
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Copperfield</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Biden</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zick Rubin</ENAMEX>
               

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Sex, death, and unreliable e-mail service<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: Aren't</ENAMEX>
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>'s big themes?

         
      
   
