
   
   
      
         
             Know <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">When To Hold 'Em, Know When To Log Off</ENAMEX>

            Hurry! Don't miss your big chance to lose your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in a game of craps. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bills</ENAMEX> are afoot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to
outlaw
online gambling before it really takes root. Though rapidly changing
technology and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freebooters</ENAMEX> who run offshore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> will likely stymie any
new legislation, that won't stop the feds from trying. So, if you're interested
in online gaming and/or wanton self-destruction, deal yourself in before it's
too late.

            Or watch me instead. I
don't have a ton of gamble in me, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> phrase goes, but I have a very
soft spot for a challenging game of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>. I also imagine that I know a lot
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> sports, and I enjoy controlled risk-taking. In short, your average,
fairly well-informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX>. So come along, as I demonstrate how to lose scads
of money in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> easy steps, without leaving my desk chair or deriving any sort
of tangible return.

            
               Step <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">showgirlscasino</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
            

            With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 600</NUMEX> gambling sites on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> and new
ones launching <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, it's tough to decide where to burn your cash. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Online</ENAMEX>
gambling is banned on a state-by-state basis, so check with your local cops
before taking the plunge.) No comprehensive guide to online gaming exists, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> that publish casino reviews take ads from those same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Reports</ENAMEX> , where are you?

            I happen upon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showgirls Casino</ENAMEX>, which, unlike many
other sites <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) requires no software download to play its games, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) posts
its odds (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">97.8 percent</NUMEX> payback on slots, which is great--the average slot
payout on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> strip is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95.7 percent</NUMEX>). In the standard routine, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showgirls</ENAMEX>
has you deposit funds with a separate e-commerce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX>; then you draw on that
account to buy virtual chips at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX>. Tapping the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> I started with, I
set up a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> account with my credit card. Once I started, there isn't much
difference from a real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pros</ENAMEX>: No destitute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hustlers</ENAMEX> lurking about
(unless you count my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>), and I didn't have to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cons</ENAMEX>: No
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocktail waitresses</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> applet is no competition for a blackjack
table's perfect green felt. It's a trade-off--you may love the privacy and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convenience</ENAMEX>, you may miss the ambience.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Showgirls</ENAMEX> (based in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dominican Republic</ENAMEX>) offers
all the usual games--craps, roulette, etc. I immediately lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX> in video
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> (if you play, learn the strategy). Then I lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX> in roulette and
another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX> on the slots. Bam--down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> clams in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Click,</ENAMEX> click,
broke. How quick and painless money-losing can be when it's all just numbers on
a screen. A session of blackjack gouges <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 more</NUMEX> (counting cards is useless
here as the deck reshuffles after every hand). After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>, I staunch the
bleeding and ask them to mail me my remaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX>. The site promises a
check in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>.

            
               Net so far:
-<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$120</NUMEX>.
            

            
               Step <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slotland</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
            

            Most online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> offer the same games and the
same software. Slotland distinguishes itself with the lowest-budget design on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>. Also, it posts no odds. I buy in for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> and get a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> first-time
bonus for registering (most sites do this). After losing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX> on the slots, I
withdraw my whole account--at a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> profit! Then I go back in and deposit
another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>, only to double my money on a single pull. (By the way, on wins of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">75 cents</NUMEX> or more, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slotland</ENAMEX> offers a link to a cheesy erotic photo.) For
bare-bones gaming, this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">place</ENAMEX> will do the trick.

            
               Net so far: -<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$92</NUMEX>,
though I'm still waiting for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slotland</ENAMEX> check, too.
            

            
               Step <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX>i-sportsbook.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
            

            Because sports betting is illegal everywhere but
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, I predict that online sports betting will become big. My friend
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glazer</ENAMEX> , a pro gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>, says some sites cancel your sports bets
if they think you're too good or if they figure out that you gamble for a
living. (Many online <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> just plain stiff their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> for no reason.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>'s advice: If you must wager on sports, go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> or stick with your
neighborhood bookie--he's probably more reputable, if more clearly illegal. If
you do go online, use an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> site, as they're the best regulated.

            Throwing caution to the wind, I try i-Sportsbook
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Antigua</ENAMEX>, because it provides the easiest interface for my credit card
deposit. I put <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Patriots</ENAMEX> as a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX>-point <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$50</ENAMEX>
on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Red Sox</ENAMEX> playoff game against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland Indians</ENAMEX>. I win both
bets, scoring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX> samoleans. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pats</ENAMEX> lose but cover the spread (they only lost
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, and the odds-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> spotted them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> points). My beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sox</ENAMEX> beat the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX>, i-Sportsbook refunds my credit card deposit, as
promised, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week later</TIMEX> I get a check for my winnings. Quite straightforward
and trustworthy, but I was making miniscule, unthreatening bets.

            Sports aren't the only events to bet on at these
sites. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> offers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6-to-5</NUMEX> odds to win the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> (bet <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> and, if
you win, get back that fiver plus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $6</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> to win, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>-2 (bet <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX> to win <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX>). You can also bet on the outcome of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial, or whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX> will <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OD</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1, 2000</TIMEX>.

            
               Net so far: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32</NUMEX> in the
black!
            

            
               Step <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, in which
unfortunate things happen: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">planetpoker</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
            

            Your best bet in any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> is at the poker
tables--real <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>, not video <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>--because you play a game of skill against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shmoes</ENAMEX> like yourself, not a game of mathematical chance against a machine or a
deck of cards. The more poker skill you acquire, the better your odds. At a
meatspace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> or a virtual <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> makes its money by taking a small
percentage rake from each poker pot, or renting the seats by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hour</TIMEX>. There
aren't a lot of live <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> games on the Web, but unhappily, I found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            All the live poker sites I visited--<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">purepoker</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, deltapoker.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>--require a download of the same software. I
decide on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PlanetPoker</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Caro</ENAMEX>, a pro <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> whom I've met
and like, endorses it. I put <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> in my account with ease, but when I try to
play I get an error message about being unable to link up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planet Poker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">server</ENAMEX>. This error message appears on a few different computers hooked up to a
few different corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> that I try, making me think that the network
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> have configured their "firewalls" to disable these games. I
succeed in connecting to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PlanetPoker</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> when I borrow a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s laptop and
connect through his Internet service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>.

            Once in the poker <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, you scan the virtual tables
for empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">seats</ENAMEX>, and click to sit down or to join the waiting list. After a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45-minute</TIMEX> wait, I still can't find a chair for the low-stakes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> Hold 'Em
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">game</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 and $6</NUMEX> bets, pots around <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> or so). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Impatient</ENAMEX>, I jump into a
higher-stakes game (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 and $10</NUMEX> bets, pots more like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>), which turns out to
be a horrible idea. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> are much better than the low-stakes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and take my money in a hurry. The playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">interface</ENAMEX> is smooth and
simple, popping up your options to fold, call, or raise when it's your turn.
But not only does my Web connection fail in the middle of one hand (if this
happens, the game assumes you have called the bet, then kicks you off the table
when the hand ends), I flat get beat when I risk any chips. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Players</ENAMEX> with
handles like "nineball" and "fatso" just outplay me. On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> tough hand that
lost me <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX>, I was pretty confident with my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> jacks--only to see "sleepy"
make a gutshot straight on the last card to whup my trips and steal my chips. I
lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> worth in under an hour, but I love the challenge. Of all the online
games, this is the one I could get frighteningly into. (Though in the future
I'll stick with the low-stakes games.)

            The drawbacks of live online <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>? You can't read
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bluffs</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>' trembling fingers and bobbing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX>. The only
guaranteed way to get a bead on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> is to watch for betting patterns to
emerge. Another thing about these games that makes me nervous is that two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in cahoots at adjacent computers could rig the table, playing in tandem
and driving up the bets when they know they've got the hand won. Finally, it's
hard to gauge the competition. With the online anonymity, for all I know I was
playing against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hellmuth Jr.</ENAMEX> But the game seemed fair, and I was simply
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overmatched</ENAMEX>.

            
               Final net: -<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$118</NUMEX>,
though I'm still waiting on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Showgirls</ENAMEX> check, and as for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slotland</ENAMEX> check,
no, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s e-mail confirmation of my withdrawal did not convince me that
it's actually on the way.
            

            
               Conclusion
            

            Online gambling is here, probably to stay, and it's
going to be unfathomably big. If you think video poker at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> is "," wait
till you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> feed their paychecks into online slots from their
desks. Depending on what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you are, this may mean you should 1)
establish an offshore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Antilles</ENAMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>
cracks down, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) wait for this stuff to shake itself out before you blow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>
bucks playing Web roulette. As long as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> are <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a few hours</TIMEX>
away, giving your credit card number to a distant and foreign Internet
operation might not be worth the risk. If you do log on, though, perhaps I'll
see you at the virtual Hold 'Em table. My handle is "seth."

         
      
   
