
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Enemies</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>

            If a picture is worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> words, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-page
spread in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , featuring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a dozen</NUMEX> pictures, can
speak volumes. And sure enough, the lavish <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 15</TIMEX> advertisement by the Turning
Point Project, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> opposed to globalization in general and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX> in particular, said more than any merely verbal
exposition about what really motivates those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> could. Indeed, it
revealed quite a bit more than its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> intended.

            The occasion for the ad
was the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> "ministerial" taking place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> has become to leftist mythology what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> is to the militia
movement: the center of a global conspiracy against all that is good and
decent. According to the myth, the "ultra-secretive" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> has become a sort of
super-governmental body that forces <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> to bow to the wishes of
multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. It destroys local cultures, the headline on the ad
read "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Global Monoculture</ENAMEX>"; it despoils the environment; and it rides roughshod
over democracy, forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to remove laws that conflict with its
sinister purposes.

            Like most successful urban legends, this one is based on a
sliver of truth. The gradual global progress toward free trade that began in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1930s</NUMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX> introduced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade Agreements Program</ENAMEX>, has
always depended on international negotiations: I'll reduce my tariffs if you
reduce yours. But there has always been the problem of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> that give
with one hand and take away with the other, that dutifully remove tariffs and
then use other excuses to keep imports out. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Certainement</ENAMEX> , there is free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, but those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>, they are not safe.) To
make agreements work there has to be some kind of quasi-judicial process that
determines when ostensibly domestic measures are de facto a reimposition of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> barriers and hence a violation of treaty. Under the pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade</ENAMEX>, this process was slow and cumbersome.
It has now become swifter and more decisive. Inevitably, some of its decisions
can be challenged: Was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ban on dolphin-unsafe tuna really a trade
barrier in disguise? But the much-feared power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> to overrule local
laws is strictly limited to enforcement of the spirit of existing agreements.
It cannot in any important way force <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that are skeptical about the
benefits of globalization to open themselves further to foreign trade and
investment. If most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> nonetheless are eager or at least willing to
participate in globalization, it is because they are convinced that it is in
their own interests.

            And by and large they are
right. The raw fact is that every successful example of economic development
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past century</TIMEX>--every case of a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> that worked its way up to a more
or less decent, or at least dramatically better, standard of living--has taken
place via globalization; that is, by producing for the world market rather than
trying for self-sufficiency. Many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who do that production for the
global market are very badly paid by First World standards. But to claim that
they have been impoverished by globalization, you have to carefully ignore
comparisons across time and space--namely, you have to forget that those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> were even poorer before the new exporting jobs became available and
ignore the fact that those who do not have access to the global market are far
worse off than those who do. (See my old 
                  Slate
                piece ".")  The
financial crisis of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997-99</TIMEX> temporarily gave those who claim that globalization
is bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> everywhere a bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ammunition</ENAMEX>, but the crisis did not go on
forever, and anyway the solution to future crises surely involves some policing
of short-term capital movements rather than a retreat from globalization as a
whole. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysians</ENAMEX> continue to welcome long-term foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and
place their faith on manufactured exports.

            What about the environment? Certainly some forests have
been cut down to feed global markets. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> that are heedless of the
environment are quite capable of doing immense damage without the help of
multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>--just ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eastern Europeans</ENAMEX>. For what it is
worth, the most conspicuous examples of environmental pillage in the Third
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> have nothing to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>. The forest fires that envelop
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> in an annual smoke cloud are set by land-hungry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>; the
subsidized destruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Amazonian</ENAMEX> rain forests began as part of a Brazilian
strategy of inward-looking development. On the whole, integration of the world
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>, which puts national actions under international scrutiny, is probably
on balance a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> toward better, not worse, environmental policies.

            But anyway, these are side issues, because what
that advertisement makes clear--clearer, I suspect, than its sponsors
intended--is that the opposition to globalization actually has very little to
do with wages or the environment. After all, leaving aside a photo of tree
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stumps</ENAMEX> and another of an outfall pipe, here are the horrors of globalization
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Turning Point</ENAMEX> Project chose to illustrate:

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> interchange, a parking lot filled with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, a traffic jam, suburban tract housing, an apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> with
numerous satellite dishes, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> with many computer screens, office workers
on a busy street, high-rise office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, a "factory <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>" with many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>, a supermarket aisle, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch</ENAMEX>.

            Each picture was
accompanied by a caption asking, "Is this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>?" "Is this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>?" etc.

            What is so horrible about these scenes? Here's what the ad
says, "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few decades ago</TIMEX>, it was still possible to leave home and go somewhere
else: The architecture was different, the landscape was different, the
language, dress, and values were different. That was a time when we could speak
of cultural diversity. But with economic globalization, diversity is fast
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disappearing</ENAMEX>."

            You can't argue with that; lives there the tourist
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> so dead that he does not wish that he could visit rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX>, or for that matter <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX> the way they were, rather than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> they are? But the world is not run for the edification of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. It is
or should be run for the benefit of ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> lives. And
that is where the indignation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Turning Point</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> starts to seem rather
strange.

            For surely the most
striking thing about the horrors of globalization illustrated in those photos
is that for most of the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they represent aspirations, things they
wish they had, rather than ominous threats. Traffic jams and ugly interchanges
are annoying, but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would gladly accept that annoyance in exchange
for the freedom that comes with owning a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> (and more to the point, being
wealthy enough to afford <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>). Tract housing and apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> may be
ugly, but they are paradise compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> huts or urban shanties.
Wearing a suit and working at a computer in an office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> are, believe it or
not, preferable to backbreaking work in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice paddy</ENAMEX>.

            Now, of course what is good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> is not
always good if everyone else does it too. Having a big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with a garden is
nice, but seeing the countryside covered by suburban sprawl is not, and we
might all be better off if we could all agree (or be convinced by tax
incentives) to take up a bit less space. The same goes for cultural choices:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> who indulge their taste for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divas</ENAMEX> do undermine the
prospects of local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer-songwriters</ENAMEX> and might be collectively better off if
local radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> had some kind of cultural content rule. But there is a
very fine line between such arguments for collective action and supercilious
paternalism, especially when cultural matters are concerned; are we warning
societies about unintended consequences or are we simply disagreeing with
individual tastes?

            And it is very clear from the advertisement in the
Times that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Turning Point</ENAMEX> Project--and the whole movement it
represents--are on the supercilious side of that line. Although they talk of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX> and democracy, their key demand is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> be prevented from
getting what they want--that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> be free, nay encouraged, to deny
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> the right to drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, work in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, eat cheeseburgers, and
watch satellite TV. Why? Presumably because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will really be happier if
they retain their traditional "language, dress, and values." Thus, Spaniards
would be happier if they still dressed in black and let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrow-minded priests</ENAMEX>
run their lives, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">American South</ENAMEX> would be happier if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">planters</ENAMEX> still sipped mint juleps, wore white suits, and accepted traditional
deference from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sharecroppers</ENAMEX> ... instead of living in this "dreary" modern
world in which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> is just like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> is just like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.

            Well, somehow I suspect that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, while they may regret some loss of tradition, prefer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modernity</ENAMEX>. And you know what? I think the rest of the world has the right to
make the same choice.

         
      
   
