
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volunteer</ENAMEX>, Dammit!

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virtue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wieseltier</ENAMEX>'s Venom

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               From: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">michael</ENAMEX> berube
            

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Nov</ENAMEX>
21

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kudos to Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> for reading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornel West</ENAMEX> on
his own instead of relying on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Wieseltier</ENAMEX>'s version. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wieseltier</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
essay on "the decline of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>" wasn't really the "devastating
critique" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>'s work that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> once took it to be, and it's relatively
good to hear that although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> had hitherto set his lights by it, he no
longer agrees with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wieseltier</ENAMEX>'s conclusion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>'s work is "almost entirely
worthless."

            The truth is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wieseltier</ENAMEX>'s piece was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shameful</ENAMEX>, spite-ridden hatchet job on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>, motivated almost entirely by the
fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> had been profiled in The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> and
then assessed (along with lesser lights bell hooks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dyson</ENAMEX>) by me in
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1995</TIMEX> essay that likened contemporary black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> to the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the postwar period</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Boynton</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 1995</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX> had pressed the same analogy, by reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelby Steele</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Crouch</ENAMEX>, and the analogy sent all too many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> into frenzies of identity politics and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">territorialism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wieseltier</ENAMEX>'s reaction was the worst, somewhat akin to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">frantic</ENAMEX>, ill-informed denunciation of the essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lionel Trilling</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> in a
recent issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scholar</ENAMEX> .)

            It's true that West can be formulaic, derivative,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clunky</ENAMEX>, and annoyingly self-absorbed (though surely in this last category
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wieseltier</ENAMEX> is more than a match for him). And he really is a mass of
contradictions. But his virtues are considerable nonetheless, and as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>
writes, suit him well for the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX>. This is much more
than can be said for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wieseltier</ENAMEX>, hence the venom of his essay. A tip of the
hat, then, to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>, whose work I've enjoyed often in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--ever since his devastating critique of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> in a fall
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Berube</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life as We Know It</ENAMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Family</ENAMEX>, and an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exceptional Child</ENAMEX> .]

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chekhov</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mon Nov</ENAMEX>
15

            A very lucid analysis. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>, you make fun of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX> references without explaining them. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> has really grappled with
the great plays and found in the lack of a central consciousness (the
protagonists are not mouthpieces for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX>) and refusal to demonize
even the most destructive-seeming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> a hallmark of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
forgiveness. I confess I don't know as much as I should about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theology</ENAMEX> (and I'm not sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX> knew all that much, either), but I do share
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>'s (and many others') view of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX> as a kind of saint of the drama
(albeit a saint with a rarely acute bullshit detector). It's not risible; I
wish all political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> would read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX>.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shapiro</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stump</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               From: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Margolick</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thurs Nov</ENAMEX>
18

            In touting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Shapiro</ENAMEX>'s candidacy for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, you neglected to mention one thing: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> is a seasoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campaigner</ENAMEX>,
having run for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann Arbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>. And more recently he's
done a lot of public speaking, appearing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> comedy-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club circuit</ENAMEX>.
After dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> that tough, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> meetings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Binghampton</ENAMEX> or Utica
would be a breeze.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Margolick</ENAMEX> is a contributing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> .]

            
               Subject: Chatterbox
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandates Volunteerism</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               From: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> Collingwood
            

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed Nov</TIMEX>
10

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX> says he supports requiring high
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">schoolers</ENAMEX> to perform some sort of volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>. If this service is a
required activity, how can it be voluntary?

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox Mandates Volunteerism</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Noah

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed Nov</TIMEX>
10

            Good point. I could argue that you still get to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">volunteer</ENAMEX> (i.e., choose) whichever service you want to provide, but probably I
shouldn't have used the word "volunteer" at all.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Jerry Brown</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               From:

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tarja</ENAMEX> Black
            

            

               Date: Tues <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov 23</TIMEX>

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> carries inside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in which he charged
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> had little interest in campaign finance reform because the current
money-raising system favors <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX>.

               --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
23

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley portrays</ENAMEX> himself as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> of an
insurgent movement fighting for campaign finance reform. But he's more closely
linked to big money than to grassroots. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s unexpected challenge to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is backed by numerous corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">titans</ENAMEX>, especially those from Wall
Street," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Broder</ENAMEX> in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 24</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> piece,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley Relies</ENAMEX> on Wall Street to Raise Funds.")

            In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s
contributions come more often from humble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> like my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. As the
current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> notes:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">trouncing</ENAMEX> challenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> in the battle to collect federal matching
money. In fact, he's on a record-breaking pace. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> matches
donations <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $250</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> allies to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">crow</ENAMEX> that they've
received more small donations than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>.

            

            The biggest contributors
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, at a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> fundraiser here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antelope</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, were my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX> Our check was for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>.

            (To reply, click
here .)

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Own</ENAMEX>
Vote.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com Experiment</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               From: Paddy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tue Nov</ENAMEX>
23

            As an interesting sidebar to your story on
vote.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, I tried it out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>. I am always looking for new ways to improve
the democratic process, and thought, taking into account the caveats in your
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, this sort of thing could work well in my job as communications manager
for a large city council in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>. I couldn't resist voting, even though
I was sure technology would catch me out as I am (a) not an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>,
nor (b) a registered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> voter [refer a].

            I plugged in my e-mail address and the zip code of
some obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and waited for the e-mail reply telling
me to go away. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nope</ENAMEX>. I got a thank-you e-mail too. Does this mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
really is taking over the world and I can now expect my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressperson</ENAMEX> to come
knocking here in good old God zone next election?

            (To reply, click here .)

         
      
   
