
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=350300619-12101999><SPAN class=350300619-12101999><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lazy Susan</ENAMEX></SPAN></SPAN>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pokémon</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Movie</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). Critics
pounce on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pikachu</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pals</ENAMEX>: "God-awful. Bad storytelling. Retrograde
animation ... dark, ominous and pretentious" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Giles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ) …
"an unoriginal warming over of a skimpy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> production … an innocuous, if
lengthy, commercial" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael O'Sullivan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ) … "its
efforts to preach nonviolence while exploiting it are both patronizing and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypocritical</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> ) … "idiotic" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> admit that they're powerless to
influence the target <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> and predict (correctly) that the film will be a
huge hit no matter what they say. (If you need help making sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pokémon</ENAMEX>,
click to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s assessment of the craze in

                  Slate
               .)

            

               
                  Anywhere But Here
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox Film Corp.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarandon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Portman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> as an immature <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and her responsible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who reverse roles when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> decides to move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> and
pursue the life she has always wanted. It's a "touching but melancholy
variation on a tune we've heard many times" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Giles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ), and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> seem a bit tired of the tune. The film is "simpatico enough to make
the less-than-cutting-edge nature" of the work enjoyable (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ), but "it's unfortunate that what we are given is so
standardized and generic" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here to read a review of the best-selling novel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> the film is based on and to read 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>" on
a real-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> from the book.)

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Messenger: The Story of Joan of Arc</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>).The
umpteenth retelling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arc</ENAMEX> story gets a mere <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> swords, er,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stars</ENAMEX>: "The movie is a mess: a gassy costume epic with nobody at the center"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun Times</ENAMEX> ). The supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> may be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">delightful</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX> catching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' eyes, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milla Jovovich</ENAMEX>--who at the time the film was made was married to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luc</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Femme Nikita</ENAMEX> ) Besson--is not quite up to the task of playing a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nuanced</ENAMEX> and thoughtful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to visit a gallery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jovovich</ENAMEX> photos.)

            

               
                  Light It Up
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox Film Corp.</ENAMEX>).Weak reviews
for this film about a group of urban high-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolers</ENAMEX> who take a security guard
hostage after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an accidental</TIMEX> shooting; they end up becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> when they
demand improvements to their run-down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> as conditions of the negotiations.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singer Usher Raymond</ENAMEX> earns praise as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, but the rest of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> goes largely unnoticed. The film achieves "not much more than the
level of a passable TV movie" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ) and "never
quite catches fire" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Koehler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Variety</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for more info on Usher
and here to
visit the official site.)

            

               Book 
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Vidal</ENAMEX>: A Biography
               ,by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Kaplan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doubleday</ENAMEX>).
"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> will be happy with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Kaplan</ENAMEX>'s new book: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Vidal</ENAMEX>,"
writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Deresiewicz</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> . It's a
common note sounded in reviews of this exhaustive authorized biography--namely
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX> simply reports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vidal</ENAMEX>'s version of events without question. Some
wonder if this is a result of having a living subject--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX> doesn't push,
doesn't ask discomfiting questions" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dyer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> )--and note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vidal</ENAMEX> "seems to have been able to exert his
considerable charm, guile, and authority over his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Rubin</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> ). Several also mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX> has been beaten
to the punch by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vidal</ENAMEX> himself, who released his own memoir, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palimpsest</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just three years ago</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chapter.)

         
      
   
