
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">346</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solid Goldberg</ENAMEX>"

            
               While introducing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> dinner <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoopi Goldberg</ENAMEX> recalled a
disturbing question one of her granddaughters recently asked. "This was kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chilling</ENAMEX>, because it wasn't even like I could say, 'No, no, it's not going to
happen.' " What was the question?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">345</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Riotous Assembly With Cheese":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Cheering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> gathered outside a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle McDonald's</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.
Why?
            

            "They
discovered that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> buns and a piece of string make an excellent gas
mask."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Glassenberg</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Fitzpatrick</ENAMEX> and Barb
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leyne</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            "Mayor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCheese</ENAMEX> recanted his support for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Bodow</ENAMEX> (similarly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Reynolds</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Germain</ENAMEX> )

            "In
defiance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>, debut of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 2000</ENAMEX> Happy
Meals."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Leary</ENAMEX>
            

            
"McLattes!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
            

            "I
throw rocks through the window of a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>. Nobody
comes to cheer me."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Gaffen</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> Talk
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Apology in Lieu of Actual</ENAMEX> Wrap-Up
            

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> responses
were rejected by 
                  Slate
               's e-mail server. Sorry about the
frustration and hassle and, though it is in no way connected with

                  Slate
                or its parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, the outcome of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s voting in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>.

            
               Global Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Demonstrators</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> blocks from the
convention <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX> meeting was scheduled,
denounced bioengineered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> cheered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jos√© Bov√</ENAMEX>© who earlier in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> drove his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractor</ENAMEX> through a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McD</ENAMEX> in his native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. "We don't want
to eat any more of that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>," he declared. "Except for the fries,
which are actually pretty good," he did not add.

            The protests forced the postponement of the opening
ceremony as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> castigated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> for being, in the words of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , "a handmaiden of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> whose rulings
undermine health, labor and environmental protections around the world."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Schell</ENAMEX> declared a state of
emergency, put the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> under a curfew, and called in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX>. A
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of masked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> did damage property, but the vast majority of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> were peaceful. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> in riot gear responded with what the
Times called "tear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>, pepper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX> and rubber <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pellets</ENAMEX>."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rubber pellets"</ENAMEX>--are
they anything like rubber bullets?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Gavaghan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's Rioting Extra</ENAMEX>:
            

            We experienced riots in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taipei</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> (the land the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> forgot), earlier
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello Kitty</ENAMEX> collectible toys were made available to the public.
Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (who are, for some reason they are unable to articulate, the
primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello Kitty</ENAMEX> products) would line up around the block in
order to get their hands on the dolls. I, however, am partial to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello Kitty</ENAMEX>'s
rival, the penguin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bad Badtz</ENAMEX>-maru, who wants to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> of everything.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Age</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age Old</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Below, uses for various
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">herbs</ENAMEX> in a pamphlet touting the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Woman's Book of Healing</ENAMEX> Herbs
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WBHH</ENAMEX> ) and in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy of Cooking</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JoC</ENAMEX> ). Mellowed out and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">natural</ENAMEX>, or thick and creamy--you must choose. Whose <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> would you rather be
invited to? Which book would make the better holiday gift? ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cool mumbo</ENAMEX> jumbo
courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn Aberg</ENAMEX> .)

            Cinnamon

            
               WBHH : Wards off bacterial infection.

            
               JoC : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">One</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">teaspoon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pfeffernusse</ENAMEX> recipe. Fun to eat, fun to say, fun to rub on whatever
part of you is infected.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sage</ENAMEX>

            
               WBHH : "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reduces</ENAMEX> or eliminates night
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sweats</ENAMEX>."

            
               JoC : "The best
known and loved of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seasonings</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Ä¶ pork</ENAMEX> and sausages, and for
duck, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX> and rabbit." Mmmm: nice heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> and then a nice sweaty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nap</ENAMEX>.

            Peppermint

            
               WBHH : Relives <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and may even boost mental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alertness</ENAMEX>.

            
               JoC : Used in mint
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sauce</ENAMEX>, "the usual accompaniment to roast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX>." If only the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX> had been a
little more mentally alert, of course, all this unpleasantness could have been
avoided.

            Cloves

            
               WBHH : Good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> if you're bothered by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">athlete</ENAMEX>'s foot.

            
               JoC : Somehow,
I've lost the will to discuss baked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX>.

            Echinacea

            
               WBHH : "saved my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s vacation."

            
               JoC : Not
mentioned, but ask yourself this, is a family vacation really something you
want to save?

            Ginger

            
               WBHH : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Herbal all-star</ENAMEX> for motion sickness
or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nausea</ENAMEX>."

            
               JoC : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingredient</ENAMEX>
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Parkin</ENAMEX>, "a not-too-sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy Fawkes Day</ENAMEX> cake." I'm damn well not inviting
someone to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy Fawkes Day</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX> who's just going to vomit all over
everything.

            Parsley

            
               WBHH : "See why it's earned a reputation for
making black and blue marks disappear."

            
               JoC : What the
hell is going on over there? Should someone call the cops? Now I can't even
think about my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish sauce</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ongoing Autobio</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are still
invited to submit the title of a much needed but as yet unwritten autobiography
of any national political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> lacking this essential election-year tool.
Answers to run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Our inadequate e-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> did not pass along
enough responses to allow for our usual scientific survey. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Curiously</ENAMEX>, it did
forward several promising invitations to make big money at home with hot teen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sluts</ENAMEX>.)

         
      
   
