
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religious Crisis</ENAMEX>

            As
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazareth</ENAMEX> stayed shut in protest at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s
cornerstone-laying ceremony for a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> on the site where the angel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX> is said to have told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> she would give birth to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open</ENAMEX>
Crisis." In a front-page editorial the paper criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
government's decision to authorize the construction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> opposite the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Basilica of the Annunciation</ENAMEX>. "To choose to build an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
religious edifice on the precise spot where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX> appeared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> is
deliberately to overthrow the sacred order that everyone has respected for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">centuries</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> said in an editorial that "relations
between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Land</ENAMEX> have suddenly sunk to their
lowest level for generations." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tensions</ENAMEX> have been stirred by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>'s strong and unhelpful denunciation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> and
by the decision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX> to make a stand as a way of recapturing
dwindling influence. The result is an unholy and distinctly unseemly row that
threatens lasting damage to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> relations worldwide."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> reported
that the inaugural ceremony, which was attended by no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, went ahead smoothly, despite the efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> to prevent it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s unexpected alliance
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> was part of his strategy to win <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> support in future
negotiations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> wants <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX> to use
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> to affirm that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> does not recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> claim as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of
their future independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said. In interviews with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Franciscan</ENAMEX>
order in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, which, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1331</TIMEX>, has been charged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vatican</ENAMEX> with
guarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Land</ENAMEX>, said the land on which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mosque</ENAMEX> is to be built was previously earmarked as a parking lot for buses
carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilgrims</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazareth</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giovanni</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Batistelli</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s reason for authorizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> is "to divide the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli Arabs</ENAMEX>, to foment disagreement between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, thus
weakening both of them--perhaps to drive them all out of the Holy Land one
day." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Batistelli</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> should not cancel his planned visit
to the region in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. "Canceling his visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazareth</ENAMEX> would leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christians</ENAMEX> even more alone, when they need all the support they can get," he
said. An opinion poll published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> showed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>
in favor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68 percent</NUMEX> against.

            There
was widespread pessimism about the prospects for the forthcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
conference of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> papers fronted the
failure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">135</NUMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to agree on a joint declaration to
submit to the conference. The Financial Times fronted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s failure to persuade other
world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to join him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. The FT also said that "big
divergences over agriculture and implementation of existing agreements finally
scuppered all chances of accord on a draft text, which would only have laid out
a set of choices for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> to make on the scope and objectives of the
negotiations." It also quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union Trade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pascal Lamy</ENAMEX>
saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> meeting might fail to launch a new trade round.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> denouncing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> for wanting to include education in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> talks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Allègre</ENAMEX>, told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that this represented <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> seeking hegemony
and that "uniform teaching would lead to a uniform world."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> has uttered hardly a word
in public about the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trade agreement. "Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>, normally
given to long-winded speeches, has maintained an eerie reticence," according to
a comment piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. It attributed this to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s fears that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> membership could precipitate an economic and
political crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. In an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> said that the front-runners in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> are showing a "reasonable perspective" on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
rather than going for quick political gains by demonizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quest</ENAMEX> for votes. "Perhaps a stable realism will emerge once the elections are
over, permitting relations which lack the damaging mood swings of recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>," it concluded.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> continued to debate the behavior of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar-</ENAMEX>winning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor-director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life Is Beautiful</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto Benigni</ENAMEX>, who smothered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> with kisses during the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX> summit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avvenire</ENAMEX> compared him to a woodpecker and said he should be
appointed state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jester</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Il Manifesto</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX>, said it expected the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pope</ENAMEX> to be the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of "the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devil</ENAMEX>'s" mouth-to-mouth kissing.

            The official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Daily</ENAMEX> reported
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sri Lanka</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> a ruling by that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s superior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> have a right to be happy. The case was brought by an animal lover
after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sri Lanka</ENAMEX> national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> sold a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bull elephant</ENAMEX> that had killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trainers</ENAMEX> to a gem <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$113,000</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> ordered that before the
sale of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX> is completed, the would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> must convince a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state-appointed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX> will be given suitable shelter,
enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, proper health care, and plenty of love. Keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>
is considered a status symbol in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sri Lanka</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Daily</ENAMEX> said.

         
      
   
