
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">340</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Say What?</ENAMEX>"

            
               It's a common
expression, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahmoud el-Azzazzay</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX> travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>: "We say it
probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> or more times a day." What expression?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 339</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bird in Hand":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 6</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> opened crates and pulled out
pheasants, then, holding them by the legs, spun the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> around to make them
dizzy; this is one feature of a program whose uneasy combination of private and
state funding is drawing increasing criticism nationwide. What is the program
called?
            

            "The
Beta <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kappa Phi-Audubon Society</ENAMEX>'s new public access show, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dude</ENAMEX>, Let's
Birdwatch! "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Werthmann</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is</ENAMEX>
this the program where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Singer</ENAMEX> comes down from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> and selects which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dizzy pheasant</ENAMEX> dies<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Doyle</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rothschild</ENAMEX> had a
similar answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Robert Byrd Can Appropriate Money for Anything He Damn Well Pleases</ENAMEX>
Game-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Swingin' Day</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Heimer</ENAMEX>
            

            "I'm
not sure, but I think it's safe to assume that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX>'s for it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCartney</ENAMEX>'s against, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Anderson …</ENAMEX> well, she has some very large
breasts."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX>
            

            "We
call it, 'I Remember <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papa</ENAMEX>.' Ah, and I do, I remember very well. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX> and I
would carry the crates. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papa</ENAMEX>, he was a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and I not so large, so I would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">curse</ENAMEX> and sweat in the tropical island heat, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papa</ENAMEX> would laugh and stop from
time to time to pull at his brown bottle. Then we would open the crates and
remove the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> and begin the flingando. Perhaps you have seen this,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">señor</ENAMEX> ? We spin the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> around and around, then release them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papa</ENAMEX>
believed that in their confused flight you could see the hand of God. He was a
very spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, señor . Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>, however, would just fly
straight up and dive down into the ground, embedding their beaks like the Daffy
Duck of the gringo cartoon features. Then we would laugh and laugh and laugh,
until he passed out, and I would steal his wallet."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            The language is
lackluster, the pacing leaden, the clichés plentiful, and the surprises
few--no, not the campaign speeches for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> caucuses (Well, yes, but I'm
thinking of something else here.)--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ric Burns</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">125-hour</TIMEX> documentary series,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> . There were a few engaging features--the astonishing
photographs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Caro</ENAMEX> talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Smith</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Tierney</ENAMEX> arguing that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triangle</ENAMEX> shirtwaist <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> could have just gotten other jobs
instead of catching fire; they were only calling attention to themselves. (OK,
that was in the Times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>, not actually a part of the series,
and I may oversimplify.) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> other illuminating sequence--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX>' presentation
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamilton</ENAMEX>'s clashing ideas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamilton</ENAMEX> championed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mercantile</ENAMEX> and the urban, what would one day be the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> we know.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX> favored the rural, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of imaginary yeoman <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> who would
eventually twirl pheasants in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>. You can catch the final <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine hours</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this evening</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX> at Play
Answer
            

            Take a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kid Pheasant Hunting Day</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This annual</TIMEX> event run by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Jersey Division of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Game</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wildlife</ENAMEX> is partly financed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle Association</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>. The state supplies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wardens</ENAMEX> and land; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> pays for birds
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ammo</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> gun clubs supply <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and doughnuts. To
eat. Nobody is shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doughnuts</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> are swung around so they're too dizzy to
fly away and will stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> can flush them out for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to shoot. The pheasants. Not the doughnuts.

            In his welcoming remarks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Carr</ENAMEX>, said: "Don't shoot a bird
on the ground; don't shoot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cripples</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> will get them. Have a fun day,
but be safe and responsible." A life lesson for us all from a respected role
model.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carr</ENAMEX> explained that farm-bred dizzy pheasants mean
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get to kill a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>. "We can't pull the trigger for them, but we can
certainly put a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> out in front of them."

            Best line from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revkin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> coverage of the event: "During a break, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> rested on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> around them, drinking from cartons of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fruit</ENAMEX> punch and talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX>."

            
               Death Method
Extra
            

            "It's legal, it works and we fully support it. We
believe it is a quick and humane way," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucia Ross</ENAMEX> on behalf of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeb Bush</ENAMEX>, a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of the electric chair. Sure, now and then
someone catches fire, and there was a lot of blood running down a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shirt</ENAMEX>--"A nosebleed!" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chuckled J.B.</ENAMEX> In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX> agreed
to decide if the electric chair constitutes cruel and unusual punishment.

            But no matter the
outcome of that case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeb Bush</ENAMEX> has options. It's not as if there aren't lots
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to kill poor black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Below, I give the method of
execution; you name the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that employs it.

            
               Methods
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Electrocution

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Hanging

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Firing Squad</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Stoning</ENAMEX> (all stadium seating)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lethal Injection</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poison Gas</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sit</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch Daytime</ENAMEX>
TV and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eat Tasteless Food All Day Until You Just Waste Away</ENAMEX>

            
               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>.
(Hence the good-natured nickname, "southern fried." I believe it is Gov.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> who is good-natured; the condemned who are so darn gloomy. And
incidentally, wouldn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>' comments about the chair apply to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>?)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> thing. You know, barbaric. Not
like our space-age methods.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Trick question. It's
just the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> nursing home where we dumped my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Milt</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Pheasants/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
