
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Trade War</ENAMEX>

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> mobbed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to protest the Third
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ministerial Conference of the World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>. They argued that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">135</NUMEX>-nation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> in which membership is voluntary but "free trade" rules
are mandatory, threatens to dissolve human rights, labor laws, and health and
environmental protections in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> of global capitalism. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Director-General Michael Moore</ENAMEX> fired back.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>, belatedly realizing that it has become a political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>,
are beginning to counter the principal spins against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Whether to trade vs. how to trade. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> want us
to ask first what political terms of trade are being offered, and then to
decide, based on how good or bad those terms are, whether or not to trade. By
this logic, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> doesn't include labor and environmental regulations
in its trade rules (thereby undermining such regulations in many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> should be suspended. "Until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>
addresses these important issues, there will be no support for a major new
round of trade negotiations," declared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sweeney</ENAMEX> several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> meeting. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, hey, ho, ho, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> has got to go,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> chanted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ad, a coalition
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> said "public interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> … want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> to stop in its
tracks. … Many feel the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> can never be democratically reformed."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wants to reverse these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> questions. He wants us to ask first whether
trading is generally good or bad, and then--only after we've agreed that it's
good--to begin discussing on what political terms we should trade. "We are
going to have to listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have legitimate economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>,
legitimate environmental concerns, legitimate labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> conceded
in a speech in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. But first, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, "Everybody has to
decide: Do you think we are better off or worse off with an increasingly
integrated global economy, where productive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have a chance to sell
their goods and services and skills around the world? I think we're better off.
That's the number one core decision we ought to make up our mind as a country
we agree about."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. What is capitalism destroying? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> contrast
global capitalism with enlightened national laws. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX>' ad, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>, by promoting and mandating unfettered trade, is
destroying "standards for safety, health and the environment" in "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> …
that try to protect the safety of their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, their jobs, small businesses or
Nature." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> should be reined in to preserve "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>'
rights" and to "protect the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, at all levels, to use their
purchasing power to reinforce their values and standards."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> argue that the regimes and laws mowed down by global
capitalism are more often corrupt than enlightened--in short, that capitalism
is an improvement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> fosters respect for the "rule of law,"
which weeds out corruption and discourages war. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Fukuyama</ENAMEX>, writing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , says poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around the world are dominated
by "local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> … interlocked with local political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> in a web of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cronyism</ENAMEX> and corruption. Globalization in the form of foreign direct investment
by multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> not only creates employment but directly
threatens these local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> by exposing them to competition."

            
Addressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> argued that global capitalism has
replaced not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> utopia but warped <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">totalitarianism</ENAMEX> and aggression.
Free trade "tore down the walls of economic and political oppression," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>. "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> learnt from the great depression, made deeper and more
lethal by rising trade barriers from which came the twin tyrannies of our age,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fascism</ENAMEX> and Marxism, thus war; hot and cold. They swore it would not happen
again, and they created an international architecture which included the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATT</ENAMEX>, now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>, to achieve that peaceful
purpose."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> permit problems or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solutions</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>
say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> is bad because it permits oppressive and environmentally
destructive practices and, by liberating greed, promotes these practices. By
focusing on the free flow of capital, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> "are not supporting human
rights and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' rights," said a union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sees it
the other way around: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> is good because it permits discussion of
these practices. "It is not wrong for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to say we don't believe
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> labor, or forced labor, or the oppression of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and sisters
who work for a living around the world--and [that] we don't believe that
growing the economy requires us to undermine the environment," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
But to make those arguments and resolve those issues with other nations
effectively, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, "You have to have some system to resolve them."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Opening the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> vs. opening world trade. Sweeney blasts
"trade accords negotiated behind closed doors" and demands that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> become
"open" and "accountable." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> an "invisible
government" that "was elected by no-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>" and "operates in secrecy." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Moore</ENAMEX>
replies that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> is democratic--"Ministers are here because their people
decided so. Our agreements must be agreed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliaments</ENAMEX>"--but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> goes
further. He frames the issue of openness more broadly, arguing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> has
made trade decisions more accountable and more universally beneficial than they
used to be. "We do have to open the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> and the world trading system to greater
public scrutiny and to greater public participation," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. But "what
we came here to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> to do" is "to open markets and
expand opportunities."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Stability vs. progress. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> focus on "stability"
and worry that unfettered trade will demolish it. Thanks to world capital flow,
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweeney</ENAMEX>, "financial collapses have grown more severe and more frequent."
But what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> call stability, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> calls stagnation: "The
least-developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are not threatened by globalization. They are
threatened by de-globalization, falling outside of the world economy and
slipping ever further behind." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> portrays the instability of big
industrial shifts--for example, the loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> jobs in steel and the
simultaneous creation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> jobs in software--as a transition to a world
in which "everybody can do what they do best." To mitigate that instability, he
promises to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> "time and support and investment to make the
transitions into the new economy."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human</ENAMEX>
nature puts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at a disadvantage in this debate. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would rather
keep what they have than risk it for a hypothetical payoff. And while the costs
of unrestricted trade tend to be visible because they're nearby and
concentrated (e.g., the closure of a local <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>), the benefits tend to be
invisible because they're faraway or diffuse (e.g., lower prices at the grocery
store or higher wages in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>). "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are going to win will
always be somewhat uncertain of their gain, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who will lose
are absolutely sure of what they are going to lose," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Therefore,
embracing free trade "will require … imagination and trust and humility and
flexibility."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Bully or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protector</ENAMEX>? Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO Director-General</ENAMEX> Renato
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruggiero</ENAMEX> once called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> a "new constitution for a single global economy,"
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> have seized on this somewhat presumptuous self-characterization
to portray the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> as a police state designed by rich <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> to facilitate the
exploitation of poor ones. "Unlike other global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> (including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>), the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> enjoys unique enforcement powers," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> warn in their ad.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Offending</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> must conform with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> rules, or face harsh sanctions."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Moore</ENAMEX>
sees these governmental analogies in a different light. He thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">constitution</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> powers will protect poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, not exploit them.
"Developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> need a secure and stable world trading system," he says.
"They need more openness, not less. Stronger rules, not weaker ones. … I'm from
a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>], but I don't see what we are doing here as a
threat to our sovereignty. I see interdependence as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guarantor</ENAMEX> of our
sovereignty and safety."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Imports vs. exports. Some goods are produced more cheaply
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> than abroad. Others are produced more cheaply abroad than
here. Unrestricted trade will help <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> category but
will wipe out those in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> category. That's why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> talks about the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> category, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> talk about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks ago</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeney</ENAMEX> brought a steelworkers union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Press Club</ENAMEX> to
illustrate how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>'s prohibition against trade barriers facilitates the
loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> manufacturing jobs to "dumped imports" and cheap labor abroad.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> chose
to talk about a different industry. "The typical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> eats <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 pounds</NUMEX> of
fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> each year," whereas "the typical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> consumes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 46</NUMEX>
pounds," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. "So <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> exported <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$353 million</NUMEX> worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>." Lowering trade barriers in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> means "more apple
sales from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>" and more help for "family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>," he observed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
joked that his apple reference was "a pander to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>," but it was
more than that. The national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> that will lose under global capitalism
and the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> that will win are--to borrow a self-illustrating
rhetorical metaphor--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oranges</ENAMEX>. And the key to reassuring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> is to talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
