
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">337</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Substandard</ENAMEX>" 

            
               To justify a
current policy, a well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> cites these conditions: "unrelenting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crowding</ENAMEX>, lack of privacy, infrequent communications with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and the
outside world, no ability even to go … for fresh air and a view." Who is
defending what policy?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 336</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three for All":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planned Parenthood</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Natural History</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>--what's the
connection?
            

            "Name
the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> entries on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liddy Dole</ENAMEX>'s résumé."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim Derby</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Failed pitch for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next season</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Real World : Wacky</ENAMEX> high jinks ensue
when a group of reproductive-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> are picked to live in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">neoclassical beaux-</ENAMEX>arts science <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park West</ENAMEX> and
have their lives taped for a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-hour</TIMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michele Siegel</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Surprisingly</ENAMEX>, they all have very cruise-y <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
Amoros
            

            
"Trendy weddings sites featured in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times 'Style'</ENAMEX> section."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is</ENAMEX>
there a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX> won't sit on?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Greenberg</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> responses
typically offer a reliable guide to what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is thinking (if only by
providing sullen and resentful counterexamples), but from time to time
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> make small errors of--well, fact would be too vulgar a word; let's
say emphasis. I would like to correct--no, let's say refine--a few of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enormities</ENAMEX>--no, let's just say fatuities.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planned Parenthood</ENAMEX> is "pro-abortion."--It would be more correct to say the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> offers a variety of reproductive options and defends a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s
right to choose.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Natural History</ENAMEX> is boring and old-fashioned.--It's pretty
obvious that some of you haven't seen the new hominid penis.

               It is only when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> runs out of airplane accidents to cover at tedious
length that it turns to the inane blather of lackluster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX>--I'm sure
there's a flaw in this, but I can't think of it now.

            

            
               Web of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sin</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            They are among the many Web sites off-limits to all
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> public school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K-12</ENAMEX>, thanks to the filtering program
installed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of education.

            After initially lying, insisting it had received no
complaints, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> shifted to the more reliable techniques of equivocating
and trivializing its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, insisting that there was no problem, and if there
was it was small, and temporary, and that those who complained were just a
bunch of complainers whose purpose is just to make some complaints.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of education's
computers use <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-Gear</ENAMEX>, a filtering package made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Symantic</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> has no
plans to remove or modify this software, although individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> may phone
for help in making their own alterations.

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Serial Violator of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>" Extra
            

            That's how some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on
local news described <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>, whose latest defeat came
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> when a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> unlawfully punished an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
group critical of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. Below, a few of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX> cases. Did he win or lose each?

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Yellow Cab Drivers</ENAMEX> vs. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX>) Safir --attempt
to block cabbies from holding a demonstration.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino Officers Association</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safir</ENAMEX> --attempt to stifle cops from
speaking to the press.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyons</ENAMEX>, etc. --attempt to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from handing out
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist Workers</ENAMEX> campaign literature.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bery</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of New York</ENAMEX> --attempt to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> from selling work
on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> without official <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> license.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner Cable</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of New York</ENAMEX> --attempt to force <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
Network onto the system.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Bunch of Idiots</ENAMEX> --attempt to brand letter "I"
on foreheads of those who disagree with him.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kalke</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of New York</ENAMEX> --attempt to thwart <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All Saints</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> from distributing condoms in city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> as part of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> education
program.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerks Who Cross</ENAMEX> Against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Light</ENAMEX> --attempt to
impose corporal punishment on those who impede any car any time with their damn
walking.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> Magazine 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">vs. City of New York</ENAMEX> --attempt to stop the
magazine from making fun of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> in ads on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX>. 

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner Cable II</ENAMEX> : This time it's
personal--attempt to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> prime-time lineup mandatory viewing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               Answers
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> lost all these
cases, except <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>, which do not exist.

            
               Extra Credit
            

            You can keep the money
you've won so far, or risk it on this follow-up: What is the overall tally in
those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> cases?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Extra Credit Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYCLU</ENAMEX> has gone to
court in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> cases against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> times. It
has prevailed, in full or in part, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> cases so far decided.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delightful Footnote</ENAMEX>
            

            Public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>
Green may sue the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> for wasting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $5 million</NUMEX> in public funds in
these "frivolous lawsuits."

            
               Read <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">More About It</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nyclu</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org/guilianifirstamnd.</ENAMEX>html

            (Special thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX>.)

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
