
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissing Outlawed</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Army</ENAMEX>

            With
the outcome of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trade negotiations still unknown, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> political settlement still in the balance, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
planned meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> still
unconsummated, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s papers focused on domestic issues and the latest
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> earthquake. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> led its front page with a new
sex code for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> armed forces. To get around a ruling by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Court of Human Rights</ENAMEX> against a ban on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, a
ban the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> hope to maintain, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is
reported to be planning to impose new rules proscribing all sexual displays,
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> or heterosexual.

            They
will restrict "sex, not sexuality" by forbidding touching and other displays of
affection across all ranks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> reported fears by senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> that the new code of conduct would damage recruitment and lead to a
flood of courts-martial, with service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> being punished for what in
civilian life is perfectly acceptable behavior. In an editorial, the paper
toyed with the idea of putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> into separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> "like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sacred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thebes</ENAMEX>," but said that "a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> comprised wholly of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> could
easily become a target for the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>." "Perhaps, on reflection, the
simplest solution is for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual soldiers</ENAMEX> to keep their mouths shut and get
on with their jobs."

            The
Times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s lead story said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland Unionist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Trimble</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate</ENAMEX>, may have taken "the biggest gamble of his career"
by considering entering in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Sinn Fein Party</ENAMEX>--the
political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX>--before a single IRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> has
been handed over. Until now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Unionists</ENAMEX> have insisted that there could be no
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">powersharing</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> until some of the IRA's
illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> were decommissioned. A new critical round of talks resumed
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX> under the chairmanship of former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>.

            In an
editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> described the re-election of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Diouf</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director-General</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Food and Agriculture Organization</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> as "a
victory for machine politics and cronysim over much-needed reform in one of the
oldest world organisations set up to ensure better food supplies for the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around the world who go hungry." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> there
are many better international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> looking at food supplies and that "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
should give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAO</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> to review its use of voluntary contributions. If
this does not improve, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> should switch its donations to other bodies and
give notice of withdrawal."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
fronted an interview with the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah II</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> he
was beginning a state visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> originally planned for his late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Hussein</ENAMEX>. In his own words, his main points included: "To invest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>
is to invest in peace in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>"; "I belong to a generation that has
been educated in the West, which has chosen what is best in both cultures and
understands the western world"; "I have never organised any meeting between
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>. I have limited myself to passing on verbal messages from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassad</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>"; "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water</ENAMEX> is a fundamental problem in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. There should be an international conference to regulate it";
"Most of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> will probably want
to remain in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>."

            With
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Clinton</ENAMEX> already in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Istanbul</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> due there
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this week</TIMEX> for a summit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization for Security</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co-operation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX> fronted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> the claim that the
disastrous earthquakes in northwestern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> were "a prelude to a cataclysmic
strike in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Istanbul</ENAMEX>." From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Duzce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reported, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seismologists</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kandilli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">observatory</ENAMEX> warned that a major fault system had been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">activated</ENAMEX>, and that it was only a question of when, not if, the metropolis
would be leveled." In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> are "thrilled to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>, especially at
a time when we are going through some very hard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, having to cope with the
national trauma of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> successive major killer earthquakes and the never-ending
hardships suffered by our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> because of economic crises."

            The
paper also noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-day</TIMEX> visit was "a record for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of state and source of satisfaction and pride for all of us." It urged the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> to encourage greater democracy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> as part of its efforts
to promote stability in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> we have had bad experiences
of how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> have pretended to condemn coups in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> while they
have actively supported them and the juntas," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "We are aware
that the world has changed and we feel the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> should give
guarantees to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> that this will never be the case
again."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX> ran an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
case, warning about the dangers of official intervention to stop aggressive
business practices in high-tech industries. Such intervention could stop the
growth of that sector, it said: "In other words, even well-meaning regulations
designed to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> could prove counterproductive." The paper
described <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Penfield Jackson</ENAMEX>'s findings of fact as "of great
significance because they point to the shape of antitrust policy in the age of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fast-paced</ENAMEX>, high-tech industries that are moving and shaking the world economy,
particularly the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> economy." It added that the high-tech industries have
created <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of new jobs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. "No doubt much of the credit
for this goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. However, the ruling underscores the need of
facilitating market access for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> and of respecting consumer
interests."

            The problem, the editorial
said, is where to draw the line: "The antitrust policy of the past--when
national borders blocked free movement of goods and services and when
traditional smokestack industries provided the main thrust of industrial
growth--no longer holds <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> moves toward international mergers and
acquisitions are picking up momentum in a broad spectrum of industries, such as
financial services, communications, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">petroleum</ENAMEX>. Of course, the
situation in these industries is different from that in the developing computer
software industry. But they all face a common question: how to balance the
demands of oligopoly and the interests of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
