
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> Under Siege

            The
riots at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX> summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> were the world's top
story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> Under Siege" was the most popular headline in the
English-language press. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> also fronted parallel
demonstrations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist protesters</ENAMEX>
battled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Euston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">railway station</ENAMEX>, leaving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> seriously
injured. Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX> began its report:
"It rains here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost every day</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> it does not, it is overcast. But
weather alone wasn't causing gloom on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Vidal</ENAMEX> gave <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the better accounts of the scene. "Strains of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Turner</ENAMEX> drift in with the tear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> of black-masked
protestors overturn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> stands," he wrote. "They try to smash a Starbucks
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coffee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> door, but give up quickly. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> window is broken, then one
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX>. They race through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, followed by TV cameras." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vidal</ENAMEX> quoted
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX>: "I cannot see how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> will not be
politically embarrassed. The world is watching. What do they see? A major city
in disorder. It looks bad." A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegate</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vidal</ENAMEX>, "We have come
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> for these talks. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is supposed to lead the world--what
has happened?"

            In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening Standard</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilton</ENAMEX> said of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> in an op-ed piece: "Most could not explain why they were
there--or what any of the others were protesting about. But they were most
certainly there in huge numbers and upset about something. That, rather than
anything specific, they said, was the message." He described them "in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nike</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trainers</ENAMEX>, excitedly loading their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Fuji</ENAMEX> film to take pictures with their
Canons, chatting on their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nokia</ENAMEX> mobiles and dancing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">intersections</ENAMEX> to
music from their Sonys" as "walking advertisements for the global economy." But
he argued that what they were really doing was protesting against the
unchallenged consensus in favor of free-market economics that has dominated the
whole world for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 10 years</TIMEX>. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">eople</ENAMEX> and circumstances being what they
are, any monopoly of political thought, however valid it may seem, becomes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unsustainable</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilton</ENAMEX> wrote. "Perhaps the real message of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are beginning, however uncertainly and inarticulately, to look for an
alternative."

            The
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> had a scoop
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. It discovered that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s military leader
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pervaiz Musharraf</ENAMEX> on his coup mission in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> had refueled twice on its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX>. This is important because the hijacking charge against ousted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaz Sharif</ENAMEX> is based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Musharraf</ENAMEX>'s claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharif</ENAMEX> refused
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> permission to land despite the fact that it was out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>. In
fact, claimed the paper, it had plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>, and the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharif</ENAMEX>
"may not finally hold ground."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> reported
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that an important <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> secretly visited an aircraft fitted
with the AWACS radar system that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has prepared especially for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">air force</ENAMEX>. The inspection by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li Peng</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National People's</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, was added to his timetable at the last moment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. It
also noted a report in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aviation Week</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
government asked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> to reconsider its deal with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>. "A senior
source in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel Military Industries</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> stance cynical and
hypocritical," it said.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> being <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World AIDS Day</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX> received much attention in the
international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> has reached an explosive
stage in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>'s most populous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. It quoted from a survey
carried out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> with help from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and the World
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Organization</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX> has entered the stage where the epidemic is
likely to increase at an exponential rate if adequate national response is not
mounted to stem its spread. While there is a window of opportunity, this window
is closing rapidly." The FT also ran an op-ed feature saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
is now the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. "The future of the next
generation rests on whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can join forces to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> the disease," it said. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> may be infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s leading newspaper, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX> , said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that while <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is declining in other developed
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, the number of new cases in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is on the rise.

            The
Independent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> reported alleged new evidence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Woodward</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-murder case
that could cast doubt on her conviction for manslaughter in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>. It said her
former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Whitfield</ENAMEX> Sharp, had interviewed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> who claimed to have seen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-and-a-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-month-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Eappen</ENAMEX> fall
from a shopping cart in a south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> while out shopping with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, apparently injuring his head. The incident was alleged to have taken
place around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas 1996</TIMEX>, just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> before the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">au pair</ENAMEX> girl
was arrested.

            In an
interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX> predicted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> will lose the
senatorial contest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of Talk , who launched her
magazine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> with Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on the cover, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> will
"undoubtedly" win because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> didn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>. They consider her "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypercareerist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perfectionist</ENAMEX> who always makes them feel inadequate, inferior,
and ill-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-ease." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are also against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> said, "They hate
her in a much more visceral manner than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>, who terrorizes them."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> also forecast that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> will beat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is "top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, very cultivated, and well up on everything," while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s "total lack of political culture is obvious and is frightening," she
said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s honeymoon with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> will begin to turn sour at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of next</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">spring</ENAMEX>," she predicted. Questioned about the furor over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX>'s role as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> said: "The savage fury against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> is the most sinister
example of the anti-feminist sexism that will dominate the coming elections. …
I think it is only a foretaste of the pseudo-political perfidy that awaits us
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few months</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere</ENAMEX> questioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Galotti</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of
Talk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Inc.</ENAMEX>, about reports that Talk is in crisis and is about to be
redesigned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliviero Toscani</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benetton</ENAMEX> advertising
campaign. "All balls" was his reply.

         
      
   
