
   
   
      
         
            Hope for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>

            "The
Future <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Starts Here</ENAMEX>" was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Independent</ENAMEX> 's front-page headline <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> as
papers on both sides of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea</ENAMEX> were full of cautious optimism about the
future of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Trimble</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>'s designated first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> in a devolved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, was warmly praised in both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republic</ENAMEX> for having won the agreement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58 percent</NUMEX> of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster Unionist Party</ENAMEX> to share power with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>, its traditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> , another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, said in an editorial headlined "The courage of Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trimble</ENAMEX>" that "[t]he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belfast Agreement</ENAMEX> may yet resonate in the collective memory of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> as
a great imaginative departure and a creative compromise between traditionally
antagonistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> went on, "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nationalists</ENAMEX> have
swallowed the bitter truth that there will be no united <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> in the
foreseeable future and if it comes, it will only happen with the consent of a
majority in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Unionists</ENAMEX> have had to accept, in the new
cross-Border structures, the legitimate aspirations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX> to build a
closer relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Government of Ireland Act of 1920</ENAMEX> is
to be repealed and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> have agreed to relinquish the
territorial claim to unity. A fundamental change in those mind-sets that froze
into place at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX> is under way." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish News</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> paper based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX>, said in an editorial,
"It was, by any standards, a testing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unionists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX>,
and many difficulties still lie ahead, but the political process and a better
future remain on course."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX> praised the "heroism" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trimble</ENAMEX> and
the "superhuman patience" of former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Mitchell</ENAMEX>, who brokered the
troubled Good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> agreement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said that,
starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, an historic step would be taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>,
culminating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> in self-government for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster</ENAMEX>. "This should be a great
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>--and for making that possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Trimble</ENAMEX> and his
party should be congratulated," it concluded. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> said
that the peace process had reached "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> base" but that "whether it advances
further now rests exclusively with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> and the IRA." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX>
remained the most skeptical of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers. In an editorial headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trimble</ENAMEX>'s still in trouble," it
doubted if the IRA would surrender its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next May</TIMEX> as promised (if
the IRA doesn't, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trimble</ENAMEX> has said that he will resign as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first minister</ENAMEX> and
thus destroy the power-sharing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>). "[I]t is almost impossible to see
what benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sinn</ENAMEX> Fein/IRA would gain from junking the threat of violence," it
said. "[A]fter all, terror has helped to win them office in part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX>."

            On the
world were apprehensive about its outcome. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Failure</ENAMEX>,
or a feeble political fudge, would leave the global trade system dangerously
adrift." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, perhaps alone, has the skills needed to provide success,
it said. "His presence [in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>], and his efforts to clinch <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>
entry, suggest he has a strong personal commitment to the global trade system,"
the FT said in an editorial. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, he has an exceptional opportunity
to prove it--and to bequeath a lasting legacy." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>, in
an editorial headed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chance in a Millennium</ENAMEX>," said the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of people
protesting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> against globalization will "do serious harm if they give
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX> inside excuses to shirk the tough decisions." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said,
"The real fear of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> is not that the trade talks will fail but that
they will succeed, for protectionism is a powerful force behind which shelter
not only state monopolies, inefficient industries and cossetted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> but
backward-looking and xenophobic ideologies."

            
Leading <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Welt</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> was a report that a research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, has
decoded the complete genetic makeup of a human chromosome. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, which also
reported the development on its front page, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> is
due to publish the composition of Chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Thursday</TIMEX>, marking the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that the hugely complex chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> of a complete human
chromosome has been revealed. "The genetic code in the chromosome is thought to
contain vital information on several hereditary conditions, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX> and deafness," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Telegraph of London</ENAMEX>
said. It added, "The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> nd chromosome is also a key immune system
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX>."

            
Commenting on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>'s general election defeat in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
Party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny Shipley</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Clark</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald of Australia</ENAMEX> noted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that "the first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> the vote, in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1893</TIMEX>, has ended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> with an election involving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> leading the
major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and with its first elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female prime minister</ENAMEX>." Nevertheless,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s victory speech "cautious and dour" and lacking in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX>.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indigenous Maori</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> are claiming descent from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> group of several dozens <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maoris</ENAMEX> is expected in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> soon "in order to renew their ties with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. … The Maoris
believe they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ephraim</ENAMEX>, who made their way to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Pacific</ENAMEX> islands <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3,000 years ago</TIMEX> and see a certain similarity between
their religion and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>
responsible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s worst ever nuclear accident, which took place
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Sept. 30</TIMEX>, has been in critical condition since his heart temporarily
stopped beating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hisashi Ouchi</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>, was exposed to huge amounts
of radiation when he and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokaimura</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX> processing
plant illegally mixed a large quantity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium solution</ENAMEX> in a stainless steel
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">container</ENAMEX>. The mixture triggered a nuclear chain reaction at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> quoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ouchi</ENAMEX> lost a great deal of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> from his intestines, and his skin has been failing to reproduce
itself.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> the same paper
reported the death at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 97</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Gray Vining</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> who served as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akihito</ENAMEX>'s tutor for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years from 1946</TIMEX> while he was still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crown prince</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. "Besides
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">teaching English</ENAMEX> to the future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vining</ENAMEX> also passed on democratic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ideals</ENAMEX>, such as freedom and respect for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. As a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quaker</ENAMEX>, she also held strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pacifist</ENAMEX> convictions, and she was the only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigner</ENAMEX> invited to the wedding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crown prince</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michiko Shoda</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
