
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God's Grandeur</ENAMEX>

            The world
is charged with the grandeur of God.

            It will flame out, like
shining from shook foil;

            It gathers to a greatness,
like the ooze of oil
Crushed. Why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> then now not reck his rod?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Generations</ENAMEX> have trod, have trod, have trod;

            And all is seared with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX>; bleared, smeared with toil;

            And
wears <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s smudge and shares <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s smell: the soil
Is bare now, nor can foot feel, being shod.

            And for
all this, nature is never spent;

            There lives the dearest
freshness deep down things;
And though the last lights off the black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">West</ENAMEX> went

            Oh, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, at the brown
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brink</ENAMEX> eastward springs--
Because the Holy Ghost over the bent

            World
broods with warm breast and with ah! bright wings.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manley Hopkins</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> convert and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> who wrote near the beginning of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>, had the gift of seeing spiritual life as dynamic,
even agonized, rather than complacently sweet. As part of that gift, he went
beyond conventional forms and images of expression. In this poem, he sees
divine grandeur not simply in a trite vision of "nature," but in nature as
human nature affects it, too: industrial images such as shaking metal foil or
crushed oil embody the grandeur. And in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">poem</ENAMEX>'s final image of the Holy
Ghost at the "brown brink eastward" appears as the sun rises in a spectacular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dawn</ENAMEX>, including the brown sky of coal-fueled industrial terrain--a vision of
godhead as sunrise in smog. Our smudge and blear and soil, he proposes, do not
efface the glory.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
