
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gas</ENAMEX> Pains<STRONG> </STRONG>

            

               Protests continued at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX> meeting in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s violent clashes, in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 500</NUMEX> arrests and used tear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and rubber bullets to
disperse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> gathered peacefully outside the city
jail and called for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>' release. Seattleites debated whether the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) were ill-prepared, outnumbered, and too accommodating of
demonstrations; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) overreacted by using riot tactics on peaceful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3</NUMEX>)
were stuck in a "Catch-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>." The gloomy spin: Sensational demonstrations are
obscuring substantive issues and embarrassing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The rosy spin:
We're showing the world democracy in
action. (In "," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> explains how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> went from complete
unknown to boogeyman, and in "," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>
have it all wrong.)

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> may be buried in mass graves in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>. After
receiving a tip from a former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> law
enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> began excavating the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ciudad Juarez</ENAMEX>, just south of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. The graves are thought to contain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of drug-related violence in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>. The rosy spins:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) This will likely solve some of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s "most gruesome
crimes"; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) it heralds a new
era of cooperation in international law enforcement. The dismal spin:
Poor law enforcement is what allowed these crimes to happen
in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.

            

               Government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> penetrated security at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> posed as airport
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and gained access to secure areas, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">117</NUMEX> out of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">173</NUMEX> attempts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> said the study showed that breaching airport
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> was "a breeze" and cited a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s oversight
of safety inadequate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> downplayed the report, saying it has addressed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> "[do] not need to be alarmed."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>'s new coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> took power. Under an
agreement reached <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> with equal representation
for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX> received governing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Parliament</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. The pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Ulster Unionists</ENAMEX> dropped
their requirement that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX> disarm before a government
could be formed. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> did not attend the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> meeting.
The pessimistic spin: This experiment in compromise faces "a bumpy ride." The
optimistic spin: It's still the best chance yet
for lasting peace. ("" examines the historic new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Some <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> veterans exhibit signs of brain damage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> found
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subnormal</ENAMEX> levels of a key chemical in the brains of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> vets with "<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> said the new research: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) "showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> were
narrowing in on chemical exposure --from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides ‚Ä</ENAMEX>¶
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nerve gas</ENAMEX>, or an experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>--as the cause of the
illness"; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) undermines a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> report suggesting the
complaints resulted from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">battlefield stress</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) could guarantee these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">veterans</ENAMEX> better coverage for treatment. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> cautioned that the
research was inconclusive and was based on a very small sample.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> proposed a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$483 billion</NUMEX> tax cut. It would
reduce tax rates at every income level, double the credit for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and
eliminate estate taxes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> camp said the cuts' focus on middle- and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">lower-income families</ENAMEX> 
underscored the compassion in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s conservatism. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> said the
plan was the same old hat, benefiting the rich, threatening to worsen the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> debt, and jeopardizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> called it "something only the timid could love--simply more political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">expediency</ENAMEX>."

            

               Hsing-Hsing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">panda</ENAMEX> died. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Keepers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Zoo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">euthanized Hsing-Hsing</ENAMEX> after deciding that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">kidney disease</ENAMEX> was causing him
agonizing pain. He was the surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> of the pair of pandas that was given
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Tse-tung</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s
historic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> visit. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> will be preserved and displayed at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian Museum of Natural History</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next year</TIMEX>. Hsing-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hsing</ENAMEX>'s keepers
declared that they were mourning the death of an old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hsing-Hsing</ENAMEX>'s almost human
personality should lessen the "sense of apartness that causes us to treat so
many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> as a commodity, or a nuisance--in either case as 'things' to be
killed or driven away." (
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> good riddance to the
slothful, boring bear.)

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Academy of Sciences</ENAMEX> recommended formation of a federal
medical-mistake-prevention program. Medical mishaps kill between
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44,000 and 98,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> per year--more than breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, car accidents,
or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>--and cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an estimated $9 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAS</ENAMEX> concluded that a
government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> that tracked and disseminated information on these errors
would reduce patient risk. The medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> emphasized that "the number
one cause of medical mistakes is not incompetence but confusion." The virtually
unanimous spin: "
There's no controversy here. ‚Ä¶ It's an ideal opportunity to increase
quality and decrease costs."

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> are battling over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 5-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli√°n Gonz√°lez</ENAMEX> was one of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who survived the sinking of a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">17-foot</NUMEX> aluminum <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> that was
carrying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> says
Gonz√°lez should be returned to his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, claiming that his mother, who
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perished</ENAMEX> in the shipwreck, had kidnapped him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> says the boy
will be allowed to gain <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> after a year in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>'s spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s lax immigration policy for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> promotes this
kind of tragedy. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s spin: No, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> oppression that makes people
want to flee.

            

               Fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> are made up of married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX> study found that this type of
household declined from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent to 26 percent</NUMEX> of the total <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1972</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Fifty-one percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> now live with their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, down from
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>. The changes were attributed to: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) increased cohabitation;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) later marriages; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) greater acceptance of divorce; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX>
with "empty nests." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> said the statistics signaled the decline of
marriage and "traditional" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are
increasingly recognizing that these "modern" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> can work.

         
      
   
