
   
   
      
         
            War and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> flew to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Istanbul</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> security summit with strong backing from his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
press for the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> must not listen to moralising in
Istanbul," warned a front-page editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novye Izvestia</ENAMEX>,
which ran above a color photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
bombing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months ago</TIMEX>. But to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX>'s embarrassment, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tabloid Versia</ENAMEX> , on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX>, became the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> paper to print
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> statement which appears to show that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> has a joint
account in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lugano</ENAMEX> with one of his key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pavel Borodin</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> has
denied that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has any foreign accounts or property.

            New
hopes for a peace settlement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> dominated the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. "Peace within their grasp" proclaimed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> 's front-page
headline after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Trimble</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Adams</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unionist</ENAMEX> and republican
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, issued separate statements committing themselves to pursuing their
conflicting objectives by "exclusively peaceful and democratic" means. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said the statements transformed the political landscape and
brought <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> to the very brink of historic compromise.

            But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> both underscored the political risks that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trimble</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate</ENAMEX>, is running by backing off from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s
traditional "no <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, no government" stand--a policy of refusing to share power
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein Party</ENAMEX> in a devolved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> before
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX> hands over any of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said
hard-line <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster Unionist Party</ENAMEX> are already plotting to oust
Trimble, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , which is fiercely supportive of the
continuing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, came close to accusing him
of betrayal. In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, it called his new conciliatory stand an
"extraordinary gamble" and demanded he come clean about what, if anything, the
IRA is secretly offering to cause him "to take this leap in the dark."

            Much
of the press around the world covered the calling in of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> to investigate
the crash of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> Flight 990 off the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">217</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> died. "Was there a kamikaze in the cockpit<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lib√</ENAMEX>©ration of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">front-page</ENAMEX> banner headline. In <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> fronted what it claimed to be the cause of
the collapse of an apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in the southern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of Foggia
which killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, had been erected on top
of an artesian well--"that is, on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>." Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the neighborhood knew
of the well, it said. "Only the city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> didn't know about it and have
continued to deny its existence even after the collapse."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also led with the decision by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>
to take legal action against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> for refusing to lift its ban on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
beef. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press highlighted a statement by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>'s
food safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> agreement to end the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad Cow</ENAMEX> war
was only "a hair's breadth" away. In a front-page editorial, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> said the affair
could be seen as just an episode in "the eternal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anglo-French</ENAMEX> conflict." An
editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX> said its legacy would be "that extra
little suspicion of our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> will be unfairly added to the great
heap of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europhobia</ENAMEX> patiently built up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Englanders</ENAMEX> in the press and
in politics."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> claimed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
now agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> is the principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> of terrorism in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>.
Writing on the eve of a speech on terrorism by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Istanbul</ENAMEX> summit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aluf Benn</ENAMEX> called this an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
"diplomatic achievement." He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> now says that its recent
attempts at dialogue with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> have "achieved nothing," and it has promised
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> that it will not defrost its relations with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that is using
terror to try to undermine the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> reported
"conspicuous silence" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> in response to a
flat denial by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> that it is buying an airborne radar system from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>--a
deal which the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has been trying to stop. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzhak Shichor</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>
University <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> relations, told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
statement was probably a result of pressure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.
"It's a typical reaction," he said. "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> we had deep ties with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
and we also had meetings with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> and everybody knew about it, but they
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flatly</ENAMEX> denied it. That's the way it is with them."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning</ENAMEX>
Post of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> warned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is already trying to
erect "roadblocks" to slow the influx of goods, services, and ideas after it
joins the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>. "Opposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> accession remains strong
among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministries</ENAMEX> and most regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX>," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willy</ENAMEX>
Wo-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lap Lam</ENAMEX> in a comment on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sino-U.S.</ENAMEX> trade agreement. He added that
"basic elements in the [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>] party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX>--such as tight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and
government control of major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>, enshrined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Committee</ENAMEX>
plenum in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>--are unlikely to change in the foreseeable future." In an
editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> expressed optimism about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Congress</ENAMEX> ratifying
the trade agreement. "Over time, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> politics gravitate towards the middle,
and extreme views seldom win," it said. "And a careful consideration of the
benefits of making <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>--plus the costs of not doing so--will
convince most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> their best interests lie in opening wide the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> door."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
welcomed the trade agreement in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> but lamented the fact
that "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, the world's first commercial power," had allowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> to do its own private deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. "More aggressive economic
diplomacy would have allowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> to defend its interests
better," it said.

            In a diary in the current
issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Collins</ENAMEX>
describes her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks ago</TIMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>. "He grasped my hands firmly," she writes. "He has beautiful
and expressive hands, by the way, and enormous feet ... I must admit I was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spellbound</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has palpable sex appeal, and is much taller and slimmer
than I'd expected. He also has wonderful breath, but not from a surfeit of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mints</ENAMEX> or mouthwash."

         
      
   
