
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">345</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Riotous Assembly With Cheese</ENAMEX>"

            
               Cheering
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> gathered outside a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle McDonald's</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. Why?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">344</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Futurific":</ENAMEX>
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              "If I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, it won't happen
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>. If I'm not, it will happen immediately." Who said this about
what?
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apocalypse</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Anne Townsend</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael C Doyle</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> seceding from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marshall</ENAMEX>
Efron
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> that will leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">humbled</ENAMEX> and enslaved."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>; return of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Dickinson</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, explaining just when he plans to set off those sarin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas capsules</ENAMEX> he's
carefully hidden around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his eight years</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>.
Do what he says, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>! He's got nothing to lose!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Many responses <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> not as a genuine
womanizer, able to exploit his transient sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> on his own merits, but
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pseudo-womanizer</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consorts</ENAMEX> see him as a sort of moon-faced
paycheck.

            But perhaps his sexual
boasting, while delightfully buffoonish, is a minor crime. Rigorous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-awareness</ENAMEX> is rarely found in bed where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will tell you just about any
damn thing. It is a setting that conspires against self-knowledge: the soft
lights, the kind words, the shape-flattering diaphanous teddy that, frankly,
wouldn't hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>'s whole look. But despite the generous spiritedness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
Quiz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> remains the perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Molière fool</ENAMEX>, supremely confident
of his splendor, supremely unaware that to everyone else he's a cartoon, Le
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bourgeois Gentilhomme</ENAMEX> with a bad haircut. But big where it counts--in the
wallet.

            
               When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatuity Turns</ENAMEX>
to Madness Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> said this about the collapse of the
stock market.

            Apparently, the ongoing
bull market can sustain itself for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more year, right up until the
presidential election, at which time, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> wins, prosperity continues, but
if he loses, the bottom drops out. In making this prediction to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> declined to release details of either
the economic theory or the satanic pact that would make this scenario
possible.

            
               
                  Talk
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine Deathwatch Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Which of the following
are actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX> rationalizations for her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s slide into darkness
(quoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Kuczynski</ENAMEX>), and which are amusing
digs at a debased editorial philosophy built around fawning over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "It takes time for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> to establish its
identity."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "Tough for a print <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> to vie with
Internet's ability to deliver the crass and shallow."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "All <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gwyneth All The Time</ENAMEX> format less popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Harvey Weinstein</ENAMEX> promised."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "It's taken time to organize our approach to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "Still shifting from old editorial policy of
uncritical worship of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> to new policy of enthusiastic
groveling before <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "I should not be absorbed in reading <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> drafts
of an article, which is what I have been doing, which has been my dilemma."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "I should send an assistant out to buy me one of
those dictionary things and then get someone to look up 'dilemma' for me."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth</ENAMEX> wouldn't pose with the donkey."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. "When I saw the success of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue, it
was a crazy wonderful thing, but I knew our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> was too small."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. "We need to make
news and break news about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX>, and that means looking for stories
with a lot of journalistic calories. By which I do not mean that Gwyneth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paltrow</ENAMEX> is fat. She's that other thing. Thin."

            
               Answers
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 4, 6, 9</ENAMEX>, and the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sentence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> minus the words "about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX>" are true
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinaisms</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ongoing Autobio</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are
invited--heck, encouraged; prodded even--to submit the title of a much-needed
but as yet unwritten autobiography of any national political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> lacking
this essential election-year tool. Answers to run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> the pseudo-womanizer; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the real
thing.

         
      
   
