
   
   
      
         
            Does the Net <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Get Politics</ENAMEX>? Ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeeves</ENAMEX>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> who write for the Internet frequently ask: Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician X</ENAMEX> get
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net</ENAMEX>?

            They
find their answers by looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> Web sites, testing their familiarity
with e-mail, and taking their temperature on Net issues, such as e-commerce
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">taxation</ENAMEX> or censorship.

            At Net
Election, though, we have an additional question: Does the Net get
politics?

            As Net
Election has documented, there are a large and growing number of Web sites
dedicated to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics, some of which are lively and informative. But
let's say you come to the Internet without knowing precisely where you want to
go--the position, we assume, of the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. How hard is it to find
solid political sites?

            If you
want general news about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>, the answer is: The Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">excels</ENAMEX>. Go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX> home
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX> , for example, and one of the main <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> categories is "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>."
Click on the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Elections</ENAMEX>" under that, and you're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> clicks away from a
page that contains a slew of info, including breaking news, links to all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">major candidates</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX>'s site, and coverage from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .

            
Curiously, not all the portals we examined make it this easy. At the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>-owned Go.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com ,</ENAMEX>
for example, no words such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, politics, or elections appear on the
front page. And even if you click on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABCNews</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> link, it still doesn't compare to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX>'s
one-stop-shopping page. That's also true for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Excite and Lycos</ENAMEX>.

            But as
you delve more deeply into the issues, the major portals quickly get muddy. Say
you want information on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s proposed overhaul of the health-care
system. Will it harm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> disproportionately because it eliminates
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> has charged? If you enter the words "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> and
health care" into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX>, the engine will actually serve up some relevant sites,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s official campaign site and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homemade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> on the issues
site . On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lycos</ENAMEX>, you get nothing so informative.

            And
heaven forbid you make an error. If, like us, you initially forget to enter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> site that comes up on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX> is for a company
that provides "training, consultation and treatment services for compulsive
gambling and related addictions" in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>

            It's
the sort of non sequitur experience that's all too familiar to Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>. We're
supposed to think: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, these are just dumb machines, after all. They can't
really judge linguistic niceties like context." That's sort of true, but not
entirely. Most search engines don't actually search the Net every time a user
enters words. Rather, they sift through a collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> pages that have
been examined and approved for use by the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s database.
Getting a site approved by a big search engine can take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to six weeks</TIMEX>. Not
surprisingly, the premium real estate on the page that shows you the search
results often goes to those who are willing to pay for it.

            
Another way of saying this is that much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is not really wired to think
the way most political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think--which may be a good thing. There are
useful aggregations of political sites available at places like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> , where you can get
guidance on every issue from animal rights to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s liberation. And there
have been some attempts to build "political portals," such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PoliticsOnline</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .
But while such <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> do a good job of making recent articles and broad-based
resources available, they've yet to combine the Net's strongest
attributes--searchability and multiple information <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>--with political
sophistication. Moreover, typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> aren't apt to stumble upon these
sites. Rather, they would need to know the specific Web addresses already.

            So
while we await the arrival of a truly intelligent political Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, we are
stuck with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ask Jeeves</ENAMEX> ,
which Net <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> consider something of a joke. Ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeeves</ENAMEX> isn't perfect; in
fact, it often exhibits a grasp of reality that falls somewhere between a
database and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Magic 8-Ball</ENAMEX>.

            And
yet, to our surprise, for certain kinds of political searches Ask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeeves</ENAMEX> fared
rather well. For example, we asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeeves</ENAMEX>, "Where can I find information about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>?" The site immediately returned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s official
site, a site for news about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>, information about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, and books about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. Not bad at all.

            Of
course, there are limits. We asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeeves</ENAMEX>: "Why did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> so
much money for advice which, presumably, he could've gotten for free?" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of
the suggested counterquestions were "How much does it cost to use America
Online as an Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Service Provider?</ENAMEX>" and "What should I know about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurant</ENAMEX> wine pricing?"

            To be fair to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeeves</ENAMEX>,
though, we're not sure anyone has a good answer to that question.

         
      
   
