
   
   
      
         
            Heads Up

            
               
                  Sleepy
Hollow
                is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Burton</ENAMEX>'s first full-gallop, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Guignol</ENAMEX>, gutbucket
horror picture. He has always borrowed from the genre, but his scary motifs
were leavened with homey ones--with elements inspired by cartoons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seuss</ENAMEX>,
and tacky <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>-monster flicks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s early <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX>, however
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fantastic</ENAMEX>, had a sadly mundane aura, like the ghosts in Beetlejuice
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>) who looked so silly in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> sheets that they couldn't even
frighten a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. In his new movie, a ghost not only frightens a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, it
beheads him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s take on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Irving</ENAMEX>'s legendary headless horseman
is one of the great nightmare images in movies. Our first glimpse is over his
shoulder as he hurtles through the woods after a fleeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX>. We hear the
scrape of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> as it's unsheathed and barely see it sweep across the frame
and pop the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s noggin into the air--so fast that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> seems to have
been shocked off its torso. The carnage ends before we can exhale.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s imagery has an
ecstatic intensity; it's too bad that the movie--loosely based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irving</ENAMEX>
classic about a ghost who haunts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson Valley</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX> after
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Revolution</ENAMEX>--has been constructed as a sort of proto- Hound of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baskervilles</ENAMEX> . In the screenplay, credited to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Kevin Walker</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>) but reportedly rewritten by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Stoppard</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">schoolteacher Ichabod Crane</ENAMEX> is now a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> constable (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Depp</ENAMEX>) who
travels upstate to solve a series of beheadings using the fledgling sciences of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pathology</ENAMEX> and deduction. The idea is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crane</ENAMEX> clings to scientific principle
in the face of the supernatural--he dumbfounds the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> by insisting that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">killer</ENAMEX> is human and appalls them by performing an autopsy on a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>.
(I was looking forward to the first thriller in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages</TIMEX> without yucko autopsies,
but there's no dodging them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>.) It soon becomes apparent that solving
the mystery will require a blend of reason and superstition--a mighty
stretch for a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose life is pledged to rationalism and whose
unconscious roils with visions of his free-spirited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Marie</ENAMEX>) being
brutalized by a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>-black tyrant" of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. The script, a bare-bones
affair with amusingly movieish period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">diction</TIMEX> ("What manner of instruments are
these?"), mixes bargain-basement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freudianism</ENAMEX> with less whodunit savvy than an
average episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder, She Wrote</ENAMEX> .

            But you don't go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Burton</ENAMEX> picture for the narrative
riches; you go because no one else packs this kind of emotion into a movie's
design. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleepy Hollow</ENAMEX> is a ferocious yet lyrical piece of filmmaking--an
enchanted bloodbath. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ichabod</ENAMEX>'s fever dream, his mother <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">levitates</ENAMEX> and twirls
amid snowy blossoms, and all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burton</ENAMEX>'s feeling for his paramour, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Marie</ENAMEX>,
comes through--he paints her as the most vulnerable of spellcasters. You know
from the start you're in a grand playpen for horror <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX>--full of mists,
covered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>, glowing pumpkin-head scarecrows, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oaks</ENAMEX> that seem frozen
in death throes. In the haunted western woods, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crane</ENAMEX> and his juvenile assistant
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Pickering</ENAMEX>, who resembles a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>) tromp over dead leaves while
above them the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bare trees</ENAMEX> bend together at their tops like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gothic</ENAMEX> arches.

            The great production
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Heinrichs</ENAMEX> has built an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> village from the
ground up. His palette (and that of the costume <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Atwood</ENAMEX>) is
white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">on ash</ENAMEX>, gray on dusty brown, ebony on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX>--the better to set off the
lurid splashes of crimson. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ichabod Crane</ENAMEX> walks through small doorways into
dark-toned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> where pasty old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in white wigs stare at him balefully and
whisper in one another's ears, their bloated waistcoats jiggling. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baltus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Tassel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Gambon</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>, intones the story of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hessian</ENAMEX> who lopped the heads off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX> for sheer love of
butchery, the flashback is mythic in its ghastliness: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Walken</ENAMEX>--his
hair swept up, with boiled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> for eyes and teeth like sharp spikes--wheels,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hacks</ENAMEX>, impales, and drenches the snow with gore. He's the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX> I've
seen in a movie who does justice to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macbeth</ENAMEX>'s terrible "whiles I see lives, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gashes/</ENAMEX> Do better upon them".

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> has learned a lot about staging and editing action
since the relatively crude martial-arts battles of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">horseman</ENAMEX> is like a samurai <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terminator</ENAMEX>; dismounted, he comes at his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">relentlessly</ENAMEX>, from all angles. (I don't know if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walken</ENAMEX> also plays the horseman
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sans head</ENAMEX>; if he doesn't, someone has done a hilarious job of recreating
his chesty swagger.) Visually and aurally, the attack scenes are built :
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Leaves rustle</ENAMEX>, torches go out in curly wisps of smoke, hoofbeats start softly
and end up pounding your head. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Elfman</ENAMEX>'s crashing gongs and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chopping-blade</ENAMEX> strings pound your head, too.) The comic touches deepen the
horror. In the first killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ichabod</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> doesn't just
fly off--it spins like a dervish and bounces between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ichabod</ENAMEX>'s legs, where the
passing horseman skewers it like a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marshmallow</ENAMEX>. As he thunders off, he knocks a
small scarecrow, which spins around--the perfect "button" for the sequence.
Then <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ichabod</ENAMEX> keels over in a dead faint.

            This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Depp</ENAMEX>'s most ingratiating performance, a
marvelous blend of passion and parody. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ichabod</ENAMEX> is a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> making like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Basil Rathbone</ENAMEX>. Puffed-up with conceit, he takes in a new piece of evidence by
raising his eyebrows, expelling a "hmmm," and spinning around to announce his
latest theory to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> who regard him with a mixture of awe and embarrassment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> relishes squirting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> in this know-it-all's face: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ichabod</ENAMEX> is the
movie's dashing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> and also the butt of its jokes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Depp</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina Ricci</ENAMEX>,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Von Tassel</ENAMEX>'s witchy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, are everything you could hope for in a
storybook <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>. It's too bad <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ricci</ENAMEX>'s dry, flat voice--so wonderful in modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comedies</ENAMEX>, when it plays against those saucer eyes and angel-baby
features--sounds amateurish amid all these declamatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s work in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleepy Hollow</ENAMEX> is transporting, but not, it should be said, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX> circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1799</TIMEX>. We're actually in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1950s and the '60s</TIMEX>,
when a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hammer Films</ENAMEX> was churning out cheap but ritzy-looking
Gothic melodramas. In all of them, scenes of repressive formality (hoary
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> sipping sherry in drawing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>) would be shattered by scenes of
Dionysian release (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX> or some other fanged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> swooping down in an
animalistic frenzy), and an aristocratic figure of both science and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX>--usually the crisply self-satisfied <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Cushing</ENAMEX>--would show up to
lecture the frightened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villagers</ENAMEX> and pound a stake through the heaving bosom of
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">temptress</ENAMEX>. Cushing, alas, is gone, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> has cast Hammer stalwarts
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Lee</ENAMEX> in a (too brief) cameo as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">burgomaster</ENAMEX> who dispatches <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crane</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleepy Hollow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Gough</ENAMEX> (also seen as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX>
films) as a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX>. He has duplicated some memorable <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hammer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compositions</ENAMEX> and has gotten the tone of those old pictures just right. Like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>, I was weaned on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hammer</ENAMEX> horror; I raise a goblet of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> to him for
bringing it all so blissfully back.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who go see the documentary 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Movie
               , directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Smith</ENAMEX> and produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Price</ENAMEX>, will expect
to revisit the title character of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Wood</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>), a stumblebum
who maintained a cockeyed optimism--and obliviousness--in the face of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infinitesimal</ENAMEX> budgets and what amounted to an anti-talent for continuity. But
the film, the story of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moviemaker</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borchardt</ENAMEX> and his efforts to finish a no-budget horror short called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coven</ENAMEX> (which he mispronounces throughout, with a long "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">o"</ENAMEX>), turns into
something much fuller--and much less easy to laugh off. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protagonist</ENAMEX> isn't oblivious. He has a surfeit of self-loathing, disparaging his
work even as he struggles to get it on screen. In debt and with a couple of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to support, juggling jobs as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery custodian</ENAMEX> and a paper boy,
Borchardt oscillates between a tendency to "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX> and dream" and a drive to
"create and compete." With an extended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that regards him--not apparently
without reason--as a dreamer and a bull <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borchardt</ENAMEX> sometimes comes off
like God's loneliest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.

            The documentary begins
with his attempt to cast a feature called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwestern</ENAMEX> , which seems
meant as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cri de coeur</ENAMEX> for a generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">druggies</ENAMEX>. When he
can't raise the money and concludes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aesthetically</ENAMEX>, I'm not ready," Borchardt
hauls the abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coven</ENAMEX> out of mothballs in spite of its "stilted"
performances and sets about the seemingly impossible task of raising money to
finish it. Most of those funds will come from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borchardt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> and skeletal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uncle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, who lives in a ramshackle trailer but has evidently managed to
sock away <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of thousands of dollars</NUMEX>. The attempt to wheedle money out of
the caustic and not-quite-there old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is the real glory of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Movie . As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borchardt</ENAMEX> shows Bill pictures of pretty actresses, offers him a
credit as an "executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>," buys him <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX>, and promises big profits and
glory down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> ("I see great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> in this." "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cinnamon?</ENAMEX>"), their
relationship becomes a bleak, absurdist parody of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moneymen</ENAMEX>. And yet, somehow, it ends warmly--even beautifully--for both.

            As I watched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Movie</ENAMEX> , a lot of it struck me
as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">untranscendent misery</ENAMEX>. But in hindsight it seems less hopeless. That might
be because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Price</ENAMEX>'s smart and compassionate work has given Borchardt
and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohorts</ENAMEX> a measure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>, which removes the sting of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">nonentity-ness.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> who visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Movie</ENAMEX> Web site will find
such features as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borchardt's</ENAMEX> daily diary and a phone number for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
Schank, a lovable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualty</ENAMEX> and talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX>--"If he's home and in the
mood he'll pick up." Ain't the Internet grand?) The vision may also seem less
grim because when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coven</ENAMEX> finally premieres, at the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Movie , the images we're shown from it have a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Romero</ENAMEX>-ish
graphic power--not at all what we expect from the comically inept production
process. Without seeing his work all the way through, it's hard for me to say
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borchardt</ENAMEX> has talent, but he might not be such a stumblebum after
all.

            Already, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the three years</TIMEX> since this documentary
was shot, digital technology has made moviemaking at this level more
affordable--which means that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> for impoverished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmakers</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borchardt</ENAMEX> will soon be less grueling. But there will be a lot--a
lot --more of them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Movie</ENAMEX> suggests that there's no such
thing as "the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the hinterlands" anymore. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Dream</ENAMEX> has
become making movies. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Movie</ENAMEX> is a hit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Dream</ENAMEX>
might become making movies about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Dream</ENAMEX> of making movies.

         
      
   
