
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers for Negative Campaigning</ENAMEX> 

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Leadership Council</ENAMEX> began running an ad that accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> of "tearing down his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> fired back at the RLC
with his own ad: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> says he wants a positive campaign. Then why
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal supporters</ENAMEX> running this negative ad attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>?"
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> press release added, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes Calls on Bush To Cease 'Politics</ENAMEX> of
Personal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Destruction</ENAMEX>' Against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>." Meanwhile, in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> denounced each other's "personal
attacks" and "scare tactics." Everyone is accusing everyone else of negative
campaigning, but nobody's answering the question that ought to come first:
What's wrong with negative campaigning? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> pretend to
explain this through a series of platitudes, none of which are convincing.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Be nice. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RLC</ENAMEX> says it's trying to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> "civil"
by pressuring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> to maintain a high "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenor</ENAMEX>." Its ad says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> needs to be
taught "If he doesn't have anything nice to say, don't say anything at all."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> gets a similar lecture from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , which accuses
him of forsaking his "pledge of chivalry" by criticizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s modest
proposals for health care and gun control. But what's so great about being nice
or chivalrous? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is running on a timid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> designed to
avoid political heat rather than to solve problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> thinks the same of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. If they're right, the worst thing they can do for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is to
refrain from pointing out these failings. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is accused of getting
"angry." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is much nicer. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s health-care
plan would bust the budget, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> answered, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>
reserves his anger for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> without health insurance." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> might
have served those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> better by directing his anger at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
misrepresentations. But that would have been impolite.)

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Stay clean. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> asks whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
criticisms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s policies belie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s professed "rectitude," his
"desire to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-</ENAMEX>clean," and "his image as an above-the-fray <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>."
But where's the virtue in such aloofness? Why should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> get credit for
keeping his hands clean and preserving his above-the-fray image if, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX>
alleges, he has achieved this by letting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RLC</ENAMEX> do his dirty work? And
shouldn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> get credit, by comparison, for striding into the fray and
leveling his charges squarely at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>?

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Be positive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> of offering "attacks"
instead of a "positive vision," based on the calculation that it's "easier to
campaign against your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> than for yourself." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> illustrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s more "positive" style. While
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">endorsing Bradley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> insisted, "I won't say anything negative about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>." What nonsense. Anyone who endorses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is saying something
negative about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. Since elections are comparative, the difference between
campaigning "against your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>" and campaigning "for yourself" is semantic.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> says he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> of big ideas and poll-free principles,
he's being just as negative as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Don't hurt others. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> and wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> love
to equate criticism with assault. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s strategy is "attack,
attack, attack, attack." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RLC</ENAMEX> decry each other's "attack ads."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> "became known as a slash-and-burn
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> for his commercials that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lacerated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mimicking Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, calls questions about whether he used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> "the
politics of personal destruction." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> bashing" at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> debate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> adviser
fears <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> will "get out the blowtorch and go after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>." All this sounds
awful, until you remember that nobody has been attacked, bashed, slashed,
burned, blowtorched, lacerated, or destroyed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> leveled charges about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s record that could be--and were--rebutted. The "bashing" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> endured in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> debate consisted largely of the observation that he had failed to
show up. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> turned out to be guilty of the central allegation in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> still hasn't answered the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> questions. The
truth often hurts. It ought to be told anyway.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Don't get personal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has alluded several times to
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> fund-raising scandal. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, he cited published reports
that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> are being asked to arrange their
travel schedules and public announcements so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> can finance his
political campaign with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> dollars when his funds run out." Rather than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rebut Bradley</ENAMEX>'s allegation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> huffed, "Personal attacks have no place in a
campaign." But isn't a campaign exactly the place where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> should be
confronted if he has indeed abused his position and violated the spirit of the
campaign finance laws? How can <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> point out another's misdeeds without
getting personal?

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Don't throw the first punch. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thinks Bradley</ENAMEX> crossed a moral line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> when he began to criticize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
on his own initiative rather than "in response to attacks by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
agrees that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who has been criticized is uniquely entitled to respond
in kind. Running a positive campaign, he argues, "doesn't mean I'm going to
stand like this forever and let someone slap my face." But why does it matter
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> first? This is a debate, not a fistfight. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> can explain why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> would be an inferior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, why should he have
to wait to say so?

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Don't be insensitive. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> began airing an ad
in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> says: "When I was pregnant with my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>
proposed a law that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> be allowed to stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX>.
Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is alive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>." When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> pointed out
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s bill hadn't passed until after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was born,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign of displaying "a real insensitivity" by
challenging the ad. "I am appalled that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would attack a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who
obviously lived through tremendous trauma, has her views, and expressed them,"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. Never mind whether the ad is true. To raise that question is to
"attack a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Don't scare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has been telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and
Hispanics that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s health-care plan would kill <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> and provide no
sufficient alternative. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> calls this a "scare tactic" and says it's
"wrong" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is "using race or ethnicity to try to scare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." But if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s assertion is true, what's wrong with conveying it to the ethnic groups
most broadly affected? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> isn't calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> a racist. He's making an
economic argument, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> can rebut and has rebutted. The "scare tactic"
charge, which implies that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is using fear and rhetoric to bypass rational
scrutiny, is itself a scare tactic.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Don't be divisive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> of "poisoning the
atmosphere" with "divisiveness." "I believe the public wants solutions that
work, not attacks that divide," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> boasts that he's
"a uniter, not a divider," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RLC</ENAMEX> complains that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, by criticizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, caused "fighting within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> that was divisive
and not inclusive." Imagine that--fighting and divisiveness in an election.
What's wrong with informing certain segments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> that your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> is using the feel-good rhetoric of "solutions" to pull a fast one at
their expense? If you're lying, shame on you. But if you're telling the truth,
why does it matter that your message is divisive?

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Don't hurt your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RLC</ENAMEX> ad says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> "hurt the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> and will "help the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> by criticizing
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Nicholson</ENAMEX> vows to
"blow the whistle on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>" who "tear down other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>." Meanwhile,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is taking heat for questioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign-finance practices. In
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">good old days</TIMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> "was more restrained,"
declining "to comment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising behavior."
But why should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> shut up about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> fund-raising scandal? And
why should <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> shut up about what he regards as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">betrayal</ENAMEX> of
conservatism? Does loyalty to party supersede loyalty to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>?

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. Don't alienate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> frets that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s attacks
on his health-care plan will "alienate the public" and foster skepticism toward
big programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Ireland</ENAMEX> warns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> that
"negative campaigning depresses the women's vote." On the bright side, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>'
campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> says <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> is "much less likely" to "run the same
kind of negative spots that he did against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>," because "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX> he
was a message <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. Now he believes he can be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." But what's wrong
with "alienating" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> from bad programs and bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>? And isn't it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nobler</ENAMEX> to deliver a depressingly true "message" than to shade the truth so you
can get elected?

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. Don't practice
politics as usual. Just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> of playing sneaky
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> politics" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> now castigates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> for resorting to the
typical "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> politics" of slash and burn. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is delighted to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reciprocate</ENAMEX>. "There goes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> again, acting like a typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>,
launching negative attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> spokesman crowed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. How
does the fact that such attacks are "typical" clarify whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is right
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> or vice versa? Never mind. All you need to know is that negative
campaigning is the oldest trick in the book. And the next oldest trick, if you
can't answer the charge, is to whine about negative campaigning.

         
      
   
