
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> who most interested the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>
at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Way</ENAMEX>" summit conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, and various <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> vainly sought a common
political platform for the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> of the center-left. They were not
very kind about her. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that she failed to make a widely
anticipated speech because she has made so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gaffes</ENAMEX> lately and that her
decision to sit in on the conference as a nonparticipant resulted in a special
program for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> being canceled "at the last moment with zero
warning and zero courtesy."

            

               Corriere della
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was upstaged by the pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cherie Blair</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>. "It was to have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">triumph</ENAMEX>, her consecration as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>, her takeoff
point for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> seat in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.
"Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> was obscured twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> on the Florentine
stage by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cherie Blair</ENAMEX>, who with her pregnancy became the protagonist of the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> Way conference, and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> electoral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> where a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the city council, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronnie Eldridge</ENAMEX>, declared in a loud
voice what many think but have till now only murmured--that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>
should withdraw her candidacy."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere</ENAMEX> also ran a story about visits by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea Clinton</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> to a market of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> luxury goods held in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">foyer</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florence</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excelsior Hotel</ENAMEX>. The headline was "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Albright</ENAMEX> cannot resist
Florentine jewels." It said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX> much admired a white linen
tablecloth but rejected it on learning its price was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $2,500</NUMEX>. She then
bought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> purses and a candle before arriving at the jewelry stand. "They
gave her a discount, but the most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in the world knows how to
value the weight and the worth of things," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "Before signing for
the purchase of a choker, she weighed it against the bracelet she was wearing
on her wrist: It is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as heavy as the choker."

            On the
substance of the summit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere</ENAMEX> noted in an editorial "the profoundly
different realities" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> on the one hand and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">continental Europe</ENAMEX> on the other. The arduous search for common policies to
reconcile the "solidaristic" social values of the left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> of the
continent with the rules of the free market will continue long after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere</ENAMEX> reported <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> urging
everyone to imitate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> model, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> highlighted a
speech by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s socialist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lionel Jospin</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Way</ENAMEX> skeptic,
in which he denounced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> retention of the death penalty. "We must be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">irreproachable</ENAMEX> in raising the problem of human rights in developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
by defending them with great rigor in our own," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jospin</ENAMEX> said. "And for this I
would like to see the death penalty disappear in all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracies</ENAMEX>."

            One
issue preoccupying the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> was where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cherie Blair</ENAMEX>'s
forthcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> was conceived--was it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX> or in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> during their
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer vacation</TIMEX>? Fending off questions about this in an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
Repubblica , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> admitted that he thought it would be a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fevered</ENAMEX> study of the diaries of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> led most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers to conclude that their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, due <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next May</TIMEX> when Cherie
will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> short of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46 years old</TIMEX>, must have been conceived while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> were staying with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth II</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balmoral</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
Mirror even published a photograph <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> in which it
claimed the conception had taken place.

            Far
the biggest story in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, however, was the disgrace of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire novelist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord Jeffrey Archer</ENAMEX>, who was forced to resign at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> as the chosen
Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> after being exposed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> for using a false alibi in a libel
action <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer</ENAMEX> won <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $750,000</NUMEX> in damages against tabloid
newspaper the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Star</ENAMEX> after it alleged that he had consorted with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer</ENAMEX> now faces possible criminal charges after admitting to
getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> to lie that they had dined together in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
the evenings in question. In editorials <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, almost all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> sharply
criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Hague</ENAMEX> for supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer</ENAMEX>'s
candidacy and praising his probity despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>'s controversial past
and warnings that he had further skeletons in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX>.

            As
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s successful launch into orbit of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shenzhou</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spacecraft</ENAMEX> received
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">saturation</ENAMEX> coverage in the state-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> press, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> military
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Business Times</ENAMEX> that the test had major military
implications. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Song Yichang</ENAMEX> said that the same low-power propulsion technology
used to adjust a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spacecraft</ENAMEX>'s orbit in flight could also be used to alter the
path of offensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, thus enabling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to overcome <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> anti-missile
defenses.

ran a commentary by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corbin Andrews</ENAMEX> saying that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other men
who died on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 22, 1963</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.S. Lewis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aldous Huxley</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Poulenc</ENAMEX>--"made contributions to our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> that far outweigh
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> said, "His legacy holds power only because it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">symbolic of America's</ENAMEX> lost innocence. His assassination marks the point when
the bubble burst and we finally realized there could never be a heaven on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huxley</ENAMEX> had been telling us that all along."

         
      
   
