
   
   
      
         
             Does <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crime Pay</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Criminals</ENAMEX>, by and large, must be
risk-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>--otherwise they'd be car-wash <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>.
Lottery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, by and large, must be risk-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>--otherwise they'd buy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bonds instead of lottery tickets. You might be tempted to conclude
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and lottery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> are often the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. That's probably
the wrong conclusion. After all, risk-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> enjoy having all their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> in one
basket, which suggests they should pursue either crime or the lottery, but not
both.

            Still, if you want to understand what attracts
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to crime, it pays to understand what attracts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to risky activities
more generally, so it pays to understand what attracts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to the
lottery.

            Lotteries are attractive when they offer big prizes
or (relatively) good odds. If you're running a lottery and you're going to pay
out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX>, you can offer a single <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> jackpot or you can offer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
prizes of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> each. Which is more appealing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>? Usually, the
former. For the most part, lottery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> prefer a small chance of a big
payout to a bigger chance of a smaller payout. That's because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
prefer a bigger chance of a smaller payout are buying certificates of deposit,
not lottery tickets. So if you want to make the lottery more attractive, it's
better to double the size of the jackpot than to double the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>.

            (More precisely,
doubling the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> makes the lottery more attractive to the sort of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who never buys lottery tickets anyway, while doubling the jackpot makes
it more attractive to the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who might actually be tempted to
play.)

            Now let's apply the same reasoning to criminal deterrence.
For the most part, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> prefer a small chance of a big punishment to a big
chance of a small punishment. That's because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who prefer a big chance
of a small punishment go into punishing careers like construction work or coal
mining instead of crime. So if you want to make crime less attractive to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>, it's better to double the odds of conviction than to double the
severity of the punishment.

            Add <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> to the
length of the average jail sentence and crime will fall. Add <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> to the
conviction rate instead and crime will fall even further. Like any risk-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> are out to beat the odds, so they get particularly demoralized when
the odds turn against them.

            So much for the theory; now to the facts. What's true of
the lottery should be true at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">racetrack</ENAMEX>. And gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maury</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX> confirms that if you're designing a complicated bet like a trifecta, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to generate the most action per dollar's worth of prize money (and hence
the most profit for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX>) is to offer very large prizes at very long odds.
Why, then, do the tracks continue to offer bets with much smaller payoffs?
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX>, it's because big prize winners take their money and go home
while small prize winners plow their winnings back into the next race. That
sets up an interesting trade-off for the track <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> big prize maximizes
profit on the current race, while several small prizes maximize the action on
the next race. Interesting as that trade-off may be, it's largely irrelevant to
the main point, which is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> like big prizes and long odds. (On
another interesting tangent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX> asked me whether there's something
inherently corrupt about a system where the proceeds from state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX> are
used to fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> that then have an incentive to produce the kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who will go out and play the lottery.)

            With regard to crime,
let's consider the most spectacular of all crimes, murder. Here the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Ehrlich</ENAMEX>, who, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'70s</TIMEX>, pioneered the use of
sophisticated statistical techniques to measure deterrent effects of conviction
and punishment. Together with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhiqiang Liu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehrlich</ENAMEX> has recently
revisited the subject, refuting his most vocal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> and offering new
evidence in support of his original conclusion: Increase the number of
convictions by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> and (to a very rough approximation) the murder rate
falls by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 1 percent</NUMEX>. Increase the number of executions by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> (which
amounts to increasing the severity of the average punishment) and (again to a
very rough approximation) the murder rate falls by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX>. (These
numbers are based on evidence from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s and 1950s</TIMEX>. Capital punishment
studies tend to focus on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> with more executions and hence more data.) As
the theory predicts, convictions matter more than punishments.

            That's not to say that punishments don't matter. Executions
may be a less-effective deterrent than convictions, but they are nevertheless
an extremely powerful deterrent; according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehrlich</ENAMEX>'s numbers, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> additional
execution in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> could well have prevented over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> murders.

            I am grateful to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehrlich</ENAMEX> for that amazingly strong
result, because I use it to illustrate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> points that I'm always eager to
drive home to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. First, incentives matter, even to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,
economic theory predicts that some incentives matter more than others, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> confirm the theory: Executions prevent murders, but convictions prevent
even more murders. And finally, if you want to give policy advice, it's not
enough to know your numbers. You've also got to know your values. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehrlich</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who proved to the satisfaction of the economics profession
that capital punishment works, is a passionate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of capital
punishment.

         
      
   
