
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Novel Predicament</ENAMEX>

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               An old and trusted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>," who lives in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and works in television suggested I send her the manuscript of a
novel I wrote because she had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who knows an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> who was looking for
works by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. I sent the manuscript and waited for a response.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> reported to me that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> loved the book. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Months</TIMEX> passed without
further information. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> told me that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> she gave my book to
turns out to be a psycho, and she doubts whether this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> even had an agent
in mind when she requested my manuscript. She apparently had a crush on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>,
who says she has since cut off all contact with her.
            

            
               My problem is that I
want my manuscript back, and while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> apologized profusely for the way things
went, she refuses to retrieve it for me, saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> would
misconstrue this as an overture. I hesitate to contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> myself,
because I don't want to get in the middle of a weird situation. I also get the
impression that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> thinks that her being upset supersedes any responsibility
she has for getting my book back.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bruised and Confused</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Apple</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Bruise</ENAMEX>,

            Guess what? You've been
had. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ditto for Jane</ENAMEX>. As for getting your manuscript back, it's pretty clear
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> isn't going to ask, and you don't want to, so let's try <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s
standby: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> letter. Surely you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> who would
write a formal letter to Psycho With a Crush requesting the return of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manuscript</ENAMEX>. That way, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psycho WAC</ENAMEX> will not have any information about how to
reach you, merely the address of a law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. Even nut cases (usually) pay
attention to letters from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. This is your best shot. Whether you choose
to continue your friendship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> or not is another issue, but Prudie
wonders why you would let your <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and only copy of a manuscript out of your
hands. Let's hope this experience has advanced your education from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psycho</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinko</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, hopefully

            
               
                  Dear
Pru,
               
            

            
               This is kind of a
different problem from what I've seen in your column, but here goes: I am not
yet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> and continue to move up in my rather buttoned-up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, where most of
the male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> are married to, shall we say, plain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> I am
seeing now, like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> before her, has--and this isn't politically correct--a
major pair of hooters. You might say this is my "type." She is very well
spoken, has a good job, and is not a bimbo by any stretch of the imagination.
She just has these ... well, anyway, they're attention-getting. What is the
best way to deal with this?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Junior Exec</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Junior</ENAMEX>,

            You and your breasted
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>--to be politically correct--need not feel there is anything
wrong with her centerfold figure. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would suggest, however, since you are
on your way up the corporate ladder in a "buttoned-up industry" that your
ladyfriend not dress them up so that undue attention is directed their way.
Conservative clothing at business-related functions ought to put you both at
ease.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, modestly

            

               
                  Prudie,
               
            

            
               When a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, in
the process of seeking your advice, reveals rather personal foibles, should you
not be alerted to the probability that such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is quite apt to be a
whacko, weirdo, misfit, or plain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loser</ENAMEX>? Then again, such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> could be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bright Yale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> who is demonstrably adept at putting on advice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX>.
I guess my question really is: How can you tell whether a letter is sincere or
fraudulent?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.E.L.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelbume</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vt.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear R.E.</ENAMEX>,

            You can't tell, though
some things have the ring of truth, and others don't. Let's call it instinct.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> feels sure you would agree that whackos, weirdoes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">misfits</ENAMEX>, or losers
have need of advice--as do bright <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. So what's the problem?

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, problematically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I need to address
your answer to the "grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grazer</ENAMEX>" question. "" should have spoken to
the store <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> about the stealing. We are trained to handle cases of this
sort in the following way: We would put a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> within sight of the customer
who's stealing without actually confronting her. If she hesitates for anything,
we would then ask her if she needed any help ... again, letting her know she is
being watched without accusing her of anything. Also, the security cameras
would be "watching" the whole time, as well. This procedure would be repeated
whenever she is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. This is designed to make her a little
uncomfortable about stealing from us while at the same time keeping a paying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. We cannot take any action without seeing the stealing
ourselves. If we didn't do it this way, we would have more lawsuits than we
could handle--and lose a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> besides. Neither of these things is
good for business. Thank you for listening to me.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">W.D.W.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear W.D.</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> and countless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who had something to say about this thank you for the information about
how store <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to deal with this problem. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wrote to say they
believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> should have been reported, and a few pointed out the hygiene
aspect: that scoops are there for a reason--hands carry germs. If enough
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> become familiar with the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> deal with grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grazers</ENAMEX>,
perhaps these pilferers can be "encouraged" to cut it out.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, gratefully

         
      
   
