
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Depp Man</ENAMEX> Walking 

            
               Movies

            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleepy Hollow</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). Strong reviews tempered by
warnings of excessive gore for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Burton</ENAMEX>'s adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irving</ENAMEX>'s classic headless-horseman tale. The art direction, costume design, and
photography are top-notch: "It's the most gorgeous, sumptuous, painterly movie
ever made about multiple decapitations" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Giles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX>
Depp, playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ichabod Crane</ENAMEX> as an effete <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> sent to get to the
bottom of a rash of beheadings, shines (or more accurately, is appropriately
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pallid</ENAMEX>). As his love interest, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina Ricci</ENAMEX> is not so well received; she
seems less adept at blending into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th century</TIMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Depp</ENAMEX> is. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">To</ENAMEX>
catch a glimpse of the tremendously creepy sets, visit the film's official
site.)

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World Is Not Enough</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Artists</ENAMEX>). The usual fun Bond
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fluff</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce Brosnan</ENAMEX> doing his best turn <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as 007</TIMEX> yet--though he's still
nowhere near the caliber of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> calls it a "splendid
comic thriller" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). The chases are inventive (skis,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">powerboats</ENAMEX>), the double-entendres apt (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bond</ENAMEX> if he'd like to
"check her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX>"), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> beautiful (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise Richards</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sophie Marceau</ENAMEX>),
and the plot irrelevant (something about oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pipelines</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say that this
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>--No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> in the series--comes in above average but isn't a classic. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here to find out
everything you ever wanted to know about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bond</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberty Heights</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Levinson</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> picture (after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diner</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tin Men</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avalon</ENAMEX> ) gets
wildly inconsistent reviews. The film follows a collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> from
different ethnic and economic backgrounds (ranging from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WASPy</ENAMEX> country-clubbers
to middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> who have recently been integrated via forced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">busing</ENAMEX>) as they mix in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX> of the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> calls the plot "schematic" and "synthetic" and says the film "loses
its way." But at the other end of the spectrum, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd McCarthy</ENAMEX> raves in
Variety that it's "a grand slam" and proclaims it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinson</ENAMEX>'s best film
yet. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to
find out more about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  All About My Mother
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox Film Corp.</ENAMEX>).
After winning Best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX> and making a splash at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Film</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Festival</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro Almodóvar</ENAMEX>'s ode to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> opens to gushing praise: "the most
moving film of his career" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). A single mother
whose teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is suddenly killed makes a pilgrimage to track down the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and in the process encounters <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> from all walks of
life--transsexuals, pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nuns</ENAMEX>, divas, and more. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>'s most famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filmmaker</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Almodóvar</ENAMEX> directed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Women on the Verge of a Nervous Breakdown</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tie Me Up</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tie Me Down</ENAMEX>! , among others--demonstrates what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX> calls "a newly sophisticated style that is far more passionate, wise,
and deeply felt" than his previous work ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (This page has biographical
information and a filmography for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Almodóvar</ENAMEX>.)

            
               Books

            

            

               
                  Timeline
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Crichton</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). Crichton
( <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jurassic Park</ENAMEX> ) follows his usual <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">MO: Turn</ENAMEX> a scientific concept into a
hi-tech thriller with loads of action and bare-bones <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. This time a
sort of quantum <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3-D</NUMEX> fax machine with the ability to digitize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and send
them back in time is at the heart of the story. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crichton</ENAMEX> isn't nearly as
interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and their inner workings as he is in things and their
inner workings," but that doesn't stop the book from being fun to read: "It's
the geeky stuff, in fact, that makes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Crichton</ENAMEX>'s books so hugely entertaining"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Mendelsohn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> can't
work up any excitement, labeling it just another "dull time-travel tale" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
Poniewozik, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ) that is bound for the movies. "His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are only
insubstantial shadows on a screen and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timeline</ENAMEX> is not a novel, but a
shooting script" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dyer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crichton</ENAMEX>'s official
site includes an excerpt from the book.)

            
               
                  Double Down:
Reflections on Gambling and Loss
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Barthelme</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barthelme</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houghton Mifflin</ENAMEX>). Uniformly first-rate reviews for this memoir of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, who become obsessed with gambling
after their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' deaths: "superb and horrifying" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom De Haven</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ); "an exquisitely crafted memoir of their three
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in the grips of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Gubernick</ENAMEX>, the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ). Not only is their story surprising, but the ending is a real
doozy: They are charged with conspiring to cheat at blackjack, even though they
have managed to lose their entire <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> inheritance in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just three years</TIMEX>.
(The charges have since been dropped.) "What Double Down teaches that
other memoirs don't--preoccupied as they tend to be with the triumph of the
individual--is that while we're busy playing with life, life is playing with us
as well" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kirn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chat</ENAMEX>
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 7</TIMEX>.)

         
      
   
