
   
   
      
         
             Regis Philbin

            The hottest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> with
no discernible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> who is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66 years old</TIMEX>--that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">462</NUMEX> in TV <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> is the most detested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> on television, and whose claims to fame are
an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> game show that no one wins ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Wants To Be a Millionaire?</ENAMEX> )
and a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> talk show where nothing happens ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live With Regis & Kathie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> ). Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regis Philbin</ENAMEX> deserves all his acclaim and more.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regis</ENAMEX> has not come from
nowhere. He has come from everywhere. Until he hit big with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live</ENAMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '80s</TIMEX>, he was the quintessential loser, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">also-ran</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notre Dame</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX>, he got his start in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '60s</TIMEX> hosting a talk show
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, and spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next quarter century</TIMEX> anchoring shows in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. Periodically, these stints would be
interrupted by a shot at the big time, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regis</ENAMEX> would invariably blow. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>, he succeeded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Allen</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westinghouse</ENAMEX>'s marquee late-night
show. It flopped, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philbin</ENAMEX> was dumped for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merv Griffin</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '60s</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philbin</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joey Bishop</ENAMEX>'s sidekick on another doomed
late-night show. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Carson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tonight Show</ENAMEX> spanked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bishop</ENAMEX> in the
ratings. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'70s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philbin</ENAMEX> bombed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> of a couple of game shows. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, he tanked as anchor of a national <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> program. No one could explain
why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regis</ENAMEX> didn't work. He was too spastic perhaps--"just a nerve ending" as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Zehme</ENAMEX>, who co-wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philbin</ENAMEX>'s delightful autobiography, puts it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regis</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, took over a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
show, hooked up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee Gifford</ENAMEX> (then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee Johnson</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
later, and went national with the show in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>. Live has been a monster
hit ever since. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX> quickly became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> of ridicule, the
embodiment of unhip. He was the toothy moron; she, the unbearable crooner.
Live sounds like a joke, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour of nothing: 20 minutes</TIMEX> of "host chat"
between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX>, celebrity interviews, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame stunts</ENAMEX>, a trivia
question. Watch it once, and it seems pathetic. Watch it twice, and you begin
to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>.

            As host of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live</ENAMEX>
(or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millionaire</ENAMEX> , or anything else he has ever done), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regis</ENAMEX> displays no
evident talent. He does not interview <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> well. He does not tell jokes. He
lacks empathy. He displays no particular intelligence. He speaks in a bizarre
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX>, equal parts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX>, sinus, and helium.

            So why is he the most watchable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on television? In
the autobiography, I'm Only <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Man</ENAMEX> , he explains his success this way:
"I started small and learned to keep it small. Small is friendlier and more
real. Small lasts <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">longer</TIMEX>." This captures one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regis</ENAMEX>' gifts. He has a modest
but captivating comic persona. He is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of umbrage. Walloped by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of rejection, failure, and sidekickdom, he has perfected the persona
of the aggrieved little guy. His hyperactivity has mellowed, but not too much.
In "host chat," his specialty, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regis</ENAMEX> turns the mundane details of his life--a
lost wallet, a urinary-tract problem, a disagreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live</ENAMEX> 's
producer--into comic gems. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> mask their insecurity with ego.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regis</ENAMEX> shares his insecurity. (He can take offense at anything.) He is cotton
candy, spinning TV <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> out of thin air.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX>, endlessly chipper and extra-perfect,
serves as superb foil for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regis</ENAMEX>' peevishness. He jabs her, mocking her singing
and her tedious stories about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. She punches right back. It is an
amusingly petty domestic drama, enacted every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regis</ENAMEX>' comic persona
reinforces his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> gift: a perfect relationship with the camera. No one
talks to the screen better than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regis</ENAMEX>. "He is the last of the true broadcasters
who can go on the air and spout about nothing," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zehme</ENAMEX>. "He is never at a
loss to speak to the camera as if it were you." This is one reason why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letterman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX>, and other TV celebs idolize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reege</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regis</ENAMEX> seems genuine on camera in part because his
personality and TV persona have joined. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Profiles of Philbin</ENAMEX> are tedious because
he has revealed everything on the show (his latest squabble with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>). There is no secret life of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regis Philbin</ENAMEX>. While criticizing
sensationalistic, confessional talk shows, he divulges everything about
himself. He just doesn't have anything salacious to tell.

            It is too bad that so many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are meeting
Regis as the host of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millionaire</ENAMEX> (click for a description of the game).
Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millionaire</ENAMEX> has brought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sweeps win since, oh, the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX>, the show does not do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>. He is a creature
of sunny <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>, not shadowy <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. He is restrained on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millionaire</ENAMEX> ,
forbidden to indulge in his stories, ad-libs, and insults. His job is to make
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contestants</ENAMEX> sweat, but he's no good at it. He's too light to play the
heavy. The dark suits he wears make him look like a lounge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>, not an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enforcer</ENAMEX>. His voice cannot convey menace. His attempts to daunt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contestants</ENAMEX> are
more genial than ominous (although "Is that your final answer?" has become a
national <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">catchphrase</ENAMEX>). And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regis</ENAMEX> certainly doesn't exude the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Olympian</ENAMEX> wisdom
you'd expect from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>. He often seems more surprised to learn the answer
than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contestants</ENAMEX> do.

            Even so, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reege</ENAMEX> may be the ideal game show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> for
this ironic age: He allows the show to be both deadly serious and parody.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millionaire</ENAMEX> is portentously heavy, yet run by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with no gravitas. It
concerns itself with something that matters--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> bucks--yet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regis</ENAMEX>'
presence makes it frivolous. With a somber <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millionaire</ENAMEX> would be
oppressive. Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regis</ENAMEX>, it is the perfect '90s experience: You can enjoy
it as challenge, kitsch, or both.

         
      
   
