
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">341</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beat the Press</ENAMEX>"

            
               The headline in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Mirror</ENAMEX> is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX>." What is the lead?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               
                  
                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 340</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Say What?</ENAMEX>":
                  
               
            

            

               
                  It's a common expression, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahmoud el-Azzazzay</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX> travel
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agent</ENAMEX>: "We say it probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> or more times a day." What
expression?
               
            

            
"Please take me to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kew Gardens</ENAMEX>. I promise I'm unarmed."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balk</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Shearer Gabel</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "I've
already contributed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX> Dolin
            

            "No,
no, that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">a's and four z's</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McDermott</ENAMEX>
(similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Star</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim Derby</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Perry</ENAMEX> )

            "No
shitting on the food cart."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gina Duclayan</ENAMEX>
            

            "
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">'Your</ENAMEX> call is very important to us. Please stay on the line.' Then we put you
on hold for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> and go to lunch. God how I love this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keenan</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Delfin</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> , and Vani
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramakrishnan</ENAMEX> )

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Many responses raged
against aviation--the cramped seats, the awful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, the plummeting. When air
disasters occur, there is an investigation to determine the cause, much as, at
the end of a relationship, we try to understand why it failed, but without the
advantage of voice recording, so we're left to squabble endlessly over who said
what. There is a theory that this search for a cause is an essentially
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superstitious</ENAMEX> act, an almost mystical hope that to name the cause is to ensure
that disaster won't recur. But in anything as complicated as aviation or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">romance</ENAMEX>, there are infinite possibilities for debacle. That's why there is much
to be said for rail travel. Not even the most depressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> can steer a
locomotive off the rails. You can get on and off right in the middle of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, avoiding the hassles of that trip to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>. Railroads provide the
happy erotic metaphor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> going into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX>; air travel offers the
grim symbolism of "crash and burn." On a train you're not trapped in your seat;
you can stroll the aisles or amble to the bar <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and meet an attractive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX> with whom to initiate what is certain to be a disastrous relationship.
Just like the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            
               Cultural Context
Answer
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tawakilt ala Allah</ENAMEX>.
            

            Heard on the cockpit voice recorder of EgyptAir
Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">990</NUMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> sentence--in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, "I put my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> in God"--was
uttered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gamil al-Batouti</ENAMEX>, the relief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-pilot</ENAMEX>, just before the autopilot was
shut off and the flaps adjusted to send the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> into a dive.

            It might be a prayer before dying, as Batouti
deliberately plunged the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> into the sea. And then again, it might be just
an ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> of speech, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> "Oh my God" or the New York
"Fuck you"--said many times during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> with no real theological or erotic
significance.

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Cornell</ENAMEX>, an associate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of religion at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University</ENAMEX>, "It's typically used to initiate
something, if you're embarking on a situation where you don't know the
outcome."

            "I say it as soon as I
get into my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to pick my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> up from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hala Arafa</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employee</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice of America</ENAMEX>. "I also say it when I start cooking in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and when I arrive at work and start my assignments."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dizzy Pheasant Leftover</ENAMEX>
and Plug for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fine Magazine</ENAMEX>:
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McSweeney</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipsy Pheasant Fantasia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> are tagged for later tracking, and each tag
has a tiny, tiny short story on it!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zach Hooker</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Angry <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> was marred (or enlivened, depending on your point of view) by
what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> described as "virulent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protests</ENAMEX>."
Which of the following are genuine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> animosity?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombing of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">junta</ENAMEX> that tyrannized
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1967-1974</TIMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s cozying up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> earlier in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. At state dinner, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> declined baklava,
demanded "real <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>, and plenty of it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> game show, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Wants To Make</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Catty Remarks About Melina Mercouri</ENAMEX>?
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> up with constant giggling at the phrase
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> style"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Resent use of their alphabet by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>-swilling
frat boys

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. New <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street character, Zorba the</ENAMEX>
Geek, wears unstylish clothing, seldom bathes, curses a blue streak

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Athenians</ENAMEX> still pissed about <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Peloponnesian War</ENAMEX>,
taking it out on everyone

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Too much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pokémon</ENAMEX>,
not enough Zeus

            
               Answers
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-3</ENAMEX> actually figured in
the chants and placards of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX>, but I'll bet they were thinking
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4-10</NUMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Petty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humiliations</ENAMEX> of flying, living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>,
dealing with the public.

         
      
   
