
   
   
      
         
            My <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Son the Mobster</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Judith</ENAMEX>,

            Let's get down to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass tacks</ENAMEX>--I wouldn't call what I gave you a
butt-kicking. That was no butt-kicking. I don't know--maybe at

                  Slate
                that was a butt-kicking.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> thing--what's wrong with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Herring</ENAMEX>" for a nickname? No way I'm
calling you "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Da Man</ENAMEX>," on account of the fact that you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (that was you
in that wedding dress <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of months ago</TIMEX>, right?).

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Herring</ENAMEX>" is a great nickname. It recalls the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">halcyon days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gangsterdom</ENAMEX>. I know I'm on record (in 
                  Slate
               , in fact) condemning the gauzy,
romantic view of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> perpetrated by certain awful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. But, to
be fair, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> had excellent nicknames--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kid Twist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Farvel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abbaddaba</ENAMEX>. Better nicknames than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> ever had.

            Look, you're my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. Would you rather be "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Herring"</ENAMEX>? Whatever makes
you feel good--there's an associate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gotti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX> "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX> (no kidding). Would you like to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX> "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shulevitz</ENAMEX>? I'm sure
we could talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX> about letting you share the name.

            Now let me tell you where you're wrong (oh, how I love writing those words):
I didn't say that mobsters aren't taking their cues from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> .
What I said was that no self-respecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> would want to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Soprano</ENAMEX>'s sad-sack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>. Until you produce for me an actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> who
says otherwise, I'll stand by this statement. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anyway</ENAMEX>, news reports are simply
stating that real-life mobsters caught on tape are griping that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> of
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sopranos</ENAMEX> are stealing their life stories; in other words, they
accuse the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> of taking their cues from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>, not vice versa.)

            Now, about you and your Culturebox. Listen, TV criticism is fine. I have no
problem with TV criticism. Some of my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. You even
employed me once as a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> (talk about a mistake on your part). All I'm
saying is, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> is being buried under a mudslide of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-intellectualizing hype, and it's suffering for it.

            Which takes me right to the point where I actually agree with you on
something:

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> episode of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sopranos</ENAMEX> is a real drag: flat, sour, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ponderous</ENAMEX>. I almost fell asleep watching it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> just seems mean and crazy
(and a bit more bloated than usual, don't you think?). And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livia</ENAMEX>? Good God.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>, and not amusing at all. It was a terrible mistake to keep her alive for
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> (apparently, some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> wanted to kill her off, but
everybody on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">set</ENAMEX> loves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Marchand</ENAMEX> so much they kept her alive and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bitching</ENAMEX>). Imagine how clean a break it would have been to open the second
season at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livia</ENAMEX>'s funeral.

            


               

                  
56.6 modem
T1 connection
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Download Windows Media Player</ENAMEX>

                  

               


            

            The only thing I liked about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> episode is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Van Zandt</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silvio</ENAMEX>
Dante imitating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay Corleone</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alright, Van Zandt</ENAMEX> is one of
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>, and I think his portrayal of a low-wattage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soprano soldier</ENAMEX> is a rip,
so I'm prejudiced, but there was a kind of joy in that one scene that is
missing from the rest of the episode.

            Oh, by the way, I think you're giving short-shrift to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> and a wannabe made<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-man</ENAMEX>. Yes, he's an asshole-junkie, but, in the capable
hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Imperioli</ENAMEX>, he is not only that: He is a cursing,
bitch-slapping metaphor for the entire decline of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>. It's all there--his
terrible work ethic, his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use, his obsession with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> of the distant
past, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> of his fantasies (of course he's writing a screenplay, and of
course he can't spell). All that's missing is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX> (out-of-control
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroid</ENAMEX> use by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>'s young <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> is what's killing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> as much as
anything else). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX> is precisely the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> who turns
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> at the thought of real jail time.

            I guess I'm answering the "What happens next?" question. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> is over
as we know it, or think we know it. It's losing its command-and-control
structure. There will always be localized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>, but a wide
network of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> who have their hooks into organized labor and adhere to a
code of silence? That's pretty much over. You can blame <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sopranos</ENAMEX> ' biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>, for that. Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> like me are always
saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> is dead, and we're always too early. But the main problems the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mob</ENAMEX> faces are only getting worse. One is recruitment: The old neighborhoods are
breaking up, and it's the old neighborhoods that produced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob farm teams</ENAMEX>.
Also, no self-respecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> wants his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to follow in his footsteps. I
hate to refer to my own work, but an article I wrote in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> focused on this very subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gotti</ENAMEX>'s fatal
flaw--as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> and as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>--was that he had his son follow him into the
business. No halfway-intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> had any respect for him after
that.

            My prediction: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> will be making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> movies long after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> as we
know it is gone. And that's when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will really have something
to bitch about (by the way, where do you stand on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX>
isn't good for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX>" question?).

            OK, enough for now. Are we good? Or are you still lining up someone from
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> to take a shot at me?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
