
   
   
      
         
            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates Dispensable</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>?
            

            The last item in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>" is a perhaps cruel joke (or
attempt at a joke) at the expense of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of barnesandnoble.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, who
announced his unexpected resignation and saw his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock price barely
move. The obvious question such an outcome provokes (so obvious that I had to
ask it) is: If the stock market doesn't care that I'm leaving, what good was I
doing in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place?

            The irony, of course, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulkeley</ENAMEX>'s departure was immediately followed
by the resignations of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two much</NUMEX>-higher-profile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Glass</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> (which just happens to own 
                  Slate
               ).
And in both those cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> reacted pretty much as they had to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulkeley</ENAMEX>'s departure. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>'s shares are down a tiny bit, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
shares are actually up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost three</NUMEX> points. Apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> are not quite as
essential as one might imagine them to be.

            As it happens, that's true, in the sense that the underlying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> of any
business are more important than the particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> at the top (although
you do have to have someone at the top who can recognize and take advantage of
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>). In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulkeley</ENAMEX>, barnesandnoble.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> has been struggling
for so long, without any obvious way of improving its business fundamentals,
that his departure wasn't seen as making a fundamental difference one way or
the other. In the cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> and, particularly, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, the economics of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> they run are so phenomenal that it's hard to imagine the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> falling to pieces in their absence.

            But the picture is more complicated than this. Take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, for example. In
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, whatever the economics of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> are, he played a major
role in creating them (certainly a larger role than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, though
probably not a larger role than the advent of personal computing). In his
single-minded focus on software, and his insistence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> create
programs that could run on multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> shaped a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> that was
almost a textbook example of how to achieve increasing returns on capital.

            At the same time, the biggest reason why the market did not react badly to
the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> was stepping down as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> is that this was truly a foregone
conclusion. The groundwork had been laid for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX>'s accession to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">throne</ENAMEX>, and it's been clear for a while that Wall Street is very comfortable
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> at the reins. This is, oddly, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' credit. The paradoxical
answer to the question I asked in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> paragraph, in fact, is that one
measure of how well a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> has done is the indifference with which the market
takes his leaving. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Holden</ENAMEX> says at the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Suite</ENAMEX> ,
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX> film about the succession battle at an old-line manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can't depend on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and still thrive. Even when that one man
is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>.

            This is not exactly a classic succession, of course, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is not
leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> at all and because Wall Street likes the idea that he will
now have more time to think deep thoughts and not have to worry about whether
the latest version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Excel</ENAMEX> is shipping on time. But when you consider that in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has gotten a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFO</ENAMEX> and a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> without even a hint
of investor discontent, it makes you realize that the strongest management
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> are also the deepest. Even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age</TIMEX> when intellectual capital
supposedly rules all, Wall Street doesn't invest in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. It invests in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
