
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley Gives Gore</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willies</ENAMEX>

            ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s note : Because of technical problems, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s
Papers" was posted late. Our apologies.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s comment
in a speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that nudging interest rates further upward is necessary to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> the temperature of an economy overheated by soaring stock prices. The
paper also notes that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just hours</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> spoke, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, in
an appearance at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX>, said that dangerous inflation
didn't seem to be a threat to this economy. No other paper fronts the story,
although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> puts it high up in its front-page
financial news index. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' announcement that, while remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, he's
handing over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> duties to long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> says that
he will spend almost all his time focused on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s software strategy.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballmer</ENAMEX> might "put a kinder, gentler face on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>" during
its antitrust settlement talks with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, but then quotes his
assessment of any government breakup of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>: "absolutely reckless and
irresponsible." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> (which high up strongly suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> will
remain the de facto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
front the story, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> puts it atop its financial news index ,
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
               

               puts it inside. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads with the latest in a story the
paper has pretty much owned: the battle between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> over whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> should cover prescription drugs. The
paper explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have long expressed the fear that coverage would
lead to government price-setting on the bulk of their sales. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
installment: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> top drug pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> now say they could accept
the coverage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> suggests that they are trying to head off a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">full-on Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> depiction as price-gougers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes
with the very rare sports lead: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA Washington Wizards</ENAMEX> have reached an
agreement in principle to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> complete control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s
front <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, including all trades, signings, draft selections, and all other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">personnel</ENAMEX> decisions. The main remaining fill-in is how much equity in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">franchise Jordan</ENAMEX> will get. A striking defect in the story: no mention of
whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> is buying that equity share or being given it or what his
other compensation would be. The story says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> is not considering a
comeback as part of the arrangement.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reefers the
revelation that under a little-known federal program, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> has been getting advanced looks at scripts for primetime TV
shows and making suggestions for changes that send an anti-drug message. Some
of the changes have been accepted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>. Under an agreement with the
government, such in-story messages allowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> to make more money
selling ads because they then don't have to run as many anti-drug public
service announcements. The story was broken by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> , a fact that the
papers report on with varying degrees of candor: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> comes clean in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> paragraph and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> holds
off until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the seventh</TIMEX>.

            Citing a story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Herald</ENAMEX> , the LAT fronts and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes inside with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s decision, with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 days</TIMEX> to go
until the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> caucuses, to hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> for introducing the racially explosive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Horton</ENAMEX> issue against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> presidential
primary bid. The controversy was later used against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> to great effect by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> had previously been eschewing
scorched-earth politics. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports on the novel spin tactics
being used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign responded by giving
out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX>' phone number, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> is quoted saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
charge is "nonsense" because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horton</ENAMEX> case was already well-known in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradleyites</ENAMEX> released the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX>' campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Estrich</ENAMEX>, who is quoted saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> campaign was indeed surprised
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horton</ENAMEX>.

            Everybody goes inside with a fresh shift in the demographics of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>: The
majority of gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> being diagnosed with the disease are now either black or
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's front-page "snapshot" shows how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> rank various
high-profile crimes for qualification as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crime of the Century</ENAMEX>." According
to the paper the No. 1 contender is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> assassination. Yet another sign of
boomer myopia: Not even making the list is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lindbergh</ENAMEX> kidnapping or the
theft of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>' atom <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> secrets.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Press Secretary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX> introduced a conference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> as having served in
"the first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs an op-ed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that says the real reason not to like the
AOL-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> deal and its ilk is that mergers inherently dilute the quality
of journalism. Of course, as the piece points out, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> aren't guaranteed
to be better than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. But this is a plausible possibility isn't it? After all,
this piece has a co-byline; it's by media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bigfeet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rosenstiel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kovach</ENAMEX>. If they're absolutely right, then why didn't they write better separate
articles instead?

         
      
   
