
   
   
      
         
            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It Illegal To Do Favors for Campaign Donors</ENAMEX>?
            

            It is widely assumed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are routinely influenced by campaign
contributions. That is usually why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> make such
contributions, and it is why many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--including many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
themselves--believe the campaign-finance system should be reformed. Yet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> investigations or prosecutions are rare (and usually involve
violations of the fund-raising limits rather than any quid pro quo). Isn't it
illegal for an elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> to trade a vote or other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> action for a
campaign contribution?  

            Answer: If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> were to write a letter saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dear Big Donor: Give my</ENAMEX>
campaign <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> and I will vote to renew the tax break for your industry," and
if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Donor</ENAMEX> were to donate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>, that would constitute illegal bribery. But
anything short of that, in terms of evidence or context, is either not illegal
or impossible to prosecute. For example, a campaign donation after the
fact--"Thanks for voting yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>. Here's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> for your re-election"--is
perfectly legal, even though the connection between the donation and the vote
is explicit. And of course in most cases there is no evidence of an explicit
connection.

            After the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keating</ENAMEX> Five" scandal of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1980s</TIMEX> (in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, were accused of interfering with the investigation of a
large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> ostensibly tightened its own ethics
rules to go beyond the legal requirements. "Rule <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX>" states that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>
can--and should--assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> in dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and other
governmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. But it bars them from doing so "on the basis of
contributions or services, or promises of contributions or services, to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX>'s political campaigns." In other words, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> supposedly cannot
treat a donor differently from any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituent</ENAMEX>. Doing so could result in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">censure</ENAMEX> or expulsion. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> has not yet convicted any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of violating
this rule.

            NOTE: Many activities are wrong although they are not illegal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX>
sorts out the rights and wrongs in an article to be posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.

            Next question?

         
      
   
