
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slander Patrol</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Litmus Test</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> are not qualified to be commander
in chief "based upon their support of a litmus test for future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairmen</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs of Staff</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> is now running ads
that say the same thing. Leaving aside the minor nuance that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> never
endorsed any test at all, let alone a "litmus" test for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> right to argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s position is unreasonable?

            Here's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said in the debate on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 5</TIMEX>, in response to a
question from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX> on whether he would have a "litmus test" for the
post of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX>:

            

               I would try to bring about the kind of change in policy, on the "don't ask,
don't tell" policy, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX> brought about after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> in integrating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>. And I think that would require those who wanted
to serve in on the position of--on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX> to be in agreement with
that policy. So, yes.

            

            In answer to a follow-up question from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> modified his answer
slightly. "I would insist, before appointing anybody to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs of</ENAMEX>
Staff, that that individual support my policy," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> said. "And,
yes, I would make that a requirement." Requiring "support" is somewhat
different than requiring "agreement" (see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kausfiles</ENAMEX>"
for further analysis of this distinction). After he was attacked for the
answer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> made clear his preference for his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> response over his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.
"I did not mean to imply that there should ever be any kind of inquiry into the
personal, political opinion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said, at an
impromptu press conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days later</TIMEX>.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> belatedly realized, "support" is the better answer, because it
leaves open the theoretical possibility of appointing a military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> so
honorable that he will work assiduously to implement a policy he personally
disagrees with. But in reality, there isn't much of a difference between
"support" and "agreement"--certainly not enough to constitute a "reversal,"
which was how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> characterized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s adjustment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairmen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX> who "personally" oppose this
particular change in policy are not likely to put their feelings aside and
implement it. They're likely to try to sabotage it.

            Consider what happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> when he tried to lift the ban on gays
in the military in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. In theory, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX> at that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>, was an obedient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> ranking directly below <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX>. In practice, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> worked around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to prevent a
policy change that he disagreed with. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was elected but before he
was sworn in, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> gave a speech at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Academy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Annapolis</ENAMEX> in which
he told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">midshipmen</ENAMEX> that if the new policy violated their beliefs, they should
consider resigning from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> describes the political reality of the situation in
his book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All Too Human</ENAMEX> . "I knew we had no cards to play," Stephanopoulos
writes, describing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX>.
"If we didn't work out a compromise with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX>, they would sabotage us on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>. While they were obliged to obey their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>, they had the right
to present their personal views to congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> publicly." It was,
in fact, the prospect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> testifying before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
about their personal opposition to allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> to serve in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> that
gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Nunn</ENAMEX> the leverage to foist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>'s own preferred compromise of
"don't ask, don't tell" on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. And had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> not acted, it's
entirely likely that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> would have worked to sabotage the new policy at
the bureaucratic level.

            For this reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s "litmus test" position is not merely defensible;
it's the only sensible <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to take if you seriously intend to get rid of "don't
ask, don't tell." By contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s stance--that he would expect the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX> to follow his orders--is utterly naive. As for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX> ever do is offer advice and obey
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX>, it's worse than naive. It's disingenuous.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> know that litmus-untested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> are likely to try to undermine a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s effort to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> to serve openly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>.
And what's more, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> want them to undermine it.

         
      
   
