
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Four</ENAMEX> Lilliputians
            

            
               Received last night.
            

            Listen, anything out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX>'s mouth would sound like pearls of wisdom
after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>' attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX> for being soft on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inch Nails</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX> is getting a major free ride for his bizarreness, because of
his alacrity in accusing anyone who doesn't go soft on him of racism.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who denounce similar tactics by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> might want to be
heard from at some point.

            And while we're at it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> has got to be thinking to himself, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perot</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, both borderline rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wackos</ENAMEX>, get taken seriously purely by their
persistence. Why not me?" Aside from the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> doesn't have funny
hair and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> got rid of his, it's a good question. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> gets treated like a
joke by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> for his quixotic bid, yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> is regarded as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">believable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. If, as I recall, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> running in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
primary in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'92</NUMEX> were known as the "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> dwarves," what index of Lilliputianism
is appropriate for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes, Bauer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>?

            Before I go back to bed and try to shake this damn <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more thing: the
lovely piece in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> advertising column about the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cash</ENAMEX>" machine, which digitally compresses the pauses and long syllables out of
talk shows so that local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> can sell more commercial time. A long time
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, when I was doing a satirical news show at a rock <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>,
they bought an analog tape machine with a rotating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, the premise being that
it wouldn't change the pitch of records, but would slyly speed them up to make
room for--more commercials. Dubbed the "Q <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>," the machine gathered dust in
the back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> when management found that it made every record run through it
sound like it was being played underwater. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX> plus ça change ...

            Be well,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
