
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley Ain't Got Game</ENAMEX>
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is the political
tug-of-war over <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> Eli√°n <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gonz√°lez.</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> become skeptical of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s chances to upset <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>.
Most programs take note of the new polls showing him more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> points behind
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. (He was beating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
Late <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edition</ENAMEX> ) notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has been spending nearly
twice as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX>, and it doesn't seem to help. Many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> ( FNS ), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LE</ENAMEX> )--call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> a
hypocrite for abandoning his "above-politics" pose with his allegation that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> had created the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Horton</ENAMEX> race-baiting tactic during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1988</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> primaries. (To read 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>"
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s charges, click here.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ceci Connolly</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> ) attributes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> surge to his attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wishy-washy</ENAMEX> farm-assistance record. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LE</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schieffer</ENAMEX> ( FTN ) predict a sweeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> victory in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, where the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are running neck-and-neck, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>
note a general lack of enthusiasm for either <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. ("If it were possible
for both of them to lose the [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>] primary, then I think that would
be conceivable," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> says on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LE</ENAMEX> .) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) argues that new national polls--which show a
narrower race between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>--are bound to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> look like
presidential material to primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TW</ENAMEX> ) predicts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address--which
falls between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> caucuses and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> primary--will give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> a
boost, for the same reason. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connolly</ENAMEX> ( FTN ) points out that
with his large cash flow, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> will not drop out of the race any time
soon.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> splinter over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s attempt to return
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">boy-refugee Eli√°n Gonz√</ENAMEX>°lez to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. Some, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TW</ENAMEX> ), and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> ( CG ), think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> has his son's interests
at heart when he requests the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s return. But others, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoge F. Will</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TW</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX> ( CG ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Barone</ENAMEX> ( MG ),
think that the deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s clear intent was for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to grow up in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barone</ENAMEX> compares <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazi Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stalinist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Beirne</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> an oppressed ethnic minority.) A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TW</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> ( CG ), think
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> should require the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> to visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>,
to ensure that his decision to raise his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> is his own rather than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>'s.

Spinning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stars</ENAMEX> and Bars

The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> Confederate-flag controversy rears its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> during
interviews with both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LE</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
repeats his mantra that the feds should let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Carolina</ENAMEX> decide whether it
wants to fly the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> flag over its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Capitol building</ENAMEX>; when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Blitzer</ENAMEX> asks him what he feels about the flag personally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> talks about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Matalin</ENAMEX>--in one of her flirtatious political duels with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">husband James Carville</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press --repeats <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>'-rights stance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carville</ENAMEX> then asks his
better half why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> didn't stay silent on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>'s recent gay-partnership
court decision. Earlier on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> reiterated his revised stance
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> flag--that it is a symbol of both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> heritage and
racist oppression. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTN</ENAMEX> , he did not mention <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heritage</ENAMEX>; see 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ballot Box</ENAMEX>"
for more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s flag backtrack.)

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Thaws Self</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundits</ENAMEX>
After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of political missteps, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> has finally
pleased the commentariat. How? By joking around on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Letterman</ENAMEX> .
Although a few talking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> complain that she had pre-screened <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letterman</ENAMEX>'s
"pop quiz" on state trivia, most find her warm and engaging. This includes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LE</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MG</ENAMEX> ), who pronounces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> "a hit. ... at ease much of the time, and
funny." To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> ( FNS ), the appearance proves that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
"applies herself and is not standing on a platform and being preachy or
whatever, [she] can be an engaging and charming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>."

Last Word
            

            

               I think his application [of loyalty] is sometimes misguided, but when it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> to me and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and, on occasion, the truth, I
appreciate it.

               

                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Matalin</ENAMEX>, commenting on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX>'s new book,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stickin</ENAMEX>'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: The Case for Loyalty</ENAMEX> ( MTP )

               

            

         
      
   
