
   
   
      
         
            Bellow the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Fertility</ENAMEX> King

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Bellow</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">84, last month</TIMEX> fathered a child born to his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 41</TIMEX>.
As a result of this news, which trickled out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellow</ENAMEX> risks being remembered not as the
brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herzog</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Adventures of Augie March</ENAMEX> , but as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly World News</ENAMEX>
curiosity. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eighty</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> is older than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77</TIMEX>, the previous
famous-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>-becomes-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-advanced-age record set by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall</ENAMEX>. (Most, though obviously nowhere near all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX> are
infertile.) It's so old, in fact, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> wondered whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellow</ENAMEX> was
the world's oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, period. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guinness World Records 2000: Millennium Edition</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alas</ENAMEX>, doesn't say, though it does serve up as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oldest Mother</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arceli Keh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">63</TIMEX> when she gave birth (with a donated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incidentally, Chatterbox</ENAMEX> must second <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luc Sante</ENAMEX>'s opinion, expressed in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 16</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review</ENAMEX> , that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guinness</ENAMEX> is so glossied-up and
dumbed-down--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, it's mainly an appendage to a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guinness World Records:</ENAMEX>
Primetime TV show--that it can no longer serve its hallowed function as
settler of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ale</ENAMEX>-fueled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX> arguments. Two whole pages are devoted to
world-record stats about supermodels; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more about "high fashion"; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
more about "street fashion." Has anyone ever argued in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX> about who the
highest-paid supermodel is? Best arse maybe, but
best-remunerated ? The latter, if you must know, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claudia Schiffer</ENAMEX>.)

            The hunt for the world's oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> to a bookmark-worthy Web
site called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"World</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sexual Records</ENAMEX>," maintained by someone who identifies himself as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J. Means</ENAMEX>
and who appears to be affiliated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Means</ENAMEX> didn't answer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s
e-mail seeking more information about his bona fides, but the UT directory
lists a senior in the engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jon Means</ENAMEX> with the same e-mail
address.) On the site's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Conception</ENAMEX>" page, the world's oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is identified
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Colley</ENAMEX>, a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mineworker</ENAMEX> who sired a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oswald</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. Colley was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX> at the time; his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, who had married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> (he told her he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 70</NUMEX>) was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colley</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years later</TIMEX>,
shortly before his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">100 th</NUMEX> birthday. An <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1996</TIMEX> article in The
Independent of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> (not available online) says that yet another
nonagenarian, "a bricklayer in his nineties," became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, but it
doesn't supply any details, so it's impossible to know whether he broke
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colley</ENAMEX>'s record. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> piece also points out that literal
interpretation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> requires the faithful to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX> begat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>.

            To summarize: We don't know who the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> ever was, but it may have
been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Colley</ENAMEX>. It certainly wasn't Bellow. This means <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bellow</ENAMEX> probably
will be remembered mostly, if not exclusively, for his literary output.
Caveat: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellow</ENAMEX> may still be the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> in
history. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> awaits more information from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stockholm</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
