
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Sullivan Flat Wrong</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flat Tax</ENAMEX>
            

            In his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> Magazine piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX> arguing
for the virtues of a flat tax, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Sullivan</ENAMEX> suggested that the flat tax
would be "the central political reform of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decade</TIMEX>," in part because it
fit so well with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s supposed newfound love of "simplicity." As the
Times' subhead put it, "[t]he flat tax is the perfect
artifact of our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-click era." For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX>, the "byzantine" nature of the
current tax system benefits the wealthy, who can afford to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
decipher it. And all the loopholes make a "nominally progressive" system much
less fair than it appears, and much less fair than a one-size-fits-all system.
In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> suggests, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-rate system is an answer to liberalism's
woes, because "by treating every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> alike," it would eliminate so much of
the complexity and indebtedness to special interests that make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hate
government.

            Actually, though, even if the current system is nominally progressive, it's
much more progressive than any flat tax--no matter what reforms accompany
it--could ever be. Under any flat-tax system, the wealthy will pay much less in
taxes than they now do, and therefore everyone else will account for a much
higher proportion of tax revenue. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> wants to tax all capital gains at
the same rate as income, and the numbers would be skewed even more by that.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX> says that the idea that a flat tax is a "giveaway to the rich" is a
knee-jerk response. But it is a giveaway to the rich. As for the idea
that the wealthy benefit from the current system because they can trick it,
there's zero evidence for that. The percentage of revenue paid by those in the
top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of income-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earners</ENAMEX> has risen steadily throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>, just
as you would expect to happen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX> when the rich have gotten much
richer.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX> may really believe that rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should get to keep as much of
their money as possible--actually, he does believe this--but if he does, he
should come out and say it, and not try to disguise the argument as somehow
about correct process or the imaginary salvation of liberalism. Nor should he
paint the flat tax as flowing logically from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' embrace of simplicity.
Especially since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> has completely imagined this embrace.

            The irony, in fact, is that the flat tax is the perfect relic of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX> when
a lack of computing power and of information made it difficult to make
meaningful distinctions between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, let alone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. But
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the trend is in the exact opposite direction from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX>
conjures up. When it came to pay, we used to live in a world of job
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classifications</ENAMEX> and pay grades, where everyone who did the "same" work got the
same pay. Increasingly, we now live in a world of dramatic differentiation in
pay. The whole idea of a "pay grade," in fact, would seem like complete
nonsense at most <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> and Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            The same is true in marketing and manufacturing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX> argues that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> today try to "project a simple image, a single product, and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recognizable</ENAMEX>, simple brand," and to be sure, there's plenty of nonsense out
there about the centrality of the brand. But what's really going on is the move
toward customization. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX> builds my computer literally to order. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> makes
recommendations to me based on other things that I've bought, not based
on what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> are buying. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> is already talking about building custom
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. Of course there will always be a place for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX>, with its piles of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">khakis</ENAMEX> and white T-shirts, and for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>, with its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-taste-for-all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX>. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are getting much better, not worse, at treating each consumer
differently, which means, in some sense, becoming a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for
everyone who buys from them.

            The same sort of fine-graining is going on with prices. Once, when you took
an airline flight, you could be fairly certain that most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the
plane paid the same price for their tickets that you did for yours. Today, you
can be fairly certain most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> paid different prices. And that's not because
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Priceline</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. It's because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> have gotten increasingly adept at using
computers to distinguish between different kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fliers</ENAMEX>, and charging
different kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fliers</ENAMEX> different fares. On the Internet, shopping engines
perform the same function in reverse, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Priceline</ENAMEX> has taken the idea of
differential pricing to its market-driven extreme. And what is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX> if not the
antithesis of fixed pricing? There are places where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-price-fits-all thinking
rules, like in the current long-distance market. But even there, consumers
happily leap from plan to plan, and bargain with long-distance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> to cut
special deals. The real <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-price-fits-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all days</TIMEX>, in fact, were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when
only AT&T provided long distance. And I don't hear too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> calling
for the return of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ma Bell</ENAMEX> anymore.

            If anything, then, a tax system in which everyone paid his or her own
particular tax rate would be more in tune with our world, and the possibilities
created by the computer, than the flat tax. (There are, though, excellent
economic and political reasons not to want that fine-grained a system.) A
culture and economy of simplicity? I don't think things have ever been more
complex.

         
      
   
