
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dueling Media</ENAMEX> Moguls
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>. The promos tell me it's a heavy week of debates, and I
started doing my civic duty by watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Matthews</ENAMEX> last night.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX>' idea of "hardball" (aside from titling his show and his book
identically, so every pause for a commercial embeds a book plug) seems to be to
yell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four half</NUMEX>-coherent questions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX> in a querulous, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bostonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenor</ENAMEX>.
Given such an interlocutor, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> would come off looking thoughtful. I do
get tired of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s praying hands, and I have no opinion on his tax
plan--or, for that matter, on anybody's tax plan--but I admit to joining the
dreaded media consensus that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> generate less pain for me, just as
public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX>, than the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herd</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> was in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>,
too, until he started complaining that he wasn't getting enough airtime because
he's black.

            Decoding life at the top begins and ends with the knowledge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX> despise each other. The current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX>
has a long piece about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX>'s roping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS News</ENAMEX> into a footage-sharing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cartel</ENAMEX>, with the main purpose being to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s footage (and logo) off all
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliates</ENAMEX>. It's in this context that we should approach the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted-Jane</ENAMEX> split. After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX> dumped his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> for a nice young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> TV
executive, and got the former Mrs. to tiptoe away nicely. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX> must feel under
pressure to do likewise, or lose a round to the awful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aussie</ENAMEX>.

            Speaking of sadly amicable divorces, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are celebrating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of running <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and where's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>? I, for one, feel enormously
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cheated by the Gingrich</ENAMEX> settlement, since we will, apparently, never know how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> answered, under oath, questions about his affair with a young woman
nominally his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinate</ENAMEX>. These answers would tell us whether or not, as I've
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long</ENAMEX> suspected, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.

            Here's a question for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who actually still cover (as opposed to, in the
case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, share) news: Does the law shoved through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> by the
computer industry limiting product-liability lawsuits connected to the "Y2K
bug" prevent state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys general</ENAMEX> from suing? If not, I bet they're meeting
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> behind the tobacco suits as we sip our coffees. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> has quotes from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX> chatrooms about disappointed
doom-expecters threatening to sue, but they have yet to read that law.

            I'll try not to be cavalier about this, but asking me whether I ever play
"real" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> means you never saw my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Wallace</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Thicke</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Night Live</ENAMEX> , and, more sadly, means that you're one of the Washingtonians
deprived of my radio broadcast, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Le Show</ENAMEX>," on which you'd hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
Tripp, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> al. Whether or not those are real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, of course, is a
judgment call. Try <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RealAudioing</ENAMEX> at my Web site for the answer.

            I like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.W.</ENAMEX> (I don't know him well enough to call
him "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Johnny"</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> all that space to indulge his love of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> (not to mention
the apparent travel budget that's taken him from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>). It's as if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Sun</ENAMEX> suddenly said to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Germond</ENAMEX>, "Take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> off,
just hang out at the world's greatest racetracks, and just write about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
