
   
   
      
         
            Debate <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>

            (With apologies to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moneybox</ENAMEX>)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "With so many debates, just about every conceivable question has now been
asked and answered repeatedly. The result is that the debates are turning
into press conferences on the latest headlines. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Tonight</TIMEX>'s topics from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rapids</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elián González</ENAMEX> (again), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Rocker</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL-Time Warner</ENAMEX>
merger . A few more debates and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> will be asking these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> what
they think of that presidential race up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>." 

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "The post-game analysis on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> was that a newly conciliatory
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> sounded like he wanted to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s running mate. When I
heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s opening spiel about the 'growing gap between the haves
and have-nots in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> ' and his criticism of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s tax cuts
favor the rich, I had a slightly different take: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> wants to be Bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s running mate."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> had another brief spasm of anti-intellectualism when he
stopped a question that referred to a comment from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> by
retorting, 'consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>.' When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s father <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>-baited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> , it was pretty disingenuous. But at least <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> didn't
actually have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> degree."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> finished his answer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Rocker</ENAMEX> question by
saying that he appreciated the effort by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Braves</ENAMEX> to get Rocker
psychological counseling. After a pause, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> interjected a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX>-like dig : 'And perhaps they should have psychological counseling for
some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> as well--to rescind their statements they've made about
religion in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.' But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> is no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s 'God help all of us' line
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashua</ENAMEX> debate made fun of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s intelligence, not his sanity or his
beliefs. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s line was funny. This time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piggy</ENAMEX> was
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> laughing."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> is replaying his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign exactly. Once more, he started the
race as an inept political amateur . And once again, he's ending it as a
destructive sore <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loser</ENAMEX> ." 

             <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> made his argument for continuing the boycott of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> drove a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> through it by asking why the same logic didn't apply to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> responded with a fatuous distinction: that trade with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> supports an "entrepreneurial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>" whereas with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> it nourishes
only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> is right to point out the inconsistency, but wrong
in his conclusion that we should isolate both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorships</ENAMEX>. Or does
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> think the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> embargo has been a big success?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "What's up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> always offering to 'share my heart '
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>? I know what he means, but in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> we usually say , 'I
want to share what's in my heart.' Otherwise it sounds like an
invitation to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aztec</ENAMEX> banquet."

         
      
   
