
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>'s Cringeworthiest Anchormen
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>,

            Your take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Kaufman</ENAMEX> sounds right. I remember thinking watching him
that he's either an incredible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> who walks off the set, after some
bizarre wrestling sketch, and shouts, "Who do I have to fuck to get a donut
around here?" or mentally ill. If it's the latter, then his comedy seemed just
a notch less cruel than the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Elephant Man</ENAMEX>. Still, not having your personal
history with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, I'm going to go see the movie. I hope <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forman</ENAMEX> does his
little trick of weird <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cameos</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> , you'll recall he had James
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carville</ENAMEX> play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Keating</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> play the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in the case,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Hanover</ENAMEX> (Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>) as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Carter Stapleton</ENAMEX>. All were quite
good, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> with his trademark high-pitched voice. Speaking of special
effects, you were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Godzilla</ENAMEX> : What's it like working in a movie all
those effects? I can imagine acting against a blue screen must be pretty
hard.

            I see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX>'s ratings are sinking, setting off buzz that he may finally
get dumped. Actually, at the moment I find him--for all his "What's the
frequency, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth"</ENAMEX> oddities--to be the least weird of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokaw</ENAMEX> is
increasingly swallowing his words, and I find his ode to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>
generation to be tiresome. (OK, we're grateful already. But look, you got
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> houses, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> college tuitions, and plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne</ENAMEX> movies. That
ain't a bad tribute.) And we've already talked about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX>. The best part of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Millennium</ENAMEX> may be the end of having to listen to "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>" on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>. "Played with a leather ball, sewn with stitches, and a
wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cylindrical</ENAMEX> object called a bat, it became the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pastime ..."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ugh</ENAMEX>.

            I see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX> took back the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX> regulations about safety
standards at home. So much for my hitting up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> for an ergonomically
correct easy chair.

            Don't forget: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> debate tonight.
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
