
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flag</ENAMEX>-Waverer

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>, defines a "gaffe" as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> accidentally
saying something truthful. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> committed a classic one of these on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, when he said on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> flag is "a
symbol of racism and slavery" and that it "is offensive in many, many ways, as
we all know." After stating these obvious truths, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next couple</TIMEX>
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> "clarifying" his position: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> flag is not a symbol of
racism or slavery but rather of "heritage" and that there's nothing offensive
about it at all.

            What explains this rather extraordinary flip-flop? As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
campaigning in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, where the flag flies controversially over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has to know this issue cold. At first blush, it appeared that
he was doing that thing that makes him so rare and appealing as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>--telling a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> within his party to get stuffed. As
we all know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> does this rather gleefully on such issues as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>,
ethanol subsidies, and campaign-finance reform. Sacrificing the crucial South
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> primary to make another such courageous point would have been an act
of self-abnegation on par with his refusal to be released from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison camp</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>.

            But in fact, I think the flag answer was the reflection of a different and
less laudable tendency on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s part: his instinct to play up to the press.
On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Schieffer</ENAMEX> had just finished telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> that
he didn't think his letters to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> were
scandalous, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> delivered an answer designed to warm every liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>'s heart--especially coming on the heels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s pusillanimous
kowtowing on the issue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> debate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> just couldn't resist charming an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> does this on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis on his campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>. But the last time it
got him in serous trouble was back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, when he told the editorial board
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> that despite his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17-year</TIMEX> pro-life voting
record, he didn't really support banning abortion. "Certainly in the short
term, or even the long term, I would not support repeal of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe vs. Wade</ENAMEX> ,
which would then force <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX>-number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to undergo illegal and
dangerous operations," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> said. As on the flag, he was roundly attacked by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> and beat a hasty retreat to a more orthodox <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
position.

            I suppose there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> possibilities here. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is a
secret liberal trapped inside the voting record of a conservative. The other,
probably more realistic, is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> just hates to disappoint his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pals</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
