
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disorganized Crime</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jeff</ENAMEX>,

            OK, you fuckin' mook. I deserved exactly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of that butt-kicking. But only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. So watch it. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> rule of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> movies is, never give someone a bigger
beating than they deserve in the first act if you don't want to get your ass
thrashed in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>.

            You're right about the writing being better than the acting, but only
because the writing is so good. You're right about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodfellas</ENAMEX> --"laugh-fest" was too strong. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> is not a belly-laugh
kinda <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. You're right about expectations having been blown out of proportion.
And you are so right that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Chase</ENAMEX> should have killed off Livia
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soprano</ENAMEX>, whose acid tongue is starting to remind me of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster drool</ENAMEX> in the
Alien movies--it eats away at the infrastructure.

            I'll get back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livia</ENAMEX> in a minute, but first I have to get up on my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> and pontificate on where you're wrong. You are wrong, sir, to say
that television criticism is about profound meaning. Most of it is critics
trying to explain how they think things work, and why they like them. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> has a right to figure stuff out, and to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who might help
them do that. The boob tube is powerful. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> watch this show and
talk about it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobsters</ENAMEX> in fact do take their cues from it, at least
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sopranos</ENAMEX>
will probably do more than any of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper Gore</ENAMEX>'s mental-health initiatives to
get insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to change their policy on psychotherapy reimbursements.
So don't shut down the entire discussion just because you've started hanging
out with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> and presumably swallowed his artsy-fartsy,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faux -modest</ENAMEX>, we're-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just</NUMEX>-making-TV-here crap.

            Now, back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second season</TIMEX>. Cards on the table: I think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Sunday</TIMEX>'s
episode is a letdown, although that was probably inevitable. It's an
advertisement for psychotherapy, only this time in reverse. Without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melfi</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">psychiatrist</ENAMEX>, around to draw out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>'s human side, he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> just
seem angry and sour. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Thugs</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX> to stick around
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob business</ENAMEX> is greasy and seedy, instead of greasy and seedy and
fun . There was a sweetness to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> when he was discovering his inner
mensch that made his and everyone else's brutality come off as ironic
and incongruous, rather than just brutal.

            Now stroke-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livia</ENAMEX> is a stringy-haired vision of evil, instead of an
amusingly tart-tongued old bitch. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, a sleazy
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pavarti</ENAMEX>, nee <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice</ENAMEX>, has shown up from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, ostensibly to
take care of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> but more likely to scam off her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>'s protégé, has a new gig as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> compliance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> involving some
complicated scheme to dump crummy stock on unsuspecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widows</ENAMEX> and shut-ins,
but basically he's the same asshole junkie he always was, and has taken to
fighting in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ariana</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carmela</ENAMEX> is more long-suffering
than ever. She is reduced in this episode to smiling sadly a lot and cooking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ziti</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melfi</ENAMEX> sees <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in a roadside motel, and when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> finally tracks her
down in a diner, she spits in his face: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fuck you</ENAMEX>!"

            And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>, my god. He has turned into a huge drag, stomping around, crashing
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUV</ENAMEX>, and throwing hissy fits at the world. The only really great moment in
the entire hour is the look on his face when the male shrink he goes to in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">desperation</ENAMEX> says he can't take on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>'s line of work. After all,
quoth the shrink, "I saw <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Analyze This !"</ENAMEX> "Analyze <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This ?</ENAMEX>" says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>, with that inimitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gandolfini I</ENAMEX>-can't-believe-I'm-hearing-this-shit
double take. "It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fuckin</ENAMEX>' comedy !"

            Oh yeah. Analyze This. Do we have to? What's there to say?

            Are mob movies played out? Who knows? As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melfi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last season</TIMEX>,
they're our national epic, or something like that. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing's for sure:
They're all going to have to refer to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> now, the way The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sopranos</ENAMEX> has to refer to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Godfather</ENAMEX>.
            

            I want to know what happens next with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>--in real life--if, as you say,
the smarter ones realize that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bada-Bing</ENAMEX> lifestyle is dead.

            And, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Herring</ENAMEX> ? What the hell kind of moniker is
that?

            Yours most critically,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">De Man</ENAMEX>" Shulevitz

         
      
   
