
   
   
      
         
            What's the Difference Between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairmen</ENAMEX>?
            

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> announced that
he was handing over the job of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> said that he would remain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>. And on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Online</ENAMEX> announced its merger with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Case</ENAMEX> was
designated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Levin</ENAMEX> was
given the position of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive officer</ENAMEX>. What's the difference between
these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> jobs? And which one is more powerful? 

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">decision-maker</ENAMEX>, and all other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>
answer to him or her. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> typically <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> many of the tactical
responsibilities to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, focusing instead on strategic issues, such
as which markets to enter, how to take on the competition, and which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
to form <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> with. This is in contrast to the chief operating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> , who oversees <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> operations and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s performance.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of directors. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> is elected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> and is responsible for protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>'
interests, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s profitability and stability. It usually meets
several times a year to set long-term goals, review financial results, evaluate
the performance of high-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, and vote on important strategic moves
proposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> appoint--and can fire--upper-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> such
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> typically wields substantial power in
setting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>'s agenda and determining the outcome of votes. But he or she
does not necessarily play an active role in everyday <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>.

            The balance of power between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> varies widely from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> cannot make major moves without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assent</ENAMEX>, and his or her job security depends on their satisfaction, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> is technically his or her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superior</ENAMEX>. And an active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> may use
this power to effectively become the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-head</ENAMEX>--and ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>--of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX>. But most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairmen</ENAMEX> are not so involved, which leaves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> with
considerable flexibility in running the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> can also affect the
composition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> through his or her selection of senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, many of whom are guaranteed board seats by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> bylaws.
Sometimes--as was the case with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, and is still the case
with Case and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX> at their current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> are the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.

            Case and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX> have not yet outlined how they will divide leadership
responsibilities. However, the press release announcing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL-Time Warner</ENAMEX>
merger says that Case will play "an active role" in leading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX> will work "closely with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Case</ENAMEX>" in setting its strategy. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> interpret this to mean that Case, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, will use his power to
its fullest, giving him an upper hand over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX>.

            Next question?

         
      
   
