
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future of Family Feuds</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with a local story: A study shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s
high-tech boom is disproportionately benefiting the rich and, consequently,
widening the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s income gap. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with a preview of the upcoming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> arguments over the constitutionality of state statutes that
guarantee visitation rights to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's off-lead
concludes that the case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troxel</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granville</ENAMEX> , will define the
government's future role in family affairs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Troxels</ENAMEX>, assisted by
governmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX>, argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> should be allowed to
mandate grandparental visitation rights to protect the welfare of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>. Their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">son</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> contends that court-mandated visitation infringes on parental
privacy. Her position is echoed by traditional religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and civil
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
worries that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> will enjoy as much as a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> soft
money spending advantage in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming election</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senatorial</ENAMEX> Campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert G. Torricelli</ENAMEX> projects that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will
raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $30 million</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torricelli</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> could garner <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>'s campaign purse is currently <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-fourth</NUMEX> the
size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">roughly $10 million</NUMEX> war chest. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>'s failure
to amass cash is attributed to its lack of a finance chair, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>' doubts
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospects</ENAMEX>, and the dissipation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising power. Party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarchs</ENAMEX> fret that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will bury
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> under an avalanche of expensive TV ads. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
points out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' public pouting could be an attempt to stimulate
fund raising.

the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> in an inside item. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCCC</ENAMEX> enters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> with more money than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Committee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> collected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $33</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> and still have <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19 million</NUMEX> left. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$48</NUMEX>
million but spent all but <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $10 million</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> front <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s release of more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> letters that he sent to federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> under the jurisdiction of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> he chairs. A reefered piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> emphasizes that the
document dump is an attempt to defuse the controversy over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s efforts on
behalf of campaign contributor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxson Communications</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, who received
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> and the use of a corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliates</ENAMEX>, encouraged the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications Commission</ENAMEX> to issue a ruling on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
acquisition of a broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> underscores that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
also intervened to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BellSouth</ENAMEX>, which contributed plane rides and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60,000</NUMEX>
to his political fortunes.

            "Generally the letters simply urged speeded-up action rather than any
specific outcome," according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . (Chatterbox
argues that there is nothing wrong with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> urging an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to act
promptly.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> claims only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> letters sought help for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> that
contributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $2,000</NUMEX> to his presidential coffers, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
points out that the campaign's count may exclude letters written to aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> piece reports that most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are unaware of the recent hullabaloo over regulatory correspondence.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager explains why <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Y2K</TIMEX> threat fizzled. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> forecasted significant disruption in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> prognosticated on the basis of poor data. They
underestimated last-minute preparations and overestimated "technology
dependence." A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Outlook</ENAMEX>" piece attributes the undue unease to good
old-fashion fear of technology.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front-pager laments the explosion of test-gaming by privileged
college-bound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who enjoy "special accommodations"
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>, including extra time, rose by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 50 percent</NUMEX> in "recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>." Most of the growth in learning disability adjustments, which schools
approve based on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s note or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX>'s recommendation, comes from
ritzy prep and public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> and perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are
taking advantage of the system.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s latest absurdity--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">vetting</ENAMEX>. The
luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> market is so overheated that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of co-ops have begun to
screen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> of potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>. Boards evaluate pet size, pedigree,
training, demeanor, and appearance. Real estate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> prepare dog
biographies for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> evaluation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Owners</ENAMEX> administer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valium</ENAMEX> to calm their
canines before co-op scrutiny.

         
      
   
