
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partial Court</ENAMEX> Press

Times lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s announcement that it will
hear cases on abortion rights and gay rights <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>. Specifically, it will
review a judgment overturning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>'s ban on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-term</TIMEX> abortions, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jersey Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruling that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> could not exclude a gay troop
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> off-leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> story, and leads with
the ongoing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAPD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>: police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>' request that charges be filed against
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. The charges would be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rampart</ENAMEX> corruption
investigation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times
                lead focuses on the
partial birth abortion ban and doesn't mention the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Boy Scout</ENAMEX> case. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the WP front (and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reefers) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
publication of a new national security doctrine. The new doctrine broadens the
conditions under which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> would use nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, and describes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, as a potential threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX>.

            All of the papers mention that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> won't actually reevaluate
the constitutional status of abortion. Nor will the hearings affect the bans on
abortions after "fetal viability" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 weeks</TIMEX> into the pregnancy) currently
pending in many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> rejected the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s ban
because its loose definition of a "partial birth abortion" could apply to many
common procedures used in early stages of pregnancy, violating a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court ruling against "undue burden" on access to abortion. The WP
scrutinizes how the timing of the hearings and rulings will affect the
presidential elections. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> will most likely hear the cases in early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> and rule in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late June</TIMEX>, just as the Campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> kicks into high gear.
This timing should make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> a major election issue, as the next
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> will likely nominate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> case, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>, turns on what sort of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization the Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> are. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scouts</ENAMEX> say that as a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>,
they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> freedom of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> to decide who to include,
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s size and tradition of "nonselectivity"
renders it a "public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>" subject to federal anti-discrimination
laws.

            Everyone quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s change of heart about nukes. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, they would be
used "in case of a threat to the existence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Federation</ENAMEX>," but in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s revised doctrine they are an option when "all other means of
resolving the crisis have been exhausted." It could have been worse: some
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> had argued for a policy that included an "early first use"
option. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also reminds us that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> doctrine is traditionally
more hawkish on the use of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, but no one mentions what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy actually is. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> agree that the added chilliness towards <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
is a result of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis and more recent criticism of the Chechen
campaign by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX> found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Croats</ENAMEX> guilty of "persecution" and crimes
against humanity for their role in ethnic cleansing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. The decision is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groundbreaking</ENAMEX> because it is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to declare ethnic cleansing a crime
against humanity. For their roles in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> massacre that ended with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 100</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> dead, the convicts could spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 25 years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> plans to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $1</NUMEX>
billion over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX> to build a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rocket</ENAMEX> capable of launching
satellites. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> fear that the plan is economically unfeasible, and
deleterious to the stability of the region: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> could export the
technology to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> who would use it to launch <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, and fears that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> might use the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rocket</ENAMEX> to deploy their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> could set off an
arms race in northeast <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> continues to mine the aftershocks
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL Time Warner</ENAMEX> merger, saying the incident has revived <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> anxiety
about technological inferiority: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> are far less likely than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
to be wired, and e-commerce revenues in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 15</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only a third of</NUMEX>
what they are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> The story blames the gap on government subsidies of
failing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> (to save jobs) and a greater cultural aversion to risk.

             In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caroline Knapp</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> the
flames of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s dog wars, lambasting snobbish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> who only want
properly sized, pedigreed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> in their co-ops. Unlike many of these whiny
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">elitists</ENAMEX>, she says, the dog is "a noble and sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> who, given
proper care, may make a far better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> than many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>." Maybe so, but at
least we're housebroken.

         
      
   
