
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flag Football</ENAMEX>

            A few observations about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s debate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX>, as viewed on
television from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>:

            

               Nobody laid a glove on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>, who is increasingly comfortable at these
events, and seemed in complete control of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> throughout <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> acquitted himself poorly nonetheless, by once again shirking an
opportunity to stand up to ugliness in his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. 

            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> first gave a pass to conservative bigotry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months ago</TIMEX> when he
was unwilling to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> didn't belong in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. He did it more
recently when he declined to meet with the an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of gay <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
because he didn't want to be a "divider." And he was at it once again <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>,
when in response to repeated questions from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Williams</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, he refused
to criticize the flying of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> flag over the state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">capitol</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX> In response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>' request for his personal opinion about
the flag, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> just kept reiterating that he thought it was up to "the people
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>" to decide.

               This was a craven, spineless response. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> had any guts, he would say
what I'd bet he really believes, which is that while it may be up to the people
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> to decide the issue, he is personally offended when he sees a
symbol of segregation flying over a public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. If he wanted to be politic
about it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> could have said that while he doesn't believe that the flag is
intended as a racist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX>, it is hurtful and divisive to many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and
should be hauled down for that reason.

               In the short run, criticizing the flag might have led to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> getting conked
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bud Light</ENAMEX> cans visible on the tables where a large
and rowdy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> sat, baying for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">red meat</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>, and gambling. But
ultimately, I think that finding some way to indicate disagreement with this
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">unattractive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> would have been both the honorable and the politically shrewd
thing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to do. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> will almost certainly win the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> nomination. That
means he should be thinking beyond the nomination. If he wins it with his
tolerant principles held high, he will be in a far stronger position in
relation to the eventual <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>. Much hinges on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s attempt to
cleanse his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of bigotry and reposition it closer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. It ought
to be obvious to him that pandering to the revanchist sentiments of a roomful
of boisterous white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX>--on national television--undermines that
effort. 

            

            

               It was almost funny that just after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s pathetic answer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>
put a question to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> that accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s black campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Brazile</ENAMEX>, of being a racist for criticizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts</ENAMEX> in
the course of suggesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> doesn't really care about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> responded that he shared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>' outrage at the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
have long "tried to smear our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> with accusations of racism." The complaint
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brazile</ENAMEX> might have carried more credence at an event where the entire
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> primary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> wasn't so actively sucking up to conventional,
white-on-black racist sentiment.

            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> turned in what I thought was his worst debate performance to
date. In place of the good nature and quick wit he has shown in all the past,
he was anxious, defensive, and far from lucid. Of course, it probably didn't
help that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> put to him was about another letter he
sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> on behalf of a big campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> tried to change
the subject back to the faults in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s tax plan. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> people
are tired of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who make promises about tax cuts they can't keep," he said.
But the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s integrity has been called into question made his
aspersions against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s honesty look churlish.

            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s nadir came when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> cleverly asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> to explain why
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> oppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s campaign-finance-reform plan. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch zinged McCain</ENAMEX>
by saying his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> was "starting to sound like an accordion player
who only knows one tune--'Lady of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>.' " Apparently unsettled by this
effective one-two punch, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> responded with a rambling compendium of his
most familiar lines on the subject of campaign finance reform culminating in
his repetition of his not very funny joke from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> should
get a better picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> for the attack ads running in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
(which aren't in fact connected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>).

               With his strongest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>, the press, suddenly turned hostile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is
clearly struggling. Luckily, there's an easy way for him to win back the
affection of the news media. All he has to do is call a press conference before
he leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> and in no uncertain terms denounce the Confederate
flag.

            

         
      
   
