
   
   
      
         
            The <i>Times</i> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sees Day Traders Everywhere</ENAMEX>
            

            As a rule, the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> trade, the worse they do relative to the
market as a whole. Frequent trading requires that you pull off the
near-impossible feat of consistently outwitting the collective intelligence of
the stock market, and do so well enough to outweigh the added burden of
commission costs and taxes (which are much higher on short-term capital gains
than on long-term gains). There has never been a serious academic study, in
fact, that has shown anything different.

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gretchen Morgenson</ENAMEX>'s front-page article in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s New York
Times lamenting the boom in short-term trading among individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
was right about the detrimental effects of such trading on the bank accounts of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doing it. But the evidence the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> offered for the
widespread nature of that boom was confused and not especially convincing. And
the attempt to draw conclusions about the broader negative effects of increased
trading was even less plausible. Short-term trading, as I've argued
here before, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>'s game. But it's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>'s game that hurts those
of us who aren't playing it.

            The premise of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgenson</ENAMEX>'s article was drawn from a new study by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanford C. Bernstein</ENAMEX>, which shows that the "average" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> now
holds shares <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only eight months</TIMEX>, whereas <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX> he/she held shares for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. What we weren't told, though, was whether the "average" here was the
mean or the median. After all, if most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are still holding stocks for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, but a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are now holding stocks for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX>,
or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX>, and trading those stocks constantly, the mean holding period
would drop significantly, even if the experience of most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> had not
materially changed.

            The same problem is even more true of the statistics about share turnover,
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> shares turning over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 200 percent</NUMEX> of its shares in a
single year. Day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> and technical-trading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> now account for a
significant percentage of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>'s volume on both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX>,
and by essentially trading stocks among themselves--and serving as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> for the rest of us--they have contributed massively to share turnover.
But it's a mistake to say they're emblematic of the investing world as a
whole.

            Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> trade more now than they ever did. If you drop the cost
of doing something by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> or more (which is what the advent of the
Internet did to commissions), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will do more of it. And as it's become
clearer and clearer that mutual-fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockbrokers</ENAMEX> are no more
likely to have market-beating knowledge than the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> is, it's also
become harder to justify giving your money to either, especially with the fees
they charge. To be sure, you shouldn't take your money from a mutual-fund
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and run it yourself. You should put it in an index fund. But even
long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> think they can be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Buffett</ENAMEX>. I know I do.

            All of this, though, is a far cry from saying that all of us who use the Net
or discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> are day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, which is what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> seems
positively bent on saying. There is no evidence for that at all. More
important, there's no evidence that all this trading is having detrimental
effects on the capital markets. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgenson</ENAMEX> argues that excessive trading is
responsible for the increased volatility of the market. But there's no control
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> here. The rise of individual investing has occurred simultaneous with the
creation of an entirely new industry, the Internet, which has spawned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
of new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> whose future prospects are incredibly difficult to evaluate.
In that situation, volatility is to be expected, since the market's view of
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospects</ENAMEX> is more likely to change rapidly than will its view of, say,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>'s future. And, as I suggested a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of weeks ago</TIMEX>, the more information you have, the more noise you'll
have in the stock market, leading to more volatility. Trading here may be a
symptom more than a cause.

            In any case, the thing to remember about all this is that every time someone
sells a stock, someone else is buying it. And in terms of capital allocation,
it's irrelevant whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> selling the stock has held it for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years or seven days</TIMEX>. All that matters is whether the price is higher or lower
than the last trade. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgenson</ENAMEX>'s article is full of these vague forebodings
that all this trading will lead to doom once the bull market ends. But just as
on the way up there have been no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX>, on the way down (if we
do go down) there will be no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>. To reiterate a point I've
made before, the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there are in the market (though how much they
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> is irrelevant), the deeper and more resilient it is, and the smarter it
is.

            So, yes, for our own sakes we should all buy and hold. But for the market's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sake</ENAMEX>, well, it doesn't really matter.

         
      
   
