
   
   
      
         
            Pay Up, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shrum</ENAMEX>!

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Shrum</ENAMEX>* attempted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manfully</ENAMEX> to deny that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> had ever suggested he'd make support of his
policy on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> in the military a "litmus test" for nomination to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiefs of Staff</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was doing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shrum</ENAMEX> said, was restating the
constitutional principle that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiefs</ENAMEX> are obliged to obey their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>:

            
               What he said ... was that he would insist that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> appointed to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs of Staff</ENAMEX> agree to support his policy as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. He never
said in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> debate that he would inquire into their personal
convictions. His litmus test is a constitutional one, civilian control of the
military ... I defy you to find a place in that transcript where he ever said
he would inquire into someone's personal position. ... I'll bet you 10 bucks.
Find him saying that he's going to examine their personal
convictions.
            

            Nice try, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>! But the transcript of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> debate makes it
pretty damn clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was saying exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shrum</ENAMEX> said he didn't say.
The video clip played by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> might not have nailed the
issue down (it showed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> declaring, "I would insist before appointing anybody
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs of Staff</ENAMEX> that that individual support my policy."). But the
discussion that precedes the clip does. The whole context was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX>'
question about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> would apply a "litmus test" to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiefs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> like that occasionally applied, controversially, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>. In the context of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, of course, "litmus test"
clearly means an inquiry into a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>'s personal convictions--on,
say, abortion or civil rights--prior to their nomination.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said he had "rejected the notion of litmus tests on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
by saying there are ways to find out the kind of judgment somebody has without
posing specific litmus tests." He then said:

            
               I think that it's a little different where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs of</ENAMEX>
Staff are concerned, because you're not interfering with an independent
judicial decision. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is giving orders, in
effect, or he is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superior</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> that are reporting to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX>. I would try to bring about the kind
of change in policy, on the "don't ask, don't tell" policy, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX> brought about after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> in integrating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> .
And I think that would require those who wanted to serve in on the position
of--on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs of Staff</ENAMEX> to be in agreement with that policy. So,
yes. [Emphasis added.]
            

            This isn't quite a smoking <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>, but it's mighty close. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> might
say, it all depends on what the definition of "in agreement with" is. It was
clear to me, watching the debate, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> meant that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>'s personal
views had to be "in agreement." For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, that is what "in agreement"
means. It's also what the explicit analogy with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> litmus test
implies. (Otherwise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> would have said, "You don't need a litmus test,
because they have to obey the policy whatever their personal views are." Or he
could have used the word "obey" or "support" instead of "be in agreement
with.")

            This interpretation is reinforced by the reality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>-in-the-military
debate: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> can't just order the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiefs</ENAMEX> to change the
"don't-ask" policy, since that policy has now been written into law by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and changing it requires congressional action. That's why it would be
so important for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to know that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>
personally support his policy (so they'll be on his side in the battle
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>) and not just that they will obey him (which wouldn't do the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> any good).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>: Don't you owe someone <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>?

            * Conflict of interest disclosure: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shrum</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marylouise Oates</ENAMEX>,
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of mine. I've eaten dinner at their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>; I've even stayed there
when in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. God, it's all too embarrassing. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shrum</ENAMEX> may have been
a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> in this instance, attempting to defend an untenable position.
But in a very brief phone conversation, he said he'd read the whole transcript,
and he seemed sincere in sticking to his interpretation. I admit I haven't been
so understanding of others, such as 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
Carville
               , who haven't fed me so many meals.
            

         
      
   
