
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain Mutiny</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> is overreacting to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> 's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 5</TIMEX> scandal story about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
attention when it first broke in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> (click here to read the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 16</TIMEX> article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-Gazette</ENAMEX> ), the story landed on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>,
and on the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> today. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">appropriately</ENAMEX>, put the story on pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A5 and B5</TIMEX>, respectively. If Chatterbox
were feeling conspiratorial, he might argue that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is hyping the
story because it previously was hyped in a newspaper its corporate parent
happens to own. But that would be precisely the sort of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-plus</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-equals-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> reasoning that made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> story Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> news to begin
with. Probably the real reason the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> gave the story big play is that
it feels self-conscious about the favorable coverage <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s candidacy has
been getting from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> in general.

            In case you missed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> story, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Koppel</ENAMEX>'s uncharacteristically clumsy interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
last night on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> , or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> follow-ups <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, here's what
we know: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, and again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, in his capacity as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Commerce</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, wrote testy letters to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>
demanding swift action on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxson Communications</ENAMEX>' proposed acquisition of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> TV station. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reprinted the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> letter; to read
it, click here) The deal had been held up for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than two years</TIMEX>,
even though, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> noted in passing, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> has never
turned down a local market license transfer." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italics Chatterbox's</ENAMEX>.) The only
significant complication in the case was that the transfer involved a public TV
station that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paxson</ENAMEX> wanted to convert to commercial use; apparently, such
conversions are rare. But this was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliates</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>. How many public TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> need? Shortly after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> prodded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> approved the acquisition,
which the (somewhat liberal) editorial page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pittsburgh Post-Gazette</ENAMEX> called "long overdue."

            The reason you're hearing about this at all is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> have
contributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $20,000</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s presidential campaign, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxson</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lent McCain</ENAMEX> its corporate jet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times (though campaign law requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
to reimburse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxson</ENAMEX> the price of a first-class ticket, that doesn't really
cover the cost). Thus the implied twin themes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> and
Times pieces: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Having been nicked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keating</ENAMEX> Five
scandal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> still doesn't understand that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> should refrain from
pressuring regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to serve the interests of their campaign
contributors; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s sermons about money corrupting politics are
hypocritical, because he's just as corrupt as everyone else.

            Based on what we know so far, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) is a bum rap. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has stated over and
over in his defense, he never told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> to approve the
transfer; he just asked it to stop dithering and make a decision. As he wrote
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the December</TIMEX> letter, "my purpose is not to suggest in any way
how you should vote--merely that you vote." This is absolutely what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that oversees the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>,
to do. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William E. Kennard</ENAMEX>'s reply, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s query was "highly
unusual," and threatened to harm "the due process rights of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>." But
anyone even vaguely familiar with the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> works knows that it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drowning</ENAMEX> in "due process." Probably a more honest reply would have been:
Look, we're not supposed to say so, but one of the ways we do policy at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> is through delay. When you interfere with our dithering, you're forcing us
to change policy. Get off my back. But that wouldn't have been a good
answer, either; in most instances, bureaucratic delay is not the best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to make policy. Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxson</ENAMEX> transfer to go through?
Yes, probably. But if the inexorable logic of making a decision was that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> would approve the transfer , that's hardly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s fault.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oddly</ENAMEX>, both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> make only glancing mention
of a separate instance in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> complained to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> that it was
applying too strict a standard of review to a deal involving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ameritech</ENAMEX>, whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> was raising money for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>. This sounds like much more of a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keating</ENAMEX>,"
but one would have to know more facts.)

            On to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>): Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> a hypocrite? After the story broke, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> said, "The
system corrupts all of us." This would argue for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">no.</ENAMEX>" On the other hand,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> doesn't carry his commitment to frankness so far as to admit that of
course he gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxson</ENAMEX>'s case more attention than he would that of someone
who didn't contribute money to his campaign. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
story, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has

            

               
                  often forwarded complaints from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> and others from outside
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> without taking any position, following the practice of most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX>.
Many of those were not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>. ... But in the vast majority of those
particular regulatory matters where Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> himself sent a letter, the
interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> had contributed to his presidential or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
campaigns.
               

            

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> on the matter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanny Davis</ENAMEX>
(formerly a legal flak <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>), got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
Reps. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steny Hoyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Udall</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Klink</ENAMEX> to go <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step further than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
and actually urge the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> to approve the sale. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> surely deserves
some credit for not doing that . The more important point, though, is
that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s campaign-finance bill were passed, the pressures that compel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoyer, et al.</ENAMEX>, to be more helpful to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> than they are to others
would (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hopes) be reduced. If this makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> a hypocrite, so are the
other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who are serious about campaign-finance
reform. The other major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>--who's already swatted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of times about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> matter--is entirely free of this taint. But
that's just another way of saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> would do nothing to curb the big-money
influence on politics.

         
      
   
