
   
   
      
         
            Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX> Ephron Broker the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL-Time Warner</ENAMEX> Deal?

            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Ephron</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s proposed acquisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>? Ephron
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">co-authored</ENAMEX> and directed the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> movie, You've Got
Mail , a somewhat flatfooted update of the charming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernst Lubitsch</ENAMEX>
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Shop Around the Corner</ENAMEX> (which was also the source material for
the even more charming <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1963 Broadway musical She Loves Me</ENAMEX> ). You've
Got Mail updated the earlier film's epistolary plot (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopkeepers</ENAMEX> hate
each other by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>, each not knowing the other is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> to whom
he/she sends anonymous love letters by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>) for the Internet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX>; in the new
version, the two swapped messages via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>. This was made clear not only by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>'s title and logo but also by a scene in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Ryan</ENAMEX> used
AOL instant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">messaging</ENAMEX> while lying on their respective beds to discuss why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> revere
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> movies.

            As it happens, You've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> was made by ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>! In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retrospect</ENAMEX>, then, it may have been not merely a romantic comedy with a little
product placement tossed in; it may have been an attempt to soften the
ground for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s latest acquisition. Although the film doesn't portray
AOL-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> in any particular light, it does portray <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX>,
scion of another giant communications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> (in this case a
Borders/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX>-type book superstore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>) as being sweet and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">misunderstood</ENAMEX>, even though he puts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Ryan</ENAMEX>'s independent bookstore out of
business! Also, think about how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meg Ryan</ENAMEX>'s leftist-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer boyfriend</ENAMEX>, played
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Kinnear</ENAMEX>, is portrayed in the film. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinnear</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> (an apparent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amalgam of New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Observer columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> and
editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Navasky</ENAMEX>) is shown to be an amusingly vain and
pretentious technophobe. This is significant, because in the film it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinnear</ENAMEX>
who gets to articulate the case against concentration of corporate power.
And he's a buffoon! You'd no sooner entrust the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy to him than
you'd entrust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Ryan</ENAMEX> to him! (Chatterbox pauses here to emphasize that he
doesn't consider either <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navasky</ENAMEX> to be vain or pretentious, though
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> is a bit of a technophobe; see his 
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dispatches</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Luddite Gets Wired</ENAMEX>," which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> was too much of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Luddite</ENAMEX> ever to
complete. In real life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Ryan</ENAMEX> would be lucky to have either gentleman for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boyfriend</ENAMEX>, though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navasky</ENAMEX> is already married.) When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX> finally
smooch at the film's end, you can think of it as a consummated romance; or, you
can think of it as ... a merger!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is well aware that he is engaging in just the sort of paranoid
logic that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinnear</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> would indulge in. Still, if the merger does go
through, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> urges the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> take the precaution of
stipulating that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL Time Warner</ENAMEX> not be permitted to film any sequels to
You've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> . Or, if such sequels are permitted, the characters
should be compelled to switch over to another Internet service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erols</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MindSpring</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mindful</ENAMEX> of his
own corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s delicate position vis-à-vis the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> won't suggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSN</ENAMEX>.)

         
      
   
