
   
   
      
         
            Politics and It's Disconnects
            

            I was watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miami TV</ENAMEX> coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> decision on "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>"--they
called it "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Decision Day</ENAMEX>"--and, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, those local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> don't want to get
nasty letters from any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. I don't know if you can access any tape
of this stuff, but the street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> were moaning over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s lost
opportunities. I'm not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, nor will I be the last, to note that family
values take a backseat to the chance at some stock options in the hearts of a
lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>.

            While on the subject of (as the current lingo has it) disconnects, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> has an interesting story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> pressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> to
take a speedy vote on an application by a contributor to his campaign to buy a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> TV station. Don't get me wrong, I'm not a fan of reform, living in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> of reform has turned our politics into an
insider's game. (The one reform that might work is free TV time, were not the
broadcast lobby one of the strongest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>--for proof, see the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Telecommunications Act of 1996</ENAMEX>.) But I note with glee that conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> of the status quo argue a version of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Unruh</ENAMEX> line about
being able to take a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s money (to fully quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>, "and eat his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, and
drink his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX>, and screw his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>") and still vote against him--but, when
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX> trots out its tabulation of how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> vote in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. General Assembly</ENAMEX>, it cross-refs those votes with how much money the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
gives each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in foreign aid. So we should only expect votes to be well
and truly bought when they're the votes of sovereign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>.

            I ascribe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiFi</ENAMEX>'s lack of opposition to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assiduous</ENAMEX> courting of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>, where major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> have lined up behind her,
and, more important, the sad state of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grey Davis</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>, is triangulating like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and it's giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reps</ENAMEX>
fits.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riordan</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, although one of those splendid reforms keeps
that fact a secret from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, and he's an amiable enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who has used his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rhetorical</ENAMEX> and organizational muscle to force some changes--or at least rumors
of changes--at the school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. But, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> is an executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> without a lot of power. He couldn't be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>
if he wanted to. Plus, we have so few <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX>, and they don't go very far, so
it's easy to make them run on time. Actually, the school system is in bad
enough shape that there's major support behind breaking up the district, and
the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> has a metastasizing scandal in one of its central-city
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stations</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of cases may have to be reopened, due to revelations that,
yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Dershowitz</ENAMEX> is right, the cops do lie), so, aside from the weather and
the economy, it's not all that golden. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riordan</ENAMEX>'s term is up shortly, though,
and, if he can lick statewide animosity toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>, he might be the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' best hope for beating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boxer</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leno</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
