
   
   
      
         
            Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Like Son</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Judith</ENAMEX>,

            Nice e-mail. I'm glad to see you're ending this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> without busting a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cap</ENAMEX> in my ass.

            OK--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carmela Soprano</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>? I want to run this one by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>.

            You've got it exactly right--it's evident from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> episodes of the new
season that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> have lost interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carmela</ENAMEX>, which is a tragedy,
because, as you put it so well (have you ever thought of taking up a career in
writing?), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Havarti</ENAMEX>, or whatever she's called, is an "epic
drag."

            Your observations about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carmela</ENAMEX>, and your questions about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meadow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony</ENAMEX>
junior, her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, bring us to one of the more interesting subtopics in
mobology: What do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> know, and how do they live with what they
know?

            The answer, especially to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> question, is mostly unknowable to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>. I have never spoken to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> who said, straight-out,
yeah, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s a made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and I'm not going to cover-up for him anymore.
Even when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s are dead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> still lie. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castellano</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> (a completely legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, as far as I could tell), told
me that there is no such thing as organized crime, and that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was set
up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> the same way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was set up. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mob families</ENAMEX> (not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX>, but actual nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>) are among the most dysfunctional on the
planet--they lie, they wear masks on top of masks, and they live off dirty
money. I remember sitting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vicky Gotti</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day last year</TIMEX>, asking her what
she thought her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> really did for a living. Remember--this is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was convicted of being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gambino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. No one in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gotti</ENAMEX> was a simple plumbing-supply <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>.
But all she could come up with was this: "There's more to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> than people
know." I asked her what she meant. She said, "There's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> to this story."
I asked her to explain further: "It's just more complicated than what you
think." She will never be able to say what she knows: that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>.
And yet, here's the irony: I don't think she's embarrassed by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s
career choice. In fact, after spending some time with her, I came to believe
that she sincerely loves him, even worships him.

            By the way, I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meadow Soprano</ENAMEX> bought her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s cover story at
all. She's the one who explained to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthony</ENAMEX> junior what their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> really did
for a living. I think you're right, though: If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meadow</ENAMEX> heard the unadorned
truth, she would be miserable. You may also be right that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meadow</ENAMEX> is on the
verge of becoming the next great female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. But I'm waiting for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthony</ENAMEX>
junior (there I go again, dissing the female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>) to ask his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> when
he's going to be a made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.

            This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> test of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob character</ENAMEX>, as I said before: He who makes his
own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>--instead of keeping him far away from the gangster life--is considered
the ultimate scumbag. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlo Gambino</ENAMEX>, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greats</ENAMEX>, would never induct his
own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>. Only after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlo</ENAMEX> died did his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> get made. Sammy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull</ENAMEX> tells a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> story: When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gotti</ENAMEX>, bursting with pride, told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent "Chin</ENAMEX>" Gigante
that he had just made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigante</ENAMEX> said that he was sorry to hear
it.

            Talk about a great story line for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> : I'd love to see how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Soprano</ENAMEX> reacts if and when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> asks to join the business. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Soprano</ENAMEX>
is an upwardly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mobile gangster</ENAMEX>, so one assumes he'd recoil in horror, but I'm
sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> could do something interesting with
this. (Despite my disappointment with the new season so far, I have a great
deal of faith.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX>, it's been great doing this piece of work (as the button <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> would
say) with you. I find you to be quite lovable, for an intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herring</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
