
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradleyites</ENAMEX> vs. the Goreheads
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>,

            So much in the papers <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>! My fave: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> has
a piece on the thuggery between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>,
where campaigners have actually gotten into shoving matches. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> gal
claims to have been nearly trampled to death by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradleyites</ENAMEX>; a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradleyite</ENAMEX> said
she was nearly pushed into the path of a minivan by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goreheads</ENAMEX>. What can
they possibly be saying? "Listen you little prick, handgun registration is fine
but licensing is a step too far. Eat this! Next time maybe your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> won't vote
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Souter</ENAMEX>'s nominations." The idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>-wielding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> is hysterical.

            Then there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> separating. Can the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonda</ENAMEX>-Torricelli union be far
behind? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arianna</ENAMEX>?

            Oh, and there in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.W.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny" Apple</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>
and final installment of his food series from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> on polenta
were one thing, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> he kicks it off with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> worlds on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Marzano</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX>! At first I laughed; now I await each dispatch. Did you miss last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> words on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rye bread</ENAMEX>?

            It's all too much for a gal like me.

            Thanks for your advice about this congressional dinner. I figured you'd had
some bad experience--maybe some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> goons did a number on you--and didn't
want to talk about it. Eh, I know what you mean about playing to the cameras,
but I do have to live in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and a bomb could set my comedy and
journalistic careers back a ways, so I plan to pander shamelessly. But that may
not be easy: This dinner's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> primary, which means
I've got to crank out some fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, and I may not be well
positioned. For some strange reason, as 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> will soon
see, I've turned out a solid <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> imitation. This, I fear, may not be a
great asset. Fortunately, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> are solid, and I think I'll have
a passable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. You ever imitate real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, or is it all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>?
(Suck-up: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX> may be one of the greatest figures ever in our culture.) Is
one harder than the other?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
