
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best of Most Possible Worlds</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jim</ENAMEX>,

            It's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 3</TIMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Clubbing</ENAMEX>, which means it's time for us to crawl back
out of the little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX> we've excavated and return to our day jobs. But before
I surrender this space, let me hit a couple of points.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> wants <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, who he mistakenly thinks have "lost touch," to drop
what they're doing and create a debate society for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, who he thinks are
"alienated," in hopes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Palaver</ENAMEX> will convince them to join together
and take a crack at solving society's problems. Body check me if I'm being
unfair--but actually solving problems takes a backseat to process
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> universe. To invoke a computer-industry cliché, process is a
strange metric to judge the success of a piece of journalism. If an article
doesn't encourage the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> to meet and cogitate, it's a failure? As I
finished his book, I couldn't help but think, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wouldn't Rosen</ENAMEX> be a lot happier
working as a union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX> or ward heeler than as a press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>?

            Like the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'80s</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> who used the phrase "economic democracy" as their
euphemism for socialism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> cribs the word "democracy" to serve as a vague
stand-in for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deweyan</ENAMEX> utopia he wants us to build. Please, include me out!
Or give me a better idea of what this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Deweyan</ENAMEX> democracy will look like.

            Rereading my previous entries, I blushed at my <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Panglossian</ENAMEX> take on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
journalism ... but when my blood pressure stablized, I felt vindicated. Whereas
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> journalism used to be crap (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sturgeon's Law</ENAMEX>), I
personally reckon that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 85 percent</NUMEX> of it is now. What strides we've made!
So if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> really wants to frame his debate--and his call to arms--around some
imagined "crisis" in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> journalism, let him make a better case about how
awful things are. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parenthetically</ENAMEX>, I agree with your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
correlation of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-'80s</TIMEX> recession and the cuts in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">newsroom</ENAMEX> budgets
with public journalism's boom. Those were dark times for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, and I
fear that some of them went grasping at straws.)

            Journalism ain't broke, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> isn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to fix it even if it is. For
the time being, I'll put my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> in that the rollicking goulash of advocacy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>, public-interest lobbying, scientific inquiry, straight-up news
reporting, first-person confessional, government documents, academic findings,
rumors, and innuendo that finds its way into print and into the wires.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Regards,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
