
   
   
      
         
            Not Gotcha

            My 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colleague Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>
argues that the ... let's call it the unfolding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s position on the great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chiefs Gay Litmus Test</ENAMEX> issue was not sufficiently flip-floppy "to
constitute a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'reversal</NUMEX>.'" Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> in 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fray</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">echo</ENAMEX> this view, dismissing the whole controversy as a phony media game of
"gotcha." I respectfully disagree.

            First, of course it was a reversal. Initially, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said he would
require that any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiefs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> be "in agreement with" his gay policy. Then he
came back and denied there should "ever be any kind of inquiry into the
personal, political opinion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>." The only "litmus
test," explained his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Shrum</ENAMEX>, was the banal "constitutional one,
civilian control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>." Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Position No. 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Schwarzkopf</ENAMEX> get bounced. Under Position No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, it would seem, they
don't, since they presumably agree with the principle of civilian control.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> says no, there is little functional difference between demanding
"agreement" and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> position (demanding constitutionally-required
"support"), since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> knows that those who disagree are likely to sabotage his
policy. The only difference, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> says, is that demanding "'support' ...
leaves open the theoretical possibility of appointing a military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> so
honorable that he will work assiduously to implement a policy he personally
disagrees with." But under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> position, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> won't know who
personally agrees or disagrees with his policy, since he says he won't inquire
into the actual views of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiefs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. (Don't Ask, Don't
Tell!)

            More important, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> assumes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> would never appoint somebody who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disagrees</ENAMEX>, and might therefore sabotage the policy (among disagreers, only the
theoretical perfectly honorable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> would pass muster). But it's exactly
that assumption that bothers those who worry about a "litmus test"--the idea
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> would give a privileged position to the gay issue, ruling out a candidate
who was otherwise a military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> and inspirational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> solely because he
had (in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s mind) retrograde views on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>.

            That implication, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s answer No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, is what made it genuinely
troubling, a legitimate gaffe. It suggested the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> was so keen on
his gay policy that he would give it higher priority than other military
issues, such as how to win wars (or counter the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> threats).
Actually, given the crippling effect of the gay controversy on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first six</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s presidency, it implied <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was willing to give the gay
issue priority over non-military issues as well. "Not that again!" you could
almost hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> saying. There are other, more important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> than integrating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> into the armed forces. It's time for some
sensible gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> to point this out. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Sullivan</ENAMEX>, are you still reading
this?)

            At best, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s gaffe revealed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> so eager to pander to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> that he lost his bearings and overstepped the bounds of
good political judgment. That's certainly forgivable--but wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s unique
selling proposition supposed to be his dull-but-sound reliability? You mean
he's boring and a bit of a hothead too?

            P.S.: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s right to ridicule <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Position No. 2</ENAMEX>--why shouldn't a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> inquire into the personal views of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, and try
to appoint someone who agrees with him? A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> who disagrees with a policy
is indeed likely to implement it unenthusiastically. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> could have said,
"Yes, I'll consider a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s views--I'd be naive not to--but I'll look at
the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and the whole range of military issues, not just this one
issue." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">somersaulting</TIMEX> from personal-views-are-a-litmus-test to "I'll never
consider personal views," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> leapt completely over this sensible, obvious
answer. But that doesn't make his performance any less of a reversal, or any
more reassuring.

         
      
   
