
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vehicles of Blame</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>--

            Here it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> and already I feel like
there's too little space to give many weighty subjects the careful analysis
they deserve. There's the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> elections and the re-establishment of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> there. There's the report by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> of the very real
possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> may now have nuclear capabilities. And let's not forget
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee Titans</ENAMEX>' improbable journey to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFC</ENAMEX> finals.

            But my favorite story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> is from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . A group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
tried to determine whether sports utility <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> (which I like to call
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SUVs</ENAMEX>") clog <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">intersections</ENAMEX> and slow down traffic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kara M. Kockelman</ENAMEX>
and her trusty graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> sidekick, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raheel A. Shabih</ENAMEX>, authored a study in
which they videotaped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> as they stopped and started at a
busy intersection. (And you can be sure that like all <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">grad-student</ENAMEX>/professor
relationships, the labor on this one was divided equally--"You know, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raheel</ENAMEX>,
normally I would be happy to stand out in the rain
and suck in all those exhaust fumes, but you know, my asthma and all. Besides,
you're so much better with the camera and I really need to finish working on
your recommendation ...")

            They determined that, compared with normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX>, light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup trucks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">minivans</ENAMEX> put more distance between
themselves when they stop and accelerate more slowly at green lights, and when
you combine these factors with the increased length of the aforementioned large
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vehicles</ENAMEX>, you get slower traffic and more traffic jams.

            Well, as far as I'm concerned, any story that knocks
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX> is a good story. I've always hated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX>. They guzzle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>, they pollute the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">air</ENAMEX>, and as far as I'm concerned, they're rolling death machines--just ask my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cousin Marshall</ENAMEX> who was nearly crushed to death by one back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'97</TIMEX>. (OK, not
really. I don't even have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX>. But I needed something to justify
my unreasonable anger.) Anyway, nothing drives me crazier than to watch one of
these monstrosities lumber through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> traffic when I
know-- know --that the toughest terrain that thing is
going to see is the gravel-covered driveway of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> home in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Westport</ENAMEX>. So now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kockelman</ENAMEX> and her trusty sidekick have proved
definitively that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX> ruin not just the environment but our very quality of
life, maybe our elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> will stop worrying so much about
ethanol subsidies and do something to get these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-wheeled menaces off our
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>.

            (And yes, I noticed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kockelman</ENAMEX> and Raheel
also included <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">minivans</ENAMEX> in the study, but I don't have a problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">minivans</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">'cause soccer</ENAMEX> moms drive them and there's no way you're going to trick me into
going after soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moms</ENAMEX> on the record.)

            By the way, what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> do you drive?

         
      
   
