
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Toobin</ENAMEX>, Hypocrite

            In his new book rehashing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Toobin</ENAMEX> is disgusted
by the "fixation on the personal" that leads <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and others to
investigate "the private lives of public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>, he says, "could
define tawdry voyeurism as the study of 'character,' but the labeling couldn't
obscure the true nature of this new kind of reporting." It amounted, Toobin
argues, to a "high-minded rationale for covering the sex lives of famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" that satisfied a "hunger for sleaze" in a "competitive market for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and journalism." The dust jacket for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toobin</ENAMEX>'s book, A Vast
Conspiracy , says it "analyzes the facts ... with a measure of dignity
[that] this story has not yet received."

            So what does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX> do to publicize his book? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dump Clinton</ENAMEX> sex documents on
the Internet! Specifically, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, the Web site for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toobin</ENAMEX>'s book promises "the complete and unexpurgated depositions of Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>," a "secretly recorded interview with Juanita
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>" [who claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sexually assaulted her], and--most dignified of
all--"the complete text of the affidavit in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> identifies
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">purported 'distinguishing characteristics'</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>."

            I called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Toobin</ENAMEX> and asked him why this wasn't hypocritical, and he offered
various semi-contradictory answers. First, he said that "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> of the
documents" is "what you would call a sex document." The "rest are highly
political." The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sex document, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toobin</ENAMEX>'s view, is the 'distinguishing
characteristic' affidavit (in which, as was reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a year ago</TIMEX>, Jones
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s penis was crooked). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX>'s classification system is
suspect. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> deposition, for example, has already been partially
made public. The parts that haven't, but that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toobin</ENAMEX> will now post, seem to
consist largely of defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> grilling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> on the details of her private
sex life. That makes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> sex documents--and gee, they just happen to
be the ones highlighted on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toobin</ENAMEX> Web site!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toobin</ENAMEX> then told me he was justified in releasing the documents because they
were "part of history now." He then switched course, saying, "There's no point
arguing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't interested in it. ... I like gossip as much as the next
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX>. The difference between me and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character police</ENAMEX> is that I don't try to
dress gossip up as more than it is." As, say, "part of history"?

            But wait a minute! Would it have been OK to report on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sex life in
all its moist detail if the press had only admitted the purpose was pure
gossip? That can't be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toobin</ENAMEX>'s position. It's impossible to read his book, with
its righteous denunciations of "tawdry voyeurism," and think his main complaint
with the coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sex life is that it wasn't forthright enough
about the pleasures of disclosing the "private lives of public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."

            I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX> can escape the charge of massive hypocrisy. He's
written a book denouncing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who sell books by revealing salacious private
sexual details--and he's selling his book by revealing salacious private sexual
details, or at least hinting he'll reveal them. (It's even less excusable, in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, to reveal those details now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
impeachment, have been settled. If something was too private to reveal then,
why not let it rest for now?) ...

            Of course, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toobin</ENAMEX>'s hypocrisy may not be enough to turn his book into a
commercial success. Are you itching to read another breathless account of what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> said to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Traylor</ENAMEX>? I didn't think so. ...

         
      
   
