
   
   
      
         
            Is AOL Paying Too Much for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>?
            

            The most telling--and remarkable--line in all the reams (virtual and real)
of commentary and analysis already written about <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$184 billion</NUMEX>
acquisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> was this one, by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justin Lahart of TheStreet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>:
"The high price that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> is willing to pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> suggests that media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can carry much higher valuations."

            Now, whether it really suggests that at all is an interesting question,
which we'll get to in a minute. But the important thing about this line is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> it illuminates just how dramatic the shift in power in the media world has
been over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three to four years</TIMEX>, and how real certain of these
supposedly inflated Internet valuations have become. Because in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lahart</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">formulation</ENAMEX>, it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> that's validating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s business by merging
with it. On the contrary, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> that has that power of validation, not just
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> but apparently for the entire world of offline media. By
acquiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> seems to be saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Content</ENAMEX> still does matter.
There is a market for more traditional forms of journalism and entertainment."
This is a nice thing for "content <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>" to hear. But what's awesome--in
that old sense of the word--is that it took <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> to say it for the market to
believe it.

            From this perspective, what's really impressive about the deal is that it's
an all-stock acquisition (aside from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>'s debt, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> will
assume). In other words, this validation of the media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> is
apparently performing is being done with a currency that old-media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> always
used to slag as "debased" or "overinflated." But neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> nor the market seems to have any problem with that. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Levin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> and the prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, put it, "We think
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL Time Warner</ENAMEX> [which is how much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> will
get in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>] is worth more than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>." And
since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>'s shares ended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 40 percent</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> do,
too. Internet money, it seems, is now real money.

            That is, as it happens, how it should be. Although there are plenty of Net
stocks whose shares are overinflated--just don't ask me which Net
stocks--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> is not one of them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is generating huge amounts of free
cash flow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, its return on invested capital is only going to rise in
the future, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> growth remains startling, and switching costs for
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> are actually higher than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> imagine. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>
was worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$83 billion</NUMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of last week</TIMEX> (which the market said it was),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> was probably worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the $161 billion</NUMEX> at which the market was valuing it.

            If you think that last sentence is pure madness, then the rest of this will
seem equally nutty. But for the sake of argument, let's say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> really is
worth what the market says it's worth. If it is, then the obvious question is:
If AOL was twice as valuable as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, why is its management
making a deal on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that treats it as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 1.2</NUMEX> times as valuable as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>?

            There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> answers. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Case</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Pittman</ENAMEX> really
think their stock is overvalued, and that this is their chance to
acquire some assets with real value before the Internet bubble bursts. But I
don't believe they think this at all (and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Levin</ENAMEX> is hoping they
don't). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, obviously, is that they believe the combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s
assets with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>'s--both its content (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, publishing, TV, movies,
and music) and its cable lines--will create more value than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
would have created had they remained apart. In other words, they think there
actually will be real synergy between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sets of assets.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Synergy</ENAMEX> is the great will-o'-the-wisp of mergers, and although I think
there's a plausible case that some real value will be created because of this
deal than otherwise would have been (click here for some
thoughts on this issue), the only question that matters is whether that value
will be equal to the premium <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> is paying for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>'s shares. And given
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s shares actually fell <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 4 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the market's initial
answer is that it won't. Right now, the market thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> overpaid--as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">acquirers</ENAMEX> almost always do--for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>.

            Let's be clear about what it would mean if the market's right. It wouldn't
mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL Time Warner</ENAMEX> won't become the most powerful media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in the
world. It wouldn't mean that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> won't be incredibly profitable in the
future. It wouldn't even mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL Time Warner</ENAMEX> isn't going to create lots
of shareholder value in the future. What it would mean is that the difference
between the value <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL Time Warner</ENAMEX> will create and the value <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> would have
created on its own (and that includes whatever return it could get on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$184</NUMEX>
billion it's shelling out) will be less than what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> just paid for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>.

            The problem, of course, is that no one keeps track of these things, and a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade from now</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL Time Warner</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200 million</NUMEX> global Internet/cable
TV<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">/wireless subscribers</ENAMEX> and a market cap of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700 billion</NUMEX>, it's going to be hard
to say the deal was a mistake, even if it was. But before we jump to the
conclusion that this deal means that other media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are worth a lot more
than we thought they were, it's worth remembering that if the stock market has
been valuing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> and other media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>--and has been valuing
them that way for a while, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>'s share price essentially didn't
move in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> comes along and says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> is actually worth almost
2X, our default assumption should not be that media stocks have been
undervalued. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Case</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Pittman</ENAMEX> are, no doubt about it, brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>.
But if you want to know what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> are really worth, you're better off
trusting the market than trusting them.

         
      
   
