
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grunts' Groans</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s proposal for establishing
a nationwide computer system for rapidly tracking the course of infectious
diseases like the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C. The New York Times</ENAMEX> lead also connects
medicine and cyberspace with a report that the rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' online
pharmaceutical purchases via foreign-based Web sites has led to record levels
of illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> imports, judging from the latest figures on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs Service</ENAMEX>
seizures of imported <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, which ran <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 4.5</NUMEX> times higher than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with good news about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>: The implementation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s campaign against fraudulent claims, combined with the low inflation rate,
has kept spending in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 25-year-old</TIMEX> program to its lowest growth rate ever.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with a private study of the
attitudes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>. Main findings of the worldwide
survey of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX>: The service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> feel overworked and underpaid, feel that
they don't have enough resources to carry out their assignments, and lack
confidence in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. But, according to the survey, they still have a
deep commitment to military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>. By the way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that
the issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> in the military was hardly ever mentioned by the service
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> study is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and is fronted at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . It runs inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . (To see that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
military isn't the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> with big problems, click here.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead explains the need to replace the current patchwork
paper-and-pencil-and-phone disease-reporting system: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thirty-five</ENAMEX> new infectious
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> have been identified since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, while some older ones have been
reincarnated as drug-resistant superbugs.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead points out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> advises <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> not to
purchase meds from foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> because they will generally be illegal
(because, for instance, they're not labeled properly or don't meet purity
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standards</ENAMEX>), but adds that usually the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> doesn't bother <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> ordering
small amounts (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to three months</TIMEX>' worth) for their own use.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> puts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> news in perspective by stating that the
cost of health-care spending by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> was up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.9 percent</NUMEX>.
An inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP AP</ENAMEX> dispatch has that figure and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> one. But the
story also states, in contrast to the fiscal optimism expressed high up by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> costs are not expected to continue to drop, once
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> begin to attain eligibility in large numbers.

            A wild but true crime tale unfolds in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's
off-lead. Somebody has tried to extort <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> from online music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> CD
Universe by threatening to release some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 300,000</NUMEX>
customer credit-card files. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> wouldn't comply, says the
Times , the intruder has released some of the card numbers on the
Internet and claims to have used some for himself. The paper points out that
the episode is apt to rekindle consumer concerns about online credit card
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX>. Also, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jerkball</ENAMEX>'s e-mail trail leads to eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, the
case stands to highlight the freedom online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> have to operate beyond
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> jurisdiction.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> report that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX>
announced an alliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> announced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX>. Both deals
will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> to register to receive model-specific e-mail
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> covering everything from oil changes to
rebates. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> account adds that the deals are intended to include
Internet access for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> as well.

            Citing a report in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> , inside stories at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say they've caught <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>
trying to smuggle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scud</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> parts through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gatwick Airport</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contretemps</ENAMEX> comes just after the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> re-established diplomatic
relations.

            The WSJ fronts a detailed feature about a type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> increasingly
common in the modern office: a company Internet snoop, who spends <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his days</TIMEX>
checking to see where other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> go on the Web. The story shows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> such
snoop reading the (deleted) e-mails of a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in
question, online access to sites with any nudity is barred, but those about
racism, extremism, violence and profanity, and sports are OK. Other types of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URLs</ENAMEX> frowned upon are music downloading <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> and online investment services.
The story never questions the fundamental assumption of the snoopers: namely
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> should be able to control their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' Web access. Now,
clearly, they have the right to, but the story might have considered whether
this is wise from a productivity point of view. It's the wage-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> mentality
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> workplace performance by input, by the number of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> worked, say.
The enlightened view of how to manage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is to judge them by their
output instead. So why should a company care where an employee surfs as
long as he/she is productive? Who knows--maybe those "irrelevant" visits
stimulate the creativity that's behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>'s next big idea.

            A letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> makes a gimlet observation about the recent upward
economic drift of journalism. The missive notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> recently
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">characterized Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s recent move into her new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> "as a seemingly
typical move on a seemingly typical day, except for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> TV cameras ..." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> goes on to point out that, ahem, this was a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7 million</NUMEX> home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRC</ENAMEX> was
moving into. Typical perhaps for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>, but ...

         
      
   
