
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> Debate: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Waiting for Godot</ENAMEX>"  Version

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Ryerson</ENAMEX> : Get started with opening statements.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> : Talk about tax cuts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> : I really want to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> go.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> : The sanctity of human life.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Logged</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12,000 miles</NUMEX> in your great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council Bluffs</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> : This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> who is fighting for the life of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard T. Meyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burlington</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Forty</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">year-old brother</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Downs</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Syndrome</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> : Provide the long-term care your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> needs.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> : I'm not just talking about it.

            
               Keyes : Shouldn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracies</ENAMEX> dictating to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Savings</ENAMEX> Accounts, etcetera.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes : Vouchers</ENAMEX> and coupons.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : Encourage the purchase of long-term care insurance.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryerson</ENAMEX> : You each have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> : I don't want <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> running it either.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch-Waxman</ENAMEX> bill.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are gridlocked by the big money from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> : You should be able to choose own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> has used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> as a political football.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryerson</ENAMEX> : Ask a question of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the others.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> : On the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> Issue, you've taken the same position.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> : I was there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> : Being naïve

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng Xiopeng</ENAMEX> rolled out the red carpet for me.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> : Might be the problem.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> : I slammed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> so hard that he gave me <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>.

            
               Keyes : <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is to be conducted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
language.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : No <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">es la verdad</ENAMEX> .

            
               Keyes : <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Es la verdad</ENAMEX>, senor .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Un</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">momento</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : Vamanos
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX>, we respect other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s heritage in this country

            
               Keyes : Made insulting and derogatory remarks about black
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : Comments are out of line.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : How anybody could defend our present system?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ought to be ashamed of
themselves.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : Influence of special interest money

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> : Have to raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> a day.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> : A <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">28-minute</TIMEX> fireside chat.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> : I hope the fire survived

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> : The corruption of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> : Its tawdry scheme to try to make money for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> : Opening up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> for exploration?

            
               Keyes : Exploit God's precious resources for the good of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : What do you say to the single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> who's working?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : I've got a tax cut for you and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> doesn't.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : Not true.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : Yes it is.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : Not true.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : All hat and no <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : Cute but.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : Cutest when they're true.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : Not true.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> two-step here.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryerson</ENAMEX> : The family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> is self-employed.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> talks about but doesn't do.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> : <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ten years ago</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> eating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> pork

            
               Keyes : Whole centralized banking system.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : That's what <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> does, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX> controlled by a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> : Whole worlds written on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grains</ENAMEX> of sand

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Fourteen billion gallons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : Helped neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> nor the environment.

            
               Keyes : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consolidated</ENAMEX> control of the banking system at the federal
level.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : We may have biomass <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethanol</ENAMEX> isn't being subsidized.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : Everybody else thinks it is.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Glawe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX> area : How to improve the dignity of the Oval
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> would not go into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> without a coat
and tie on.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine</ENAMEX> and I have been married for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43 years</TIMEX>.

            
               Keyes : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radical</ENAMEX> homosexual agenda.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain : Feckless</ENAMEX> photo-op foreign policy.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> who will see service to our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as a great privilege
and who will not stain the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> of seemingly limited abilities could rise to the
occasion.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessie Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concerned</ENAMEX> about the government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overstepping</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> : Trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, not politicians

            
               Keyes : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abolish the Department of Education</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Choice</ENAMEX> and competition, that's the answer.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : No second-rate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, no second-rate dreams.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> : The founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> were much wiser than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryerson</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Married</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> paying an additional tax of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,400</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Trust Fund</ENAMEX> is a ticking time bomb.

            
               Keyes : All these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> are gong to give you something.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> : Moving chairs around on the deck of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> : I like all the tax plans that have been given here.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> : Flat tax would help stay-at-home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moms</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : Plan that is realistic. That is doable.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is not a hapless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bystander</ENAMEX>.

            
               Keyes : What do we call that? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slavery</ENAMEX>!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> : Under my flat tax plan, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> make out well.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> : I can be for any of these programs.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> : Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> have never seen those tax cuts.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sixty</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nine percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> said overwhelmingly, `you're
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>!'

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> never saw the tax cuts.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : Not true.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryerson</ENAMEX> : How do you post the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten Commandments</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> : The basis of Western Civilization.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> as a great prophet.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : Begin proceedings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> with prayer.

            
               Keyes : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schools</ENAMEX> in the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who pray.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : Seems like to me `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thou Shalt Not Kill'</ENAMEX> is pretty universal.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> : Giving each other the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> salute in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallway</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryerson</ENAMEX> : Tougher laws are needed to protect our environment?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standards</ENAMEX> set by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that rely upon science.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> : Fashionable things that have no real proof like global
warming.

            
               Baue r: Out of control federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyoto Accords</ENAMEX> could add <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3000</NUMEX> to everyone's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> bills.

            
               Keyes : Is there any shortage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> in the world?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX> was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> and is.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryerson</ENAMEX> : Trim the closing remarks

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> : Message that's positive and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> : I'm an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>.

            
               Keyes : <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Join me in a prayer to Our Creator</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> : Give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> back to you.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> : I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ryerson : Goodbye</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
