
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Wins</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> Beauty Contest
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>,

            I did catch the debate last night, as well as a fair amount of post-game
analysis. First, if you didn't know who the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> were and you were told that one
of them was, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>, one of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
you wouldn't have picked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>. Puffy, jowly, and tired, he looked
pretty awful--is this heart thing worse than they're letting on?--while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
had the full (pre-accident) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Reeves</ENAMEX> look about him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">navy</ENAMEX> suit
worked, I thought. [For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s instant analysis of the debate, click
here.]

            I hate the pre-packaged zinger lines more than anything. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>, if you'd spent time in the private sector ..." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, when you talk
about weighted averages, it reminds me of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with his head in the oven and
his feet on a block of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. His average temperature was fine but he wasn't too
comfortable." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yuck</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington bunker</ENAMEX>" line seemed particularly
annoying from someone who spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and now wants to live in
... <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s trifecta of supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, opposing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'81</NUMEX> budget cuts, and supporting welfare reform seemed pretty effective to me.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, though, was far more charming in the post-game show, where he told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Russert that he was going to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was asked if he, too, was
going to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>, he paused and seemed to search for the best focus-group
tested answer. "I might," he said. "Or a decaf <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>." Double yuck.

            Will <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> find peace in the land of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hatfields</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCoys</ENAMEX>? It must be weird when they hold top-level summit meetings in these
small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>. I went through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassboro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>--home of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ-Khrushchev</ENAMEX> summit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'64</TIMEX>. I can only imagine what the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> premier made
of his first cheesesteak.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> had a thing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> I thought was pretty interesting: How
the glut of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX>-worthy movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the end of the year</TIMEX> is turning off
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moviegoers</ENAMEX>. You know the drill: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> release their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX>-contending
dramatic efforts at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> because films from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX>
tend to do better come <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar Night</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. (This must have something to do
with the fact that most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy members</ENAMEX> are septuagenarians.) Thus, we have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow Falling on Cedars</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Magnolia</ENAMEX> ,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End of the Affair</ENAMEX> , and a bunch of other heavies inundating the
screen. Have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man on the Moon</ENAMEX> yet? I haven't but loved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> and many of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forman</ENAMEX>'s other flix. Did you know the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Kaufman</ENAMEX>
and do you have a take on this cult of personality that's grown up around him?
And yet they continue to ignore the important work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foster Brooks</ENAMEX>?!

            Later.
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
