
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man on the Dark Side of the Moon</ENAMEX>
            

            I agree about one thing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is one of the most compelling arguments for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>'s cancellation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Old-Timers' Game</ENAMEX>. Actually, since the debate
occurred around twilight on this coast, I experienced most of it on the radio,
and I thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> was responding to coaching that he be (slightly) more
punchy in his delivery. On the other hand, when the subject of religion came
up, he told precisely the same story, in precisely the same words, that he had
used on his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> on MSNBC <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day before</TIMEX>. I know, that's my fault for
paying attention.

            I'm an admirer of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milos Forman</ENAMEX>, I enjoyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> as
well, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> nature hasn't made enough wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> to get me to see a movie
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Kaufman</ENAMEX>. Having both seen him as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience member</ENAMEX> and shared
stages with him, I became convinced that he was--how shall we put this
gently?--mentally ill, and that charging money to see him alternately irritate
and infantilize his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> was the modern equivalent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bedlam</ENAMEX>. Why the
posthumous cult of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>? Here's a theory: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaufman</ENAMEX> acted out, in
arguably "interesting" ways, the hostility toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that most people
in show business feel but try (with varying degrees of success) to conceal. He
seemed to me to be part of the wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in comedy who learned the wrong
lesson from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Brooks</ENAMEX>. In his standup and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tonight Show</ENAMEX> work, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albert</ENAMEX>
demonstrated how you could delay the laugh, really prolong the suspense, and
get a much better laugh at the end. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX> and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> took
this to mean you could postpone the laugh forever.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX>, did you open a can of worms. Now, as for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s penchant for
releasing the "classy" movies as close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> time as the rules and the
calendar allow, I agree that the ravages of memory have a lot to do with it.
There's also the fact the industry has developed a code that you can't release
anything short on special effects in the summertime, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and movies that
appeal to them aren't welcome in the plexes until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least October</TIMEX>.
Semi-serious (or intelligently funny, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galaxy Quest</ENAMEX> ) movies around
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> break is at least a better cultural tradition than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christmases</ENAMEX> are rated by whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> had a good slate of
specials and whose awful record made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas</TIMEX> No 1 list.

            See you at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>'s ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
