
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Evolutionary Psychology Teaches Rape</ENAMEX> 101

            Culturebox was not surprised to learn from the latest issue of The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sciences</ENAMEX> that evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> have come up with an answer to the
question of why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> rape. From the beginning, ev psych has portrayed the war
between the sexes as both natural and inevitable: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> have to spread their
genes around by having sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promiscuously</ENAMEX> and by whatever means necessary; women
lavish their scarce reproductive resources only on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> who'll stick around
to ensure that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> thrive. So there was nothing startling about the
arguments of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig T. Palmer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Thornhill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of a famous study on
beauty arguing that throughout world cultures, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> prize symmetrical
features, which correspond to genetic health): <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rape</ENAMEX>, they say, is either a
direct reproductive strategy--what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> resort to when all else fails--or the
byproduct of other reproductive strategies, "such as a strong male sex drive
and the male desire to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> with a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>." What was newsworthy is
what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> suggests we should do to prevent rape.

            Now, before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> reveals <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thornhill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palmer</ENAMEX>'s nifty solution to this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age-old</TIMEX> problem, she has to digress a bit on the subject of evolutionary
psychology. Here's her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> with it: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evolutionary</ENAMEX> psychology is not very good
on the aspect of the human psyche she's personally most interested in, which is
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> are different from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ev</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">psych</ENAMEX> insists, rightly, that we not
ignore our similarities to the higher- and lower-order <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX>, but it's weak
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">subjectivity</TIMEX>, self-awareness, self-consciousness, whatever you want to call
it--on how we explain our tangled mass of hormonal impulses to ourselves. And
yet this ability to reflect on ourselves underlies art, architecture, poetry,
government, journalism, and all the other forms of willed culture and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> don't and can't have. The new sociobiologists
do address complex social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>--particularly ones that require
cooperation--but only in the broadest of terms. They find ways to boil them
down into high-end, unconscious reproductive strategies.

            Some evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> understand the limitations of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>.
They know that it has explanatory power only in general terms, and is useless
in the particular case. They know that their account of human motivation is
deliberately reductive--designed to make it easy to grasp large patterns of
behavior--rather than a rich and accurate description of what and who we are.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thornhill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palmer</ENAMEX>, however, are not among these modest evolutionary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX>. And so they boldly stray into efforts to modify the behaviors of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. They propose a course to teach young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> about rape:

            

               Completion of such a course might be required, say, before a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is
granted a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license. The program might start by inducing the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>
to acknowledge the power of their sexual impulses, and then explaining why
human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> have evolved in that way. The young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> should learn that past
Darwinian selection is the reason that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can get an erection just by
looking at a photo of a naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, why he may be tempted to demand sex even
if he knows that his date truly doesn't want it, and why he might mistake a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX>'s friendly comment or tight blouse as an invitation to sex. Most of all,
the program should stress that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s evolved sexual desires offer him no
excuse whatsoever for raping a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, and that if he understands and resists
those desires, he may be able to prevent their manifestation in sexually
coercive behavior. The criminal penalties for rape should also be discussed in
detail.

            

            Now, anyone who has read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Orwell</ENAMEX> or seen A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clockwork Orange</ENAMEX> can
imagine the scene: The strapping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> slump embarrassed in their seats while
evolution <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructors</ENAMEX> lay out their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>-sanctioned definition of human
nature. The first message to be drilled into boys' heads is: We believe you're
genetically programmed to rape. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> (and inevitably less impressive)
message is: Oh, and by the way, we're not going to let you do it.

            Here's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thornhill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palmer</ENAMEX> propose for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>:

            

               Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> should be informed that, during the evolution of human
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sexuality</ENAMEX>, the existence of female choice has favored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who are quickly
aroused by signals of a female's willingness to grant sexual access.
Furthermore, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> need to realize that, because selection favored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> who
had many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> tend to read signals of acceptance into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s actions
even when no such signals are intended.

               In spite of protestations to the contrary, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> should also be advised that
the way they dress can put them at risk.

            

            In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thornhill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palmer</ENAMEX> are asking the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to say that it
believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapists</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are under an obligation not
to dress or act provocatively. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> can see the criminal lawyers
composing their genetic-determinist <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">defenses</ENAMEX> already: Why, even the state
said he couldn't help himself!
            

            Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX> popularized the field of
evolutionary psychology with his book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Moral Animal</ENAMEX> , he wrote an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> on ev psych and feminism in which he acknowledged that evolutionary
psychology would be used to "naturalize" sexist behavior. He thought
philandering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> would be the ones taking advantage of the argument about
how cheating was hard to control. He did not foresee <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> when evolutionary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> would call for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to sponsor their theories in a way
virtually guaranteed to generate the very behaviors they are supposed to
prevent. But it was a foregone conclusion that when evolutionary psychology
began to focus on genetic predispositions and majoritarian norms to the
exclusion of everything else, some literalists would in fact forget everything
else. They would forget that we are products not just of evolution, but also of
what we imagine ourselves to be. And that if we teach our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to see
themselves strictly as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX>, they're bound to act like them.

         
      
   
