
   
   
      
         
            That <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ain't Synergy, My Friend</ENAMEX>
            

            What follows is a short rant. Apologies in advance for the strident tone.
But this has to stop.

            
               From an article in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> today about--what else?--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s
acquisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>:
            

            

               
                  Not that synergy in its old-fashioned sense doesn't continue to play a
part. As the [cable] ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exec</ENAMEX> noted, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MovieFone</ENAMEX> is now part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>. So you can
call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MovieFone</ENAMEX> and book your seat for the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> release."
               

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hey</ENAMEX>! This is not freakin' synergy, in its old-fashioned sense or otherwise!
Guess what! I can call <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MovieFone</ENAMEX> right now and book my seat for the latest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> release, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> will make some money off that and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> will make
some money off that, and between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them they will make just as much
money off my phone call to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MovieFone</ENAMEX> as they would have if they were part of
the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Where is the synergy? What's next? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> use credit cards to
buy tickets over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MovieFone</ENAMEX>, so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> should buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX>?

            Once and for all--not really, since I'm sure I'll be writing about this
again soon--synergy only exists when putting assets under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> corporate
umbrella creates more value than those assets would have produced on their own.
So if you could convince me that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> is going to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig MovieFone</ENAMEX> to make me want
to go see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>' movies--and that it couldn't have been convinced to do
that through a licensing or contract deal--then I might say there's synergy. Or
if you could convince me that just being in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> as Internet guys
is going to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Blitzer</ENAMEX> a more productive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, then
I might say there's synergy.

            The most amazing thing about all of this is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who was quoted
(unfortunately, anonymously) is a cable advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>. I wonder if he's
in there right now, trying to convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> he works for that it should
just buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide</ENAMEX> to find our
shows. So if we owned it, there'd be synergy!"

         
      
   
