
   
   
      
         
            Roll Over, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Keaton</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jeffrey</ENAMEX>:

            What's misogynistic about saying, "I don't fall asleep when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soprano</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are on screen." You're onto something here. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are another way
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sopranos</ENAMEX> breaks with the past. What was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Keaton</ENAMEX> doing in The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> ? I always thought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> married her because she was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wasp</ENAMEX>--because she embodied his abandoned dream of assimilation, and also
because she gave him cover. In other words, he married her because of what she
represented, rather than who she was, and the story never freed her from that
dehumanizing fact--never gave her any individuality, dignity, presence, which
meant that we never felt compelled and maybe even didn't want to watch her.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Except in III</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carmela Soprano</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loverboy-priest</ENAMEX> speak for
all of us on that one: What the hell was that?)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carmela</ENAMEX>'s just the opposite. Or at least she used to be--they don't give her
much to do in what we've seen so far. She's been supplanted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>'s sister
Pavarti, aka <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice</ENAMEX>, who, as you say, is an epic drag--a bullying,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-important</ENAMEX>, unsympathetic, bohemian drag. But back when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> were
interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carmela</ENAMEX>, which was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half of last season</TIMEX>, she had all the
qualities that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Keaton</ENAMEX> lacked. She was a real counterweight to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silvio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paulie Walnuts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pussy</ENAMEX> and all the charm they hold for the likes
of you, which in a mob context amounts to a giant feminist manifesto. Edie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falco</ENAMEX> does the hardest thing an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> can do--she makes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carmela</ENAMEX>'s suburban
decency both fierce and interesting. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carmela</ENAMEX> sees through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>, but takes
tender care of him anyway because, frankly, what else is she going to do? She
may not say much--hey, she's supposed to be emblematic of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>'s new yuppie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">isolation</ENAMEX>, so who would she say it to?--but she's plenty smart and aware, as we
learned when she dressed down <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> for being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schnorrer</ENAMEX> who
plays head games with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely women</ENAMEX> because he "likes the whiff of sexuality."
This being the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sopranos</ENAMEX>, however, which lets the moss of goodness gather on no
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carmela</ENAMEX> can also be a self-deluded, preening, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAP</ENAMEX>. There was that
wonderful episode <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early last year</TIMEX> where she's appallingly condescending to an
old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">restaurateur</ENAMEX> who's been burned out of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>.
She hires the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> to cater some fund-raising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, then, in a room
presumably filled with all their mutual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, waves her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> over as if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bossing</ENAMEX> around some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX>. She's clearly forgotten upon what her higher
financial status rests, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> wastes no time reminding her.

            Which brings us to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soprano</ENAMEX> marriage, which is, as you say, compulsively
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">watchable</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> suggested to me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that it's a somewhat
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Clintonesque</ENAMEX> marriage--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> whom he fucks rather joylessly and
with whom he never has an actual conversation, but he's really dependent on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (although unlike with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, you have the sense that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> screws
around mostly because that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob bosses</ENAMEX> are supposed to do rather than out
of real need). In another likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> parallel, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them have a long
history of hurting each other that makes it impossible for them to get the
important stuff out there, even though their desire to do so is palpable. All
this just hangs around in the air, unresolved, which makes you wish the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>
would get back to it. I dunno. Maybe I'm just getting my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap</ENAMEX>-opera yayas out
with a nighttime series. But I do think their marriage has the rare distinction
(on television, anyway) of feeling like something living, breathing, and
evolving--another feminist touch, in its way.

            So here's my question to you, who know so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob children</ENAMEX> (as opposed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hasids</ENAMEX>--though weren't you once friendly with some big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hasidic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>? Didn't
you cover them back in your Forward <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, before you abandoned the
chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to hang out with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you claim are the envy of the world?)
What do you make of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carmela</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meadow and Anthony</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX>? Do you
buy how easily Meadow swallows her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s bullshit about what he does for a
living, even after she has pointedly asked about it? I do, absolutely. I think
it's an excellent dramatization of the weird <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of knowing-and-not-knowing
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob kids</ENAMEX> are forced to live in. She's not deceived by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s lies,
as she makes clear in lots of little sarcastic asides. But if he actually
'fessed up, then she'd have to deal with his unpleasant reality, which would
rock her world a little more than she's ready for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>.

            All this, in fact, is taking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meadow</ENAMEX> to the verge of becoming The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sopranos</ENAMEX> ' next great female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. As far as I'm concerned, the best
thing that happens in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second season</TIMEX> is a major discovery we make about her
in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Episode 3</ENAMEX>, which for once I'm not going to give away. Suffice it to say that
she might not be an unbearably self-involved spoiled brat after all, though of
course she's that too. Maybe I just want to see her get in on the action 'cause
I was a huge self-involved spoiled brat in my day, but I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> has
potential.

            Spoiled or not, I was taught enough manners to say: It has been a pleasure
doing business with you, even if you did chop my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herring</ENAMEX> up and stir it into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">onions</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream sauce</ENAMEX>. I find that you are not, in fact, a mook. Quite the
opposite.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
