
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Strokes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luck</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
government's finding, based on an independent medical examination, that Gen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX>, under house arrest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, is too sick to be tried on the
human rights charges awaiting him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>. This means, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> could instead return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> soon. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
final edition leads with a saber-rattling leak from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ/Microsoft</ENAMEX> wrangle:
that government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> will shortly offer up during negotiations with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> a proposal for a breakup yielding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, one for the Windows
operating system, another for software programs. The story says that it's
unclear where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> Internet activities would go. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> is
quoted saying a breakup "would do great harm to the industry." The top
non-local story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> (which fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>) is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court's ruling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>,
do not enjoy the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s protection against age discrimination,
yet another example, says the paper, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s recent championing of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' rights. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts the decision. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> runs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> one-two at
the top of its front-page news box.

            The papers say that a decision to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>--who was found to have
suffered a series of small strokes--to return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> is in the hands of the
home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> and may come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> still may face charges back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> adds that
although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> was granted legal immunity in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> in return for his
step-down from power, it's not clear that the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is willing to
honor it. On the other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reminds that while he's been in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> has received the support of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX>, who, it says, was "delighted" with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' report.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> and even many human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accept Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s escape of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> charges because, as all the papers
note, the case has, via the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, created a historic precedent: A
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> can be brought to trial in another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for crimes
against humanity committed in his home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> while in office.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-leads <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX> drop-off in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s stock
price, significant, notes the paper, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> plans to purchase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>
with its stock.

            
               USAT fronts the latest wrinkle in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli√°n Gonz√</ENAMEX>°lez saga. It seems
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who just delayed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> plan to return the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> employed--during her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> election campaign--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. The
numbers vary a bit from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> to paper, but <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballpark</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> received a total
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60,000</NUMEX>. The stories say the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> does not require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> in this
sort of situation to recuse themselves.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Kuczynski</ENAMEX> effort reporting a surprising image manipulation at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS News</ENAMEX>. It seems that the
network's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> news broadcast for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 30 and Dec. 31</TIMEX> included images of
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Square</ENAMEX> with a billboard advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS News</ENAMEX>. But the billboard and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> ad are not actually in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX>. They were digitally inserted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>
into the shot. The story says the anchor on the show, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX>, learned about
the practice during the broadcast but did not protest. Rather did not return a
phone call from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . By the way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who don't return
phone calls from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> are precisely the sorts who don't hesitate to
manipulate content--it's all part of the belief that the rules they constantly
apply to others don't apply to themselves.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reliable Source</ENAMEX>" says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> will appear on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Letterman</ENAMEX> tonight. Maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> can digitally give her a prayer in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>.

            On the WP op-ed page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy Williams</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX>, does a good
nuts-and-boltsy job of bringing some reality to the topic of military pay raises. The author notes that the alleged gap
of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> and military pay fails to take into account
allowances for food and housing. Also, she notes that some of the allowances
are not taxed. Such details help to explain why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> typically earn more
money than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> with similar backgrounds. And there are some
concrete earnings examples: a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> master <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> in makes
more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX>, better than a senior firefighter or police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, and both
of those civilian jobs are as dangerous or more so than the typical military
job. And a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonel</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26 years</TIMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> makes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $108,000</NUMEX>. And none of
this includes, the op-ed notes, re-enlistment and other special bonuses. The
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> leaves out that would make her argument even stronger: the
very young retirement ages available to military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>. That <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonel</ENAMEX>, for
instance, can retire on a nice pension at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 47</TIMEX>.

            In a letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , a working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> explains how her household
handles her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s homework: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> ask the babysitter for help; if that
fails, try <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>'s fax if she's not traveling to close a deal; if that fails, try
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dad</ENAMEX>'s fax if he's not in court, and if all of the above fail, call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandma Ro</ENAMEX>.
(No fax available.)"

         
      
   
