
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Preemptive Strike</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mornin'</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>,

            I suppose I should begin this with a word to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, noting that you
and I are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, have known each other for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a decade</TIMEX>, and don't usually
talk to each other this way. For the purposes of this "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>," we've
agreed to write to each other in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>"-ese, a particular idiom in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> are cleverer and breezier and far more avid news junkies
than they usually would be in real life. (At least, I'm assuming. Who knows?
Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Ephron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Andersen</ENAMEX> write e-mails that sound "Breakfast
Table"-y all the time. They probably do.) It may be a tad artificial, but it's
better than the alternative, which would be our writing to one another the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> we talk to each other.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DAVE</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, how's it going?
ME: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fine</ENAMEX>. You?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DAVE</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fine</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ME: How's Abby</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DAVE</ENAMEX>: She's good. Thanks for asking.
etc.

            So. Where were we? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX>. I drive a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic</ENAMEX>, and am therefore terrified
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX>. Also, a small thing I've noticed: Many street signs seem to have been
designed before the advent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX>, which means that they're too low to see if
you're in, say, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic</ENAMEX>, surrounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX>. This is not, admittedly, a
very trenchant or interesting observation. But if there are any traffic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> out there listening, well, you now have a problem to solve.

            I imagine that the preceding comment will be picked over in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fray</ENAMEX>." A
traffic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> will write in, noting that the signs cannot, in fact, be
placed any higher due to some ordinance, which any moron would know about. Then
another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> will write in, correcting that first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX>. Then others
will pile on. Then the topic will turn to funding for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>, or libertarianism,
and things will get ugly. I am, in case you can't tell, deeply afraid of the
Fray. I've had nightmares of our Fray reviews--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">worst Breakfast Table ever</ENAMEX>," "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disgrace</ENAMEX>," "is this for real? this is a joke, right?"--and have come to the
conclusion that, instead of running scared, we should try to generate the most
negative Fray threads ever. I'll begin: I don't know why there isn't more
animal testing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. Especially on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX>.

            Your turn.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
