
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luce Change</ENAMEX>

            Yes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> debated again last night, and yes, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> at least momentarily delayed the return of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli√°n Gonz√</ENAMEX>°lez to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, and yes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has to let its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">temp workers</ENAMEX> in
on its good-deal stock purchase plan, but everybody leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
surprise announcement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> acquisition
of an old media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> (co-founded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75 years ago</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Luce</ENAMEX>) by a new media
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 15 years old</TIMEX>), the largest media merger of all time, and indeed, the
just-plain largest merger of all time. Although there isn't complete agreement
about how large: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says the purchase value of the stock is
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$183 billion</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
says <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$165 billion</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$163 billion</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
says <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$160 billion</NUMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$156 billion</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says
the deal will produce the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>-most-valuable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, one with
a stock market value "roughly equal to the gross domestic product of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>."
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next week</TIMEX>'s big story: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL TIME WARNER DOUBLES SIZE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ACQUIRES MEXICO</ENAMEX>.")

            The coverage agrees on the basic logic of the deal: In one swell foop, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TW</ENAMEX>
gets a tremendous Internet presence for marketing, for instance, its books and
CDs; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> gets a wide range of content in the form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TW</ENAMEX>'s many media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">properties</ENAMEX>, ranging from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> goes from
having no broadband capability to being positioned to go into computers in the
homes wired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s No. 2 high-speed cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Road Runner</ENAMEX>, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TW</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of. The papers say that there now will be a spate of other
old-new media merger deals, so that rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can compete against this
newly integrated juggernaut.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> has only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-fifth</NUMEX> the revenue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TW</ENAMEX>, but
it was able to handle the deal because it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times as much profit and a
much higher stock value. The papers all reflect a sense that nonetheless it was
surprising to think that the young <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was buying the old one instead of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX> versa.

            As is typical of press coverage of mergers, breathlessness is the order of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least eight</NUMEX> stories on the deal, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 12</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> goes with special reports in each of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
sections. Its front-page "cover story" compares the deal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonies</ENAMEX>' defeat of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> seems completely out of step
when it bothers to point out that because of the debt the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will take
on to seal the deal, it could be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> before it reports a profit.

            Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> take a crack at turning the spreadsheet into a novel,
centering on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Case</ENAMEX>, who will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of
the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TW</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Levin</ENAMEX>, who will be its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>, with the WP
putting the most effort into it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's tale includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX>'s
decision-making "walk in the woods" and the code words and letters used to keep
doings confidential. Case gets the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' instant cult of personality
treatment: Everybody notes that he likes casual clothes (although he wore a
suit to the press conference and it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX> who showed up all caj and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tieless</ENAMEX>) and used to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza Hut</ENAMEX> topping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on a stick is one <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert McChesney</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Illinois</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of a book about media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mergers</ENAMEX>. He's
quoted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different WP front-pagers and by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . Although
to be fair, if he weren't quoted there would hardly be any doubts raised in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dailies</ENAMEX> at all about the wonderful wonderfullitude of it all. He thinks the
deal is bad for freedom of expression. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> also takes a crack at the threat the deal
poses to independent journalism, creating as it does more financial
relationships between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and institutions they might be covering. His
column ends with the credit line: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> appears on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> media
program."

         
      
   
