
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stranger Than Parody</ENAMEX>
            

            Well, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> aren't going to learn smoking from
television, then where are they going to learn it? It's not like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are
teaching them anymore, what with their selfish two-career
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lifestyles</ENAMEX>.

            Speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and smoking, did you see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>? (I'm back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, and one of my favorite things about
returning here is the careful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of labor among the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>:
They seem to have a tacit understanding that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> will supply the
city with its news, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> will supply those things that people
actually want to read about. One is never in danger of finding out about, say,
the latest news from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . Similarly,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> will never read about the latest exploits of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean "Puffy</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Combs</ENAMEX> and
Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Lopez</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . Essay question: How would each paper
cover it, should Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean "Puffy</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Combs</ENAMEX> ever bitch-slap the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>? I'd imagine each would have to have a nut-graf identifying one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> : "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Combs</ENAMEX> is a hip-hop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> is a large country <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several hundred miles</NUMEX> to the north
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Affleck</ENAMEX> went there once.")

            In any case, Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> is about "herbal
cigarettes"--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>-free cigarettes that seem to be marketed at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, as a
sort of on-ramp to smoking. What I love about it is, the pack they chose to
illustrate the story is something called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Herbal Gold Cherry Flavor</ENAMEX>," and it
depicts a jolly leprechaun with a shamrock in one hand and a cigarette in the
other. It is so perfect, so absurd, that it's one of those increasingly common
instances where real life defies parody. Had you and I spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> trying to
mock a cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> targeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, we couldn't have come up with
something so perfect. This seems to be part of a larger trend of real life
outpacing satire. There is, for instance, the much-remarked-upon fact that
Wag the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX> --which I'm sure seemed daring and bold when it was being
filmed--had become tepid and understated by the time it hit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, I remember seeing an episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Critic</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Sherman</ENAMEX>
attended a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> musical based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Hunchback of Notre Dame</ENAMEX> ; it
seemed funny at the time, but less so when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> released a musical version of
Hunchback of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notre Dame</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years later</TIMEX>. And remember how, in The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Player</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard E. Grant</ENAMEX> keeps pitching a project called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Habeas Corpus</ENAMEX>"
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death Row</ENAMEX> who falls in love with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>? Ever see Last
Dance ?

            Speaking of self-parody, have you seen the cover of the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s
Content ? It features a giant close-up of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, along with
the following cover language: "Why does the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year-old</TIMEX> murder of a little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> continue to captivate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>? Because there's fast cash to be made,
even if it means letting tabloid tactics and undisguised spin rule the story."
Not, of course, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's Content</ENAMEX> would ever do something so
exploitative as to plaster a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s image across the cover of its--oh,
wait. Never mind. I can't wait for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>'s issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>,
featuring a scantily clad <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> and the caption, "Why does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penthouse</ENAMEX>
feature nude pictorials? Because there's fast cash to be made, even if it is
degrading to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. (More pictures inside, pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 to 78</TIMEX>.)"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's</ENAMEX> has, by the way, been mysteriously silent on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL-Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> merger. Or, at least, its Web site has--not a peep since the deal was
announced. Since we both work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>, do you have any
thoughts on being owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> now? I actually quite enjoy the new system
they've put in place in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>, so that every time I enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, a
voice announces, "You've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>!"

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
