
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dems</ENAMEX> Debate Race

            The questions at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown Forum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX> were the best
at any of the presidential debates so far. I especially liked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> correspondent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soledad O'Brien</ENAMEX>'s one about why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> are allowed to stay in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> are not. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Brien</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tavis Smiley</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Entertainment Television</ENAMEX>, came up with an
equally shrewd question about whether the priority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lily</ENAMEX>-white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX> in the presidential primaries is unfair to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>. Yet another
sharp question came from one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik Parker</ENAMEX> of the music
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine The Source</ENAMEX> , who asked whether it was right to deprive convicted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX> of the right to vote.

            What was especially impressive about these questions is that they were
unexpected without being obscure, trivial, or overly clever. Each was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">substantive</ENAMEX>, framing a significant problem in a surprising and fresh way. And
each was designed to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> squirm, but without being merely a
trick or a trap.

            In each case, the answers were revealing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> stumbled over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Brien</ENAMEX>'s
immigration question by trying to argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
should be treated differently. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Brien</ENAMEX> rightly pointed out that this answer
didn't account for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smiley</ENAMEX>'s question on the primaries provoked both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> into utterly unconvincing defenses of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-in-the<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">-nation</ENAMEX> status. And the question about voting rights for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX>
caused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> to say he'd reconsider whether non-violent convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX>
deserved the right to vote. One could reasonably defend this position. The
problem is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> never did so before being asked about it
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s answer was an attempted constituency-pleaser on par with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> in the military answer from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> debates ago. The difference is that
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> ought to have appreciated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s effort, I'm not sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> support
the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> voting any more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> do.

            Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> sometimes crossed the line from deeply felt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pandering</ENAMEX>. In his answer to the voting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX> question, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> implied that the
disproportionately high incarceration rate for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> was
principally the result of bias, which is preposterous. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">solicitousness</ENAMEX> expressed itself less in his specific answers than in his
slightly excessive effort to bond with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. When he said that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> not only talked the talk, but also walked the walk on
civil rights, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> actually drew boos from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>-friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> for his
somewhat hokey-sounding appropriation of street language.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was also clumsy in the way he constantly invoked his close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has been speaking to largely white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> and barely mentioning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s name. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Tonight</TIMEX>, in front of an
audience composed of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> sympathetic to minority <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice-president</ENAMEX> bragged extensively about the record of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> he seldom
mentions: "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> administration." When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> zinged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> by
proposing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice-president</ENAMEX> walk down the corridor to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> and
tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to sign an executive order banning racial profiling, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> shot
right back in defense of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>: "I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> needs
a lecture from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> about how to stand up and fight for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latinos</ENAMEX>." This was an excellent rejoinder, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> will
get himself into trouble very soon if he doesn't figure out a single attitude
toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and stick with it.

            More persuasive was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s emulation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s style, which after
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a thousand</NUMEX> tries finally came off in one portion of the debate. When a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> by the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Mahone</ENAMEX> asked both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> about the
under-representation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> in medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> responded with a
routine defense of affirmative action. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, who was either better prepared
or better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clued</ENAMEX>-in, recognized the questioner as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> who delivered the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCaughy Septuplets</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahone</ENAMEX>, I recognize you," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said. "And when you performed that
medical miracle, you made not only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> proud, but the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> proud. And
I think it is fair to say that there were countless young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">girls</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> of all backgrounds who saw you on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> television screens at the very top of your profession demonstrating to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and all that there's nothing you don't know how to do in the field of
medicine. And they thought to themselves: You know, I can do that."

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> heaped praise on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahone</ENAMEX>, he seemed truly moved, and the audience
seemed moved with him. For one brief moment, you even might have thought you
were listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
