
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> buys <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> steps down as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sega</ENAMEX> now
has <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> video-game market. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Mutual Holding</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, has agreed to buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Life Insurance Company</ENAMEX>.
Who can possibly keep up? All the more reason to buy really expensive Internet
stocks, which can just keep going up. ... Actually, that doesn't seem to be
working so well. Perhaps it's time to think about the virtues of municipal
bonds.

            The truth is while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL-Time Warner</ENAMEX> deal was huge, it's more unusual now
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> to pass without a similar announcement. (Though I can't quite
get over the shock of that insurance deal.) In a way, the most confusing part
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> was the breathtaking volatility in the stock market, and in
particular in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX>. After a week in which tech stocks mainly moved in one
direction--down--they came rallying back powerfully, but instead of resuming
their steady upward ascent, they've begun swinging around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">wildly</TIMEX> (even more
wildly than usual). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> that have reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">blowout quarters</TIMEX>--like Yahoo
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akamai</ENAMEX>--have been punished for no apparent reason, while other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
are trading much higher or lower on no news at all.

            You might say, of course, that this is just par for the course. But it feels
a little different. It feels, in fact, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> might be thinking a
little more seriously about risk. But then it could just be the sunspots. And
with that, on to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cocktail Chat</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> unveiled its forthcoming line of electric <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> , and said
they will be sold under the new brand name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Th</ENAMEX>!<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nk</ENAMEX>. (An odd choice, given the
fact that thexclamationpointunk doesn't really trip off the tongue.)
Company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> will presumably be <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Artist Formerly Known As ...</ENAMEX>, and I
imagine the advertising campaign will break new ground in the inventive use of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heretofore</ENAMEX> ignored punctuation marks."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "The astonishing volatility of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> has clearly driven some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> batty . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TheStreet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> quoted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> who said that since
you can look at a chart of the Nasdaq 100 and can see 'perfect
double-top' (which is like looking at a cloud and seeing an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>), we
should 'buckle our seatbelts.' The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX> requested anonymity, which isn't
surprising. Would you want to be quoted saying something that meaningless<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "Most curious headline of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> , from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> : 'GM
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presses Bid</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daewoo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vowing to Preserve Its Identity</ENAMEX> .' I don't know.
I may be naive, but I think that even if this deal does go through, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> will not
disappear. But, then, I'm a dreamer."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Hilfiger</ENAMEX>'s stock was crushed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> after the company
announced that its earnings for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth quarter</TIMEX> would be well below
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>' expectations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> attributed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s problems to overly
subdued colors in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hilfiger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s line . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> did say it was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'fully</ENAMEX> committed to enhancing long-term shareholder value.' But what we want to
know is: Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> now fully committed to bright colors<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Attacking America Online</ENAMEX>'s acquisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> as a danger to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Cohen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAIR</ENAMEX> included as part of his indictment of AOL
its use of controversial accounting methods . Why not? God knows that how
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AOL</ENAMEX> used to amortize its marketing costs should certainly be front-and-center
in any discussion of this deal."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>, in a column about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
obsession with the stock market , wrote that 'now your personal trainer
knows as much about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> price movements as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Buffett</ENAMEX> .'
Actually, I think the whole point of investing the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Buffett</ENAMEX> does is
that personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trainers</ENAMEX> have always known more about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> price
movements than he has."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Bulkeley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of barnesandnoble.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, resigned in order to, yes,
spend more time with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> . In response, the stock dropped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cents</ENAMEX> . Must be comforting to know that's how much difference investors
thought his departure would make."

         
      
   
