
   
   
      
         
            Big <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Beautiful</ENAMEX>

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> announced their merger, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s media
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> autodialed the usual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of media conglomeration: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McChesney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rosenstiel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Bagdikian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Crispin Miller</ENAMEX>. Their
collective complaint, known to every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> , was duly recorded:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomeration</ENAMEX> is bad for journalism and society.

            "It's a business thing," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McChesney</ENAMEX> said in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . "Good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX> is bad business and bad journalism is, regrettably, at times good
business." In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miami Herald</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bagdikian</ENAMEX> fretted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL Time Warner</ENAMEX>'s
devotion to the bottom line would injure democracy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosenstiel</ENAMEX> warned the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> of the conflicts of interest posed by the purchase.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX> would stuff <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> movies down
our throats via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McChesneyite</ENAMEX> critique of big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> misses the long-term trend that
started with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gutenberg</ENAMEX> and is accelerating with the Internet: As information
processing becomes cheaper, so does pluralism and decentralization, which comes
at the expense of entrenched powers--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guild</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nobility</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Media God Henry Luce</ENAMEX>
founded. Do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McChesney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> think we were better off in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, when there
were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> TV news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, than we are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, when there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six or eight</NUMEX>?
Better off before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
become national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>? Before FM radio and cable? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evidentially</ENAMEX> so.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McChesney</ENAMEX> obsesses about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> global media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, but as this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Journalism Review</ENAMEX> page shows, there are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three dozen</NUMEX> big media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> alone.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> of big media suffer from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallacy</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Era</ENAMEX>. They think
things were better in the past, but they never specify the status quo to which
they want us to ante. Was small really small enough to be beautiful in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1898</TIMEX>,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Randolph Hearst</ENAMEX> ran the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How Do You Like the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>?"? How about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> press corps
ignored the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s infirmities and poor health? Or the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1950s</NUMEX>, when Scotty
Reston carried official <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s water?

            From my vantage point, this is journalism's golden age--we just have a hard
time detecting its luster because golden ages always shine more brightly from a
distance. Another thing that tarnishes modern journalism is the recent
proliferation of media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, who bring brisk scrutiny to every ethical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lapse</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX> got a free ride compared with
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>.

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McChesney</ENAMEX>'s "good journalism is bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>" formula, I can only
offer a horse laugh. Only a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> would say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post haven't paired editorial quality with financial success. Nor does
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McChesney</ENAMEX> acknowledge that as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> has become a better paper, it
has become more viable as a business. Truth be told, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>conglomerate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conglomerate</ENAMEX> seems less vexed by conglomerate meddling in journalism--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> scandal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's decision to put
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pokémon</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> release) on its cover, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">capitulation</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, who wanted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> off his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX>--than by the
ultra-evil the media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX> might do in the future.

            Essentially, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McChesneyites</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> beefs: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Consolidation reduces the
number of voices. That's true only if you rig the tally, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McChesney</ENAMEX>
does. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Global consolidation promotes cultural imperialism. Cultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">imperialism</ENAMEX> isn't always bad, and new technology makes it easier for small
cultures to export their voices. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The more the press acts like a
business, the less attention it pays to its civic functions. See the
previous note on golden ages . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Big media treats its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McChesneyites</ENAMEX> hate anything
that doesn't conform to their idea of democracy.
            

            The critique of big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> invariably romanticizes small, independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. But for every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emporia Gazette</ENAMEX> edited by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Allen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>, there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchester Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> piloted by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Loeb</ENAMEX>. As a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX>, I care more about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> I read than who owns it. Most of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">independents</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>-operated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> blighted by the biological
law of "regression to the mean," which dictates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> are rarely as bright
or motivated as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> (look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> ). So let's
not reflexively mourn the gobbling of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> by big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>.

            Small, independently owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> routinely pull punches when covering local
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>, real estate, and industry, to whom they are in deep hock. The
chains that buy up the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Podunk Banner s</ENAMEX> don't necessarily do a better
journalistic job (look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gannett</ENAMEX>), but they're not as beholden to the local
powers that be as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">independents" are</ENAMEX>. What's more, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>
(independent or corporate) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Podunk Banner</ENAMEX> flinch from a story
about contaminated groundwater or police brutality, the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> New York
Times or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> can parachute in and do the story without fear
or favor. Hurrah for big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>!

            Whatever its shortcomings--and they are many--only big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> possesses the
means to consistently hold big business and big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> accountable. In the
'80s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX> visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to
complain about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s coverage. According to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who was present,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> suggested that it might have to pull the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s advertising from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> in protest. At that point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Taylor</ENAMEX>
responded, "I didn't know advertising was one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX>'s philanthropic
activities." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> threat proved hollow. As big as it was, it couldn't hurt
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> . How would the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Podunk Banner</ENAMEX> have fared against a
similar threat from the area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>?

            If you don't believe big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> has a leg up in making government behave, try
this. Call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Say that you're from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Podunk Banner</ENAMEX> and that you want to talk to her about some new policy.
Then make a similar call posing as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .
I needn't ask which call would get returned.

            Fundamentally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">McChesney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brigade</ENAMEX> worries more about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL Time Warner</ENAMEX>'s
pulling journalistic punches than about any lost "independence." (Remember,
they weren't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> prior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> deal.) But they
exaggerate the propaganda power of Time Warner media. Not even a cover rave in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> --a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> release--could turn that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plodding</ENAMEX> movie into a hit. (By the way, I believe the rave was genuine, and not
ginned up to sell tickets.) Any sustained effort--conscious or unconscious--by
a media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX> to slant the news in favor of its holdings will only
damage the long-term value of its journalistic properties. Bad press is bad for
anybody, but bad press is worse when it's directed at the press, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
learned when it killed a story by its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> that criticized
safety at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> would have been better off letting the
negative story run.

            Some would have big media erect <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Columns</ENAMEX> within their walls, but
navel-gazing doesn't automatically impress, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times-Mirror</ENAMEX> flagship <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> learned after publishing a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX>-word self-examination on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> scandal. One prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> called the story a
"whitewash." What damaged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> most after the initial
revelations seeped out (from an alternative <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> that didn't exist 20 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, it's worth noting) was the beating it took from other big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. Big media
strives to be ethical for the same reason big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and big business do:
New technology prevents it from controlling information the way it used to, and
being exposed by others hurts too much.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomeration</ENAMEX> runs in cycles, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> currently progressing
through the bellies of the media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> may not stay there for long. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>,
the media hysterics prophesied the end of literature when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX> bought
the family-owned book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> for their "synergy." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCA</ENAMEX> snared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX> took <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bobbs-Merrill</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> bought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rinehart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winston</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. A
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> abandoned their "synergy" plans and sold
their book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX>. Good publishing survived <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCA</ENAMEX>. Good journalism will
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">survive AOL</ENAMEX>.

            
               [Full disclosure: I draw my paycheck from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, which co-owns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Electric</ENAMEX>.]
            

         
      
   
