
   
   
      
         
            If a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bohemian Falls</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Forest</ENAMEX> ...

            Is there currently an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> bohemia? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> the official organ of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> cultural bohemianism, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> , was sold to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX> without a complaint from its once fiercely anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist readers</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. Also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Education</ENAMEX> proclaimed
the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> bohemianism: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior professor</ENAMEX> of English
at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> bemoaned the fact that his most brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are being lured
into high-paid consulting jobs (higher-paid than his!), rather than pursuing
the life of genteel poverty demanded by academic or artistic careers. Oh sure,
he says, he knows the occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ivy Leaguer</ENAMEX> who works <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine-to-five</TIMEX> so that she
can rush off at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilles Deleuze</ENAMEX> or play rock 'n' roll. But she's
an anachronism. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, at least, is "postbohemian."

            Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been proclaiming the death of bohemia ever since a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">19 th -century Parisian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Murger</ENAMEX>, wrote a book that would become
an opera that would become synonymous with the artistic life right up to the
moment when the whole concoction was boiled down to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn syrup</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">musical Rent</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerrold Seigel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of an excellent history of
bohemianism, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bohemian Paris</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics, and the Boundaries of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bourgeois Life</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1830-1930</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>), says that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go around saying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bohemia</ENAMEX> is dead, what they usually mean is that they can't see how to wiggle
free of commercialism and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convention</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> experience bohemia as a form of
authentic existence." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bohemia</ENAMEX> is a state of mind, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seigel</ENAMEX>. It's not just
the collective experience of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX> and artistes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cafes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> or the
lofts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Williamsburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bohemianism</ENAMEX> is a life self-consciously
positioned on the margins in order to express ambivalence about the
mainstream.

            But does the aggregate of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who happen to be living the bohemian
lifestyle right now add up to an actual bohemia? That's a tougher question.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seigel</ENAMEX> also says that bohemians have a role to play in society: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theirs</ENAMEX> is to
act out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bourgeoisie</ENAMEX>'s quashed longings and confusions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bohemians</ENAMEX> should be
mirrors in which we see what we might have been, had we dared.

            So who's doing that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>? Obviously, we can rule out the hipsters paying
exorbitant sums to inhabit gentrified downtowns and sport the latest iteration
of poverty chic. But there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> living lives quietly on
the fringe. We get a glimpse of them in a forthcoming book by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Powers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weird Like Us: My Bohemian America</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23</NUMEX>) is a charming, rambling account of her coming of
age as a music-store <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX>/riot-grrrl <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">punkster</ENAMEX>/aspiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, interspersed with interviews of her old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Bohemia, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powers</ENAMEX>
admits, is geographically dispersed. It looks moribund. But, she says, it
thrives sight unseen. It is "everywhere somebody opens a used-record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laundromat-caf√©</ENAMEX>, and a punk rock <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>." It's a "floating underground, which is
really more a life path than a place. ... It is a challenge undertaken in
privacy ... to confront and reinvigorate the premises of society, the
definitions of kinship, labor, love, leisure, consumerism, and identity
itself."

            Here's the problem with this definition: Can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bohemia</ENAMEX> exist "in privacy"?
What if society isn't aware that its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX> are being reinvigorated, its
contradictions being dramatized? What if the bourgeoisie, whom the bohemians
are supposed to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">√</NUMEX>©pater , seems un- √©pater -able? What if it just
doesn't give a damn? If there is a bohemia <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, it seems to be neither hated
nor celebrated. This strikes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> as a mortal condition. The great
bohemias of history--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murger's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Baudelaire</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th -century</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomsbury</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> Dadaists, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surrealists</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beats</ENAMEX>,
the indie rock scene--were flamboyant and self-enthralled. They hogged the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">limelight</ENAMEX>. They made themselves seem the center of the artistic universe. In so
doing, they really did change the world.

            There was a moment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a decade ago</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>-house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwellers</ENAMEX> and
music-store <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> whose lives Powers details so minutely rose to the level of
a bohemia. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> opened up and gave us <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Cobain</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s
Strand bookstore yielded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Gaitskill</ENAMEX>; video-store culture belched forth
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Tarantino</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Smith</ENAMEX>. Now, however, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powers</ENAMEX> returns to her old
music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, she is bewildered by how little she finds. "I could see no sign of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planet</ENAMEX> attitude, no surly looks in the eyes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> behind the cash
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">register</ENAMEX>," she writes. Then she thinks she understands: "I realized that I was
on the other side of it now. To the sly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the cultured proletariat I
looked like an average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>, not a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> who knew and approved of
their tricks."

            Perhaps. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powers</ENAMEX> describes sounds frankly too subterranean to amount to
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bohemia</ENAMEX> anymore. At best, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>-faced attitudes of retail-outlet clerks
have become the manifestation of a subculture that is soon to disappear, like
all the other subcultures that have faded into history. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most
remarkable facts about this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">turn of the century</TIMEX>, so far, is that if you want to
be on the cutting edge, you have to leave the margins for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. That, the
domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> industry and entrepreneurship, is where the interesting
ideas--the innovation, the subversion, the re-imagining of the boundaries of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>--are coming from. That's the bohemia of the moment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great American</ENAMEX>
bohemias have bubbled up from the depths in the past, and more surely will in
the future. But there's nothing going on down there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
