
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Mellows</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s note : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> has filed a report from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s debate among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. Click here to read
it.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DURHAM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H</ENAMEX>--A good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>. His progress in this, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> debate, was finally arriving at a reasonable tone. As in the
previous encounters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was highly critical of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>. But this time he
was able to be critical of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> without coming off as smarmy or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hectoring</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> made all his familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX>--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> wasn't putting
any money aside for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, that his health-care plan wouldn't cover
everybody, and that when the going got tough in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> got going.
But absent was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 80 percent</NUMEX> of the sense of artificiality that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">characterized Gore</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> performances. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> dispensed with the vocalized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sighs</ENAMEX> and weary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-shakings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX>
debate. This meant that you could listen to what he was saying without
having to spend the whole time disliking him.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> also included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> new attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> that was very much on point. He
finally took the advice of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kausfiles</ENAMEX>" and nailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> for opposing welfare reform in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.
Given the opportunity to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> a direct question, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> asked whether his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> thought he made a mistake on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> big votes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>--in favor
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> budget cuts, against the use of force resolution the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>,
and against welfare reform. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> responded with a stream of gobbledygook,
the thrust of which was that he stood by his decisions and would do the same
again, even with the benefit of hindsight.

            "I think all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of them were a mistake," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> responded, neatly
underscoring the lameness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s answer. "I think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were
trapped in the old welfare system. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> would still be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>
if we had tried to rely on sanctions. Those budget cuts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> hurt
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX>, who was a somewhat off-key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> throughout the event,
then asked a pointless thumbsucker of a follow-up: "How large a mistake is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> allowed to make?" The occasion not being a seminar at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
School, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> wisely ignored him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX>' other moment of weirdness
was asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> "what you really thought when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> held out his hand" in the
last debate--as if he was hosting some kind of debate post-game show rather
than the debate itself. Infinitely less adept at stoking an argument than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Russert, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX> kept trying to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to repeat highlights from
their previous session. But perhaps because arguing offends his sense of
politeness, he kept trying to change the subject when they did start scrapping.
Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX> was confused about how to handle a broadcast that didn't
involve any costume changes.

            His pathetic answer on welfare aside, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> turned in a strong performance
as well. Substantively, I thought his best moment was his question to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> wouldn't join him in supporting the registration
and licensing of all handguns. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX> response was that "it doesn't have a
prayer of ever becoming law." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> then delivered a lecture on what it means
to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. "Where would the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>'s too difficult to do? Of if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>'s too
difficult to do? The essence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> is taking something that is
difficult and making it possible because you engage the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in an
attempt to make it happen."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s other best riff came after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> asked him again why he hadn't put
money aside for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. After explaining that continued strong economic
growth might vaporize the problem, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> tried to cast <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> as a small-minded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inside-the-Beltway</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> for dwelling on the point. "When I hear you talk,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>, it reminds me of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> bunker. I think you're in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bunker</ENAMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> shouldn't be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> bunker with
you."

            Canned as it probably was, this was a wicked sound bite. It would have been
more effective, though, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> had been badgering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> the way he has in
previous debates. But for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> wasn't the clear aggressor--and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> wasn't clearly the aggrieved.

         
      
   
