
   
   
      
         
            More on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL-Time Warner</ENAMEX> Deal
            

            Some further notes on this AOL-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> blockbuster (multiple
conflict-of-interest note: I write for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> , which is owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>; I actually owned shares of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">around lunchtime</TIMEX>, when I sold
them; and I'm writing this column for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, which is probably affected by
this deal in some way):

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) There's no doubt that acquiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> will immediately solve many
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s current and future dilemmas. It will strengthen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s ability to
provide content to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>, which isn't insignificant insofar as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> is
still in part a proprietary service. It will speed the convergence of the
Internet and television. The deal creates really interesting possibilities in
terms of the delivery of downloadable music and video over the Net, because of
the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>'s catalogs. And, perhaps most importantly, it appears
to eliminate a lot of the concerns about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s ability to make a transition
into the world of broadband access. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> will now be one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s key
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, which means that it can position itself as a dominant player
in the high-speed-cable-modem world.

            What's interesting, though, is that it's not clear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> needed actually to
buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> in order to make any of these solutions work. Content,
especially Internet content, is eminently licensable, and as far as the
music/video <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> goes, it's really easy to imagine a deal in which AOL
would have given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> access to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> in exchange for a cut of the
business. Even when it comes to broadband, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s strategy seemed to be working
well. It had cut deals with key telcos to have access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, a deal
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> (once its exclusive arrangement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excite@Home</ENAMEX> expired) felt
like a foregone conclusion, and again cutting a deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> could not
have been that hard a proposition. And when you consider that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Case</ENAMEX> said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> he's committed to open access over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>'s wires--that is, people
who get high-speed Internet access from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> cable will be able to use
ISPs other than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>--actually owning the wires doesn't seem to add that much to
the value of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>.

            The point is that most of the business components of the deal seem to make
perfect sense. It's just that acquiring all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> to get them,
especially at such a high price, doesn't automatically follow. The odd thing is
that at this moment when markets are replacing hierarchies all across the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> business landscape, you also have all these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom/CBS</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DaimlerChrysler</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>--doing the exact opposite,
making deals on the assumption that you need to have everything under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> roof
to really reap all the benefits.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s press conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Levin</ENAMEX> explained that
he thought it made more sense to buy an Internet presence rather than try to
build <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> organically. Which would be an interesting thing to think about,
if he were buying an Internet presence . Instead, of course, AOL
is buying an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offline</ENAMEX>/cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">presence</ENAMEX> . And if you turn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX>'s statement
around, that leads you to an interesting conclusion about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s wisdom in doing
this deal.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of the deal, of course, are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who owned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> shares on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. It's interesting, though, that even after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
close there was a significant gap--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 20 percent</NUMEX>--between the price of Time
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>'s shares and the price that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> will pay for them when the deal closes.
In other words, if the deal were a sure thing, there's a rather nice risk-free
return just sitting there waiting to be picked up. What that means is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arbitrageurs</ENAMEX> think the deal is not a sure thing.

            (It's also unclear whether there's a collar on the deal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> are going to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> shares for every AOL share. But that means
that if the value of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s shares falls, so too will the value of the deal for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>. A collar would essentially put a floor on that value,
so that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s share price fell below a certain point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> would get more shares.)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Despite the scope of the deal, though, antitrust concerns don't really
seem to be much of a factor here. Because the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are
complementary rather than competitive (that is, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> doesn't offer
regular Internet access, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> isn't in TV or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> or music), the deal will
probably go through without much of a hitch. It would be interesting, though,
if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> were to embrace a broader definition of
"competition" and to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> as essentially <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> in this
amorphous thing we call "media." In that case, the conglomeration of so many
different kinds of assets might be seen as anti-competitive. But it's a
stretch.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>, living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, whose cable system
is still so antiquated that I can't even get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner Classic Movies</ENAMEX> (which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> actually owns), let alone high-speed Internet access. If this deal will
get me <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCM</ENAMEX> and true broadband access, then all I can say is: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good</ENAMEX> going,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>!"

         
      
   
