
   
   
      
         
            Anarchy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s note: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> 
               here 
               for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saletan</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> debate.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DURHAM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>--It didn't take long for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> debate to devolve
into chaos. The proximate cause was a decision by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX>,
to focus most of the attention on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>. While as an exercise in news judgment this was eminently
reasonable, it was also unfair. As soon as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigious</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> caught wind of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russert</ENAMEX> was doing, they staged a mutiny, refusing to
yield the floor to him or follow his orders. The result was a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ultimate</ENAMEX> fighting contest, in which the rules were suspended and each candidate
fought according to his wits. The way each behaved in this unexpectedly
Hobbesian environment was somewhat revealing.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> reverted to type--namely "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piggy</ENAMEX>," the thick-goggled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Flies</ENAMEX> . You knew it was going to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a bad</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX>
from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question put to him by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John DiStaso</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchester</ENAMEX>
Union<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-Leader</ENAMEX> , the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that has actually endorsed him.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiStasio</ENAMEX>'s question was basically: You've been running for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>,
you're a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dilettante</ENAMEX> and no one in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> likes you, so why don't
you get the hell off the stage and out of the race? Because the question
included the charge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> was "aloof," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> responded with his version
of a joke: "Maybe you want me to give a hug to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>," he said.

            At that point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>--who was standing next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> and seemed to be
having the time of his life--said, "I'd be glad to, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>," and actually
stepped over and gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> a squeeze while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> was trying to answer the
question. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>' expression while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> was hugging him recalled the scene in
the novel (OK, the movie) where the savage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> requisition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piggy</ENAMEX>'s eyeglasses.
As the situation grew even more disordered, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> simply assumed the fetal
position, going totally silent in hopes of being spared further indignities. He
was road kill by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the hour</TIMEX>.

            To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, it was more like a great dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> food fight. He threw the
most rolls. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few serious minutes</TIMEX> in which he defended himself fairly
effectively against accusations of hypocrisy for leaning on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> on behalf
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> seemed transported back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his days</TIMEX> at the naval
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">academy</ENAMEX>, when he made it his object to acquire as many demerits as possible
without actually being expelled. After hugging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, he got into a "Yes it
does" / "No it doesn't" tug of war with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> over whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s tax plan would
use up the entire projected budget surplus. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> was right that yes it does,
according to independent estimates of the cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s proposal to end what
he calls "the death penalty.") But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s best sport came when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyes</ENAMEX> asked
him a lunatic question premised on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX>' not understanding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">joking</ENAMEX> when he said he was a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of the thrash <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">band Nine Inch Nails</ENAMEX>. Keyes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accused McCain</ENAMEX> of "aiding and abetting cultural murder" for saying he liked
such music.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> rolled his eyes, giggled, and turned into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contestant</ENAMEX> on Who
Wants to Be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Millionaire</ENAMEX> . "Can I get a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">lifeline?</ENAMEX>" he asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russert</ENAMEX>.

            "I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and I'm not laughing," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyes</ENAMEX> responded.

            "I haven't been able to entertain you very often in the past," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> shot
back, rolling his eyes and giggling some more.

            Keyes, who was wearing the exploding lilac necktie that is often a harbinger
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his "episodes," also took the mayhem as a prompt to express his
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">truest</ENAMEX> self. In other words, he jumped on the nearest soapbox and started
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ranting</ENAMEX> to no one in particular about such evils as atheism, homosexuality, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX>. He lacked only a sandwich <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> proclaiming, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The End is Near</ENAMEX>."
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyes</ENAMEX> has one great advantage in an up-for-grabs situation, which is that
you literally can't interrupt him. He comes up for air less often than a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dolphin</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, seemed unequipped to deal with pandemonium. Another of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison King</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Cable</ENAMEX>
News, asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> a go-back-where-you-came-from question similar to the one
asked of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX>. "Your campaign has been flat at best," she commented.

            "Don't count out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> answered, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>-style. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> was pretty much out of the rest of the debate, bewildered by the carnage
around him and unsure how to respond to it. "It's gotten a lot more nasty," he
remarked at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, displaying a keen grasp of the obvious.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX>, by contrast, was a shrewd and vicious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opportunist</ENAMEX>. As soon as he
realized the power was out, he began looting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>. He brutally joined in the
assault on the hapless <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piggy</ENAMEX>, accusing him of being anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> for wanting to
take away the mortgage interest deduction. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> for not adhering
to conservative values, being clandestinely pro-abortion, and assorted other
sins. His most vicious moment came when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russert</ENAMEX>, following up on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
controversial "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Christ</ENAMEX>" answer in the last debate, pressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> on
whether he was really a closet theocrat. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russert</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> whether he would
"take an expression like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'What Would Jesus Do</ENAMEX>?' into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>."

            "I would take an expression in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> of 'Dear God, Help <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me</ENAMEX>,' "
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> responded.

            "So would we, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> fired back, apparently unable to resist the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apercu</ENAMEX> .

            But though he was a constant target for almost everyone else, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> absorbed
such shots good-naturedly, firing back when he had to, but not getting hot
under the collar. After answering one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s attacks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> actually winked
at the wily evangelical. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> seemed to recognize this kind of contained riot
as a familiar situation--a frat party gone slightly out of control. He stuck
close to the keg, smirked a lot, and got through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> without getting
puked on.

            What do we learn from this? In a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> environment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> know how to survive.

         
      
   
