
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Equal-Opportunity Stereotyping</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jeffrey</ENAMEX>:

            To be perfectly honest, I would prefer "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Herring</ENAMEX>." If you must
hang a moniker on me that has inevitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> to a certain part of the
male anatomy, I figure it might as well start with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big</ENAMEX>."

            Now back to our show, you fuckin' mook. (What is a mook, anyway?)

            Here's why I did the right thing in hiring you as a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>--and why I'll
let you live, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>: You understood <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX> better than I did. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperioli</ENAMEX> does deserve more credit. He's taken a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> who's truly dim and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">callow</ENAMEX> and found a way to give him a certain hapless appeal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX> isn't
just a good explanation for why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>'s tanking, though with his crank and
inability even to get his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> references straight, for chrissake,
he's that too. He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult body</ENAMEX> trying to grow up and getting
it wrong every time. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Imperioli</ENAMEX> located humanity in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX> at exactly two
points <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> had an identity crisis over the fact that
his murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> was named on TV and he wasn't; and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, when he tried to
help his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> switch careers from cocktail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> to music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>. The
band she was representing sucked; the producer she was making nice to was just
trying to get into her pants; but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX> overlooked all that because he
wanted to make her happy. Of course, she walked out on him, but that's how
everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX> does turns out. What he's really evolving into is an
instant anxiety-booster. Whenever he's onscreen and manages not to do or say
something that gets him shot, I'm hugely relieved.

            And now, as if the chronically stupid <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX> and the paranoid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle</ENAMEX>
Junior and the wily, batty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livia</ENAMEX> weren't enough to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> strung out, we've
got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richie Aprile</ENAMEX>. What do you make of him? Here's a made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> fresh out of
prison looking to fuck <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up, and doing a good job of it so far. He appears
in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Episode 2</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">by Episode 3</ENAMEX>, he's jumpstarted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX>. The show
definitely goes into higher gear when he's around. He's sort of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>
figure--lean, mean, and out of control. All malevolence, all the time. He wants
to kill a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> for no apparent reason; he's wooing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>; he's visiting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. He's a whirlwind of bad karma. It's as if, having lost the Melfi
method of making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> seem human, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> have struck on another way to do
it: play him off someone really angry and crazy, so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soprano MO</ENAMEX> comes
off as sanity itself.

            

               

                  
56.6 modem
T1 connection
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Download Windows Media Player</ENAMEX>

                  

               

            

            Now, on to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melfi</ENAMEX>. You tell me. Am I crazy? Am I just soft on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> who
happen to be female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> for the obvious reasons? I really like her
and, as you know, the whole psychiatric framing device. Did you? Or do you hate
it? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my favorite film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Wolcott</ENAMEX>, hated it. He dissed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorraine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bracco</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, saying her psychobabble sounded
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memorized</ENAMEX>. I like the way she spoke in those sessions, carefully choosing her
words and drawing out her syllables for fear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> would get the wrong
idea, which he usually did. (I loved it when she uttered banalities about
needing to let one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly parents</ENAMEX> retain an illusion of control, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
turned that into a sneaky strategy for letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Uncle Junior</ENAMEX> think he was
fronting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> was really running things.) She's back in Episode
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, and not a moment too soon. She runs into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> at a restaurant
and flirts with them, of all things, much to her dismay later, when she repeats
to her shrink, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Bogdanovich</ENAMEX>, what she said when she waved
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">goodbye</ENAMEX>: "Toodle-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fuckin</ENAMEX>'-oo? What the fuck was I thinking?" I loved the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> she said "Toodle-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fuckin</ENAMEX>'-oo," as if she were channeling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tonyspeak</ENAMEX>. We're
gonna get some weird plot twists with that one, I can tell.

            Do I think <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> is bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>? Yeah, but it's
equal-opportunity in its disrespect for ethnic sensitivity. What about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hasid</ENAMEX> who hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> to rough up his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX>, and then welshed on his
payments? (I loved the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX>, by the way. He was so gutsy. A real tough
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>. You have more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hasidic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> than I do. Were you offended? Were they?)
What about the streetwise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapper</ENAMEX> who turns out to be a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> with a
sociology degree? Or the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> on the take, whom we meet in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Episode</ENAMEX> 2
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX>? What about the condescending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wasps</ENAMEX> who let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> into their
country club exactly once, then treated him like he was some kind of freak? No
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> comes off without stereotyping, but it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shylock</ENAMEX> (if I
may get all high-minded on you again): A good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> takes stereotypes and
turns them into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, which in turns makes you reconsider the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stereotypes</ENAMEX>. Unless you're one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who won't go see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Merchant</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX> because it's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> wrote in to suggest that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> clone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livia</ENAMEX> and create a twin
who's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and sweet as a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX> and who can't believe the
things she's hearing about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> on TV, it's such a horrible smear on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. Which strikes me as an excellent way to solve the Livia
problem. Got any other suggestions for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>?

            Yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith "Really Huge Herring</ENAMEX>" Shulevitz

         
      
   
