
   
   
      
         
            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weak</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>?
            

            Some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, disparage him
because he occupies a "constitutionally weak governorship." What makes a
governorship strong or weak? Should it reflect poorly on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> if he is a "weak"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>?

            State constitutions grant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> a variety of powers--among them the
power to veto bills, appoint <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, and submit a budget to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>.
A constitutionally strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York's</ENAMEX>, can both veto bills and
apply a line-item veto to portions of measures he disfavors. A strong governor
also appoints most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> and can serve multiple
terms.

            Constitutionally weak <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> appoint few top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. In many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> elect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">treasurer</ENAMEX>, etc. This
makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> accountable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, and
diffuses his power. Weak <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> also face limits of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or two terms, making
them automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lame ducks</ENAMEX>: They tend to govern less independently and exercise
less clout with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislatures</ENAMEX> than strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>, who, because they can
repeatedly succeed themselves, amass more and more political power.

            By most of these criteria, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is a weak <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> elect the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comptroller</ENAMEX>, general land <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX>, and state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">treasurer</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> are run by commissions or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> outlast the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> who appointed them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenant governor</ENAMEX> runs
separately from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> and can belong to a different political
party. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> is not subject to term limits, however.

            The job of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenant governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is thought by some to be a more
powerful but less glamorous job than that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>. The lieutenant governor
presides over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, appoints the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> and committee
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">chairs</ENAMEX>, controls the flow of bills to the floor, and co-chairs the powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislative Budget Board</ENAMEX>. (The current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenant governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> can submit a budget to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> (he
doesn't have to), but his recommendations are usually discarded. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> can't grant clemency to a death-row <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX>, although he can grant a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-day</TIMEX> reprieve until a state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> reviews the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX>'s plea.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> can veto bills and make line-item vetoes on
appropriations bills. He can also call special legislative sessions, something
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has never done. But a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s clout doesn't rest only in institutional
trappings. Despite the limitations of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is still the most
powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. Personal charisma, a hefty electoral mandate, and
the cooperation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> can augment the power of any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX>, and he has used them to persuade the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> to enact
incremental portions of his agenda on issues such as education, welfare, and
taxes. Add the likelihood of a major-party presidential nomination to the list,
and you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> who wields a sizable amount of power, even if it can't
be found in the state constitution.

            Next question?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> thanks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thad Beyle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of political science at the
            

         
      
   
