
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Yardeni</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Extreme Film Critic</ENAMEX>

            In addition to being a financial prognosticator of some renown, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX>, chief global <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> and investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche Bank</ENAMEX>
Securities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, is a film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX>'s Web site includes ratings <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> has made of
various movies, in the form of plus and minus signs. Judging from his current
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> of movie ratings, the highest score <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> hands out is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pluses, and
the lowest is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> minuses. (In marked contrast to his financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pronouncements</ENAMEX>, no commentary accompanies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX>'s movie ratings.)

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> observed in an earlier
item, within the realm of financial predictions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> tends to stick his
neck out. This served him well during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, when he predicted accurately
the astonishing growth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy. It didn't serve him so well this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, when his dire warnings that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K</ENAMEX> computer glitches would create a massive
worldwide recession failed to come true. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> wondered: Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> go
for the extremes in his movie ratings, too?

            Indeed he does. Out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> movies rates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> gave maximally favorable or
unfavorable ratings to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>. In other words, fully <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27 percent</NUMEX> of the films
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> sees strike him as being either great or terrible. This doesn't jibe at
all with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s moviegoing and movie-rental experience, which would put
the "great or terrible" proportion no higher <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> . (Even Mrs.
Chatterbox, whose view of life is somewhat more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Manichean</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox's</ENAMEX>,
puts the "great or terrible" proportion only at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> .)

            In contrast with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> views, but in keeping with the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Wave</ENAMEX>"
economics he championed throughout the (mostly recession-free) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX>'s
movie ratings are heavily favorable. All but one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX>'s "great or
terrible" ratings fall in the "great" category; the only movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> appears
to have outright hated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boogie Nights</ENAMEX> ,* a film that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> would assign <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> plus sign. Overall, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 16 percent</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX>'s movie ratings consist of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more minuses, while fully 84
percent consist of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more pluses. To <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s thinking, this is
bullishness taken to an irresponsible extreme. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> would put the
proportion of worth-seeing films at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">no more than 60 percent</NUMEX> ; Mrs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> puts it a little higher, at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> , but stipulates that
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 2 percent</NUMEX> warrant going out and hiring a babysitter.)

            Among the films <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> inexplicably assigns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pluses to are
Contact , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deconstructing Harry</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pleasantville</ENAMEX> . More
conventionally, he gives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pluses to the popular-but-dreadful films As
Good <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">As It Gets , Good Will Hunting , and Titanic</ENAMEX>. The only top
ratings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> can endorse are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">pluses for Saving Private</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Full Monty , and Wag the Dog</ENAMEX> .

            In the few instances when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> does respond unfavorably to a film, his
negative judgments are highly questionable. There is no way The Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lebowski</ENAMEX> deserves less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pluses, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> gives it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> minuses.
The ambitious but flawed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Thin Red Line</ENAMEX> deserves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> plus
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Nolte</ENAMEX>'s fine performance, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> gives it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> minuses.
Armageddon, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bullworth</ENAMEX>, and the new Star Wars movie all deserve at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> plus as well, but instead get one minus.

            *<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boogie Nights</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-minuses rating might fairly be characterized as
the cinematic equivalent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX>'s prediction of worldwide recession in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 2000</TIMEX>.
            

         
      
   
