
   
   
      
         
            Headline

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bushspeak</ENAMEX> II
The tortured syntax of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> has been visited upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> says. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> stumbled over
"missile launches" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, instead uttering the phrase, "a
world of madmen and uncertainty and potential mental losses." Other recent
gaffes include: "The question we need to ask: Is our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> learning?" and
blending "trade" and "barriers" into a warning against "terriers."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netizens</ENAMEX> to FEC: Keep out! Everyone
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> has told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
Election <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> to keep its nose out of the Internet, the New York
Times reports. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> asked for input on in its role in regulating
online campaigning. The response: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 1,200</NUMEX> e-mail messages, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99 percent</NUMEX>
of which opposed regulation.

            
               Ballot
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box</ENAMEX>
You will need to edit
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX> for this piece.Be sure to include <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Show</ENAMEX> and idMessage 

            
               Ballot <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box</ENAMEX>
You will need to edit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX> for this piece.Be sure to include <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Show</ENAMEX> and
idMessage   

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
Jeers
Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Prudie</ENAMEX>,I received the worst version of the dreaded
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> letter--addressed to no one in particular--with an early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX>. The computerized letter began with the rundown of every family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'accomplishments</ENAMEX>' for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX>. Included in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">'accomplishments'</ENAMEX> were
being fired from a job, suing someone for discrimination, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> near-death
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">experiences</ENAMEX>, and an extended hospital stay. 

            
               Antler
Envy
You know it must be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX> season in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tabloidland</ENAMEX> when all those dirty secrets about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX> the
Red-Nosed Reindeer start to surface. With the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> claiming that singing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cowboy Gene Autry 'hated</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX>'s theme song and had to be persuaded to
record the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> classic, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> weighs in with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'surprising</ENAMEX> revelation': 'Rudolph is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>!' According to 'top university
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reindeer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Berg</ENAMEX>, male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reindeer</ENAMEX> have already shed their antlers by
late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, meaning that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> antler-topped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">reindeer</ENAMEX> traditionally seen
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX> must be female. 

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
Jeers
Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Prudie</ENAMEX>,I
received the worst version of the dreaded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> letter--addressed to no one
in particular--with an early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> card. The computerized letter began with
the rundown of every family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>'s 'accomplishments' for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX>.
Included in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">'accomplishments'</ENAMEX> were being fired from a job, suing someone
for discrimination, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> near-death experiences, and an extended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
stay.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
Jeers
Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Prudie</ENAMEX>,I
received the worst version of the dreaded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> letter--addressed to no one
in particular--with an early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> card. The computerized letter began with
the rundown of every family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>'s 'accomplishments' for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX>.
Included in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">'accomplishments'</ENAMEX> were being fired from a job, suing someone
for discrimination, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> near-death experiences, and an extended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
stay.  

         
      
   
