
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa Democratic Debate</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remembering Lenny</ENAMEX>

            I now understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> wants to debate so much. On his better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, he's
damned good at it. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> debate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
was truly formidable, performing better than he has in any of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> previous
encounters with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>. To be sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was demagogic, gimmicky, and
condescending at times--he can't help it. But he was also lethal
throughout.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s most devastating shot came with the help of what I believe may be a
technical innovation in presidential debating: the use of human props. As he
put a question about agriculture to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> asked a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Peterson</ENAMEX> to stand. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peterson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> explained, was an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">400 acres</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> of which were flooded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> noted,
voted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> against emergency federal aid for those affected. "Why did
you vote against disaster relief for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Peterson</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> asked. 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, who should have been prepared to defend this vote, simply had no
answer at all to the question of why he wanted to drown this friendly looking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> along with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hogs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX>. He tried to play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s question off with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame bromide</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> should be talking not about the past but
about the future. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> came back at him again with the question, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">irrelevantly</ENAMEX> asserted that he supported the federal tax subsidy for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> was so clearly nailed on this failing-to-pander charge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was
able to resist his usual urge to flog a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>, and didn't bring it up a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> time.

            Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peterson</ENAMEX>, and of a public school
teacher he had also planted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> was compelling, I don't think it
will lead to any good. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> introduced a similar device in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">first State of the Union</ENAMEX> address in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>--by inviting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenny Skutnik</ENAMEX>, a
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> who dived into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Potomac</ENAMEX> to rescue a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX> of an
airplane accident--it was a nice touch.  Since then, though, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>-in-the-gallery gambit has gotten completely out of hand, turning the
State of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> address into a version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grammys</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can't
sing.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> did <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other notably shrewd thing <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX>. Responding to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s "bunker mentality" charge from the last debate, he finally stood up
and took credit for the record of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. "The other night
in a debate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> criticized me and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> for being in what
he called a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> bunker," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said in his opening statement. "So I want
to start by telling you what we were doing in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> bunker. We
created <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 million</NUMEX> new jobs, cut the welfare rolls in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>, passed the toughest
gun control in a generation, and created the strongest economy in the history
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States of America</ENAMEX>." 

            I was wondering when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was going to get around to sticking up for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Running away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has been doing makes the liability
of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fatigue" into a self-fulfilling prophecy. But embracing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accomplishments</ENAMEX> plays to what I consider to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s single greatest asset as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>: that he represents the continuation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s popular and
successful policies without the continuation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> himself.

         
      
   
