
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moomba Mania</ENAMEX>
            

            I hate to say it, but I missed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> today. I love
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> , especially the gossip page. I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> goals in life: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
Make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> by launching a Web site called "getkidssmoking.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>" (got the idea
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> after discussing the whole smoking TV show thing with you), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
see my name in boldface on the gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> . I think goal No.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1</ENAMEX> is no problem, but No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> seems to be out of reach. Unfortunately, I'm neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> nor famous, don't date a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>-addicted supermodel (or non-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>
addicted supermodel, for that matter), and I've never been to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moomba</ENAMEX>. I don't
even know where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moomba</ENAMEX> is. In fact, I'm not even sure what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moomba</ENAMEX> is. I
think it's either a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> or some sort of pet-supply <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. I'll have to
get back to you on that one.

            Instead of reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> , I went to the gym and read
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> preview issue. (Full disclosure: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EW</ENAMEX> is
owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, which, as you pointed out, also owns our respective
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications MAD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> and, since the announcement of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> merger, is now in direct competition with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> of

                  Slate
               ], which is sort of in competition with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>, which made
the computer I'm typing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>.) Anyway, best I can tell, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EW</ENAMEX> claims this
is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> for us to finally see some hot, new young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> have breakout
performances, for some familiar faces to turn up in surprising roles, for a few
unlikely onscreen couplings and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Damon</ENAMEX> that anyone deserves. And I,
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, can't wait!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, now that you're in town, give me a call. We'll go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moomba</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
