
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbed Prose</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with the
election victory in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> of a socialist--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of that political
persuasion to lead <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvador Allende</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> puts the story atop its front-page news
index box, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> fronts it, going instead with how as few
as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two dozen</NUMEX> seats will determine if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> hold on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this</TIMEX>
fall. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> internal audit
showing rampant lax security. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
lead is a follow-on to a story the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>: the emergence of
the possibility that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> might agree on some form
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> coverage for prescription drugs. The latest: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmaceutical</ENAMEX> execs
will meet on the topic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX>. Also, the
paper says, a new industry ad campaign will, unlike previously adversarial
spots, be conciliatory on the subject.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> explain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> election marks not only the
resuscitation of socialism in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but also of the dormant right--the
margin of victory was slim over a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>. Another significant
development the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note: The rightist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> to personally congratulate him.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> grip on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> is "especially
tenuous" because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> has the slimmest majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">either party</ENAMEX>'s had there
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> fund raising is more effective than it's historically
been, and because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than three</NUMEX> times as many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are vacating their seats.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead says that the security audit showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
failed to sweep <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> where classified intelligence reports of the utmost
sensitivity were handled and that in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">time-frame</ENAMEX> studied, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 10</NUMEX>
percent of those reports were not returned to their proper storage <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place</ENAMEX>. The
paper also reports that the audit was completed before the discovery of a
listening device (and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> nearby) at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late last</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, but after a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> incident in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> came in, took some classified
materials, and left. The paper reveals the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was never identified and the
materials were never recovered.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-lead on the anti-missile shield system being tested by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> says that the system could defend against at most <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 or 30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>,
and explains that this limitation is being stressed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>, who have
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 5,000</NUMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, as a reason for them not to worry about it. Even
if it passes the important tests in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the months ahead</TIMEX> and gets full funding, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> won't be ready until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's front-page "snapshot" is a sober-up for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Day</ENAMEX>
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Census Bureau</ENAMEX>. When it comes to educational attainment, blacks
still lag substantially behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> are high
school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>, but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 55 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> are.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs a column in the metro section by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Scheer</ENAMEX>
siding with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra Streisand</ENAMEX> in a zoning dispute she's having with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malibu</ENAMEX>
government over construction plans at her new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheer</ENAMEX>'s friendship
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streisand</ENAMEX> clouding his judgment? Well, in his column he describes her as
"the hardest working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>" and says her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of work is "widely recognized
as a national treasure."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that a business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statesman</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boise</ENAMEX> has quit over his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s practice of submitting stories about Micron
Technology, a major local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for review before publishing
them. A heavy at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is quoted as defending the practice as a method of
fact-checking. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Papers sides</ENAMEX> with the departed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, but would add
that there is nothing wrong with showing copy to a story <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> or subject for
fact-checking purposes. What is wrong is surrendering control of that copy to
such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>. But a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> doesn't have to do that if he's willing to fight
against powerful local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> for what he knows is right. In
other words, the traditional view against advance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peeks</ENAMEX> sacrifices
fact-checking primarily to take the easy way out. But journalism should almost
always take the hard way out.

            Another reminder of how shoddy small-time journalism can be comes with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's report on the sudden departure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Oklahoman</ENAMEX> 's executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, apparently for displeasing local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">behemoth</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerr-McGee Corporation</ENAMEX>
with a story about the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Silkwood</ENAMEX>, a would-be whistleblower
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.

            Of course not all shoddiness is local. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> run
follow-on stories to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s revelation that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s drug office
had a program of financial incentives for networks incorporating anti-drug
themes into their shows. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s coverage focuses mostly on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s claim that it
stopped trying to get the financial credits after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> asked to see
scripts before broadcast. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disappointingly</ENAMEX>, neither paper mentions the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> that broke the story-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. On the other hand,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Shapiro</ENAMEX>'s column in USAT touching on the controversy does
properly credit <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> . Not doing so is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> and cheats the reader
out of being able to look at more facts. Another nagging question: How is it
that the TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, which were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> to the deal, failed to break the
story?

         
      
   
