
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX>(er)s in the Head
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>,

            You keep forgetting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Billionaire</ENAMEX> himself who, I suspect, won't be
able to forgo a run at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval</ENAMEX>. All kidding aside, it actually might be nice
to have someone at the debate who doesn't think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> is the greatest thing
since the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">GI Bill</ENAMEX> and who doesn't think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> is God. As for my
take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>, it's not that he's not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>. He just hates <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. As for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>, I'm still hoping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merv Griffin</ENAMEX> gets in.

            I see on the wires <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX> that abortions have hit a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year</TIMEX> low. Is
there any indicia of social health that isn't getting better? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'90s</ENAMEX> are
making the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'80s</NUMEX> look like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s</TIMEX>.

            I also see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major League Baseball</ENAMEX> is going to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Rocker</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX>
who made racist remarks in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Illustrated</ENAMEX> --undergo psychological
counseling. Obviously, what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocker</ENAMEX> said was repugnant; his exact comments had
to do with all the ethnic groups <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> deals with on a subway ride to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shea Stadium</ENAMEX>. But shouldn't the appropriate punishment for racist talk be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> ostracism--no endorsements ever, for instance; being shunned by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX>. The idea of sending him to some kind of re-education session seems
absurd if not a bit totalitarian. The idea that racist behavior can be
eradicated with psychotherapy also seems a tad dubious. ("Remember, I'll be
gone all of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goebbels</ENAMEX>.") Should <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> now attempt to reform their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">athletes</ENAMEX> views on other issues, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, etc? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reggie White</ENAMEX> made some pretty
outrageous remarks. But it would have been nuts to try and put him on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX>
and beat them out of him. Please.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
