
   
   
      
         
            Who Are the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibetan Lamas</ENAMEX>?
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karmapa Lama</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibetan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Buddhist Leader</ENAMEX>, fled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years ago</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> sparked controversy by nominating a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> for
the position of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panchen Lama</ENAMEX> than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> had chosen. Who are
all these lamas?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama</ENAMEX>, which translates as "superior <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>," is a title officially extended
only to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">few dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monks</ENAMEX> who have achieved the highest
level of spiritual development. (In informal conversation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lama</ENAMEX> is used to
refer to any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk</ENAMEX>.) Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lamas</ENAMEX> are believed to be
reincarnations of previous lamas or holy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and their places in the hierarchy
are determined by these reincarnated identities. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tibetan Buddhism</ENAMEX> is divided
into multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panchen Lama</ENAMEX> lead the largest sect,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karmapa Lama</ENAMEX> heads the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> largest.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> is considered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>'s spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, since he holds
the highest position within the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gelugpa</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yellow Hat"</ENAMEX>) sect. The title
was <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> adopted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gelugpa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16 th century</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mongols</ENAMEX> deemed the position one of spiritual and
temporal power. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14 th</NUMEX> and present <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> assumed the post as
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year-old</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>. (When a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> dies, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> enters the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of a
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is identified through physical and mental tests, including
familiarity with the previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>'s belongings.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> fled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetans</ENAMEX>' failed uprising against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communists</ENAMEX>, who
had taken over in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>. He has continued to serve as a religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in
exile and received the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> for his peaceful efforts to
end <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> rule in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>'s official Web site.) 

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panchen Lama</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> highest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gelugpa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, but does not
have civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> fled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> government
tried to elevate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panchen Lama</ENAMEX> to take his place. Although he partly
cooperated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panchen Lama</ENAMEX> continued to protest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> rule
and demand religious freedom. He was imprisoned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>, released in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, and
died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six years later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>, who traditionally determines the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panchen Lama</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, announced his choice for the position. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
government asserted that it had the authority to make the selection, and last
summer enthroned a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine-year-old</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panchen Lama</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> does not
recognize the choice, and most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Buddhists</ENAMEX> continue to worship the
original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, who has been missing since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> and is assumed to be in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> custody. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to learn more about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>-designated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panchen Lama</ENAMEX>, and
here
for information on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>'s choice.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karmapa Lama</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karmapa</ENAMEX> sect of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibetan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX>. The current <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karmapa</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 year-old</TIMEX>, is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incarnation</ENAMEX> and is the only high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lama</ENAMEX> accepted by both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has pointed to its acceptance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karmapa Lama</ENAMEX> as an example
of its religious tolerance. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karmapa Lama</ENAMEX> is said to have fled because
of recent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> restrictions on his movement and teachings. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> has not yet
decided whether to grant him asylum. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karmapa Lama</ENAMEX>'s homepage.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> thanks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Gerritsen</ENAMEX> for suggesting the
topic .

            Next question?

         
      
   
