
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">112</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with news that global stock markets strongly
rebounded on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> from a dramatic dip <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the week</TIMEX>, sending the Dow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> industrial average to an all-time high: 11,522.56.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times lead, poorly written and edited, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
retreated from a declaration made during his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> debate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>
that he would require any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> he nominated to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX> position to
"agree in advance [that is, before getting the nomination,] to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> serve
openly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>." A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> story, reefered on the front in an early
edition and fronted in a later one, explains the story more clearly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
position, now the same as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> should be allowed to serve
openly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, and he would require his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs of Staff</ENAMEX> to carry
out such a policy, but not require them to support it before appointment. The
LAT
stuffs the news.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impending announcement
of an aid package promising <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX> more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. He developed the proposal after congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> proposed their
own <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.6-billion-</NUMEX>over-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-years plan; and after <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andres</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pastrana</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to help pay for a comprehensive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> improvement
plan he developed. The big difference in the two packages is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> wants
most of the money to go to police and drug trafficking while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wants it
"more evenly divided between those efforts and government infrastructure and
economic assistance," like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pastrana</ENAMEX> wants. The issue of giving military aid to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX> is complicated by the rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> that control "most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
drug-producing regions" and by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>'s "unsavory human rights record." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> doesn't seem
to carry the story at all; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs a wire piece about it.

            Speaking of unsavory human rights records ... a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front piece announces
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florida Passes Bill to Quicken Execution Pace</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeb Bush</ENAMEX> proposed and
pushed through the bill, modeled on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> law his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> and presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>, proposed and pushed through. GWB
has overseen the executions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">111</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. (By the way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> claims
that there have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">581</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> executions since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> reinstated the
death penalty in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>. So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GWB</ENAMEX> has been responsible for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost one-fifth</NUMEX> of the
total.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> law will "shorten the length between sentencing and
execution to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 years</TIMEX>" from the current average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
plans to "review <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>'s use of the electric chair" because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> has
botched a number of executions. Unfortunately, it's not until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost the end of</TIMEX>
the piece that we learn "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">87</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on death row in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> have been
found to be wrongly convicted, and released [since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>]. The average time
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> spent on death row was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half years</TIMEX>." Not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>. The
piece does not say, though it should, how much it costs to execute, or to house
per year, someone on death row. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> doesn't
have this important story; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> only has a graph on it halfway through its "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nation In</ENAMEX>
Brief" section.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s suspension of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airstrikes</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grozny</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>. Rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> helped cause
the moratorium. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> claimed the pause "was intended to allow the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> still trapped in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grozny</ENAMEX> to escape from the fighting"
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ). But, since
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> senior field <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> were replaced concurrently, the "reason
behind the [suspension] ... was not entirely clear" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ). The WP piece focuses on the dismissals. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reminds that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">generals</ENAMEX> claimed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> they would quicfkly crush the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>. Both
Times point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s new acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>,
needs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to continue to appear successful in the war to retain popular
support. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is alone in quoting a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> who
thinks "the initiative is slipping from the hands of the worn-out military and
into the hands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>"; and in citing another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> who
thought it suspicious that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> removed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of his most ardent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>,
also <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reefers a story the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> off-leads
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a
wire piece about: A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lama</ENAMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibetan Buddhism</ENAMEX>'s most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">honored</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, secretly fled from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, joining the exile movement
led by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scholars</ENAMEX> agree the defection is likely embarrassing to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s spin is that "it was due
to a split in his movement rather than disillusionment with life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>." As
the LAT
says, the escape "appeared to dash whatever hopes remained for a compromise
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
correction addressed an inconsistency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> noted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>: "After <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> said, 'I would take an
expression into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dear God</ENAMEX>--help me!" ' it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary L. Bauer</ENAMEX>,
not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>, who replied, 'So would we, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>.' "

         
      
   
