
   
   
      
         
            More <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Minutes of the Media Conspiracy</ENAMEX>

            The central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of the media
conspiracy met again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s minutes.) We were all
supposed to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> to cover <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> debate, but given the cold
weather and a series of interesting honoraria being given by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprise Institute</ENAMEX>, we decided to gather instead for lunch at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm</ENAMEX>
Restaurant in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>

            All the usual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">luminaries</ENAMEX> were there, with the exception of the incredibly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dedicated David Broder</ENAMEX>, who video-conferenced in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winterset</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Broder</ENAMEX>
was out there wrapping up a marathon outdoor focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Methodists</ENAMEX>
expected to attend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s caucuses. It was a bit difficult to hear him
through his balaclava, but I'm pretty sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX>'s point was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> were peaking too early. He wanted to know what we should do to ensure
the longest possible primary season.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Seib</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> made the first suggestion: Why
not just continue to sprinkle <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> with adoring coverage? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX>
said he was planning to publish a column about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> was winning
admiration in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick</ENAMEX> stance on campaign-finance reform. He
added that every time he ran this column, he got a nice note from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wertheimer</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie</ENAMEX> could barely control their sniggering. It fell to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Berke</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> to explain to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX> why this wouldn't work. For
one thing, the story had to change--we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> couldn't very well keep
writing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> were on the rise. What's more, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> pointed
out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> were already flirting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EOB</ENAMEX> in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EOB</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX>
explained to me, stands for "extreme & overt bias," and it's a violation of
the conspiracy's bylaws.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Fineman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> offered an alternative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seib</ENAMEX>'s idea. Why
not offer a round of seemingly harsh but actually harmless stories about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>? This would create the appearance of media fair play without
doing either of our favorites much damage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> pointed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s letters
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> as an example, though he noted that this kind of story always has
the potential to get out of hand. The meeting dissolved into laughter when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> joked that he nearly had to sit down and read the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> letters <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.

            Syndicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> said he thought a barrage of mild
criticism was a nifty idea because it would allow for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> CWRs
("conventional-wisdom reversals," according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between now</TIMEX> and the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX> primary. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> could sag <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> and then surge the
following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, achieving "come from behind" victories in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. The
beauty of the plan, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> said, was that it was possible without any actual
candidate movement in the polls.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seib</ENAMEX> loved the idea. He even offered to write the first draft of a column
about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> had a highly conservative voting record. While appearing
critical, this story could help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> by putting distance between him and the
liberal media, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seib</ENAMEX> said.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> apologized for raining on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX>'s parade, but said he thought the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as</NUMEX>-closet-conservative story would be more effective if it weren't
written by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>. He suggested handing the idea off to some "shoe-leather
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnny Apple</ENAMEX> jumped in at this point to complain that shoe leather was what
he was eating for lunch. Shouting for the "garçon ," he complained that
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone steak</ENAMEX> was overcooked and that he had powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weights</ENAMEX> and Measures who might be interested in checking to see whether it
really was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 ounces</NUMEX> as advertised. The waiter apologetically took the bone
back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and quickly brought Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Apple</ENAMEX> another.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fineman</ENAMEX> then raised a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>: Wouldn't it be unfair to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> to
criticize him for being too conservative? According to conspiracy rules, all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> were supposed to receive credit ("new respect") for turning more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal</ENAMEX>. But this problem was quickly resolved when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, who was attending
the lunch as a guest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , 
                  Slate
               , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , said he
wouldn't mind the criticism a bit.

            What of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lance Morrow</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL-Time Warner</ENAMEX> asked.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam & Cokie</ENAMEX> proposed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> be charged with general arrogance
since he wouldn't say publicly what his favorite movie was (while acknowledging
off-the-record to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look Who's Talking II</ENAMEX> ). Fineman
added that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> could also be charged with hypocrisy since "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mr. Sharp Elbows</ENAMEX>"
wasn't living up to his own elevated standard of positive campaigning.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis Hortoo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis Hortoo</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Germond</ENAMEX> exclaimed, perhaps referring to
a recent interview in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley castigated Gore</ENAMEX> for discovering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horton</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> campaign. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martini</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morrow</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s arrogance and hypocrisy were both fine issues and that
the newsmagazines would work out the details of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX> at their usual
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> planning session. He reminded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fineman</ENAMEX> that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's turn
to put together <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s outline. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>, who by this point was mostly
covered in a snowdrift, was impatient to bring the meeting to a close. He
wished everyone a lively campaign and reminded us to dress warmly for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">toboggan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dixville Notch</ENAMEX>. He said I could bring the hot cocoa.

         
      
   
