
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wise Guys; Annoying Gals</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Biggie</ENAMEX>,

            Wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a frigging second</TIMEX>--could you please explain to me the phallic symbolism
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herring</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herring</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream sauce</ENAMEX>, maybe, but regular old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herring</ENAMEX>?

            Again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX>, too many thoughts. I don't know where to begin with you. Oh,
I know where--by telling you I finally get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">De Man</ENAMEX>" Shulevitz joke.
Like, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Man</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>-symp deconstructionist. You're pretty funny, for an
intellectual. Let me repeat that last part--for an intellectual. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept. of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mortifying Amplification</ENAMEX>: I finally got the joke because someone explained it
to me. OK, you explained it to me. Let's never talk about this again. I hate
you comp-lit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>).

            May I make one observation? There is way too much hype now about this show.
Did you see the cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide</ENAMEX> ? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> is all there, and they're on
the cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> , and they're in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> ,
and the newsweeklies, ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infinitum</ENAMEX>. This is crazy already. I feel the backlash
beginning.

            OK. I don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richie Aprile</ENAMEX>, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX> on the block, precisely because
he's such a malevolent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX>, at least so far (yeah, he's a bit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Agey</ENAMEX>, but
his whole yoga <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shtick</ENAMEX> feels forced, as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> decided that each and
every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> had to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the sensitive, slightly feminized
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">postmodern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>). I think it's dangerous for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> to introduce an
ongoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> who's flat-out bad. (Though I guess that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikey Palmice</ENAMEX>,
Junior's now-dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">henchman</ENAMEX>, filled that role <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last season</TIMEX>.) All malevolence, all
the time, as you put it, is fine for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casino</ENAMEX> --think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Pesci</ENAMEX>--but in
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sopranos</ENAMEX> ? The joy of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> is that all these bad-ass
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> are possessed of some complicating goodness, or at least some kind of
benign dream of a better life.

            But don't get me wrong: I much prefer the addition of a flat-out gangster to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> than yet another annoying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (uh oh, am I in trouble now?).

            By annoying, I am referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, who is with us for the entire
season, apparently. Talk about a drag on the show. It's funny--in advance of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s discussion, I wanted to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Episodes 2</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> again, but I couldn't
bring myself to do it: They bored me, and I realized that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>'s sister
who bored me the most. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX>, they should have killed off Livia when they had the
chance, and that way they wouldn't have to saddle us with her dreary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>.

            Don't get wrong, I do enjoy the story lines that don't deal directly with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting whacked, and I could watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edie Falco</ENAMEX>, who plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>,
spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 hours</TIMEX> reading the phone book. To herself. I could even watch her in
the execrable <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oz</ENAMEX> , in which she plays a prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>. (How could <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>
simultaneously make a show as good as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> and as bad as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oz</ENAMEX> ?)

            Here's the thing: Generally speaking, I like my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> movies straight-up male:
I still don't understand what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Keaton</ENAMEX> is doing in The Godfather
(not to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sofia Coppola</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">III</ENAMEX> ). I love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>, and I love
mob intrigue. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Chase</ENAMEX> has made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>'s relationship with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> so
interesting--and, at least in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>'s relationship with
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> so appalling--that I don't generally fall asleep when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soprano</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are on screen. (I know you think I'm some kind of misogynist now,
yes?).

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melfi</ENAMEX>, I've always had mixed feelings about her. She is at the center
of the story, of course; without her, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> would be unredeemed, and dead. Maybe
I don't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorraine Bracco</ENAMEX> is a bit of a stiff. I don't
know. I'm a simple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. I'd rather watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silvo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paulie Walnuts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pussy</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> shoot pool and gripe and plot to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and I'd rather watch Hesh
scheme and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX> explode, than watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorraine Bracco</ENAMEX> act.

            On the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and their gripes about The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sopranos</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>, I'm with you (thought I must admit <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Merchant of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX> ain't my all-time favorite. Who wrote that piece of shit, anyway?
Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Man</ENAMEX>?). I grew up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike Lee</ENAMEX> movie: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> needled the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> who beat-up the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> who harassed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> (well, not really) and so
on. I like ethnic humor. Besides, I have a theory about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s fascination
with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>: said fascination is merely an extension of the world's
love for everything <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>--culture, opera, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, art, architecture. It's all
of a piece. At least, this is what I tell <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who write me
incredibly nasty letters when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> stories appear.

            By the way, since when do I have <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hasidic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>? God, what do you think of
me?

            Oh--A mook is kind of like a gavone, which is kind of like an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">schmuck</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
