
   
   
      
         
            Hooked on Debate

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s announcement by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> that they would support a tax cut <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> the
size of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$792 billion</NUMEX> cuts package they put forward <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> that was
vetoed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The paper quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hastert</ENAMEX> opining
that there is a tax agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> in the offing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feds</ENAMEX>' new anti-terror measures, including tighter performance
standards for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that do airport security screenings and a plan to
be announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to make government computers safer from attack.
Its most novel aspect: a college scholarship program that would give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
graduate and undergraduate tuition subsidies in return for postgraduate
government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> as information technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>'s
report stating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PricewaterhouseCoopers</ENAMEX>, the world's largest accounting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, violated the rule prohibiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> from having investments
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> it audits. As a result, says the paper, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will check
out the other major accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>' compliance. The story seems oversold (by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> and by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ): The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> the
violations resulted from complications relating to the merger that created the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, and no examples are given of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> audits that were in any way rendered
dubious by prima facie investment conflicts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> decision to continue to delay
implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> provision opening <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>.
The paper quotes unnamed senior trade and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> explaining
that the plan is to ensure that the matter is not resolved while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is
running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, thus keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX>, who vehemently oppose the
opening, from abandoning him. With the exception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's fronting of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> story, none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leads</ENAMEX> makes the others' fronts.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> debate, which also
tops the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page news box, but the late metro
edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> stuffs it. According to the coverage, the debates
were highlighted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s declaration going his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s famous
pledge one better: "This is not only no new taxes. This is tax cuts, so help me
God"; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> arguing about campaign-finance reform, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> defending the compatibility of his reform stance with his recently
exposed letter writing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> to force a decision concerning a TV station
that one of his major contributors wanted to purchase, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> claiming that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s reform would "hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> cause." All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> debaters
came out against open service of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, contradicting the stance
favored <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> before by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> in their debate.

            The papers report that when asked if he would take the mantra "What would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> do?" into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> replied, "I would take an expression into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office of</ENAMEX>, 'Dear God, help me!' " The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>
added, "So would we." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> attribute the quip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyes</ENAMEX> criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> for saying he
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">liked Nine Inch Nails</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> climbed down quickly, saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> was a "poor
choice."

            The editorial pages seize on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> letters, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> saying
he "badly overstepped the rules," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> calling the letters
"improper." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> says the real scandal is that unelected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> have power over large swaths of the private economy and that the
least our elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> can do is ride <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herd</ENAMEX> on them.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports in a story inside that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> disclosed
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that the explanation it offered during the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> war of how a
passenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> came to be bombed had a flaw. The official explanation at the time, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
pilot locked onto an empty railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>, and only after that did the train
very quickly come onto it, was buttressed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s showing of a
nose-cone video. But, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> now admits the video was
shown to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times normal speed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that all other
bombing videos released to the press during the war were shown at normal speed.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> insists the speed selection was inadvertent. In other words,
they're willing to admit to a mistake in a non-combat zone, when lots of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> are involved, with lots of lead time, and involving simple
technology but can't contemplate a mistake when none of these favorable
conditions obtain.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> run wire service stories reporting that
legal abortions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> (for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the latest year</TIMEX> for which data is
available) is at its lowest point since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story says that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX> didn't try to figure out why the drop occurred. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says it did
and mentions among the factors "possibly different attitudes about the moral
implications of abortion." Will there be more study of this last question by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX> or is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> afraid to find out and/or publicize a possible
result indicating an increasing belief that abortion is immoral?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reefers, and the other papers run inside, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major League</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Baseball</ENAMEX>'s decision that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Rocker</ENAMEX> must undergo psychological testing before
it decides whether or not to discipline him for his recent disparaging remarks
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> thinks this makes sense, since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prejudice</ENAMEX> is a mentally disordered way of looking at the world. And, hey, while
we're at it, how about psychological testing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis</ENAMEX>
Farrakhan, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
