
   
   
      
         
            Analyze This!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Judith</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus H. Christ</ENAMEX>! How many thoughts can you squeeze into a single e-mail?

            I want to tell you a story: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1998</TIMEX>, I was hanging around the
Westchester federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX>, waiting for another of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John A. Gotti</ENAMEX>'s
interminable pre-trial hearings to begin, when I bumped into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gotti</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelo Ruggiero Jr. Fat Angie</ENAMEX> (I think they call him <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Fat Angie</ENAMEX>) is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelo "Quack-Quack" Ruggerio</ENAMEX>, who got his nickname because he talked too much
into government wires. Ruggerio the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Son</ENAMEX> is a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, not too smart, maybe,
but nice, and we made small talk about his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Filas</ENAMEX>.

            There was, in fact, not much I needed to know from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelo</ENAMEX>. But I did have
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> question: Why did he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy-boy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> eat so often at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cracker Barrel</ENAMEX>?
This was one of the amazing true facts I uncovered about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Junior Gotti</ENAMEX> (some mob
reporters uncover complex union kickback scams; I expose the secret dining
habits of pathetic goombahs). What I asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelo</ENAMEX> was this: Why would an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Italian-American</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to the greatest cuisine on the planet, stoop to eat
chicken-fried steak at a redneck restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelo</ENAMEX> looked at me,
shrugged his shoulders and said, "I don't know. I mean, how much <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> food
can you eat?"

            Your e-mail--and the cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>'s obsession with the The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sopranos</ENAMEX> --reminds me of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angie</ENAMEX>'s profound comment. What I mean is, how much
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Culturebox</ENAMEX>-style commentary about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> can the public eat?

            I know what you're thinking. You're thinking, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, I got your Culturebox
right here, you fuckin' mook you."

            I also know I'm as guilty as anyone of overhyping <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> . I
just recently wrote that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> is the best TV show ever.

            So please don't think for a second that I don't want to hear your theories.
I have always counted on you for all of that hermeneutics and semiotics and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dianetics</ENAMEX> and other really dope <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lingua Franca</ENAMEX> shit. It's just that I
fear that too much in the way of high-end yammering about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX>
and its profound meaning will cause a backlash against the show. Expectations
are just too ridiculously high (i.e., the comparison to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Nevsky</ENAMEX> in the
Times , etc.). I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> would have been smart to
intentionally lower expectations over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past six months</TIMEX> by leaking stories
about massive attacks of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> on the set. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Chase</ENAMEX>, the
series' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX>, should have killed off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livia Soprano</ENAMEX> (not that I don't love
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Marchand</ENAMEX>) when he had the chance. But more on that later.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whoa</ENAMEX>. I think I just hinted at my opinion of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new season</TIMEX>. No way I'm
showing you mine until you show me yours.

            Let me address your pet theories. I agree with most everything you've said
(or at least, everything you said that I understood), except that I wouldn't
characterize any part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodfellas</ENAMEX> as a "jaunty laugh-fest."

            I think you've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing exactly right: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> works so
well precisely because it is understated, because it is the opposite of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">operatic Godfather</ENAMEX> . Together, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Godfather and The</ENAMEX>
Sopranos make up some kind of whole, but here's the fundamental difference
between them: Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> I've ever met imagines himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> . I interviewed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Gravano</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX> and he said as much;
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> invested the lives of mobsters, who are in fact seedy and
boring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, with honor and drama.

            But I haven't talked to a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> who would take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Soprano</ENAMEX>'s life
over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Corleone</ENAMEX>'s. We're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> , so
it's a bit too early to say if this particular manifestation of mob art is
influencing mob life, but I think it's fair to say that no one in actual
organized crime would ever want to be hooked up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Soprano</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>.

            In a way, I think I've just answered the interesting question you've posed,
namely, how realistic is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> ? Very, I'd say. Not being an
actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> (to my everlasting regret), my assessment might be worth bupkus
(as the hysterical <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silvio Dante</ENAMEX> would say), but <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> accurately
captures the desperation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s mobsters. The smarter wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> know that
they are the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX>-suit-wearing equivalents of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those prehistoric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX>
living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Orinoco River Basin</ENAMEX>, just waiting for extinction.

            I was talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Chase</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks ago</TIMEX> (am I just the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">insufferable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">name-dropper</ENAMEX>, or what?), and we got to talking about
his use of humor. What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chase</ENAMEX> evidently realized (and what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coppola</ENAMEX> didn't,
Clemenza aside) is that real-life mobsters can be quite funny--self-consciously
funny--in a non slapsticky, non- Analyze This , sort of way. Knowing this
makes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> seem real to me. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s mobsters, too, are fluent in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">psychobabble</ENAMEX> and in the language of self-improvement, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chase</ENAMEX>, of course,
captures this beautifully (I will disagree with you on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing at the outset:
the writing on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> is better than the acting, not that there's
anything really wrong with the acting.)

            By the way, can we also talk about how badly Analyze This sucked?

            I'm going to sign off for the moment, but first I wanted to tell you I think
you ought to have a mob moniker, at least for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>. How about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Herring" Shulevitz</ENAMEX>?

            Also, a question, for your consideration: Do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> movies are dead?
The genre's tired, obviously, but is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> a sign of new
life?

            Also, tell me what you think of the new season already. Inquiring minds want
to know.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fuckin' Mook</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
