
   
   
      
         
            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> Percent Solution
            

            I was lucky in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Godzilla</ENAMEX> , all my scenes were with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--no blue
screen required. Oh, there was one scene where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Cartwright</ENAMEX> saw the thing
over my shoulder, but I was blissfully unaware.

            Just saw on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential Debate Commission</ENAMEX> is requiring that
any third-party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> get <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 15 percent</NUMEX> in the polls to be eligible
for the debates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX>. Given the now widely known fact that response
rates to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> has fallen in some cases to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as low as 20 percent</NUMEX> (thanks in
part to telemarketers driving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> crazy at dinnertime), it seems a little
wacky to let something important ride on the results of a poll. Television
schedules, OK, who cares, but presidential debates should be treated a little
more seriously than the fate of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It's Like ... You Know</ENAMEX> . By the way, how
do you stand on the really important nomination contest--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>, of course, may not be an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semite</ENAMEX>, but he plays <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on TV. On the other
hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> could at least give us a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> who's a supermodel.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX> has been in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> place for so long now he has to be praying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>
doesn't start a national newscast. I agree about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX> (I have a
wonderful videotape of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX> trying to figure out how to ad-lib a story
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> voting down the flag-burning amendment; apparently, they don't
teach the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> constitutional amendment process in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>), but I
do think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX> should pick a hair color and stick to it. He keeps daring us not
to notice that it's changing.

            If they had a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> criterion for the primary debates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> would
have long since been reduced to yelling "racism" from the sidelines.

            Later,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
