
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hardball: 1776</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mea maxima culpa</ENAMEX>. I had seen the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> and forgotten. As for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Le Show</ENAMEX>,"
I'm going straight to the Web site.

            I totally agree re <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Matthews</ENAMEX>. I find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> personable whenever I see
him around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. But the show's pretty unbelieveable. I try to imagine
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hardball: 1776</ENAMEX>." "Isn't this whole Declaration thing just a bunch of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Monticello elitists</ENAMEX> sitting around telling the rest of us--us common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX>--what
to do? I mean, he's up there with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Hemmings</ENAMEX> lecturing to the rest of us
about virtue. Give me a break."

            You got a take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riordan</ENAMEX>? I saw him on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these millennium shows
flicking the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>-sign fireworks with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Leno</ENAMEX>, which seemed pretty goofy.
But from a distance, he seems pretty good at making the trains run on time
without <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s authoritarian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenor</ENAMEX>. Also, how does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di Fi</ENAMEX> manage to run
without a serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>? It seems fairly amazing to me that they can't find
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repub</ENAMEX> of any heft to put up against her.

            I love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> endorsing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> at the same time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> endorses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. Is this
not like the meeting of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">The Godfather</ENAMEX> . "We sell the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. But it never goes into the neighborhood." I half expect to hear Poppy
drive away with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is a ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pimp</ENAMEX>. It was not until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> that I
realized all along it was ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>."

            What would be wrong with a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Germond tour d'steakhouses</ENAMEX> and racetracks?
Believe me, it was easier greeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> column on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Marzano</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> than a column on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> reappointment. Gotta run.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
