
   
   
      
         
            In God They Trust
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>,

            Sorry, you've got the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> here are filled with stories about how
fast it's spreading and how everyone should get shots. You've inspired yours
truly to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> debate was ugly, but in some ways so much more satisfying than the
Dems, who essentially agreed on everything but who's shrillness knew no bounds.
A few thoughts: As long as these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have nothing to say about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>,
prescription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, and education (besides vouchers), they're going to have a
tough time winning back the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, I totally agree re <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX>. True
connoisseurs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX> noticed his constant reference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of</ENAMEX>
Independence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Die-hard Straussians</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> of the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo Strauss</ENAMEX>, of whom
I gather <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyes</ENAMEX> is one--love the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration</ENAMEX> more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> because
it's got God in the lead. Normally, one might think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>
preempts the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration</ENAMEX>, but not for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> tries to imagine what would
happen if an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant secretary</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> kept running in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> primaries. It would, of course, be a joke.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s edgy smile--clearly designed to make him look friendly, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crazy</ENAMEX>--seemed a tad annoying, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was the most impressive overall, I
thought. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> did pretty well, but he never answered the heaven question
directly. Seemed to me he doesn't believe that non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> go to heaven. Not
that this matters especially.

            Have we gone over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> plastic surgery? My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> have an exclusive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on how it was done. The doc says it was
tricky because she was built like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, I gather, are tougher to work
on. This makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Goodman</ENAMEX> impression on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> all
the better.

            I see the "tech-heavy" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> continues its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX> sell-off. I gather
inflation fears are still gripping the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. Please. Inflation's been pretty
much slayed, but the bond-holding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> can't let go of their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'70s</NUMEX>-esque fears
of soaring prices. It ain't gonna happen for a lot of complicated reasons. None
of this would matter so much except it's keeping wages down. Whenever wages
start to go up a bit--God forbid, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> should see their salaries jump--Wall
Street gets jittery about inflation and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> pumps the brakes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
percent growth is great, but on this one I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. I think we can grow
faster.

            Enough of that. Anything fun in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
