
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mental-Health Care for Republican Candidates</ENAMEX>
            

            For some reason, I find it easier to think about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Relenza</ENAMEX> and antibiotics
right about now than--ugh--another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> debate tonight. What colorful tie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">will Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> break out as he talks about himself in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>--or perhaps
by now, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>? How many boxes will <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> be standing on? Will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> finally go back on his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX>?

            OK, I'll admit it, I almost never read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> (I'll
tell you sometime the whole reason--it has to do with finding out how the paper
is edited), but there was a cute story in there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about the police
arresting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for feeding the homeless in downtown's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pershing Square</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> explained that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> were interfering with the temporary
ice-skating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rink</ENAMEX>. Now, it helps to understand that there is no more desolate
example of urban-renewing a place into the ground in all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> than
the once-charming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pershing Square</ENAMEX>. Green space was removed (attracted the
homeless). My nomination for the unspoken issue of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>'
debates is--what does society do with the mentally ill that we kicked out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mental</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three decades ago</TIMEX> and who have become, willy-nilly, the
homeless? Not to mention the fact that "a history of mental problems" turns up
in the résumés of more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troublemakers</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.

            Just saw a news conference featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>, and it
makes me salivate with anticipation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> convention <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>.
Those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, plus the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buchanan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brigade</ENAMEX>--personally, I hope it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX>, so
I can drive down there, but wherever it is, it'll be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>'s best
show.

            Did you hear the story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s sending notes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> recently? Can't quite pin it down (heard it on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Harvey</ENAMEX>, which doesn't
say much for its accuracy, but, hey, those airbeds are great). But on the
subject of "those gals," if I paid the kind of money <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s supporters
must have paid for her makeover, I'd be expecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> to keep his mouth
shut.

            It's been a variety of fun. Thanks for the ride.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
