



A Brief History
Little is known of the earliest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone Age</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe‚</ENAMEX>Äôs southwestern extremity. The ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> called them the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynetes</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cunetes</ENAMEX>). Whatever their origins, their culture evolved under the pressure and influence of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. Among the many invading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> that settled here and contributed to nascent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> culture were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phoenicians</ENAMEX>, who settled in the area <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">around 1,000 b.c.</NUMEX>, followed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celts, Iberians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carthaginians</ENAMEX>.
But it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX>, who arrived late in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third century</TIMEX> b.c., who most greatly influenced all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iberia</ENAMEX>. They built <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>, industries, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>, developed agriculture, and bequeathed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> language, of which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> is a direct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendant</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> named the southwestern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of the peninsula <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lusitania</ENAMEX>, oddly enough for one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Celtiberian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> they defeated, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third century</TIMEX> a.d. had introduced Christianity. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the fourth century</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algarve</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishop</ENAMEX> in place, based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Faro</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> had already fallen into decay, and soon hordes of northern tribesmen took over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algarve</ENAMEX> fell to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visigoths</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-fifth century</TIMEX>.
Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moorish Rule</ENAMEX>
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 711</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moors</ENAMEX> brought powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Africa</ENAMEX> and launched a devastating attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iberian</ENAMEX> peninsula, conquering much of what would become <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>. They imposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> and left an indelible influence on the countryside and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algarve</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moorish</ENAMEX> legacy can still be seen in the form of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> and waterwheels, squat white <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, the dark complexions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and in the very name given the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">region¬†‚Äî¬†taken</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Al-Gharb</ENAMEX>, which means ‚Äúcountry of the west‚Äù (when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moors</ENAMEX> conquered the territory, it was the most westerly in the known world).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moors</ENAMEX> governed their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iberian</ENAMEX> kingdoms from across the border in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seville</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algarve</ENAMEX> had its own regional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> and huge, invulnerable fortress. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelb</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xelb</ENAMEX>), and it was bigger and better defended than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lisbon</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silves</ENAMEX>, (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX>) is a provincial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outpost</ENAMEX> whose only besiegers are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">busloads</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> who climb the narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> up to the old Moorish ramparts.
The long struggle by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> to expel the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moors</ENAMEX> (a campaign known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconquista</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconquest</ENAMEX>) began towards <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the eighth century</TIMEX> a.d. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 11th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portucale</ENAMEX> consisted of a small section of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castile</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le√≥n</ENAMEX> (today‚Äôs northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>). Yet it wasn‚Äôt until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 12th century</TIMEX> that significant gains were made to take back southern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iberia</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of the end</TIMEX> came in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle of Ourique</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1139</TIMEX>. After the victory, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Count Afonso Henriques</ENAMEX> proclaimed himself the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>, making it one of the first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconquest of Silves</ENAMEX>, not achieved for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another 50 years</TIMEX>, was a grisly affair. A mixed bag of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusaders</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northern Europe</ENAMEX> were recruited en route to their battles east in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Land</ENAMEX>. They sailed upon the river <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silves</ENAMEX> and, ignoring conditional offers of surrender, slew all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> (at no small loss to themselves) and pillaged the great treasures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years later</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> rallied again, retaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silves</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconquista</ENAMEX> stumbled on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another half century</TIMEX>. So many inter-religious alliances reigned, and so pervasive was the intermingling of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>, that it was hard to tell who was on which side and for which piece of land they were fighting. On top of that, the situation was further clouded by a feud between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, each of them claiming sovereignty over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algarve</ENAMEX>. However, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1249</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Faro</ENAMEX> and the western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algarve</ENAMEX> were retaken under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Afonso III</ENAMEX>, completing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconquest</ENAMEX>. The possibility of war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> was averted by an expeditious royal marriage, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the century</TIMEX> a treaty with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> drew up the boundaries of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> that stand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algarve</ENAMEX> was a region regarded separately within the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>, as is evidenced by the royal title ‚ÄúKingdom of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algarve</ENAMEX>.‚Äù In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>, the notion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algarve</ENAMEX> as a distinct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> did make some sense: like an island, it was cut off to the south and west by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>, to the east by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Guadiana River</ENAMEX>, and to the north by the mountains. The region‚Äôs titular autonomy was upheld until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>, when the monarchy itself was overthrown.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navigator</ENAMEX>
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1415</TIMEX>, long after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconquista</ENAMEX> was completed, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> assembled on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">River Tagus</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lisbon</ENAMEX> for an assault on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moors</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX>. Crossing the Straits <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">of Gibraltar</ENAMEX>, the armada attacked and seized the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ceuta</ENAMEX>. An illustrious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the famous raid was the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King Jo√£o I</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philippa</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lancaster</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ceuta</ENAMEX> would be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and only military victory, though he was destined to establish <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> as a major world power, helping to develop important world trade routes by the time of his death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1460</TIMEX>.
At the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 21</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX> assembled a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Navigation</ENAMEX>. It was certainly not a formal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> of lectures and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX>, but probably resembled an informal modern-day ‚Äúthink-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tank</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Prince Henry¬</ENAMEX>†‚Äî¬†made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algarve</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1418¬†‚</NUMEX>Äî¬†had the money, influence, enthusiasm, and vision to lead and cajole the best astronomers, cartographers, boat-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>, and seamen of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> to expand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Portugal‚</ENAMEX>Äôs maritime horizons.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> at the western extreme of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algarve</ENAMEX> were all that was known to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>. Once they were beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabo de S√£o Vicente</ENAMEX>, they faced the unknown, with no communications and no possibility of rescue if the voyage turned out badly. Yet out into the unknown they went; for the glory of God and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and in search of personal fame and fortune. Their mission was made easier by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft Algarve shipwrights</ENAMEX> had developed, a successor to the lumbering <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>: the caravel. It was light, fast, and very maneuverable. Any breeze was enough for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> to steer it where he wanted to go. With the subsequent development of new navigational techniques, it was no longer necessary to stay within sight of land. Now the only limits to maritime exploration were man‚Äôs ingenuity and courage.
According to tradition, the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sagres</ENAMEX> peninsula (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>), though there is little there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to persuade you of this. The actual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navigation School</ENAMEX> may have been <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 miles</NUMEX>) east, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lagos</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>). This location had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shipyards</ENAMEX>, and was home to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> in his role as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algarve</ENAMEX>.
During <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Henry‚</ENAMEX>Äôs lifetime, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Portugal‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">caravels</ENAMEX> sailed beyond the most westerly point of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. They colonized the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> islands of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madeira</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azores</ENAMEX>, laying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX> for the future <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>. Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> was over, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">compatriots</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bartolomeu Dias</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vasco da Gama</ENAMEX> completed epic voyages, rounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cape</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good Hope</ENAMEX> and reaching <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, respectively, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro √Ålves Cabral</ENAMEX> claimed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1519 and 1522</TIMEX> another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">explorer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferdinand Magellan</ENAMEX>, led the first expedition to circumnavigate the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercantilist Portugal</ENAMEX> became a rich maritime superpower.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Intrigues</ENAMEX>
To protect its seagoing interests and trade routes, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> established strategic garrisons in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Goa</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malacca</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East Indies</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hormuz</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> explorers then embarked upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macau</ENAMEX> (now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macao</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congo</ENAMEX>, and various other parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> policy was to avoid armed strife and to develop a trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>, rather than to conquer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. To this end it succeeded with relatively few <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">soaked</NUMEX> episodes in its colonial history.
Adventures abroad, however, proved disastrous during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half of the 16th century</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1557</TIMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy-king</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sebasti√</ENAMEX>£o ascended the throne, the beginning of a calamitous reign that was to end at the battle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alcacer-Quiber</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX>) in pursuit of a vain crusade. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sebasti√£o‚Äôs</ENAMEX> untimely demise, alongside <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 18,000</NUMEX> ill-prepared, badly led <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>, set the stage for a crisis of succession. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> afterwards, legends and rumors bizarrely insisted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> was still alive, and imposters turned up from time to time claiming the throne; those who were plausible enough to be deemed a threat were summarily executed.
In fact, the only rightful claimant to the crown was the elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>. But after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> of alternating between the throne and his sickbed, he died, heirless. Surveying the situation and smelling an opportunity, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> occupied the power vacuum, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> and long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonist</ENAMEX> became its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> rule dictated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portugal‚</ENAMEX>Äôs inadvertent involvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain‚</ENAMEX>Äôs ongoing wars. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1587</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squadron</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> commanded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Drake</ENAMEX> attacked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algarve</ENAMEX> (now a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúlegitimate target‚</ENAMEX>Äù as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">territory</ENAMEX>) and sacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sagres</ENAMEX>, thus depriving the world of the relics of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry the Navigator</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nine years later</TIMEX> Faro was torched. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1386 Treaty</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windsor</ENAMEX>, by which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> had pledged eternal friendship, seemed a distant memory.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Portugal‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> was gradually eroded, and many of its trading posts (with the notable exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>) were picked off by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>. Finally, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">noblemen</ENAMEX> (aided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, then at war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>) organized a palace coup and restored independence.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Great Disaster</ENAMEX>
Portugal‚Äôs greatest misfortune struck on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All Saint‚Äôs Day</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1755</TIMEX>. With the candlelit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> crowded with worshippers, a monstrous earthquake struck, followed by fast-spreading fires and a devastating tidal wave that swept over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algarve</ENAMEX> inland <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as far as 6.5 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 miles</NUMEX>). The exact casualty figure will never be known, but it is estimated that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> died immediately and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">between 40,000 and 60,000 perished</NUMEX> as a result of secondary injuries and the ensuing famine and pestilence. The epicenter of the earthquake is thought to have been off the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Algarve coast</ENAMEX>, possibly between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tavira</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faro</ENAMEX>, but it devastated places as far away as the capital, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lisbon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Witnesses</ENAMEX> claim to have seen a fiery volcano erupt from beneath the sea just before the first jolt.
Throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algarve</ENAMEX> and much of the rest of southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>, virtually every important monument, cathedral, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> was destroyed, or at least critically damaged in the earthquake. Among the hardest hit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lagos</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>) which lost its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>, its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry the Navigator</ENAMEX> had once lived.
Political Upheaval
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of the 19th century</TIMEX> brought further alarm to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. This time the epicenter was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, and the cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Napoleon</ENAMEX>. Just as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portugal‚Äôs</ENAMEX> forced alliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> had made the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> a target for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drake‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16th-century</TIMEX> raids, now her friendly alliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> rankled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1807</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lisbon</ENAMEX>, causing the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to flee to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>, rose up against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX>, in what came to be known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Peninsular War</ENAMEX>.
Among the early blows struck for independence was a rebellion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olh√£o</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX>). On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 June 1808</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">townsfolk¬†‚Äî¬†armed</ENAMEX> with little more than ancient swords, spears, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stones¬†‚Äî¬†attacked</ENAMEX> and captured the local <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garrison</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> said that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> then set sail from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olh√</ENAMEX>£o all the way to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, without maps or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">navigational aids</ENAMEX>, to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of the insurrection. The real battle, however, was waged under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wellington</ENAMEX>, whose coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> expelled the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> of bitter fighting.
The war left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portugal</ENAMEX> further weakened, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1822</TIMEX> its major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire outpost</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, declared independence. At the same time, a dispute over the crown continually raged between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro IV</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">absentee monarch</ENAMEX> who preferred to reign as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> rather than return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miguel</ENAMEX>. The power struggle, with strong overtones of absolutism versus liberalism, excited the interest and intervention of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX>. With <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">help</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro</ENAMEX> defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miguel</ENAMEX> off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cape St. Vincent</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1833</TIMEX>, and his expeditionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> marched to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lisbon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro</ENAMEX> took the throne, though armed struggle continued for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> and the lingering bitterness long after that.
By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1892</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>, racked by wars and the continuing expense of maintaining its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> (including those of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mozambique</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angola</ENAMEX>), declared itself bankrupt. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX> of discontent with absolutist rule were sown.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kingdom‚Äôs End</ENAMEX>
Bloodshed would haunt the remaining years of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> monarchy. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 February 1908</TIMEX>, the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was riding in an open carriage along the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lisbon</ENAMEX> river front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terreiro do Pa√ßo</ENAMEX>, when an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX> opened fire and killed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to the throne, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Filipe</ENAMEX>. The prince‚Äôs younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manuel</ENAMEX>, was also hit, but he survived and was thus propelled to the throne at the tender age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>.
Amid republican agitation, a surprise uprising led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> within the armed forces deposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manuel</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>. Having ruled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than three years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manuel</ENAMEX> died in exile in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>.
The sudden end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than seven centuries</TIMEX> of monarchy brought confusion and crisis to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presidents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime ministers</ENAMEX> were ushered into and out of office an unbelievable <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1910 and 1926</TIMEX>, until a military revolution suspended <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Portugal‚</ENAMEX>Äôs problematic democracy. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> of power, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Carmona</ENAMEX> appointed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">finance minister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ant√≥nio de Oliveira Salazar</ENAMEX>, to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>, a position he was to hold until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>. Salazar‚Äôs repressive rule and austerity measures rid the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> economy of debt, though poverty increased. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> remained neutral during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, and Salazar demonstrated his financial acumen by selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> and supplies to both sides.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> the elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salazar</ENAMEX> was forced into retirement after a stroke. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcelo Caetano</ENAMEX>, feeling the spirit of the age, began tentative relaxations of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. The armed forces finally overthrew him in a popular bloodless coup, known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">‚ÄúCarnation Revolution</ENAMEX>,‚Äù on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 April 1974</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portugal</ENAMEX> finally began to pull itself out of the long and fruitless struggle against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX> in its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX>, and granted independence to the remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>. This, too, caused major upheavals, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> rushed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">motherland</ENAMEX>, aggravating the shortage of housing and jobs.
Although economic problems continued to beset the young <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>, the political scene was greatly stabilized. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> backwater of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Economic Community</ENAMEX> (now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>).
With aid from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> became one of the fastest-growing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algarve</ENAMEX>, already a favorite of sun-seeking beach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern Europe</ENAMEX>, also benefited from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> funds to build up its infrastructure and to invest in tourism. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portugal</ENAMEX> hosted the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Expo</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lisbon</ENAMEX>, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> further consolidated its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> by accepting the gradual introduction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euro</ENAMEX>, the single currency also adopted by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and others.



