



What to Do
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
What to Buy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crafts</ENAMEX>. Bahamians have always had to fend for themselves, and this resourcefulness has led them to become proficient at a number of practical handicrafts, many of which make beautiful souvenirs. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Straw goods</ENAMEX> are the most ubiquitous. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seminole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Bay</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX> are said to produce the finest work on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>, though each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> has its own individual patterns and differences in style. It is still possible to watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> at work on the islands of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX> and at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exuma</ENAMEX>. Straw work can be bought from small workshops in people‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> or from the better quality straw <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>. Prices can be high, but even small bowls make beautiful and practical reminders of your trip. The handmade <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> are likely to become rare within a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>, because so few young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bahamian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are now taking up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>. Be aware that much of the straw work, particularly the mass-market goods like hats and bags, is not made in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. If you want to be sure of getting genuine Bahamian straw work, buy from places such as The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plait Lady</ENAMEX>, who has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bay Street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>; you‚Äôll have to pay a little more but you‚Äôll be sure you‚Äôre getting an authentic handmade work of art.
Paintings and art work with scenes of everyday life also make beautiful mementos. The work of a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alton Lowe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Minnis</ENAMEX>, is becoming very collectable and prices can be high. On the other end of the scale, street art, including things like driftwood paintings, can be fun and much more affordable.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Wood carvings</ENAMEX> are made from a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>. Some of the best are made from the lignum vitae, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bahamian</ENAMEX> national <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>, and from the wild tamarind. The carvings come in a bewildering variety, though animal and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> motifs seem to predominate. Always check a piece thoroughly before you buy as they are vary in quality. Don‚Äôt buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> if it looks green¬†‚Äî¬†this usually means the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> has not been allowed to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, and it may split as it dries.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seashells</ENAMEX> and sponges can be found in every market and souvenir shop in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. They make beautiful, natural souvenirs, but some may come from protected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. Do not buy <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">coral or</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> products as this is illegal and only encourages further damage to these delicate and rare forms of sea life.
Clothing. If you like, you could take an empty bag and buy your holiday wardrobe when you arrive in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. Many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bay Street</ENAMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Bazaar</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Port Lucaya Market</ENAMEX> Place offer beachwear and T-shirts galore. Sarongs, printed dresses, and shirts in light fabrics are sold in almost every craft <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stall</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">straw</ENAMEX> markets. Light-cotton <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Androsia</ENAMEX> clothing, made on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX>, is perfect for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian</ENAMEX> climate; you‚Äôll find these items all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>.
Straw hats, which will protect you from the strong sun and save you from a wrinkle or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, are abundant and inexpensive. You‚Äôll be able to choose from styles ranging from the understated to the extremely flamboyant.
Duty-free luxury goods. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX> have a good range of luxury duty-free goods for sale. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> tend to be clustered together, which makes it easy to compare prices and quality before you buy; in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> you‚Äôll find them on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bay Street</ENAMEX> and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Bazaar</ENAMEX>, and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Port Lucaya Market</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX>. Things to keep an eye out for include <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and silver jewelry and such <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gem stones</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamonds</ENAMEX>, sapphires, and emeralds set in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Dior</ENAMEX> and other leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abaco Gold</ENAMEX> is a range of jewelry designed and sold only in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> and unusual pieces such as rare <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and silver coins brought from treasure found on the seabed, and mounted in gold to be worn as pendants or brooches. If it‚Äôs time for a new timepiece, you can choose from a comprehensive range of watches by names such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolex</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breitling</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tag Hauer</ENAMEX>. Fragrances from around the world, fine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crystal</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> leather goods are also on display in most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>.
Duty-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> will make claims that they save you <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30‚Äì40 percent</NUMEX> on prices you‚Äôd pay back home, but this is not universally true, and it‚Äôs always important to so some research on prices in your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> before you go. Some goods are only slightly cheaper than back home; doing a little homework before hand will help you sniff out the ‚Äúreal‚Äù bargains.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Rum</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bacardi</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> brands, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appletons</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>, and almost all international brands of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX> can be found at good prices. Look out for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coconut rum</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit rums¬†‚Äî¬†there‚Äôs</ENAMEX> a tremendous variety.
Where to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shop</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay Street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Bazaar</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Freeport</ENAMEX> are the major tourist shopping areas, but Out <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islanders</ENAMEX> often sell hand-crafted items, and some resorts have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Stores</ENAMEX> are generally open <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">9am‚Äì5pm</NUMEX>, and are closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX>, and possibly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Freeport</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">straw</ENAMEX> markets are open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and even sometimes after dark. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Shops</ENAMEX> will often mail your purchases home for you.
Bargaining at outdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX>, something of a tourist pastime for the straw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>, might get you a discount. But don‚Äôt bother trying in regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> where you pay the posted price. There is no sales tax in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>.
Here are some of the most dependable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Out Islands: In Hope Town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water‚Äôs Edge Studios</ENAMEX> offers wood carvings by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ Ervin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Island Gallery</ENAMEX> stocks selected handicrafts and souvenirs. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Island Made Gift Shop in Gregory Town</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eleuthera</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">335-5369</ENAMEX>) has a good supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian</ENAMEX> gifts and crafts. Reliable spots to shop for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abaco Gold</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Green Turtle Cay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marsh Harbour</ENAMEX>.
Sports
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aviation Information Centre</ENAMEX> provides complete information about sports facilities in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. Call them toll-free at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800-32</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPORT</ENAMEX> (within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> only) or at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">305-932-0051</ENAMEX>, or write for information to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19495</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Biscayne Boulevard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Suite 809</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aventura</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33180</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water Sports</ENAMEX>
Wind <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">surfing</ENAMEX>. With its many shallow lagoons, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> is a great place for wind <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">surfing</ENAMEX>. Most large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> for rent. Para-sailing (soaring overhead in a parachute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harness</ENAMEX> pulled by a speedboat) is also available in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cable Beach</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise Island</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucaya</ENAMEX>), but make sure you‚Äôre fully insured before taking to the air¬†‚Äî¬†many policies exclude this popular activity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea Sports</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau Marriott Resort</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cable Beach</ENAMEX> has a full compliment of water-sport equipment for rent (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">327-6200</ENAMEX>).
Diving and snorkeling. Opportunities for diving and snorkeling in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> are almost unrivaled in terms of both the quality of the experience and the variety of stunning habitats. The area‚Äôs clear waters and numerous coral reefs and rocky outcrops offer an ideal environment for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of species of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX>, and, yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX>. A number of dive centers offer transport to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> along with the assistance of experienced and qualified dive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau and Grand Bahama</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau Scuba Centre</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">362-1964</TIMEX>; fax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">362-1198</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">954</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">462-3400</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> fax (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">954</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">462-4100</TIMEX>; website <http://www.nassau-scuba-centre.com,)> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNEXSO</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">373-1244</TIMEX>; fax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">373-8956</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">954</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">351-9889</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> fax (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">954</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">351-9740</ENAMEX>). Both of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> also run trips to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros, Eleuthera</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exuma</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> also find diving and snorkeling opportunities on the main islands of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX>. And there are special places around the Out Islands that offer exceptional experiences, though not much lively entertainment out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Here is a list of particularly exciting sites:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thunderball</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canonball</ENAMEX> reefs. Just off the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rose Island</ENAMEX> and named for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX> films that were filmed here; the coral formations are impressive and large <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> such as grouper are numerous.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theo‚Äôs Wreck</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MV Island Cement</ENAMEX> was deliberately sunk in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> to create an artificial dive site, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> that inhabit the area don‚Äôt seem to be bothered by the man-made skeleton. Moray eels and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">angel fish</ENAMEX> now live among the coral and sponges.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX>. The barrier reef here is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> longest in the world. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60 ft</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX>) below the surface, it is for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divers</ENAMEX> only, though snorkelers can splash around in the shallow coastal areas, which are also rich in sea life. Spectacular large <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> are usually sighted here at the ‚ÄúTongue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ocean</ENAMEX>,‚Äù which in some places lies <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only 120 ft</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX>) offshore but drops an amazing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6000</TIMEX> ft (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2000 m</ENAMEX>) to the ocean trench. There are also several ‚Äúblue <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">holes‚Äù¬†‚Äî¬†vivid</ENAMEX> blue ocean holes, some with mazes of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnels</ENAMEX> and caves¬†‚Äî¬†to be explored. Small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hope Bay Lodge</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Andros</ENAMEX> offers diving vacations (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">368-2014</TIMEX>; fax <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">368-2015</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bimini</ENAMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise Point</ENAMEX> you can explore the formations that are said to be the lost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atlantis</ENAMEX>. Contact <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill and Nowddla Keefe‚Äôs Bimini Undersea</ENAMEX> for information on excursions (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">347-3089</TIMEX>; fax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">652-9148</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">305</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">653-5572</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> fax (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">305</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">652-9148</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Salvador</ENAMEX>. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">reef wall</ENAMEX> here lies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 40</NUMEX> ft (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX>) below the surface, this site is much more accessible for less experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divers</ENAMEX> than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX> reef. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> said to be a great place to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of hammerhead sharks as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX> and huge rays. Contact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riding Rock Inn</ENAMEX> for information on diving (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">331-2631</TIMEX>; fax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">331-2020</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">954</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">359-8353</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> fax (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">954</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">359-8254</ENAMEX>).
Long <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Shark Reef</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stella Maris</ENAMEX> is the most famous area in the islands for close encounters with that most feared aquatic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX>. Here you can watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúfeeding frenzy‚Äù</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">close quarters</TIMEX>. There are also pristine reef walls off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Conception Island</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rum Cay</ENAMEX>. Contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stella Maris Resort</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">338-2050</TIMEX>; fax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">338-2052</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">954</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">359-8236</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> fax (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">954</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">359-8238</ENAMEX>).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abacos</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral</ENAMEX>, west of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guana Cay</ENAMEX>, is a huge cave lit with sunlight streaming through holes in the ceiling; The large entrance makes it relatively safe for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novice divers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walkers Cay‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shark</ENAMEX>-feeding program allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divers</ENAMEX> to watch large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> fight over a frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish ‚Äúchumsickle‚Äù</ENAMEX> (buckets of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> parts frozen into a block that thaws in the warm <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, releasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> slowly to prolong the feeding). Contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walkers Cay Undersea Adventures</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">352-1252</TIMEX>; fax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">353-1339</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">954</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">462-3400</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> fax (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">954</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">462-4100</ENAMEX>).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exumas</ENAMEX>. Pick almost any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> or islet here for tremendous possibilities. Fast power <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">whisk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trips to enjoy the area. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Holes</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stocking Island</ENAMEX> attract varied fish life. Contact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exuma Fantasea</ENAMEX> for more information (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. and fax <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">336-2483</ENAMEX>).
Remember to take your dive certificate <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">along¬†‚Äî¬†you won‚</ENAMEX>Äôt be allowed to rent equipment and dive unless you can prove your competence.
If you want to learn to dive in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>, or if you want to upgrade your skills, you can contact one of the many excellent dive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> that offer training for all levels. All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> are affiliated with one of the major certifying bodies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PADI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professional Association of Diving Instructors</ENAMEX>) being the most common. The basic qualification, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open Water</ENAMEX> certificate, takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> to complete. Once you have this, you‚Äôll be allowed to dive with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> to a depth of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> ft (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX>), which opens up many dive sites in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> to you.
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> also offer an introductory session commonly known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúDiscover Scuba Programme</ENAMEX>.‚Äù This involves a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning or afternoon</TIMEX> of theory and swimming-pool work that will give you the chance to try out the basic techniques. Many large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> offer this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äútaster‚Äù</ENAMEX> to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>.
Sport fishing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> around the islands and cays teem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> also happen to be on the migration routes of many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. This all adds up to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> one of the world‚Äôs greatest territories for game fishing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonwealth</ENAMEX> currently holds world records for several species of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>. Sport <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fishing¬†‚Äî¬†that</ENAMEX> is, catching <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and returning them to the water¬†‚Äî¬†is hugely popular, and you can charter fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the half-day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full day</TIMEX>, or week on almost every one of the main islands. The local guides are especially experienced and helpful. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bimini Islands</ENAMEX> have been the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of sport fishing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>; here you‚Äôll find <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> lining the marinas waiting to be taken out into the teeming waters. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Hemingway</ENAMEX> led the way here.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonefishing</ENAMEX> is also big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> around the islands. Large, strong inedible <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> that frequent the shallows and sand flats, bonefish are said to be the most difficult species in the world to catch. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX> has long claimed to be the ‚Äúbonefishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of the world,‚Äù but other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian</ENAMEX> islands are vying for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crown</ENAMEX>. Bimini offers exciting opportunities and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exumas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Eleuthera</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Salvador</ENAMEX> are all throwing their gloves into the ring. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Acklins Island</ENAMEX> is said to be surrounded by virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">anglers¬†‚Äî¬†the fish</ENAMEX> are still unaware of the lure or the fly, though tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> are limited here.
You have to move out to the deep-water sounds, however, to get to the big fish such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marlin</ENAMEX>, sailfish, and tuna. The ‚ÄúTongue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ocean</ENAMEX>,‚Äù especially where it narrows between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Exuma Sound</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat Island</ENAMEX> are well loved by the knowledgeable.
As a general rule, the larger and more populous islands have the newer and better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> for rent. Prices vary, but a full day‚Äôs charter of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> averages <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400‚Äì$500</NUMEX>. Half-day rentals are also available. Contact one of the following for additional information: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Days Catch Charter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abaco</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">809/336-0059</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coopers Charter Service</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exuma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">809/336-2711</ENAMEX>); or Peace and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plenty Bonefish Lodge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exuma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">345-5555</TIMEX>; fax <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">345-5556</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Andros Island Bonefishing Lodge</ENAMEX> is a prime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for bonefishing expeditions (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">368-5167</TIMEX>; fax <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">368-2026</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sailing</ENAMEX>. With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of unpopulated</NUMEX> islands and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of empty beaches surrounded by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of shallow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> and sounds the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> are paradise for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>. Safe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">harbors</ENAMEX> with superb <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, cozy coves for a night alone, and the possibility of making short hops to a different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX> to experience all the different atmospheres of the various islands.
On many of the islands, renting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> is as easy as renting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">destinations¬†‚Äî¬†especially</ENAMEX> on the more populated Out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islands</ENAMEX>. Rentals can vary from small runabouts that will get you around the harbor and the coastal shallows to large sailing yachts and motor launches for inter-island expeditions. Rates vary enormously. To make more of a stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abacos</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exumas</ENAMEX>, where there are many outlaying cays, you can rent a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>-ft (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">51‚ÅÑ2-m</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> with small outboard motor for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $80</NUMEX> per day. Larger vessels come with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX>; if you sail your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>, you can take advantage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of a local guide to take you to fishing, snorkeling, or dive sites.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abacos</ENAMEX> are most popular spot for sailing, primarily because of the many sheltered harbors and the many islands and cays that you can reach without having to go outside of the reefs and into ocean waters. If you want to get out and see a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> without doing any sailing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regattas</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats crowd</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">harbors</ENAMEX> and the little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> are full of yachtsmen. Listen to the stories of heroic deeds in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> and enjoy the wonderful views of masts filling the skies.
For information about sailing rentals contact The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moorings</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">367-4000</TIMEX>; fax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">367-4004</TIMEX>; website <http://www.moorings. com>).=Smaller boats=for local=jaunts can=be rented=at Sea=Horse Boat=Rentals, Marsh=Harbour, Abacos=(Tel. 367-2513;=fax 367-2516;=website <http://www.sea-horse.com>.=Nassau Yacht=Haven also=has sailboats=for rent=(Tel. 393-8173).</txt>=<txt>Flying
For qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> offers one of the ultimate flying experiences. There are numerous small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airfields</ENAMEX> on the outlying islands, and flying between the islands is relatively safe, with short transfers. Looking down at the shallow waters and deep ocean trenches is perhaps the only way to truly appreciate the beauty of the shifting sand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and tranquil remote islands. Private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> can rent <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Bahama Aero Clubs</ENAMEX>; it‚Äôs also relatively simple to rent an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> for the short hop into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> has a number of PGA-level courses. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX> has the well tended <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lucaya Golf and Country Club</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">373-1066</ENAMEX>), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bahamas Princess Golf and Country Club</ENAMEX>, part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Complex</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Freeport</ENAMEX>, has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">352-6721</ENAMEX>) both designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Wilson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paradise Island Golf Club</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">363-3925</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cable Beach</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">327-6000</ENAMEX>). On <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abaco Island, Treasure Beach</ENAMEX> has an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">18-hole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">365-8045</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boat Tours</ENAMEX>
If you don‚Äôt sail yourself, this is a great way to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Even if you can‚Äôt get out to some of the Out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islands</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exumas</ENAMEX>, you can sail out to one of the cays near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> to get a feel for the atmosphere of the more remote parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. Top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sail Yacht Cruises</ENAMEX> takes small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Colonial Beach Dock</ENAMEX> to places like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rose Island</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">393-0820</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Majestic Tours</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince George Dock</ENAMEX>, has the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">322-2606</ENAMEX>). On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Bahama, Superior Watersports</ENAMEX> offers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> cruises (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">373-7863</ENAMEX>).
Nightlife
Your evening‚Äôs entertainment depends on the island on which you find yourself. On many of the Out Islands fun <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> around having dinner and a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> in the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, finishing a few pages of the book you brought, watching the stars, or planning the next day‚Äôs diving or sailing. On <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau and Grand Bahama</ENAMEX>, however, there‚Äôs plenty to keep you occupied until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning hours</TIMEX>. The largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort hotels</ENAMEX> on both islands have activities that continue around the clock.
Gambling
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marriott Resort</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cable Beach</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">327-6200</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atlantis</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise Island</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">363-3000</ENAMEX>), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Princess Resort</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">352-7811</ENAMEX>) all offer roulette, craps, and blackjack as well as slot machines. The slot machines operated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours a day</TIMEX>, but there are limited <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> for the gaming tables: at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atlantis</ENAMEX> they‚Äôre open <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">10am‚Äì4am</NUMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princess Casino</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marriott</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9am‚Äì3am</ENAMEX>.
Floor Shows
If gambling is not your cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>, allow yourself to be dazzled by one of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nightly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Las Vegas‚Äìstyle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> shows at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marriott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atlantis</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Princess</ENAMEX>. For information about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess cabaret</ENAMEX>, call <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">352-6721</TIMEX>; for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marriott Palace Revue</ENAMEX>, call <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">327-6200</TIMEX>, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atlantis</ENAMEX>, call <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">363-3000</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>
There‚Äôs nothing young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> like better than a sandy beach and the sea. Most big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> have clean, safe beaches where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can frolic and play. 
Older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> enjoy snorkeling or taking a ride on a glass-bottom <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>. Back on land, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> enjoy having their hair braided.
Other attractions for younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> include:
Horse-drawn surrey rides. A great way to see all the sights of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> are trained and the pace is slow.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pirates</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau Attraction</ENAMEX>. Discover the pirate lifestyle.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dig, Atlantis Paradise Beach</ENAMEX>. Explore the world of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fictitious ‚ÄúAtlanteans‚Äù</ENAMEX> and watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> and other sea <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creatures</ENAMEX> in the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">aquarium</ENAMEX> in the world.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Crystal Cay</ENAMEX>. Explore beneath the sea, without getting wet.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolphin Encounters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Lagoon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX>, or UNEXSO on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX>. Swim with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX>.



