



A Brief History
Centuries before the arrival of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>, a peaceful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Amerindian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who called themselves the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luccucairi</ENAMEX> had settled in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. Originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>, they had traveled up through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> islands, surviving by cultivating modest <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> and from what they caught from sea and shore. Nothing in the experience of these gentle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could have prepared them for the arrival of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinta</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ni√±a</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Maria</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Salvador</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 October 1492</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> believed that he had reached the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East Indies</ENAMEX> and mistakenly called these people <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>. We know them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucayans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbus</ENAMEX> claimed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> and others in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> for his royal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX>, but not finding the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and other riches he was seeking, he stayed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two weeks</TIMEX> before sailing towards <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spaniards</ENAMEX> never bothered to settle in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>, but the number of shipwrecks attest that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleons</ENAMEX> frequently passed through the archipelago en route to and from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>, and their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home ports</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eleuthera</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">explorers</ENAMEX> dug a fresh<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-water well¬†‚Äî¬†at</ENAMEX> a spot now known as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúSpanish Wells‚Äù¬†‚Äî¬†which</ENAMEX> was used to replenish the supplies of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> before they began the long journey back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> with their cargoes of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>. As for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucayans</ENAMEX>, within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> all of them, perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 30,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, were removed from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> to work¬<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">†‚Äî¬†and die¬†‚Äî¬†in Spanish</ENAMEX> gold <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> and on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> and pearl fisheries on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hispaniola</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, and elsewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>.
English sea captains also came to know the beautiful but deserted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian</ENAMEX> islands during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">England‚Äôs</ENAMEX> first formal move was on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 October 1629</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> I granted the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> and a chunk of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> south to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX>, Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Health</ENAMEX>. But nothing came of that, nor of a rival <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> move in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1633</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cardinal Richelieu</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">statesman</ENAMEX>, tried claiming the islands for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colonization</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piracy</ENAMEX>
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1648</TIMEX> a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English Puritans</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Sayle</ENAMEX>, sailed to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bahamian</ENAMEX> waters and established the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">settlement</ENAMEX> on the island they named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleutheria (now Eleuthera</ENAMEX>) after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> word for freedom. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX> called themselves the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eleutherian Adventurers</ENAMEX>, but life was very difficult and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> never flourished, though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sayle</ENAMEX> was long honored for the effort. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1666</TIMEX> a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> (called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sayle‚Äôs</ENAMEX> island) with a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX> was settled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermudians</ENAMEX> and renamed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX>. It was later to become known as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>, capital of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1670</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lords Proprietors of Carolina</ENAMEX> were granted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahama</ENAMEX> islands by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles II</ENAMEX>, but for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 50 years</TIMEX> their weak <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> either couldn‚Äôt or wouldn‚Äôt suppress the piracy raging through the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">archipelago</ENAMEX>. Then, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1684</TIMEX>, to avenge countless raids against their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> dispatched a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squadron</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>. This sent the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> fleeing to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, but didn‚Äôt have much effect on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX>.
Most feared of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> or more swashbucklers operating from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> lair was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Teach</ENAMEX>, better known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackbeard</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> you can visit a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> east of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> named after him. Another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> infamous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Bonney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary Read</ENAMEX> had exceptionally bloodthirsty reputations and are still celebrated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> raided anything on the sea, living totally lawless¬<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">†‚Äî¬†and</ENAMEX> often not very lengthy¬<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">†‚Äî¬†lives</ENAMEX>. Moreover, there was not always a clear distinction between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> and privateers, the latter officially authorized by their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to plunder enemy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">time</TIMEX> of war. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anarchy</ENAMEX> and confusion reigned throughout the area.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1718</TIMEX>, shortly after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> became a crown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Woodes Rogers</ENAMEX>, a renowned ex-privateer, was named the first royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>. Arriving in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> with a powerful force and promising amnesty for surrender, he became a legend by cleaning out many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> and establishing some order. This incident inspired the national motto <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Expulsis Piratis¬†‚Äî¬†Restituta Commercia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pirates Expelled¬†‚Äî¬†Commerce Restored</ENAMEX>), which was retained until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years later</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX> quit the islands only to return for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1729</TIMEX> after a period of bankruptcy and debtor‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. Before he died in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1732</TIMEX> he had summoned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamas‚</ENAMEX>Äô <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assembly</ENAMEX>, composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> each for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harbour Island</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eleuthera</ENAMEX>. At this time, in all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about 2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> knew some spells of prosperity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-18th century</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">privateering</ENAMEX> resumed with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> at war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> expanded, and improvements were made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1760 and 1768</TIMEX> by another revered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shirley</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Revolutionary War</ENAMEX>
When the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX>, enraged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Stamp Tax</ENAMEX>, got into the war that eventually brought independence, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> somewhat reluctantly found itself on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England‚</ENAMEX>Äôs side. But reluctance dissolved as profits from privateering once again flowed into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>. This time the plundered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, but not all the victories were won by the privateers. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 March 1776</TIMEX>, a rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squadron</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commodore Esek Hopkins</ENAMEX> arrived and occupied <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>, a bloodless undertaking that emptied the island‚Äôs forts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> supplies. A smaller and equally non-violent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1778</TIMEX> lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than three days</TIMEX>.
As the colonies‚Äô war effort picked up steam, both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> weighed in against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1782</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> surrendered to a large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> invasion <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> ruled the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>.
News traveled slowly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Treaty of Versailles</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1783</TIMEX> formally restored the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, but actual liberation came through a famous escapade that would never have happened in the age of the telegraph. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lieutenant-Colonel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Deveaux</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loyalist</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, sailed from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>, picked up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Harbour Island</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleuthera</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚Äúinvaded‚Äù Nassau</ENAMEX>. Though vastly outnumbered and outgunned, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deveaux</ENAMEX> employed elaborate ruses with his little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> to convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> was overpowering. The humiliating <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> surrender is proudly recalled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamian</ENAMEX> history, even though it was all unnecessary: the peace treaty had been signed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous week</TIMEX>.
Deveaux was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 7,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loyalists</ENAMEX> who, with slaves and the promise of land grants, came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> from the southern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">colonies</ENAMEX> in the wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> defeat in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolutionary War</ENAMEX>. This influx profoundly affected the islands. A number of prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamians</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of loyalists or their slaves. As a reward for his efforts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deveaux</ENAMEX> was given acreage on both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat Island</ENAMEX>. Other loyalists set up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX> on various islands, and slaves soon became the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emancipation</ENAMEX> and Decline
In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1780s</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well over 100</NUMEX> cotton <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX> were founded and flourished around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. Prosperity from the land finally seemed a possibility. But by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton</ENAMEX> had fallen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> to a devastating plague of chenille bugs and exhaustion of the weak soil. Most of the planters left the islands and depression returned, only partly relieved by ‚Äúwrecking,‚Äù the freelance business of salvaging cargo from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> forever running aground in the dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bahamian waters</ENAMEX>. (Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> were deliberately misguided by lights on shore; <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau harbor</ENAMEX> did not have a proper lighthouse until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1816</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nassau</ENAMEX> became a free <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX>, sparking a surge in trading activity. Loyalists built a number of the attractive colonial-style <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> still standing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, and during the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War of 1812</ENAMEX>, privateers enjoyed another profitable spell against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX>.
Slavery in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> was not as widespread or as vicious as on many <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> islands in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> were voluntarily freed or sold their liberty by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loyalist owners</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1804</TIMEX>, no slaves were imported into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1822</TIMEX>, the first registration counted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,808</NUMEX> slaves on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> inhabited islands or island clusters. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> abolished slavery in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1833</TIMEX>, there was a transitional <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">apprenticeship period of 5 years</TIMEX> before all slaves in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> became fully free on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 August 1838</TIMEX>. This included <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few thousand slaves</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> captured by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Navy</ENAMEX>. They were housed in specially founded settlements on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> and the Out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islands</ENAMEX>.
Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Blockade Running</ENAMEX>
Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the centuries</TIMEX>, trouble on the nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> continent has often meant good news for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> ordered a blockade of the southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1861</TIMEX> after the outbreak of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> quickly boomed. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nassau</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX> was busy with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> unloading <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Confederate cotton</ENAMEX> and tobacco and taking aboard <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, and manufactured goods, mainly from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, to be run back through the northern blockade. As the war went on, speedy and camouflaged contraband <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX> were built to slip past the ever-increasing Federal patrols. Profits from blockade running were incredible, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> went wild. But the extravagant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and carefree spending stopped abruptly with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">North‚Äôs</ENAMEX> victory in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865</TIMEX>. Late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following year</TIMEX> an immense hurricane sent a tidal wave over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hog Island</ENAMEX> (today <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise Island</ENAMEX>), smashing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nassau‚</ENAMEX>Äôs flimsy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and ruining <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX>. Other islands were also devastated. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> sank back into economic doldrums, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> turned to agriculture, fishing, or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt raking</ENAMEX>. The spread of lighthouses and decent navigational charts had crippled the old standby, the wrecking trade.
For a time a new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX> called sisal seemed promising. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamian</ENAMEX> soil was too poor and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> grew a better <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neville Chamberlain</ENAMEX>, future <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>, took over his family‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisal operation</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1890s</TIMEX>. It failed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX> said, because of that island‚Äôs evil elves called chickcharnies, who cast a spell on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> for disturbing the land. Hopes were raised, and also fizzled, over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamian</ENAMEX> citrus and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pineapple</ENAMEX>. Sponging, another vitally important industry at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 19th century</TIMEX>, also had setbacks. A hurricane in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1839</TIMEX> drowned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 300</NUMEX> sponge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX> in the ‚Äòmud‚Äô off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andros</ENAMEX>, and a devastating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fungus</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some 40 years later</TIMEX> killed almost all the sponges.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">20th Century</ENAMEX>
Desperate for work, perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bahamian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> left to take construction jobs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the turn of the century</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I. During</ENAMEX> that war <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamians</ENAMEX> saw active service with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. The islands suffered food shortages and a serious bank failure, but nothing more threatening militarily than rumors of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> submarines offshore.
Prohibition brought gloom to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, but for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> it brought the biggest bonanza in history. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 1919</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Volstead Act</ENAMEX> outlawing the manufacture, sale, or transport of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intoxicating beverages</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian</ENAMEX> islands (where the temperance crusade never had much chance) were perfectly placed to help thirsty <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 years</TIMEX>, until the controversial law was finally repealed, bootlegging changed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West End</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bimini</ENAMEX> beyond recognition. With just as much gusto as they‚Äôd shown in the past for wrecking, privateering, and blockade running, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bahamians</ENAMEX> took to the seas with illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX>. Trying to outwit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Coast Guard</ENAMEX> was risky but enormously profitable. Fortunes were made by respected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> turned liquor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum</ENAMEX>-running <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat captains</ENAMEX>, notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>, shady <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> government (which collected duty on temporarily imported <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX>).
Liquor money bought <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> better <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, lighting, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sewers</ENAMEX>, docks, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>. The city‚Äôs first gambling casino opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1920</TIMEX>; the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> air service from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>; the yacht set decided <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> was fashionable, and many wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX> built <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> on the islands.
When the boom suddenly came to an end with the worldwide depression and the repeal of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>, unemployment rose again, despite the first significant tourism the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> had known.
In some respects, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> put the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> on the international map. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> was chosen to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the sites <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> leased to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin D. Roosevelt‚Äôs ‚Äúdestroyers</ENAMEX> for bases‚Äù deal in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> operated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">submarine</ENAMEX>-hunting and air-sea rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> on the islands; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">frogmen</ENAMEX> were trained here, and much <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">trans-Atlantic</ENAMEX> air traffic passed through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>.
Then, to the astonishment of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windsor</ENAMEX>, having given up his throne for an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> divorc√©e, was named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of the little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>. He and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duchess</ENAMEX> remained until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> intervened in the investigation of the murder of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">multimillionaire</ENAMEX> Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Oakes</ENAMEX>, a longtime benefactor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> who gave his name to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nassau‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airfield</ENAMEX>. The sensational case, never solved, made world headlines for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> and is still discussed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
After the construction of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> wartime <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> air <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> was completed, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bahamians</ENAMEX> left to work on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, a migration that continued well into the postwar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>. But employment opportunities began to grow at home. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1950</TIMEX>, a promotion campaign under Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stafford Sands</ENAMEX> was hugely successful in attracting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. Denied the sun, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX>, and sin of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro‚</ENAMEX>Äôs takeover in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vacationers</ENAMEX> set their sights on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. The influx was spurred by gambling, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> and harbor improvement on the major islands, and the creation of the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Freeport</ENAMEX> (which had been set in motion by the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hawksbill Creek Agreement of 1955</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resort hotels</ENAMEX> began to appear and the advent of air-conditioning improved the often stifling humidity of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>.
Under a new constitution in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> was given self-government with a ministerial-parliamentary system. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> elections, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive Liberal Party</ENAMEX> was victorious, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynden O. Pindling</ENAMEX> becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premier</ENAMEX>. Following a constitutional conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> became fully independent on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10, 1973</TIMEX>, and is now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Commonwealth</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1992</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive Liberal Party</ENAMEX>, still headed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynden O. Pindling</ENAMEX>, was toppled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free National Movement</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> in power. Today‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubert Ingraham</ENAMEX>.
Since independence the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> has kept <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX> and government yet has moved closer economically to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">near neighbor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian Government</ENAMEX> has deliberately pursued tourism as the major industry of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bahamian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">commonwealth</ENAMEX> and is happy to welcome many <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to its shores. The growth in cruise traffic has been particularly strong. The other islands, called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Family Islands</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> but generally referred to as the Out Islands by the tourist trade, have not shared this huge growth in numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. Together they offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> almost any form of vacation experience, from the bustle of the busy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to the silence of the desert <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian Government</ENAMEX> began working on ways to expand the country‚Äôs economic base. While tourism remains a top priority¬†‚Äî¬†the opening of the vast <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atlantis</ENAMEX> resort on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise Island</ENAMEX> leaves little doubt about that¬<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">†‚Äî¬†a</ENAMEX> number of measures have also been taken to make the country‚Äôs laws and tax codes more attractive to offshore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. As a result, money has been making its way into financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> from around the world, and a large number of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> have opened brand-new air-conditioned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> surrounded by carefully manicured gardens.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the major questions still facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> is how to accommodate the increasing numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> while still preserving the special architectural and social heritage of the Out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islands</ENAMEX>, as well as of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>. Will it be possible to enjoy the natural splendors of places like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inagua</ENAMEX> without upsetting the delicate balance of nature? At the moment, the thinking is that it‚Äôs perhaps best to leave these smaller, less developed islands in peace.



