



Where to Go
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX>
It‚Äôs not the largest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> islands and not the most stunningly beautiful, yet when most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> they first think of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> or its major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only 80 square miles</NUMEX> in size yet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180,000</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">280,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bahamians</ENAMEX> lives here. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> and international <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> are the hub for every activity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. Government, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, taxes, and furniture shipments for new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> all start from here and radiate out to the other islands. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> also attracts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 3 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> is one of the main cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is a magnet for fun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX> and serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX>, and it serves both very well.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nassau</ENAMEX>
Nassau <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> has a fine pedigree dating back through colonial times, and the compact town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> still has the feel of life under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. Out in the natural harbor, which offered shelter to many a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pirate ship</ENAMEX>, is a major port that can accommodate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> large cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time. This capacity was created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX> when public money was invested to dredge the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX>, specifically to allow bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> to enter. The huge vessels, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of feet</NUMEX> high, dwarf the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towns buildings</ENAMEX>, which regulations set at a maximum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> stories, and create one of the most effective juxtapositions of modernity and history found anywhere in the world. The cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince George Wharf</ENAMEX> brings in by far the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>.
Immediately in front of the cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">port you‚</ENAMEX>Äôll find a line of horse-drawn surreys waiting to offer you a genteel tour along the historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> wait under the cooling shade for their next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. (In the hot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer months</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> are not allowed to work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">from 2‚Äì4pm</TIMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> trot slowly past all the sights in town, but you can also easily stroll around yourself and see everything in a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hours¬†‚Äî¬†if you‚</ENAMEX>Äôre not seduced by the many shopping opportunities between the docks and the historic old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.
The first sight that will attract your attention is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Straw Market</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Market Plaza</ENAMEX>, which backs onto <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodes Rodgers</ENAMEX> Walk. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> this has been the showcase for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian</ENAMEX> handicrafts. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Straw goods</ENAMEX>, including baskets and mats, are favorite souvenirs; each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> produces <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">straw goods</ENAMEX> in its own style and patterns. Bestsellers are hats, dolls, bags, and baskets. There is some exquisite work to be found, but be aware that with a decline in basket-making throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>, an increasing number of articles are imported from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far East</ENAMEX>; most of these are at the cheaper end of the scale. The ubiquitous modern souvenir, the T-shirt, is also available, with an almost limitless number of pictures, patterns, and slogans. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> who run the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX> are easy-going and seem to have limitless enthusiasm for the next sale. You‚Äôll hear numerous calls of ‚ÄúHey, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, come look for something nice here.‚Äù
The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">straw</ENAMEX> market fronts onto <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bay Street</ENAMEX>, one of the leading duty-free shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX> of the world. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only a few years ago</TIMEX> this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> was the domain of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay Street Boys</ENAMEX>, a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who controlled all economic activity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>; now <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bay Street</ENAMEX> seduces <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> with huge sparkling gems, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of ounces</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, and the smell of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> fragrances. The fa√ßades of the pretty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> hide modern air-conditioned shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> piled high with luxury goods.
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, especially those with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a few hours</TIMEX> to spare, go no farther than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nassau¬†‚Äî¬†shopping</ENAMEX> for a bargain can be exhausting. It would be a shame, however, not to explore what the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> has to offer, as there are a number of historic gems to be discovered in and around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bahamian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> appreciate and enjoy the many touches of colonial history retained from its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> as part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Empire</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rawson Square</ENAMEX>, just in front of the entrance to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince George Wharf</ENAMEX>, is a good place to start your tour. The tourist information <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> here can arm you with leaflets and maps that will help you make the most of your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>. Directly opposite <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rawson Square</ENAMEX>, across <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bay Street</ENAMEX>, are the Public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Buildings</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament Square</ENAMEX>, which have been in continuous use since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1812</TIMEX>. They were modeled on the governmental <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Bern</ENAMEX>, capital of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two centuries ago</TIMEX>. A marble statue of a young, seated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX> in front recalls the era of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> rule. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX> of the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Assembly</ENAMEX> meet in the so-called western <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> (on the right side if you‚Äôre facing from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>); the public-records <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications department</ENAMEX> are housed in the other historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. Behind them in modern edifices are the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Law Courts</ENAMEX>. Here you may find yourself in the middle of a parade to open <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> or convene the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. The smart uniforms and pomp are taken directly from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> ceremonial activities, but the ambiance is truly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian</ENAMEX>. Check with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Board</ENAMEX> for dates of ceremonial occasions, all of which happen frequently.
Behind the modern law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> complex is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nassau Public Library</ENAMEX>, interesting because it used to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">island‚Äôs jail</ENAMEX>. The octagonal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shirley Street</ENAMEX> dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1797</TIMEX> and has a pretty exterior, but the interior is more fascinating. The old cells were retained when the structure became the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1873</TIMEX> and books line every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX>, replacing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> and creating private reading areas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library museum</ENAMEX> also has a collection of old maps and charts used to navigate the waters around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>.
If you‚<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Äôre</ENAMEX> walking, continue east along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shirley Street</ENAMEX> until you reach <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elizabeth Avenue</ENAMEX>, and turn right. The land rises suddenly here. This area, behind the downtown area, had been used to great strategic effect by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Fincastle</ENAMEX> was built atop the rise in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1793</TIMEX> to watch the shipping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> and protect <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau harbor</ENAMEX>. The tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">fort</ENAMEX> is shaped like the prow of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>, though there is hardly enough room to fit a football <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, never mind a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of the queen‚Äôs soldiery. To reach the fort you must climb the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen‚Äôs Staircase</ENAMEX>, an artificial narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gorge</ENAMEX> leading to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX> steps that climb a hillside. Both the gorge and the staircase, created to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> to reach or leave the fort quickly, were hewn from the solid limestone by a contingent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave workers</ENAMEX>. At the top of the staircase and next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">fort</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water Tower</ENAMEX> offers a bird‚Äôs-eye view over <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise Island</ENAMEX>, and most of the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX>. A small elevator in the concrete structure will carry you 125 ft (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX>) to the top. Don‚Äôt forget your camera.
After a visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>, return to the compact town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. Stroll along any <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and you‚Äôll bump into fine historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several date</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1700s</TIMEX> and most are painted in pretty pastels that cheerfully reflect the bright Bahamian sunlight. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pink-and-white Balcony House</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Market Street</ENAMEX> is a particularly fine example. The oldest wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">island¬†‚Äî¬†it</ENAMEX> was built by shipwrights around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1790</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> soft <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cedar¬†‚Äî¬†it</ENAMEX> has been restored and is now a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> that offers a delightful view of life in well-to-do <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX>. Once a private home visited by the likes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windsor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston Churchill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Graycliff Mansion on West Hill Street</ENAMEX> is now a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> with a well regarded menu and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> list. Many of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> Colonial features have been retained, and a collection of photographs provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> with a glimpse into the building‚Äôs genteel past.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vendue House</ENAMEX>, at the western end of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bay Street</ENAMEX>, at the corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Street</ENAMEX>, was once the site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> auction. It now houses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pompey Museum of Slavery</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Emancipation</ENAMEX>. The pale pink stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is unassuming, but the interior tells of the plight of slaves on the islands and of the positive work that was undertaken in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> following emancipation.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pirates of Nassau</ENAMEX> attraction at the corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Marlborough Streets</ENAMEX> brings to life the dramatic and exciting world of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> itself dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX>; the attraction inside recreates the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> quayside of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX>. A three-quarter-size <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">corvette ship</ENAMEX> and quayside <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> have been stunningly brought to life. As you walk along the ‚Äúdock,‚Äù costumed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> act out the roles of shipmate and pirate and regale you with tales of their everyday lives and deeds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> then step inside the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX>-ft- (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">23-m-</NUMEX>) long vessel to examine the paraphernalia of the pirate‚Äôs trade that line the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corridors</ENAMEX> and decks. Treasure chests mix with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum casks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> tell of their lives at sea in the lonely and dangerous times. Listen to the groaning of injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> the rudimentary and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">unsanitary</ENAMEX> surgical techniques that led to so many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deaths¬†‚Äî¬†the ship‚</ENAMEX>Äôs carpenter doubled as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX>. Read about the crew‚Äôs diet of ‚Äúsalmagundi,‚Äù a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stew</ENAMEX> of pickled herrings, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> mixed with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and vinegar, which served to both preserve the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> and disguise the taste. Battle scenes are vividly recreated, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> find out the truth about what finally became of some of the most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX>.
The next <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> to the west is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Hill Road</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 1,640</NUMEX> ft (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500 m</ENAMEX>) south of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shirley Street</ENAMEX>, opposite <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Graycliff Mansion</ENAMEX>, stands <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government House</ENAMEX>, the official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor-General</ENAMEX>, painted in the same shade of pink as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament Square</ENAMEX>. At the north gate is a statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christopher Columbus</ENAMEX> in a rather dashing pose reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Errol Flynn</ENAMEX> in one of his swashbuckling films. Once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> there is a solemn Changing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guard</ENAMEX> parade, similar to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buckingham Palace</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, performed to the accompaniment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Police Band</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last Friday</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January to June</TIMEX> all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> are invited to attend a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> party on the grounds.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paradise Island</ENAMEX>
Across <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau Harbour</ENAMEX> north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise Island</ENAMEX>, known until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hog Island</ENAMEX>. For many centuries the island simply acted as a protective barrier against bad weather and attack from invaders. Its recent history is fascinating: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> it was owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Axel Wenner-Gren</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> manufacturer who was found to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> sympathizer. He sold the island to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntingdon Hartford</ENAMEX>, who changed the name from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hog</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> and created a beautiful private retreat, now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean Club Hotel</ENAMEX>. Later gangster <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Per Lansky</ENAMEX> began the process that transformed the island from a private <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX> with magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. The wonderful beaches, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cabbage Beach</ENAMEX> on the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">coast</ENAMEX>, were the focus of the development. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> began to appear in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> when gambling was a lure to the rich and famous. As <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise Island</ENAMEX> saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merv Griffin</ENAMEX> come and go, it went through a continuing series of developments and re-developments.
Today <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise Island</ENAMEX> may be close to fulfilling the dream of the perfect vacation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX>. It has many of the essential ingredients needed: fine white-sand beaches, a protected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">marina</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX>, a group of fine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, and perhaps the biggest adult playground this side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brainchild</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sol Group</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atlantis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise Island</ENAMEX> is a new concept in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">resorts¬†‚Äî¬†it‚Äôs</ENAMEX> a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> with an amazing theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and entertainment village all on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> site. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> takes its name, and inspiration, from the lost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atlantis</ENAMEX>, said by some to lie off the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bimini</ENAMEX>. This theme runs throughout the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX>. The vast open foyers and public areas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> have high columns of cathedral-like dimensions; the walkways and outside terraces recall <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mayan</ENAMEX> temples, with large <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> covering the fa√ßade. Waterfalls literally or figuratively cascade to give a feeling of a city just having risen from the ocean. Man-made sheltered lagoons provide for safe swimming, snorkeling, and sunbathing.
The masterpiece of the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atlantis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> is the enormous <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Aquarium</ENAMEX>,¬†which can be viewed from almost any point in the resort¬†‚Äî¬†from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> above in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>, from ground level, and from below ground. Within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aquarium</ENAMEX> is an area called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dig</ENAMEX>, a spectacular underwater environment complete with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sunken ‚Äútreasures</ENAMEX>,‚Äù vast stone columns, fallen temples, and godlike figures, all intended to show what <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atlantis</ENAMEX> might look like while being excavated. The entire attraction has then been filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">sea</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and a complete ecosystem of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and crustaceans, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> in all. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Sharks</ENAMEX> and rays patrol the waterways, eels and lobsters lurk in the crevices and fissures. A truly awe-inspiring sight.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> boasts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>, and a vast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> area. Outside, water slides, nature <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX>, and swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> indicate that no expense has been spared to create the ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX> for all age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> drop in just to marvel at the artistry and technical skill that was employed to create this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. Non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> must pay a fee to enjoy the resort <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and an extra fee for a visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dig</ENAMEX>.
At the eastern end of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise Island</ENAMEX> stands a much older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> that offers the opportunity for restful contemplation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cloisters</ENAMEX> are the remains of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> that was bought in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntingdon Hartford</ENAMEX>, taken apart, and rebuilt in the grounds of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean Club</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hartford</ENAMEX> set the small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> on a rise <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several hundred yards</NUMEX> away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and created an elaborate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garden</ENAMEX> to lead to the edifice. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Versailles Gardens</ENAMEX>, based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis XIV‚</ENAMEX>Äôs formal palace gardens outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, have terraces, fountains, and statues that provide a soothing vista, leading the eye from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to the cloisters. It is possible to visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cloisters</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daylight hours¬</TIMEX>†‚Äî¬†they stand next to the only <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> that traverses the island¬†‚Äî¬†but they are used regularly for wedding ceremonies, so you might find them closed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise Island</ENAMEX> is connected to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> that rise high into the air to allow boat traffic to pass beneath. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">bridge</ENAMEX> carries traffic on to the island, the other takes traffic back to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> (there is a small toll for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>). At the foot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> is a small quay where you can catch a ferry to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodes Rogers</ENAMEX> Walk in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX>. This is also the docking point for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Lagoon</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dolphin Experience</ENAMEX>. A small cay just a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20-minute</TIMEX> boat ride from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Lagoon</ENAMEX> is the site of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> where you can swim with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX> or help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> look after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> for a day. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Boats</ENAMEX> leave several times a day.
No public buses¬<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">†‚Äî¬†jitneys¬†‚Äî¬†are</ENAMEX> allowed over the toll <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise Island</ENAMEX>. You‚Äôll need to take a taxi to and from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> if you don‚Äôt use the ferry. Once on the island, however, you can use the public bus service, which runs the length of the island, linking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> with the quayside and the small shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>.
Underneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> in the harbor is a small island called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Potter‚Äôs Cay</ENAMEX>. This is where fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> and mail <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">boats dock</ENAMEX> and where real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bahamian</ENAMEX> life happens. Stalls sell fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">conch salad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sit and wait for the night‚Äôs sailing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor master‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> here can help you with mail-boat schedules and prices.
Beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>
There are a number of interesting attractions outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> that make it worthwhile to rent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or hire a taxi for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>.
West of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> west out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> and within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of minutes</TIMEX> you‚Äôll encounter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> very different attractions. There‚Äôs no missing the austere gray ramparts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Charlotte</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> the western approaches to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau Harbour</ENAMEX>. Built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunmore</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1787‚Äì89</NUMEX>, during the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Napoleonic Wars</ENAMEX>, and named after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George III</ENAMEX>, this is the largest fort in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. But not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> shot was ever fired from here in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">anger¬†‚Äî¬†the</ENAMEX> only volleys ever launched were part of ceremonial salutes. Life must have been pretty boring for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> as many had the time to carve their names in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> along the battlements. Guides <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escort visitors</ENAMEX> around the interior of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">fort</ENAMEX> as well as through the dungeons, which, thankfully, saw little torture. In fact <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Charlotte</ENAMEX> is well regarded by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX> during hurricanes.
Nearby is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ardastra Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoo</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservation Centre</ENAMEX>, a landscaped <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> famed for its pink flamingos, which are paraded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times a day into a small enclosure to offer visitors a closer look. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>, once common in certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian</ENAMEX> islands, are now disappearing, though the reasons for the decline are disputed. Another endangered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bahamian Parrot</ENAMEX>, is under threat from loss of habitat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gardens</ENAMEX> is one of only a small number of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> that has developed a breeding program for this vocal and gregarious <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> in the hope of replenishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> in the wild. There are many more species of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> mammals, reptiles, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> to find as you explore the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">51‚ÅÑ2 acres</NUMEX> of tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">parkland</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> back to the main coast road and you will find <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> small cays lying immediately offshore. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arawak Cay</ENAMEX>, home to the local fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX>. A number of colorful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shacks</ENAMEX> line the approach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> where you can buy conch and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fried fish</ENAMEX>, always fresh and always delicious. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weekends</ENAMEX> can be busy with local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. Travel through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arawak Cay</ENAMEX> to reach <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Silver Cay</ENAMEX>, where there is a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> with a pretty beach. Here you will find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal Cay</ENAMEX>, site of a marine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> where you can take a close look at the undersea world without getting wet. A man-made coral reef has been created on the sea bottom and you can watch all the marine activity from an underwater <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">observatory</ENAMEX>. The reef attracts many kinds of aquatic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> that are free to come and go as they please. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">observatory</ENAMEX> looks decidedly futuristic and can be seen quite clearly from the road as you travel along the coast. Other activities at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal Cay</ENAMEX> include a sea <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> environment, a touch pool where you can stroke a sting ray or pet a conch, and a snorkel trail, if you want to get into the water yourself.
A little further west along the coast you will find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cable Beach</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of tourism on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX>. Several luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> line the shore, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only 5 minutes</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> from central <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nassau Marriott Resort Hotel</ENAMEX> attracts many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> with its casino, stage shows, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cable Beach ‚Äústrip‚Äù</ENAMEX> is under continual development, and a number of private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> have opened recently to provide alternatives for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> staying at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East of Nassau</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">territory east</ENAMEX> and southeast of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> has seen a great deal of development in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>; many of the major residential areas that have sprung up hold little interest for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. One legacy of the past is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Blackbeard‚Äôs Tower</ENAMEX>, said to have been a lookout post for the famous pirate. It is a little careworn and forlorn <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and may be worth visiting only for its view of the harbor. Guarding the eastern entrance to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau harbor</ENAMEX> is tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Montague</ENAMEX>, least visited of the old colonial fortifications. It now looks out towards the pleasure <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise Island</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Bahama Island</ENAMEX> was largely ignored through colonial history and was for a long time a comparative backwater. That it is now the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> most popular tourist destination in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> is all due to the forethought of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> man¬†‚Äî¬†and a great deal of investment made since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> had little interest in developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> lies only <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">55 miles</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> coast, and in the post‚<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">ÄìWorld War II</ENAMEX> period it finally attracted the attention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX>. As the economy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> grew and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian‚</ENAMEX>ÄìUS trade increased, a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace Groves</ENAMEX>, saw the potential in the development of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> signed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hawksbill Agreement</ENAMEX>, which gave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Groves</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50,000 acres</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20,000 hectares</NUMEX>) of land and a concession to import duty-free goods. In return <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groves</ENAMEX> agreed to build a deep-water harbor and to encourage business development. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> there was boom, then there was bust, but a container <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> is breathing new life into the flagging commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX>. The opening of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> casino in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX> sparked the tourist boom and, since then, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX> has been busy developing as a tourist ‚Äúmecca.‚Äù Its modernity and the close links with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> create a totally different atmosphere and style compared to what you‚Äôll find in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX>, and many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> enjoy the more ‚ÄúAmerican‚Äù feel.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Freeport</ENAMEX>-Lucaya
The main settlement on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Freeport</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucaya</ENAMEX> is in fact two separate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> that have now grown together. In theory <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Freeport</ENAMEX> was the commercial center and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucaya</ENAMEX> the coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">resort</ENAMEX>. In reality the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> now mix so successfully it is difficult to tell where the dividing line is. Most of the island‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live here and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> continue to develop. There are no historical attractions here but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeport-Lucaya</ENAMEX> is happy to offer the alternative of unashamed hedonistic pleasure and relaxation.
Not surprisingly for a duty-free island, shopping plays a large part in a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Bazaar</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Freeport</ENAMEX> takes you on a shopping trip around the world. Enter the bazaar through the red <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> Torii or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúwelcome gate‚Äù</ENAMEX> and you can visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, all within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX>. Unusual offerings such as rare stamps can be found among the standard duty-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> that carry the most exclusive names in watches, jewelry, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">perfume</ENAMEX>. Behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South American</ENAMEX> area you‚Äôll find the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Perfume Factory</ENAMEX>, where you can create your own personal fragrance. Mix essential <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oils</ENAMEX> to balance with your skin and give a name to your exclusive product. You can even record the recipe on computer so that you can re-order the exact fragrance at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later date</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúfactory‚Äù</ENAMEX> is set in a pretty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion replica</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five-minute</TIMEX> tours take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> into the small commercial production <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, where some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Factory‚</ENAMEX>Äôs own signature perfumes are made.
Make your way past the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Continental Pavilion</ENAMEX> at the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Bazaar</ENAMEX> to reach <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goombay Market</ENAMEX>. Here you‚Äôll find an amazing range of straw work, wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carvings</ENAMEX>, and other handicrafts. There are over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX>, so it‚Äôs a great place to barter for a bargain.
Next door to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Bazaar</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Princess Casino</ENAMEX> with its distinctive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Moorish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">domes</ENAMEX>. You‚Äôll be able to play alongside the ‚Äúhigh rollers‚Äù at the roulette or craps tables or put a few coins in the slot machines. There is also a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> that hosts nightly dance show performances. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> is part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bahamas Princess Resort</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casino</ENAMEX>, where you‚Äôll also find a country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> excellent 18-hole golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucaya</ENAMEX> is set on a fine sandy beach and the expansive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Lucaya marina</ENAMEX> gives the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> a very nautical feel. A number of large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> line the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lucayan Beach</ENAMEX>, their massive fa√ßades softened by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of masts of the yachts moored on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">inlet</ENAMEX>. As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1999</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> and many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> were being given a facelift and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> on the waterfront were being reconfigured into a single <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Port Lucaya</ENAMEX> Marketplace is the center of all activity for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> the duty-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>-style shopping village tempt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> with jewelry, clothing, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">perfume</ENAMEX>; colorful wooden huts <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house craft stalls</ENAMEX> selling straw work and carvings. As the sun sinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> gather at the marketplace after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> on the beach or sailing offshore. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> come alive as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> fill up and bands play live music at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Count Basie Bandstand</ENAMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">square adjoining</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">marina</ENAMEX>.
On the south side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">marina</ENAMEX>, accessible from the main beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Underwater Explorers Society</ENAMEX> or UNEXSO. The oldest diving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNEXSO</ENAMEX> provides diving experience sessions and training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>. The large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square building</ENAMEX> contains a diving pool and decompression <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>; those with no interest in actually practicing the sport can visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, which charts the development of diving to the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCUBA</ENAMEX> (self-contained underwater breathing apparatus) method developed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Cousteau</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>. There is also a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> on site, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brass Helmet</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">short boatride</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Lucaya</ENAMEX> takes you to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sanctuary Bay</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">UNEXSO Dolphin Experience</ENAMEX>. A family of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bottlenose dolphins</ENAMEX> have set up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> here. You can linger by the side of the bay and hope they come to you, get in the water and swim with them, or spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> as an assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX> and help the staff care for these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gentle creatures</ENAMEX>.
Just north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Marina</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lucayan Golf and Country Club</ENAMEX>, which has some of the best-groomed <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> and a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> for those who want to watch rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">play¬†‚Äî¬†diners</ENAMEX> enjoy panoramic views over the driving range and several holes.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeport-Lucaya</ENAMEX> may be a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of concrete and tarmac, but within the city limits are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> natural areas that could be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a million miles</NUMEX> away from the bustle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rand Memorial Nature Centre</ENAMEX>, on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 acres</NUMEX> of land on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Settlers</ENAMEX> Way to the east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Freeport</ENAMEX>, is used as a resource for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> on the island, but there‚Äôs nothing dry and academic about it. Here you can learn about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plants native</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> and find out which ones were used for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bush medicine</ENAMEX> and for what purpose. A flock of flamingos and numerous other native <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird species</ENAMEX> make their home here.
To the east of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lucaya on Midshipman Road is Parrot Jungle‚Äôs Garden of the Groves</ENAMEX>. This beautiful garden was created in tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace Groves</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11 acres</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">41‚ÅÑ2 hectares</NUMEX>) contain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 10,000</NUMEX> different plant species. The landscaping is delightful, with ponds, waterfalls, and shady places to sit and enjoy the view. A pretty chapel atop a small hill offers a fine vantage point over the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in all of us the small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">petting zoo</ENAMEX> is great fun.
Beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Freeport</ENAMEX>-Lucaya
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX> is relatively easy to explore by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> running east to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">McLean‚Äôs Town</ENAMEX> and another north to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West End</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Grand Bahama</ENAMEX>
As you head east out of town <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">you‚Äôll</ENAMEX> soon leave the trappings of modernity behind and find yourself on a good <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> through acres of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian</ENAMEX> forest. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> crosses a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canals</ENAMEX>, and just off the south coast is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Petersons Cay</ENAMEX>, a tiny but beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coral cay</ENAMEX> with a beach¬†‚Äî¬†a great spot for a day of swimming, snorkeling, sunbathing, and picnicking.
After traveling approximately <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 miles</NUMEX> on the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> you‚Äôll come to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lucaya National Park</ENAMEX> (there‚Äôs a small parking lot on your left). The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40-acre</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16-hectare</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> sits on both sides of the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> and protects a range of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian</ENAMEX> ecosystems. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inland</ENAMEX>, trails lead to one of the largest surveyed cave systems in the world, much of which lies underwater. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ben‚Äôs Cave</ENAMEX>, also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bats Cave</ENAMEX> for reasons that will be obvious when you enter, is the most accessible and in fact rather small. It links to the larger caves through subterranean <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnels</ENAMEX>. The pool in the bottom has layers of fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> lying on top of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt water</ENAMEX>. Remains of several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucayan Indians</ENAMEX> that were found at the cave entrance are now being studied in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>. The caves are also home to a rare <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> of crustacean, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spelonectes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucayensis</ENAMEX>, which is said to resemble a swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centipede</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben‚Äôs Cave</ENAMEX> is closed during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June and July</TIMEX> to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bats</ENAMEX> during the breeding season.
From the right-hand side of the road, well-marked trails lead through the vegetation and out toward the coast, just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few hundred meters</NUMEX> away (a line of casuarina <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> marks the spot). Wooden walkways lead you farther out over a tidal mangrove swamp to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gold Rock Beach</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most beautiful beaches on the island, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gold Rock</ENAMEX> must really be seen at low tide to appreciate its full glory. At high tide a shallow layer of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only a couple of inches</NUMEX> deep, covers much of the beach, leaving only a narrow arc of sand above the waterline. This whole area can also be explored by bicycle or kayak or by taking an eco-tour. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that offers both eco- and cultural tours of the area is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East End Adventures</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">373-6662</TIMEX>; e-mail <safari@batalnet.bs>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Grand Bahama</ENAMEX>
Heading west from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Freeport</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lucaya</ENAMEX>, you‚Äôll first travel past the cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> and container <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX>. Across from the entrance to the cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pier One Restaurant</ENAMEX>, where you can enjoy wonderful food and feed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> that gather underneath the terraces in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>. Farther west, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Deadman‚Äôs Reef</ENAMEX>, are the remains of an ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lucayan</ENAMEX> settlement discovered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.
The last settlement on the journey is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West End</ENAMEX>, the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> home to conch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Bahamians</ENAMEX> like to gather here on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>; there‚Äôs always a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúfish fry‚Äù</ENAMEX> (kind of like a large communal barbecue) and plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kalik</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> for sale. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rest of the week</TIMEX>, the village takes on a sleepy air. There‚Äôs little evidence left of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the bad old days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runners</ENAMEX> here made fortunes smuggling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
The Out Islands
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> has traditionally been divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX>, and all the rest of the islands, brought together under the collective name of the Out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islands</ENAMEX>, sometimes also referred to as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Family Islands</ENAMEX>. Most of the Out Islands are sparsely populated, and the traditional ways of island life are much more prevalent than they are on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main islands. The rhythm of life is slower, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> are smaller, and time seems to stand still. What activity there is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> that continually move quietly in and out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">harbors</ENAMEX>.
The Abacos
A vaguely boomerang-shaped cluster of islands east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Bahama</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abacos</ENAMEX> offer perfect waters to explore by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>. Stretching for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">some 130 miles</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abaco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> consists of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúmainland‚Äù Little Abaco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Abaco</ENAMEX> and an attendant string of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of cays and islets. They are a sailor‚Äôs paradise because the numerous safe anchorages and bays have been enhanced in modern times by comprehensive back-up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abacos</ENAMEX> were settled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English Loyalists</ENAMEX> during and after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Revolution</ENAMEX>, who brought with them the distinctive architectural and decorative style of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>. These new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> made a living from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX> production and collecting sponges, but after several disastrous harvests and a fierce hurricane, a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abaconians</ENAMEX> left to create a sister community on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Key West</ENAMEX> off the southern tip of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abacos</ENAMEX> remained staunchly pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> even into modern times, and of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamians</ENAMEX> they were the ones who expressed the most apprehension about the bid for independence in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marsh Harbour</ENAMEX>, in the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Abaco Island</ENAMEX>, is the proverbial heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abacos</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> has a large harbor and has grown into a major sailing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. It is now the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">settlement</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau and Freeport-Lucaya</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Ships chandlers</ENAMEX> and hardware <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> provide everything needed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>, and liquor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarkets</ENAMEX> have everything for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>. A number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> in and around the wide marina and bay provide opportunities for intimate dining experiences or rowdier live-music sing-alongs.
Although it is difficult to get to all the outlying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cays</ENAMEX> without a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX> for information about rentals), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marsh Harbour</ENAMEX> makes a good base for trips to the central section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abacos</ENAMEX> cays. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of reliable ferry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> runs to all the major cays, most of them no more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> offshore.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Elbow Cay</ENAMEX>, southeast of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marsh Harbour</ENAMEX>, is the most popular, and its capital, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hope Town</ENAMEX>, is one of the most charming spots in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. Yachts at anchor clutter the nearly circular harbor beneath a candy-striped lighthouse few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> can resist. Rising <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">120 ft</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX>) above sea level, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hope Town Lighthouse</ENAMEX> can be seen from a distance of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">17 miles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">27 km</NUMEX>). When it was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1864</TIMEX> it helped drastically reduce the number of shipping accidents and shipwrecks, but it was unpopular with the native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who relied on lucrative salvage activities to make a living. It is one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> manual lighthouses in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> and has to be turned throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and night by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lighthouse workers</ENAMEX>. Climb the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> steps to the top for fantastic views over the whole of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Elbow Cay</ENAMEX>.
A pretty little village of pastel-colored clapboard <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hope Town</ENAMEX> is full of friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> run safely in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of the traffic-free <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town center</ENAMEX> and along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Queens Highway</ENAMEX>, only slightly wider than a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX>. Shoes are optional in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> at the water‚Äôs edge, and as the sun sets you‚Äôll hear <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> stories here about the one that got away. Watch out for the sign ‚ÄúTourists treated just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>,‚Äù for you‚Äôll soon feel as though you‚Äôve lived here forever. You‚Äôll be exchanging greetings, and before you know it, life stories. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wyannie Malone Historical Museum</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Queens Highway</ENAMEX> is the place to find out more about these fascinating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and their home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>.
To the northwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marsh Harbour</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man-O-War Cay</ENAMEX>, a small island of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants famous</ENAMEX> for its boatyards. The dinghies and runabouts built here are hand-crafted; <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX> is used to seal gaps between the wooden planks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> are then sunk so that the wet cotton expands to make them watertight. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man-O</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> is unusual in that it has always been a dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cay¬†‚Äî¬†no alcohol</ENAMEX> is sold anywhere.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Guana Cay</ENAMEX>, northwest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">of Man</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">O-War</ENAMEX>, has wonderful long, lonely beaches that run for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> along the island‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">eastern</ENAMEX> rim. A total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live in the island‚Äôs few small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">settlements</ENAMEX>, and the chief activity seems to be sitting under the large <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fig tree</ENAMEX> on the harbor front and gossiping. Sailors touring through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> love to anchor offshore <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">here¬†‚Äî¬†this</ENAMEX> serene spot is one of the best places to switch off the rest of the world. Those who don‚Äôt have their own transport can take one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> ferries that run over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marsh Harbour</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North of Marsh Harbour</ENAMEX> you‚Äôll see signs for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Treasure Cay</ENAMEX>, which is, strictly speaking, a peninsula rather than a cay. The land here has been developed into one of the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">resort areas</ENAMEX> outside the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main islands. A large <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">marina</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">18-hole</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> attract a mixed group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but the initial lure, and reason for the whole development, is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Treasure Beach</ENAMEX>, one of the best in the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>. This <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6-mile arc</NUMEX> of soft <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX> was for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian</ENAMEX> secret.
An <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Treasure Cay</ENAMEX> serves the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> and the northern offshore cays. A regular ferry service links with the flight times. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> offshore is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Green Turtle Cay</ENAMEX>. Much more lush than many of the other islands in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>, this <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hilly, 3-mile</NUMEX>- (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5-km-</TIMEX>) long cay is covered with pine woodland that camouflages many of its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and resorts. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Loyalist</ENAMEX> settlement dating from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1783¬†‚Äî¬†groups</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX> were evacuated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savannah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX> along with black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> who escaped their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">owners¬†‚Äî¬†Green Turtle</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> has become a getaway for the rich and famous. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> here have all the luxuries you could ever need, yet you might feel as if you‚Äôre <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a million miles</NUMEX> away from the worries of the world. The cay is small enough to explore on foot but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> choose to rent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">golf cart</ENAMEX> or bicycle (your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> can make the arrangements).
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Plymouth</ENAMEX> is the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> on the cay. It really has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> main route, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> Street, which is full of trim and brightly painted wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> with picket fences. As you walk down the street you‚Äôll hear the sounds of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> activity floating through the open windows, occasionally a radio station with news, or maybe evangelical songs. You can browse in the general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and souvenir <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> or visit one of the small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art galleries</ENAMEX> that sell original works and prints by local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. On the left as you walk away from the harbor you‚Äôll find the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Memorial Sculpture Garden</ENAMEX>, dedicated to the brave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> who founded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Plymouth</ENAMEX>. A little farther along, on the right, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albert Lowe Museum</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an 18th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, is brim full of artifacts and knickknacks, maps, and newspaper articles that tell the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Plymouth</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowe</ENAMEX> was a sailor and prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shipbuilder</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is now owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roland Alton Lowe</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendant</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> and an acclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bahamian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>; his paintings and prints are sold at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abaco Gold</ENAMEX> necklaces, bracelets, and rings¬†‚Äî¬†including some with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> and conch <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shell motifs¬†‚Äî¬†are</ENAMEX> sold at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sand Dollar Shoppe on Parliament Street</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">365-4221</ENAMEX>).
Eleuthera
The longest unbroken island in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slender</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleuthera</ENAMEX> (pronounced ‚Äúe-LOOTH-ra‚Äù) extends <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 miles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">160 km</NUMEX>) from north to south yet has many stretches that are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">barely half</NUMEX> a mile (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 km</NUMEX>) wide. Some of the wildest Bahamian landscapes are to be found on this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> that seems to be more in touch with the moods of the sea than other islands are. The rocky outcrops and sometimes towering waves on the east contrast with calm waters and sandy flats on the west. In the northwest a series of cays and sand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> reach out to fill the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60 miles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">96 km</NUMEX>) or so between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eleuthera</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Bahamian</ENAMEX> history began on this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1648</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eleutherian Adventurers</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Sayle</ENAMEX>, arrived from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> and founded their shaky <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>. They landed near the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governor‚Äôs Harbour</ENAMEX> on the middle of the island, but after a period of feuding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sayle</ENAMEX> and some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> moved north to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harbour Island</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> still live there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Although they named the island <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleuthera</ENAMEX>, you may find that the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> call the island <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cigatoo</ENAMEX>, its old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucayan</ENAMEX> name.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harbour Island</ENAMEX>, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúBriland‚Äù</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>, sits off the northeastern corner of the main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>. You can reach it via a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15-minute</TIMEX> ride on a small ferry; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxis</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Eleuthera Airport</ENAMEX> run reliable service to the docks for a set price per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. The island‚Äôs main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunmore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX>, is a cluster of narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> lined by clapboard houses festooned with bougainvillea; handsome roosters strut here and there in the undergrowth. Boat building and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> production used to be the main ways the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> earned a living; <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum</ENAMEX> production also made the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> popular with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition</ENAMEX>. Now tourism is the major industry.
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bay Street</ENAMEX> runs along the harbor-front, where you‚Äôll find a small <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">straw market¬†‚Äî¬†five</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> colorful stalls hugging the beach¬†‚Äî¬†and the tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> at the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jetty</ENAMEX>. Wandering around (you can stroll over the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX>) you‚Äôll find the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Loyalist Cottage</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-18th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">settler‚Äôs home</ENAMEX>, as well as several simple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, including the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. John‚Äôs.</ENAMEX> A number of souvenir <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> have some interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bahamian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> gifts.
The beautiful pink sand beach on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is also a big draw. The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five miles</NUMEX> of sand are a beautiful sight, especially in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early morning</TIMEX> or just before sunset when the color reflects more deeply. Any of the several luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> tucked just behind the dunes make a good base for the beach or the delights of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only a few minutes‚Äô</NUMEX> walk away.
Just off the northern tip of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eleuthera</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish Wells</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spaniards</ENAMEX> sank a well here to supply their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">treasure fleets</ENAMEX> with fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> for the long journey back across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wells</ENAMEX> are noted seamen and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> (they were given land to farm on the main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX>); many still make their living by fishing for crawfish, grouper, yellowtail, and conch, or by building <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>, though the best-known local product is perhaps the wide-brimmed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> straw hat. Not as much a tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harbour Island</ENAMEX>, this quiet settlement nevertheless attracts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> with its beaches, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">marina</ENAMEX>, and miles of offshore reef, particularly good for diving. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wells Museum</ENAMEX> (open <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mon‚ÄìSat 10am‚Äì12pm</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1‚Äì3pm</ENAMEX>) records the island‚Äôs history and culture.
On the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northern</ENAMEX> coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eleuthera Island is Preacher‚Äôs Cave</ENAMEX>, the spot where the original adventurers are said to have been shipwrecked. It is cathedral-like in its dimensions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> wrote their names in charcoal on the walls of the cavern and erected a stone altar for their services (unfortunately the entrance to the cave is now littered with rubbish left by modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>). Several deserted beaches nearby, including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Preacher‚Äôs Cay Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bain Bay</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ridley Head</ENAMEX>, offer opportunities for solitude or very good close-to-shore <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">snorkeling</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">A few miles</NUMEX> south of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Eleuthera Airport</ENAMEX> the island narrows to a rocky ridge <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just 80 ft</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX>) wide. Over the millennia, an arched hole had been created here by the pounding of the waves of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>; known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass Window</ENAMEX>, this opening made it possible for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Exuma Sound</ENAMEX> to see ‚Äúthrough the island‚Äù to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>. The natural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> that had been formed at the top of the arch collapsed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> during a hurricane and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you pass over the still dramatic gap from north to central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eleuthera</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">man-made Glass Window Bridge</ENAMEX>. The bridge requires continual maintenance because storms, hurricanes, high winds, and heavy seas take a constant toll; in turbulent weather the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> rises in great waves pushing towards the still, calm <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> settlement after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glass Window Bridge</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Town</ENAMEX>, a pretty hillside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of colorful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> overlooking a tiny harbor. This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pineapple</ENAMEX> production in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. Try the fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pies</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson‚Äôs Bakery</ENAMEX> on the top of a hill east of the harbor. Halfway down the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governor‚Äôs Harbour</ENAMEX>, a photogenic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> set on the sheltered eastern coastline. It is a major <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>, who come here to stock up on all the essentials, obtain spare parts, and have repairs done.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Windermere Island</ENAMEX>, just off the east coast, was once the place to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>, but its smart resort <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> is now closed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Cousteau</ENAMEX> had a home here and used it as a base for exploring the seas around the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian</ENAMEX> islands.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Eleuthera</ENAMEX> is served by an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> near the little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rock Sound</ENAMEX>, which is famed for its blue hole, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Cousteau</ENAMEX> spent time investigating. Although it is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only half a mile</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> side of the island, it actually reaches out <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several miles</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic Ocean</ENAMEX> and has yet to be fully explored.
Andros
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX> is the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bahamas¬†‚Äî¬†at</ENAMEX> a little <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 100 miles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">160 km</NUMEX>) long and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 miles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">64 km</NUMEX>) wide, it‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost four</NUMEX> times larger than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Commonwealth¬†‚Äî¬</ENAMEX>†though much of its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> is covered by uninhabitable mangrove swamp and coral limestone escarpments divided by wide creeks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is fringed by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> of shallow sand flats on the west and ringed by coral reef on the east. Perhaps because of its vastness and rugged terrain, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andros</ENAMEX> became a favorite of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pirate fleets</ENAMEX>; one of its major <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">settlements</ENAMEX> is called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Morgan‚Äôs Bluff</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirate leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Morgan</ENAMEX>, who is said to have buried treasure on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the beaches in the area.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1821</TIMEX> a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seminole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> left their native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and settled on the northern tip of the island. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> still live around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Bays</ENAMEX>, practicing the skills of basket weaving for which they are greatly admired. Their work, which is of extremely high quality, is said to be so tightly woven that the baskets can hold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neville Chamberlain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> who attempted to negotiate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, created a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sisal farm</ENAMEX> on the island, but the attempt failed miserably.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX> is famed for its natural attractions: It has the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> longest barrier reef in the world, lying just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one mile</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11‚ÅÑ2 km</NUMEX>) offshore and stretching <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">140 miles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">225 km</NUMEX>) down the east coast. This makes it a popular destination with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divers</ENAMEX> who come to explore the tidal shallows, the reef, and the deep reef walls, which plunge <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX> ft (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,829 m</NUMEX>) down into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tongue</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ocean</ENAMEX>, the deep passage between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX>. Numerous species of sea life flourish at every level and contribute to the abundant variety of diving environments available for all ability levels. Experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divers</ENAMEX> also come to explore the numerous so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúblue holes‚Äù</ENAMEX> that dot the interior of the island. Created by erosion of the limestone rock, these holes have a layer of fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> that lies on top and tidal sea water below; <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">sea</ENAMEX> water forced in through countless underground fissures causes their water levels to rise or fall with the tides. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX> is awash with fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, which is put to good use: <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 6 million gallons</NUMEX> are pumped into <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tankers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX> and shipped across to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX>, where fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is much in demand.
The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shallow ‚Äúflats‚Äù</ENAMEX> that meet the mangrove swamps along the west coast are an ideal environment for bonefish, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andros</ENAMEX> lays claim to being the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bonefishing Capital of the World</ENAMEX>. The fishing is extremely challenging, either from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> off the island or by wading in the shallows just offshore. Onshore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird watcher‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">paradise¬†‚Äî¬†hardwood forests</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bahamian mahogany</ENAMEX> and mangrove and smaller areas of pine offer a varied habitat to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 120</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">migratory species</ENAMEX>.
Most of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">settlements</ENAMEX> lie along the eastern side of the island. They are widely scattered, from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Congo Town</ENAMEX> in the south through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nicholls Town</ENAMEX> in the north. Getting around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is time consuming and difficult because it is divided by wide creeks, swamps, and lakes, but each of these main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">settlements</ENAMEX> is served by an airport.
At <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Andros Town</ENAMEX>, known as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fresh Creek</ENAMEX> to local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, there are a few <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> and a number of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most popular Bahamian souvenirs is produced nearby. Androsia <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">batik¬†‚Äî¬†brightly colored cotton fabric</ENAMEX> with tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit motifs¬†‚Äî¬</ENAMEX>†is hand-produced at a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> just outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>. You can watch the patterns being pressed in wax onto the white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton fabric</ENAMEX> and view the skeins as they‚Äôre allowed to dry naturally in the warm Bahamian sun. The finished batik is then used to make clothing and other products in the small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> next door. The products are available in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>, but you can save a good deal by buying direct from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>.
The Exumas
Running in a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100-mile</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">160-km</TIMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> directly south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exumas</ENAMEX> have a cay for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day of the year</TIMEX>, though some of these tiny islands are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only a few hundred square feet</NUMEX> in size and most are uninhabited. The breathtaking waters surrounding these islands, ranging from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">turquoise</ENAMEX> blue to jade green, are a sailor‚Äôs delight, and numerous yachts can be seen weaving around the sandy shallows and cutting through to deeper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.
The name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Exuma</ENAMEX> is said to be a derivation of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lucayan Indian</ENAMEX> words that had been used for this group of islands, yumey and suma. The largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exuma Cays</ENAMEX> were settled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Loyalists</ENAMEX> following the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Revolution</ENAMEX>. Chief among these was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Rolle</ENAMEX>, who brought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 100</NUMEX> slaves with him to start a cotton <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> began to fail after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few years</TIMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis</ENAMEX> passed the land onto his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1834</TIMEX> slavery was abolished and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Rolle</ENAMEX> freed his slaves and deeded the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rolle</ENAMEX> land on to them ‚Äúin commonage‚Äù at his death. This allowed only those directly related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolle</ENAMEX> slaves to farm or build on the inherited land. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> most of the native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants of the Exumas</ENAMEX> bear the family name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rolle</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exumas</ENAMEX> are divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> distinct sections: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Exuma Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Exuma Island</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exhuma Cays</ENAMEX>, which lie north of the main islands. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Town</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Exuma Island</ENAMEX>, is served by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">regular</NUMEX> flights from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> and makes the most convenient base for non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>. It has a sleepy and laid-back atmosphere and offers a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. A compact <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">straw</ENAMEX> and vegetable market sits at the main crossroads. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> lies on the coast at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elizabeth Harbour</ENAMEX>, a large, sheltered stretch of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> that is a popular stopping off point for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>. The quiet town comes to life every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> when it hosts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Island Regatta</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahamian</ENAMEX> working <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> fill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Harbour</ENAMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> vying for the right to call themselves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> of the regatta.
From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX> you can take the short ferry trip to nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stocking Cay</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten-minute</TIMEX> journey across the sound (courtesy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club Peace and Plenty hotel</ENAMEX>) takes you to an island of sublime beaches, underwater caves to dive in, and rocky inlets to explore by snorkel. You can find sand dollars and starfish and spot rays and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX>. The few holiday <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> do nothing to spoil the natural beauty, and you‚Äôll still be able to find a deserted beach in one of the many sheltered bays.
Much of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Exuma</ENAMEX> is given over to agricultural production¬†, providing the island <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX> with a lot of its fresh produce. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> like onions as well as such ‚Äúexotics‚Äù as avocados are grown in the interior. The only other major settlement besides <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Town</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX>, once part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolle</ENAMEX> estate. It is said that the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> were the family‚Äôs domestic slaves; the plantation slaves made their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolleville</ENAMEX> farther north. A number of tombs in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rolle Town</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX> from the earliest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loyalist</ENAMEX> settlement.
A little bridge links <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Exuma</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Exuma</ENAMEX> in the south. Until the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> was opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX> the only way to reach the island was by ferry <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>, and the first small settlement on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little Exuma</ENAMEX> side is called, appropriately, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Ferry</ENAMEX>. Here you can meet with the ‚ÄúShark <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady</ENAMEX>.‚Äù The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Regatta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Patience</ENAMEX> was given her nickname because of the many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> she has caught. She has created a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> in her home, the only one of its kind in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exumas</ENAMEX>, to document and illustrate the history and lifestyle of the island‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
Traveling north from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX> you‚Äôll pass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Sisters Rock</ENAMEX>, a formation that lies just offshore from a sandy beach; the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> rocks are said to represent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> who drowned in the waters here. Gradually the island narrows, and past <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolleville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Exuma</ENAMEX> gives way to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exuma Cays</ENAMEX>, a ribbon of small islands of which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only four</NUMEX> are inhabited. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stanial Cay</ENAMEX> offers accommodation as well as yachting supplies. It also has an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airfield</ENAMEX> with regular service from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Lauderdale</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> coast. These cays are home to the endangered iguana along with numerous rare <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">plant species</ENAMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">22-mile</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35-km</NUMEX>) stretch north of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Conch Cut</ENAMEX> has been protected for future generations by the creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exuma Cays Land</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea Park</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">175 sq miles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">453 sq km</NUMEX>) of land and sea that includes some of the best yet most remote beaches in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> is only accessible by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">boat¬†‚Äî¬†except</ENAMEX> for the occasional powerboats bringing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> over from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> for a day of snorkeling and picnics on the beach, the only sounds you‚Äôll hear will be the wind whipping through the sails of yachts anchored offshore.
Bimini
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> tiny islands <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only 9 sq miles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">23 sq km</NUMEX>) in total area, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North and South Bimini</ENAMEX> lie just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 miles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">80 km</NUMEX>) east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> in the midst of some of the best sport fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> in the world. Both have had an illustrious list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ponce de Leon</ENAMEX> searched for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Fountain of Youth</ENAMEX> here. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Hemingway</ENAMEX> spent a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">time</TIMEX> fishing and writing here¬†‚Äî¬†photographs of this prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> still adorn the walls of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compleat Angler Hotel</ENAMEX>, where he wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Have and Have Not</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Clayton Powell</ENAMEX>, who was regularly seen at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">marina of Alice Town</ENAMEX>, the major settlement, helped raise the profile of the place in the eyes of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. The islands flourished during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Prohibition</ENAMEX>, when many came here to enjoy a shot or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of hard liquor.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Town</ENAMEX> with its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> is still the center of the action. A series of fishing competitions make up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúseason‚Äù</ENAMEX> for the rich, bright, and beautiful, who descend to fish during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and enjoy the lively social scene after dark. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bimini</ENAMEX> does not have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> shows of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau and Grand Bahama</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX> legacy seems to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> along the quay in a perpetual state of jovial excess. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Offshore</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only 15 ft</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">41‚ÅÑ2 m</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, lies the famed ancient roadway said to be part of the lost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atlantis</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berry</ENAMEX> Islands
This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of islands north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Providence</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only 12 sq miles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">41‚ÅÑ2 sq km</NUMEX>) in all, are known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúfishbowl of the Bahamas‚</ENAMEX>Äù because of the rich seas around them. They are a paradise for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divers</ENAMEX>, and snorkelers. Scattered across some of the prettiest seas in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>, with shallow sand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a thousand translucent hues</NUMEX> of green and blue, these cays can be seen quite clearly from the air on flights from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>. They can also be explored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>; anchoring in the sheltered waters provides outstanding opportunities for swimming and snorkeling.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berry</ENAMEX> Islands offer tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chub Cay</ENAMEX>, nearest to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>, is a favored sport-fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">resort¬†‚Äî¬†anglers sail</ENAMEX> out from here to the northern tip of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tongue</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ocean</ENAMEX> to catch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">marlin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scuba</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divers</ENAMEX> and snorkelers enjoy the shallow reefs close to the island. The shallow coral reef off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mamma Rhoda Rock</ENAMEX>, a brief motorboat ride from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chub Cay marina</ENAMEX>, is an outstanding experience. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Harbour Cay</ENAMEX>, covered with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>-top <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">palms</ENAMEX> and sea grape, is a pretty island with a number of marvelous beaches. At the impressive marina, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">yachtsmen¬†‚Äî¬†many</ENAMEX> visiting from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coast¬†‚Äî¬†park</ENAMEX> in slips beneath their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">townhouses</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat Island</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cat Islanders</ENAMEX> can still be said to be living a little in the past. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, they dispute nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Salvador‚</ENAMEX>Äôs claim to be the landing place of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>; they still feel, as archaeologists and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> used to, that the explorer first made <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">landfall</ENAMEX> on their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cat Islanders</ENAMEX> also retain a powerful attachment to obeah, the world of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spirits</ENAMEX> and natural healing.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> itself also has peculiarities that separate it from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamian Islands</ENAMEX>. It is the most undulating of the islands; one could even call it <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hilly</NUMEX>, with the highest point of land in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonwealth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Alvernia</ENAMEX>, rising to the heady heights of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">216</NUMEX> ft (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">66m</NUMEX>) above sea level.
