



A Brief History
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Today‚Äôs Indonesians</ENAMEX> mainly descend from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who came from south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> via the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> peninsula and moved along the island <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali, Lombok</ENAMEX>, and beyond, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3000 to 1000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">b.c. Archaeological</ENAMEX> finds show that there was a flourishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronze Age</ENAMEX> culture in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lombok</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between about 1000 and 100</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">b.c. Trade</ENAMEX> and cultural exchanges with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX> had certainly begun by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX>, and there were frequent contacts with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">a.d.¬†100</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About this time</TIMEX>, too, wet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice cultivation</ENAMEX> was introduced to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>, changing the face of the countryside to its present appearance of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice paddy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX> and terraces.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> brought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>. It had only a limited influence in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>, however, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> continued in their ancient animist beliefs, worshipping the spirits of the mountains, rivers, and other natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hinduism</ENAMEX> Comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>
In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries a.d.</TIMEX>, several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Java</ENAMEX> converted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinduism</ENAMEX>, along with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. This time, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX> followed suit, perhaps attracted by the complex <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mythology</ENAMEX> ‚Äî the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balinese</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> still have a love of the old stories ‚Äî and by the way their local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gods</ENAMEX> could be housed easily in the crowded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu pantheon</ENAMEX>. Around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">930</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Java</ENAMEX> conquered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX> and the conversion process accelerated. A mild form of the caste system and the concept of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu trinity of Brahma, Shiva</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vishnu</ENAMEX> were introduced. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX> was no mere vassal state of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1019 to 1042</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Airlangga</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Udayana</ENAMEX>, ruled over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Java</ENAMEX> with the help of a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Javanese princess</ENAMEX>, while his young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> acted as regent in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 12th and 13th centuries</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX> was often independent.
A powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> named after its capital, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Majapahit</ENAMEX>, united all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1320</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Majapahit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gajah Mada</ENAMEX> reconquered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1343</TIMEX>, and annexed a large part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archipelago</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> art and scholarship spread through the islands, but on most of the islands, this flowering was short-lived. With the death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1389</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hayam Wurukin</ENAMEX>, its last great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Majapahit</ENAMEX> began to¬†decline.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Muslim traders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> had already started converting several of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java‚</ENAMEX>Äôs princes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>, especially in coastal areas, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 14th and 15th centuries</TIMEX> the movement spread to the interior. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1500</TIMEX>, seeing their world breaking up, many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Majapahit</ENAMEX> aristocrats, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> fled to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>, where their culture continued to flourish. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> never gained a strong foothold in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>, which was difficult to invade because of its many reefs and lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">harbors</ENAMEX>, and had few products to attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 16th century</TIMEX> also brought the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> waters, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> came in search of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX> and set up trading posts ‚Äî though not on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1550</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX> was united under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Batu Renggong</ENAMEX>, the formidable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dewa Agung</ENAMEX> (god-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gelgel</ENAMEX>, near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Klungkung</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> even succeeded in turning back the tide of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> for a short while, adding eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Java</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lombok</ENAMEX> to his domains. During his rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balinese</ENAMEX> power, culture, and influence reached a peak, with a boom in temple <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and the associated crafts of sculpture and woodcarving.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 250 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> fell to squabbling among themselves and the island split into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or more rajadoms. Bali‚Äôs contact with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> was restricted to providing slaves ‚Äî mainly Balinese who had broken the rajas‚Äô laws or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">priests‚Äô taboos ‚Äî</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Dutch East Indies Company</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vereenigde Oostindische Compagnie</ENAMEX>, or VOC). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was the instrument of influence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX> until it went bankrupt in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1799</TIMEX> and was superseded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> influence and authority slowly spread across the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archipelago</ENAMEX>, but bypassed the relatively poor, unimportant island of¬†Bali.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1811 and 1817</TIMEX>, during the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Napoleonic Wars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> took control of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> and seriously thought of staying once the wars were over. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britain‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stamford Raffles</ENAMEX>, who was named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lieutenant Governor</ENAMEX>, even visited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>, and may have had it in mind to build a trading <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> here. After the war, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> decided to restore <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> territory and interests ‚Äî and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raffles</ENAMEX> found another site, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> and future port of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> Take Over
Once re-established in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Java</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> attempted to increase their influence and also to prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balinese</ENAMEX> from plundering <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> wrecked off the coast (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balinese</ENAMEX> considered shipwrecks to be gifts from the deities of the seas, and felt it would be insulting to refuse them). Following the looting of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1841</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> decided to use force. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Some 1,600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, recruited mainly from other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> islands, landed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">north</ENAMEX> coast in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1846</TIMEX> and burned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singaraja</ENAMEX>. Immediately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rajas</ENAMEX> agreed to stop the plundering of wrecks, and to pay compensation for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1841</TIMEX> incident, but it soon became clear that they had no intention of honoring the deal. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1848</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> landed a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> military expedition in the north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>. Advancing inland to attack the¬†Balinese <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jagaraga</ENAMEX>, they were ambushed by a bigger but less well-armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jelantik</ENAMEX>, younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raja of Bululeng</ENAMEX>. In spite of appalling losses, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balinese</ENAMEX> won <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. The defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> invaders retreated in disorder to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> military expedition, far stronger than its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>, landed near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singaraja</ENAMEX>. The northern rajadoms sued for peace; they were offered terms calling for them to disarm and submit to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> rule. The response of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jelantik</ENAMEX> was to fall back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jagaraga</ENAMEX> and prepare to fight. This time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balinese</ENAMEX> were overwhelmed and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> were killed, some in a suicidal march towards enemy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, a ritual death in battle known in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Balinese</ENAMEX> language as puputan. After a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> landing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Padangbai Bay</ENAMEX>, the puputan ritual was repeated when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raja of Karangasem</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> threw themselves on the enemy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rest of the 19th century</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>, using the rajas and other aristocrats as regents, took control over most of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>, but their influence in the south remained limited. This was emphasized in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904</TIMEX> when a ship wrecked off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanur</ENAMEX> was plundered of its cargo. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> demanded reparations for this act; the southern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rajas</ENAMEX> refused. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1906</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of mainly Moluccan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> led by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> marched on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denpasar</ENAMEX> to enforce compliance. They found the place almost deserted, until suddenly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raja of Badung</ENAMEX>, together with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of courtiers</NUMEX>, emerged from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>. On a signal from the raja, one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> stabbed him with a kris (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX>), and then, pausing only to stab their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> first, the rest of the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> began a puputan, either killing themselves or running suicidally towards the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. When the dreadful scene was repeated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dewa Agung</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908</TIMEX> in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klungkung</ENAMEX>, the rajas‚Äô resistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> rule was at an end.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX> was appalled by these grisly events. From then on, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balinese</ENAMEX> came to be looked on as unique <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äî</ENAMEX> to be protected from the colonial treatment that had turned the other islands into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations exploited</ENAMEX> for profit. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourism</ENAMEX> was discouraged, although a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> did make the journey and returned to the outside world with news of the island‚Äôs extraordinary culture. An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Koke</ENAMEX>, opened the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuta Beach</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise G. Koke‚</ENAMEX>Äôs memoir, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Hotel In Bali</ENAMEX>, provides an idyllic portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, tenuous endeavor at tourism from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX> until the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> invasion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>. 
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s and 1930s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokorde Gde Agung Sukawati</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ubud</ENAMEX>, extended a long Sukawati family tradition of patronizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> and craftsmanship by hosting visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Spies</ENAMEX>, who stayed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 years</TIMEX>. Spies‚Äô influence revolutionized painting in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>, which had previously been one of the least inventive of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bali‚Äôs</ENAMEX> arts, bound by repetitive conventions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pita Maha</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX>-influenced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> emerged (also influenced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pastel-ist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolf Bonnet</ENAMEX>), putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ubud</ENAMEX> on the world map of contemporary art. Spies‚Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>-fed swimming pool (now part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tjampuhan Hotel</ENAMEX>) were visited by Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> of theater and film. Deeply involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Balinese</ENAMEX> culture, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spies</ENAMEX> himself choreographed the still-performed version of the most famous Balinese dance, the kecak, based on a story from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúRamayana</ENAMEX>.‚Äù When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spies</ENAMEX> was interned as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> alien. He died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>, when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> on which he was being transported to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Ceylon</ENAMEX> was torpedoed by the¬†Japanese.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1900</TIMEX> until the start of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, many young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indonesians</ENAMEX> received a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> education, with the brightest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> language gave the vast polyglot archipelago a sense of unity, even among islands that had been bitter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> nationalism and a movement for independence from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holland</ENAMEX> gained strength.
War and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Independence</ENAMEX>
Early in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>, soon after their attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> invaded and occupied <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, with the intention of exploiting its oil and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX>. Until the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, the difficult <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX> continued; with the surrender of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> declared its independence. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years from 1946 to 1949</TIMEX> saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> trying to reassert control; however, weakened as it was from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> occupation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX> was not able to muster the huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> needed to recapture all the¬†islands.
On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> nationalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ngurah Rai</ENAMEX>, found themselves trapped by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marga</ENAMEX>, north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tabenan</ENAMEX>. Outnumbered and outgunned, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ngurah Rai</ENAMEX> and all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> were killed in what is regarded as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bali‚Äôs</ENAMEX> last puputan. Their sacrifice is commemorated by a monument and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> at the site, together with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> bearing the names of each of those who died on the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX> during the struggle for independence (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX>).
Finally on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 August 1950</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years to the day</TIMEX> after independence was first declared, the fledgling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic of Indonesia</ENAMEX> was recognized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>. Sukarno, preeminent in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist</ENAMEX> movement, emerged as the new nation‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX> Afro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bandung</ENAMEX> heralded the arrival of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sukarno</ENAMEX> was welcomed to the world stage. Together with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India‚Äôs Nehru</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, he was credited with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of the non-aligned movement.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX> of Confusion
A succession of short-lived coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> wrestled with the problems posed by separatist movements of the various island <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, dislocation caused by war and its aftermath, a badly neglected infrastructure, and the colo-nial legacy of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-exploited <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX>. Frustrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesia‚</ENAMEX>Äôs loss of direction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sukarno</ENAMEX> declared a form of martial law in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>. A so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúguided democracy‚Äù</ENAMEX> and an appointed national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> and non-party <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> took the place of the elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> and ineffectual coalitions.
The period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1959 and 1965</TIMEX> was a surreal time of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> by means of slogans and Orwellian acronyms. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sukarno</ENAMEX> attempted to control the competing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist</ENAMEX>, religious, and communist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASAKOM</ENAMEX> was the word he used to represent their supposed common interests. As if that wasn‚Äôt enough, processions paraded with placards emblazoned with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANIPOL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sukarno‚</ENAMEX>Äôs political manifesto) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEKON</ENAMEX> (his economic declaration) written on them, and there were others which condemned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEKOLIM</ENAMEX> (neo-colonialism and imperialism). In the meantime, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> economy collapsed and hyper-inflation destroyed the currency.
The country‚Äôs limited foreign-exchange reserves were squandered on window-dressing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX>, grand monuments, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> to host the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Games</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>, seen as part of a plan to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> into the world spotlight. International travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> were given a tour of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, including a visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX> that coincided with an important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balinese</ENAMEX> ceremony in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1963</TIMEX> at the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúmother temple‚Äù Besakih</ENAMEX>, on the slopes of the island‚Äôs highest mountain, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gunung Agung</ENAMEX>. Portentously, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gunung Agung</ENAMEX>, though long dormant, chose this particular moment to begin emitting smoke and firing rocks into the air, but the ceremony went ahead anyway, literally under a cloud. The official <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> had scarcely left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gunung Agung</ENAMEX> exploded in what was the most violent eruption the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> had seen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Lava</ENAMEX> flowed down its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slopes</ENAMEX>, but despite the impressions conveyed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> (and by photographs seen in many books), it covered only a limited area. The chief instrument of destruction was the volcanic ash that showered down on the northern <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>, covering it with a layer 40¬†cm (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15¬†inches</NUMEX>) thick. <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Crops</ENAMEX> were wiped out; the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice terraces</ENAMEX> were devastated, and starvation threatened.
The ash fall also blocked rivers, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dams</ENAMEX> it formed could not retain the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> for long. When they broke, torrents of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX> and rock tore down the valleys and through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> along the river <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. The official death toll of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,600</NUMEX> was a wild underestimate. The sky went black even over southern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>, although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denpasar</ENAMEX> received only a sprinkling of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ash</ENAMEX>.
Coup and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revenge</ENAMEX>
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 September 1965</TIMEX>, a group of army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX>, who claimed they acted to prevent a possible coup against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sukarno</ENAMEX>, kidnapped and killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Suharto</ENAMEX>, one of the most senior surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX>, isolated the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX> and effectively seized power. The blame for the killings was pinned on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKI</ENAMEX>, which denied any involvement. A pogrom was then unleashed, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Java</ENAMEX> and next in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>, with widespread killings of suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX>, mainly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopkeepers</ENAMEX>, moneylenders, and other small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businesspeople</ENAMEX>, were also a target. In common with the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant groups</ENAMEX>, they had been compelled by law to display the flag of their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of origin, even if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> had passed since their ancestors had come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. Throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> business, marked by the flag of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, and associated in people‚Äôs minds with communism, was attacked. The numbers killed will never be known: in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX> alone the total casualties may have exceeded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60,000</NUMEX>.
Sukarno‚Äôs association with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKI</ENAMEX> led to his being forced to yield most of his powers. Only his honored role in the independence struggle saved him from trial. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX> took over the presidency. 
Growth and Modernization
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX> following, the economy stabilized as growing oil revenues fueled expansion. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, backbone of the nation‚Äôs economy, carefully rebuilt its commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX>, this time much less visibly. Tourism to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX> was seen as a money-spinner: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> saw a rapid increase in the numbers of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> decided to develop a more up-market tourism on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nusa Dua</ENAMEX> was designated to become a huge tourist enclave where only large, luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> would be built. To bring the necessary volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> traffic to fill all the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denpasar Airport‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">runway</ENAMEX> was extended out into the sea to handle big <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airliners</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decade</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX> became one of the most prosperous places in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. In order to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balinese</ENAMEX> better prepare for new jobs in the tourism market, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language courses became mandatory in middle and secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the¬</TIMEX>†island.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1990s</TIMEX> were a period of disillusionment with the long-lived <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX> regime‚Äôs many failings and widespread corruption. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> economy faltered, ethnic conflicts erupted in many parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>; even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lombok</ENAMEX> experienced a brief flare-up of violence against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX>, with its unique <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> culture and its international, tourism-oriented outlook, has remained an island of stability throughout this unsettled period of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> history.



