



Where To Go
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has fascinating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> and neighborhoods to stroll. However, the main attractions are scattered throughout this sprawling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, so you‚Äôll be taking frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>, or subway rides no matter where your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> is located. Following the ancient city plan, we have divided the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> like a compass, with the downtown sights in the center surrounded by quadrants to the north, south, east, and west.
The main urban area of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> covers <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">750 sq km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">290 sq miles</NUMEX>), with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City and Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chang‚Äôan Avenue</ENAMEX> bisects these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> and forms the capital‚Äôs long, wide east‚Äìwest axis. A north‚Äìsouth axis runs <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 miles</NUMEX>) from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of Heaven through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>. Old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, once surrounded by massive city walls and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> towering gates, is now encircled by a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX> and a major expressway, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Ring Road</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">231‚ÅÑ2 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">141‚ÅÑ2 miles</NUMEX>) around. In turn, a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Third Ring Road</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">48 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 miles</NUMEX>) around, encompasses most of urban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is bulging outward toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Ring</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City and Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>, separated by the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">east‚Äìwest thoroughfare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chang‚Äôan Avenue</ENAMEX>, stand at the center of downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. They are convenient references for locating the attractions in the north, south, east, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">west districts</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Center</ENAMEX>
The center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> contains <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs outstanding historical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>. Across <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chang‚Äôan Avenue</ENAMEX> to the south is the capital‚Äôs premier modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>. Just east of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most important shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wangfujing Dajie</ENAMEX>. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> places happen to be within walking distance of each other, a rarity for sightseeing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>
Completed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yongle</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1420</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zijin Cheng</ENAMEX>) in the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> was the home to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> consecutive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1368‚Äì1644</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qing</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1644‚Äì1911</ENAMEX>) dynasties. The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9-m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30-ft</NUMEX>) walls enclose <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">74 hectares</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">183 acres</NUMEX>) of magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>, courtyards, and imperial gardens, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX> number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 10,000</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> call the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City the Palace Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gu Gong</ENAMEX>), and it is indeed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> of imperial architecture, artifacts, and private collections of the emperors.
The main entrance is from the south, through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate of Heaven</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen</ENAMEX>), the large archway decorated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao‚</ENAMEX>Äôs portrait facing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chang‚Äôan Avenue</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>. The ticket <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX> is due north along a central corridor at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meridian Gate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wumen</ENAMEX>), where audio tapes can be rented in a variety of languages. Beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meridian Gate</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outer Court</ENAMEX>, which contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> magnificent ceremonial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> and their vast courtyards. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meridian Gate</ENAMEX> is connected to the first great <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate of Great Harmony</ENAMEX>, which has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> white marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outer Court</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Great Harmony</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tai He Dian</ENAMEX>), contains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">emperor‚Äôs Dragon Throne</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of Middle Harmony</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhong He Dian</ENAMEX>), contains a smaller throne, from which emperors addressed their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>. The final hall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outer Court</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Preserving Harmony</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bao He Dian</ENAMEX>), is where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperors</ENAMEX> received <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from the annual imperial examinations that determined who would enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> date from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1420</TIMEX> but were renovated or rebuilt under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing</ENAMEX> emperors.
Between the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Outer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Exhibition Halls</ENAMEX>, requiring a detour to the right as one proceeds north. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Clocks</ENAMEX>, located in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of Worshipping Ancestors</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feng Xian Dian</ENAMEX>), contains the imperial collection of timepieces, many of them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> gifts from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. Nearby is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Jewelry</ENAMEX>, housed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Palace of Tranquillity and Longevity</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ning Shou Gong</ENAMEX>), with another display of royal treasures, including robes worn by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress Dowager Cixi</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress Dowager‚</ENAMEX>Äôs private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qianlong‚</ENAMEX>Äôs rock garden, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nine Dragon Screen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jiu Long Bi</ENAMEX>), a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30-m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-ft) ceramic mosaic created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1773</TIMEX>, are also located in this section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> private pavilions make up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inner Court</ENAMEX>, located on the central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">axis</ENAMEX> in the northern portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> were used as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX> by the emperors and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. The imperial concubines and eunuchs also lived here, with household <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> often numbering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 1,000</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Palace of Heavenly Purity</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qian Qing Gong</ENAMEX>), the private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX> emperors. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of Union</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiao Tai Dian</ENAMEX>), which contains the throne of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing</ENAMEX> empress. The final <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Palace of Earthly Tranquillity</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kun Ning Gong</ENAMEX>), where the last <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puyi</ENAMEX>, was married as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX>.
Near the northern gate to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Imperial Garden</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yu Hua Yuan</ENAMEX>), filled with small pavilions, ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cypress trees</ENAMEX>, and complex rookeries, all built during the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ming Dynasty</ENAMEX>. The final major <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of Imperial Peace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jin An Dian</ENAMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Daoist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xuanwu</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God of Fire</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>
Occupying <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 hectares</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">99 acres</NUMEX>) directly south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Guangchang</ENAMEX>) is the largest public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> on earth. This vast expanse did not exist during the time of the emperors, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX> it became <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs primary public meeting place for national ceremonies and political demonstrations. It was enlarged to its present size under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Zedong</ENAMEX>. To celebrate the golden anniversary of the founding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">People‚Äôs Republic</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 October 1949</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> was recently renovated, with granite replacing the old paving blocks.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">500-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qianmen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Front Gate</ENAMEX>), one of the original <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> gates of the city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX>, still stands at the south end of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> (next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrow Tower</ENAMEX>). Most of the other gates fell when the wall was demolished during the modernization of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1958‚Äì1959</NUMEX>. This towering edifice, which houses a photographic exhibition of old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, can be climbed for a view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>. The imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> once passed through here on its annual procession to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of Heaven.
Also located on the south side of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Zedong Mausoleum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Zhuxi Jinian Bei</ENAMEX>), opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chairman‚</ENAMEX>Äôs death. Especially popular with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, it consists of a reception <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall¬†‚Äî¬†with</ENAMEX> a statue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Helmsman</ENAMEX> seated on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúthrone‚Äù¬†‚Äî¬</ENAMEX>†and an inner <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> lies in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in a crystal sarcophagus. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> maintain a respectful silence and are quickly ushered through to a gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> at the back.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monument</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">People‚Äôs Heroes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renmin Yinxiong Jinian Bei</ENAMEX>), on the west side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>, became internationally renowned when it served as the command post for pro-democracy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1989</TIMEX> occupation of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen</ENAMEX>. The granite obelisk, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">38 m</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">124 ft</ENAMEX>) high, was erected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>. It contains calligraphy carved in the hand of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> and is engraved with stirring scenes of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary</ENAMEX> history.
The massive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Hall of the People</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renmin Dahui Tang</ENAMEX>) borders the west side of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">nearly 1 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over half</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX>). It opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX> and has served as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislative headquarters</ENAMEX> ever since. Whenever the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National People‚Äôs Congress</ENAMEX> is not in session, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Hall</ENAMEX> is open to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, who can enter its banquet <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> reception <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> (one for each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX>), and glittering main auditorium, which holds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> is home to the large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard halls</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>. To the north is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of the Chinese Revolution</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zhongguo Gemin Lishi Bowuguan</ENAMEX>), with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 10,000</NUMEX> items that document revolutionary politics, most focusing on events in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early</TIMEX> history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1919‚Äì1949</ENAMEX>).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Chinese History</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zhongguo Lishi Bowuguan</ENAMEX>), to the south, is of more general interest. It ranks among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> and has the nation‚Äôs largest holdings. Its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX> priceless artifacts, displayed on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> levels, are arranged chronologically from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone Age</ENAMEX> through the final dynasty, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing</ENAMEX>. Although bereft of up-to-date display cases and featuring explanations written in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> only, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> provides the most exhaustive overview of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">civilization¬†‚Äî¬†illustrated</ENAMEX> with national treasures¬†‚Äî¬†of any <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.
Wangfujing Street
Beijing‚Äôs top shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> is also the site of many cultural and historic attractions. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wangfujing Street</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wangfujing Dajie</ENAMEX>) begins a few blocks east of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> and runs north from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chang‚Äôan Avenue</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing Hotel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing Fandian</ENAMEX>) began as the ‚ÄúGrand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel de Pekin‚Äù</ENAMEX> under foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX>, has had several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX> added over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX>, and is worth strolling through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as an architectural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs evolution in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX>. Wangfujing itself has a long history, serving as the exclusive neighborhood of the well-connected and the rich during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing</ENAMEX> dynasties. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Westerners</ENAMEX> moved to the district in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late-19th century</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> was known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison Street</ENAMEX> for a time, after a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Times</ENAMEX> correspondent. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tradesmen</ENAMEX> had long done business in the neighborhood‚Äôs tiny attached <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX>, which are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> filled with an assortment of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, silk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art galleries</ENAMEX>, street markets, and modern shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plazas</ENAMEX>.
Beijing‚Äôs grandest modern shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Dong</ENAMEX> An <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Plaza</ENAMEX> (at No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wangfujing</ENAMEX>): <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> levels of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarkets</ENAMEX>, and fast-food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>. Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wangfujing Department Store</ENAMEX> (at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 255</NUMEX>), once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most up-to-date emporium but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> something of an amusing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">throwback</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>. Farther up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs best stop for book browsers, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Language Bookstore</ENAMEX> (at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 235</NUMEX>), boasting the capital‚Äôs largest collection of non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> books and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> again to find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph‚Äôs Catholic Church</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dong Tang</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúEast Church‚</ENAMEX>Äù that was leveled during the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Boxer Rebellion</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>) and immediately rebuilt; it is now open for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> masses (in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> only).
At the north end of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wangfujing Street</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">China Art Gallery</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zhongguo Meishuguan</ENAMEX>), the national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art gallery</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Within this monumental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> style, are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> with contemporary as well as traditional artworks. There are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> at work in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>, and recent works can be purchased in the gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>.
At the south end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wangfujing</ENAMEX> (one block west, on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dongdan Street</ENAMEX>), near an open-air stamp and coin market, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Hospital</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xiehe Yiyuan</ENAMEX>), which has an emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>. It was founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915</TIMEX>, located in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX>, and underwritten by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Rockefeller</ENAMEX>. It was previously known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peking Union Medical Hospital</ENAMEX>.
Nearby, at the intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wangfujing</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chang‚Äôan Avenue</ENAMEX>, is the capital‚Äôs oldest site, the recently unearthed remains of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20,000-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone Age</ENAMEX> settlement, complete with human fossils, buffalo bones, and hunting tools. Ironically, it is situated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs newest attractions: the huge <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Oriental Plaza</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Beijing</ENAMEX>
The neighborhoods north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> are the most scenic in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, encompassing imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and lakes, temples and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>, princely <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX>, and some of the city‚Äôs most interesting older neighborhoods.
An atmosphere of imperial leisure is cast by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jingshan Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jingshan Gongyuan</ENAMEX>), also called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coal Hill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meishan</ENAMEX>), rising immediately north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>. Jingshan was built by hand from soil dredged out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace moat</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early-15th century</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A ten-minute</TIMEX> hike to the summit at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pavilion</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Everlasting Spring</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanchun Ting</ENAMEX>) is rewarded by the finest view possible of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> and its golden-tiled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>. To the right (west) of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> is a new version, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zhongnanhai</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">China‚Äôs communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are ensconced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (strictly off-limits to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beihai Park</ENAMEX>
Beijing‚Äôs oldest imperial garden, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beihai Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beihai Gongyuan</ENAMEX>), was built on the capital‚Äôs largest lake over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">800 years ago</TIMEX>. Near the south entrance, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Round City</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tuan Cheng</ENAMEX>), is a large ceremonial vessel of green jade presented in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1265</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kublai Khan</ENAMEX>, who built a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> here and entertained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco Polo</ENAMEX> on these lake shores in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 13th century</TIMEX>.
Scenic <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hortensia Island</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qionghua Dao</ENAMEX>), built from the soil excavated to create <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beihai‚Äôs lake</ENAMEX>, is crowned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Pagoda</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bai Ta</ENAMEX>), one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs landmarks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tibetan</ENAMEX> in style, this dagoba commemorates a visit by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1651</TIMEX> and measures <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">36 m</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">118 ft</ENAMEX>) in height. At its foot on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jade Hill</ENAMEX>, to the south, is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yongan Temple</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yongan Si</ENAMEX>), a well-preserved <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lamaist Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. The north shore of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is bordered by a covered walkway, known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Painted Gallery</ENAMEX>, and a cluster of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX> imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>. Located here is a traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fangshan</ENAMEX>, founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chefs</ENAMEX> who once cooked for the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>.
On the western shore of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beihai‚</ENAMEX>Äôs lake are several pavilions and gardens built during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX>, including a fine rock and water garden, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hao Pu Jian</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Empress Dowager Cixi</ENAMEX> listened to music. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Studio of the Painted Boat</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hua Fang Zhai</ENAMEX>) is another shore <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garden</ENAMEX>, built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qianlong</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX>, famous for its large square stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pool</ENAMEX>. On the northern shore of the lake is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Studio of the Serene Mind</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jing Xin Zhai</ENAMEX>), a favorite retreat of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚Äôs</ENAMEX> last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puyi</ENAMEX>. On the eastern shore is a double-sided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nine Dragon Screen</ENAMEX>, created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX> from glazed tiles, similar to the more famous version in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>.
The pavilions, pagodas, and rookeries on the northeast shore are known collectively as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gardens Within Gardens</ENAMEX>, where the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> once enjoyed the lake. Its most arresting site is Little Western Heaven (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xiao Xi Tian</ENAMEX>), which consists of a square pagoda and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>, erected as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Goddess of Mercy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guanyin</ENAMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1770</TIMEX>. Tour <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> depart the eastern shore from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Five Dragons Pavilion</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hortensia Island</ENAMEX>.
Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beihai</ENAMEX> lake is no longer restricted to the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, and it is the most popular spot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> to rent a rowboat in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> or to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-skate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX>.
Back <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX> and Hutongs
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> front lakes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nanhai, Zhonghai</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beihai</ENAMEX>, run along the west side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chang‚Äôan Avenue</ENAMEX> north to where they connect with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Back Lakes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shi Sha Hai</ENAMEX>), known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qianhai, Houhai</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xihai</ENAMEX>. These lakes once comprised the route used to ship <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grain</ENAMEX> and luxuries via the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Canal</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>. Later, this was the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">waterway</ENAMEX> employed by imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">barges</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> desired an outing. These interconnected lakes are marvelous places to stroll. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Back Lakes District</ENAMEX> contains many landmarks of old <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Beijing¬†‚Äî¬</ENAMEX>†from princely <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX> to old temples and gardens¬†‚Äî¬†but it is best known for its colorful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alleyways</ENAMEX> and traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard houses</ENAMEX>.
At the northern tip of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Back Lakes</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huifeng Temple</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huifeng Si</ENAMEX>). Perched on a tiny rocky isle in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Xihai Lake</ENAMEX>, it is a wonderful spot for a lake view and a picnic. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, on the north side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Ring Road</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deshengmen Arrow Tower</ENAMEX>, a gate and archers‚Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ming Dynasty</ENAMEX> that survived the demolition of the great city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX>. Inside is a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> devoted to the history of the local hutong neighborhoods. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gate‚Äôs courtyard</ENAMEX> are a coin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> and antiques market.
On the eastern shore of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houhai Lake</ENAMEX>, the middle of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Back Lakes</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Soong Ching-ling Residence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Song Ching Ling Guzhu</ENAMEX>), where the famous Soong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> who married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sun Yat-sen</ENAMEX> lived from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> until her death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>. Her estate and its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">200-year-old</TIMEX> classical garden are now a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, filled with photographs and heirlooms of her remarkable life. On the same lake shore is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guanghua Temple</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guanghua Si</ENAMEX>), a small <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> that has returned to life after being severely damaged by rampaging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Guards</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cultural Revolution</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1966‚Äì1976</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly two dozen</NUMEX> monks reside here.
A few blocks east of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guanghau Temple</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Drum Tower</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gu Lou) and Bell Tower</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhong Lou</ENAMEX>). Both can be climbed for splendid views of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Back Lakes District</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Drum Tower</ENAMEX> (open <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9am‚Äì4:30pm</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>; free) is the more interesting of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. The capital‚Äôs first <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Drum Tower</ENAMEX>, from which the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> were signaled with drums, was built here by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kublai Khan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1272</TIMEX>, rebuilt by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming Emperor Yongle</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1420</TIMEX>, and renovated under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing</ENAMEX> emperors. A side stairway leads to the balcony, where one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> original watch drums remains, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">what‚Äôs</ENAMEX> claimed to be the world‚Äôs largest drum (made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>).
Qianhai, the most southern of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Back Lakes</ENAMEX>, connects to the lake in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beihai Park</ENAMEX>. It is famous for its views of the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hills</ENAMEX>. Under the willow <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> on its western shore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> set up an enormous outdoor market (known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus Flower Market</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lianghua Shichang</ENAMEX>), which sells <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> opera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> in the evenings.
On the west side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Back Lakes</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gong‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mansion</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gong Wang Fu</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs best-preserved example of an imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prince Gong</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚Äôs</ENAMEX> last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puyi</ENAMEX>, occupied this estate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-19th century</TIMEX>, making use of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> and pavilions as his private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>. The estate contains numerous courtyards, arched <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>, ponds, rock gardens, and its own pagoda.
The neighborhoods of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Back Lakes District</ENAMEX> are filled with the hutongs (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX>) and siheyuans (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard houses</ENAMEX>) that were characteristic of urban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing</ENAMEX> dynasties. They are common even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> of the capital‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> living in some form of rectangular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard compound</ENAMEX>. Nevertheless, hutongs and siheyuans are endangered symbols of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Beijing‚Äôs</ENAMEX> past, constantly under threat of urban renewal. Fewer than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard dwellings</ENAMEX> are preserved in cultural protection zones. Although it would have once been occupied by a single rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> (plus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is shared by many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
The hutongs can be toured on your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">own¬†‚Äî¬†on</ENAMEX> foot, by rented <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycle</ENAMEX>, or by hiring one of the canopied pedicabs in the area. But most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> prefer a guided tour. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing Hutong Tourist Agency</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6615-9097</TIMEX>), which books tours through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> desks, has a fleet of red-canopied pedicabs led by an English-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX>. Its hutong tour combines many of the sights in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Back Lakes District</ENAMEX> with the opportunity to step inside a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard house</ENAMEX> and talk with its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">modern-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama Temple</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confucius Temple</ENAMEX>
Beijing‚Äôs most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama Temple</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yong He Gong</ENAMEX>). Built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1694</TIMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> who became the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yongzheng</ENAMEX>, it was converted to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1744</TIMEX>. Under the reign of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qianlong</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> served as the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibetan Buddhism</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yellow Hat sect</ENAMEX>) outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lhasa</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama Temple</ENAMEX> is large and ornate, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 200</NUMEX> monks in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
Its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> central worship <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> are spacious. Between the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> is the capital‚Äôs oldest incense burner (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1747</TIMEX>). The throne of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> is in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">worship hall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Dian</ENAMEX>). The final hall contains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama Temple‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most revered statue, a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">23-m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX>-ft) image of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> carved from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">sandalwood tree</ENAMEX>, its head peeking out of the pavilion‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> story. The side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> have large collections of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> and carved <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> figures, including many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tantric</ENAMEX> statues whose more explicit features are discreetly draped in colorful silk scarves.
Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from the usually packed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama Temple</ENAMEX> is the serene <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confucius Temple</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kong Miao</ENAMEX>), the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> to the great philosopher outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confucius‚</ENAMEX>Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qu Fu</ENAMEX>. Built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1306</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> was long part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial College</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guozi Jian</ENAMEX>), and its courtyards teem with scores of carved stone tablets honoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who passed the nationwide civil service examinations from the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kublai Khan</ENAMEX>.
The most interesting display is located in the long side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> on the eastern wall. It is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> history that furnishes a comprehensive overview, with signs in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>. In another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confucius Temple</ENAMEX> is a complete edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confucian</ENAMEX> classics carved in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>. Near the entrance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> (just inside the main gate) is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donald Sussman Center for Chinese Antiquities</ENAMEX>, opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. At the north end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> there is a statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confucius</ENAMEX> and a collection of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> stone drums used in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Confucian</ENAMEX> ceremonies.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Beijing</ENAMEX>
Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> venture into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xuanwu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chongwen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> south of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chang‚Äôan Avenue</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> except to visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of Heaven and perhaps to walk along the charming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Liulichang Culture Street</ENAMEX>. But there are other sights of interest.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Legation</ENAMEX>, where foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> maintained their own autonomous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1860 to 1937</TIMEX>, lies east of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>. No longer the location of the diplomatic compounds in the capital, this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> still contains many former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, and commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, most now converted to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. The architecture is fascinating. Located along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taijichang Dajie</ENAMEX> (the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs Street</ENAMEX>), directly south of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dongchang‚Äôan Jie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chang‚Äôan Avenue East</ENAMEX>), are the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> Legation (now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute of International Studies</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> Legation (now the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People‚Äôs Association</ENAMEX> for Friendship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Countries</ENAMEX>), the private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Peking Club</ENAMEX> (now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing People‚Äôs Congress</ENAMEX>), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Legation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Barracks</ENAMEX> (now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Workers Union</ENAMEX>).
Westward along <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jiaominxiang</ENAMEX> toward <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">neo-Gothic St. Michael‚Äôs Church</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1902</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and still active. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> also find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">German Hospital</ENAMEX> (now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing Hospital</ENAMEX>) here, and the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX> up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhengyi Lu</ENAMEX> (the former <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Canal Street</ENAMEX>) back toward <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chang‚Äôan Avenue</ENAMEX> are the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> Legation (now the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing Mayor‚Äôs office</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Legation</ENAMEX>, once the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> stronghold in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> (occupied from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860 to 1959</TIMEX>), now the stronghold of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> security services.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>, in the city‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Xuanwu District</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ox Street Mosque</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Niu Jie Qingzhen Si</ENAMEX>), the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most vibrant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Muslem quarter</TIMEX>. Here the capital‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hui</ENAMEX> minority¬†‚Äî¬†largely indistinguishable from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Beijing‚Äôs Han Chinese majority¬†‚Äî¬</ENAMEX>†practice many of the ways of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>, which arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> from the far western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silk Road</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tang Dynasty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">618‚Äì907</ENAMEX>). This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>, originally constructed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 996</TIMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> in style but contains a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-sided astronomical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>, a bathhouse, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prayer hall</ENAMEX> facing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mecca</ENAMEX>, a minaret for calling the faithful to prayer, and tombs of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Moslem</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> dating to the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kublai Khan</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Beijing</ENAMEX> is also the location of the city‚Äôs main <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Cathedral</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nan Tang</ENAMEX>), also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary‚Äôs Church</ENAMEX>. It was constructed on the site of missionary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matteo Ricci‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1650</TIMEX> and rebuilt for the last time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904</TIMEX> after being destroyed during the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Boxer Rebellion</ENAMEX>. Offering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Cathedral</ENAMEX> has a rock garden dedicated to the Virgin near its southern entrance on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Qianmen Street</ENAMEX> West.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Source of Law</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fayuan Si</ENAMEX>), near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ox Street Mosque</ENAMEX>, dates from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tang Dynasty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">696</ENAMEX>) and houses a national <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> college and religious publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. In addition to dozens of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novice monks</ENAMEX> in training, this large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> is famous for its <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ming- and Qing-</ENAMEX>era statues and bronzes, carved stone tablets, bells, paintings, and incense <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">burners</ENAMEX>. The last of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> contains a large reclining <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Buddha 6 m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">191‚ÅÑ2 ft</ENAMEX>) long.
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand View Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daguan Yuan</ENAMEX>), located at the southwest corner of the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Ring Road</ENAMEX>, is one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs newest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> on the former site of the imperial vegetable gardens. Built to re-create the classic garden portrayed in the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> novel <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dream</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Chamber</ENAMEX>, it is filled with traditional features of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mandarin estates</ENAMEX>: lakes, pavilions, arched <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>, and pagodas.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chongwen District</ENAMEX> of southeast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> popular attractions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panjiayuan</ENAMEX> (known variously as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dirt Market or Ghost Market</ENAMEX>) is the capital‚Äôs top open-air market for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antiques</ENAMEX> and curios, best visited as early as possible on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural History Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ziran Bowuguan</ENAMEX>) has China‚Äôs best display of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur skeletons</ENAMEX>. It is located near south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs leading attraction, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of Heaven (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiantan</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of Heaven
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of Heaven (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiantan</ENAMEX>), built under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming Emperor Yongle</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1420</TIMEX> as a site for sacred rites, is located directly south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the site is called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heaven Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiantan Gongyuan</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> would lead a procession from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> to the altar here to perform the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> rites and sacrifices to heaven. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most remarkable architectural works survives from that era of imperial ritual, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hall of Prayer for Good Harvests</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qinian Dian</ENAMEX>), a circular hall with blue-tiled roofs capped by a golden sphere. The entire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> was constructed without nails or cross beams, its magnificent arched ceiling supported by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> carved pillars. This <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> survived until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1889</TIMEX>, when lightning burned it to the ground, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reconstruction</ENAMEX> is superb, and the round <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> has become an emblem of imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately, its ornate interior can only be glimpsed from outside, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> are no longer allowed within.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other important monuments survive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tiantan Park</ENAMEX>, both located on the axis running south from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hall of Prayer for Good Harvests</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial Vault of Heaven</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang Qiong Yu</ENAMEX>), built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1530</TIMEX>, resembles the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Prayer</ENAMEX>; stone tablets used in the winter solstice rituals were once stored here. It is surrounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echo Wall</ENAMEX>, into which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> attempt to whisper messages that can be heard by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> at distant points along the wall. The southernmost monument is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Circular Altar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yuan Qiu</ENAMEX>), an open platform dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1530</TIMEX> where silk was once burned as a sacrifice to the heavenly powers. Its acoustics are said to allow orations to be broadcast for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> in all directions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heaven Park</ENAMEX> is an excellent place to take a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> stroll. It‚Äôs popular with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> seeking a quiet bench for reading and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> performing their <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> tai chi exercises.
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Liulichang Culture Street</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dazhalan Mall</ENAMEX>
The flavor of the old capital‚Äôs commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> is best preserved along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Liulichang Culture Street</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liulichang Xijie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liulichang Dongjie</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dazhalan Mall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dazhalan Jie</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">conjoined avenues</ENAMEX> south of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> that run east-to-west for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 11‚ÅÑ2 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 mile</NUMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Liulichang Culture Street</ENAMEX>, the shopping haunt of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and antiques fanciers since the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ming Dynasty</ENAMEX>, was restored in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. Its tile-roofed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> sell curios, antiques, traditional art supplies, scrolls, paintings, prints, and old books. Among its renowned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rongbaozhai</ENAMEX> (art and art supplies), the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">China Bookstore</ENAMEX> (old books), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jijuge</ENAMEX> (a teahouse featuring clay figures from tombs), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wenshenzhai</ENAMEX> (former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purveyor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> and paper lanterns to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX>).
Liulichang merges with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dazhalan Mall</ENAMEX>, a cobblestone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> closed to motor traffic that offers still more window-shopping: historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> for traditional herbal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX>, shoes, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pickles</ENAMEX>, and silk fabric and clothing. The east end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dazhalan</ENAMEX> pedestrian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> is intersected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhubaoshi Jie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jewelry Street</ENAMEX>), once the major theater and brothel district of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> and now the site of a lively <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk bazaar</ENAMEX>. Zhubaoshi Street connects <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dazhalan</ENAMEX> directly to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qianmen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Beijing</ENAMEX>
The areas east of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chang‚Äôan Avenue</ENAMEX> and northeast up the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Third Ring Road</ENAMEX> (both sections of the vast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chaoyang</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX>) have received the brunt of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs modernization. Here <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chang‚Äôan Avenue</ENAMEX> changes its name to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jianguomenwai Dajie</ENAMEX>, the location of some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs finest international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs best shopping opportunities. The same can be said for the northeast section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Third Ring Road</ENAMEX>, where major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plazas</ENAMEX> are also concentrated, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚Äôs first Hard Rock Cafe</ENAMEX>. Located between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stretches is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sanlitun Diplomatic Compound</ENAMEX>, which has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">capital‚Äôs liveliest nightlife</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, caf√©s, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, and historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east Beijing</ENAMEX> attract <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> and after dark.
Jianguomen
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">eastern</ENAMEX> section of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chang‚Äôan Avenue</ENAMEX>, between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second</ENAMEX> and Third <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring roads</ENAMEX>, is known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jianguomen</ENAMEX> (after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of old <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> gates, now the site of a subway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>). A number of international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> have located here, and there also numerous shopping opportunities
At the intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jianguomenwai Dajie</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Ring Road East</ENAMEX> there is a major shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> in the massive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China World Trade Center</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> range from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Starbucks</ENAMEX> coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a cyber-caf√©</NUMEX> to an ice-skating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rink</ENAMEX>. Additional shopping options along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jianguomenwai Dajie</ENAMEX> include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friendship Store</ENAMEX>, the best place to browse for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> gifts and souvenirs, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silk Alley Market</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xiushui Shichang</ENAMEX>), the city‚Äôs most popular open-air clothing market. Once celebrated for its silks and bargain prices, the crowded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silk Alley</ENAMEX> stalls are now filled with name-brand, logo, and knockoff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> sportswear. Running north for several blocks from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jianguomenwai Dajie, Silk Alley</ENAMEX> is a lively bazaar requiring abundant bargaining and haggling skills; there are no set prices. The market leads into a quiet, modern foreign diplomatic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>, home to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> including those of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>.
Just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silk Alley</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friendship Store</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ritan Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritan Gongyuan</ENAMEX>), location in imperial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Altar</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>. The altar¬†‚Äî¬†where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> performed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">rites¬†‚Äî¬†was erected</ENAMEX> on a hill in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1530</TIMEX> and is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> crowned by a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ritan Park</ENAMEX> contains a serene rock garden and fishing pond in its southwest corner. On its northwest side is the large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Market</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yabaolu</ENAMEX>), where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> cater to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> with carpets, crafts, and clothing, including <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leather goods</ENAMEX>, furs, and boots.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient Observatory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚Äôs Ancient Observatory</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guguan Xiang Tai</ENAMEX>) was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1442</TIMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ming Dynasty</ENAMEX>. It is at the intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chang‚Äôan Avenue</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Ring Road East</ENAMEX>; almost immediately below it is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway station</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">observatory</ENAMEX> supplanted one created by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kublai Khan</ENAMEX>. Inside the brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>, which looks like a remnant of the old city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX>, are astronomical displays, including a gold foil map of the heavens as they were plotted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">500 years ago</TIMEX>. On the open roof is a fine collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX> bronze instruments (copies) devised by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jesuit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> who resided in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX>. The view from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX> of downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> is superb.
Sanlitun
Located in the heart of a large foreign diplomatic district between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dongzhimenwai Dajie</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Liangma River</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanlitun</ENAMEX> has become the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nightlife district</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. Many of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> or more small <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">caf√©s¬†‚Äî¬†offering international cuisine</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> and drinking and music by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">night¬†‚Äî¬†are</ENAMEX> located on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanlitun Lu</ENAMEX>, which has been officially named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanlitun Bar Street</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanlitun Jiuba Jie</ENAMEX>). Many of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expatriates</ENAMEX> and foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, as well as the city‚Äôs younger <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, gather here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each summer</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> drinking, dining, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>-watching. On the west side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanlitun Lu</ENAMEX> there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> open-air markets, one selling rattan furniture and bamboo crafts, the other offering Western-style <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>-label clothing.
Sanlitun caf√©s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> now stretch southeast of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanlitun Lu</ENAMEX> down a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lane</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dongdaqiao Xie Jie</ENAMEX>. This leads to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Workers‚Äô Stadium</ENAMEX> area and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs oldest expatriate American-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">grill, Frank‚Äôs Place</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanlitun</ENAMEX> is devoid of historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, it stands out as modern <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most international neighborhood.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Beijing</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs top attractions, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX> and the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hills</ENAMEX>, are located northwest of the capital‚Äôs relentless urban sprawl. This is the beautiful, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hilly</NUMEX> countryside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Haidian District</ENAMEX> (home to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> and computer technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX>). And closer to city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, the western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">precincts</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> are the site of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> major temples, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing Art Museum</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing Zoo</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summer Palace</ENAMEX>
The site of imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> since the reign of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kublai Khan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yi He Yuan</ENAMEX>) achieved its present form during reconstructions from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1749 to 1764</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emperor Qianlong</ENAMEX> saw to the expansion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, its hills, and its lake, and he added pavilions and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> that stand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> used the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX> as its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> home, escaping the heat of central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>. Today, it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> alike. Many say it is the most beautiful imperial garden in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">China¬†‚Äî¬</ENAMEX>†a large-scale garden equivalent to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> or estate.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX> was twice destroyed after its expansion under the early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Qing</ENAMEX> emperors. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860</TIMEX>, during the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Opium War</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> and ransacked and ruined many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Empress Dowager Cixi</ENAMEX> saw to a complete restoration in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1886</TIMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> returned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX> in retaliation for the siege of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Legation</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Boxer Rebellion</ENAMEX>. Undaunted, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress Dowager</ENAMEX> completed a second restoration in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX> became her countryside version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> of choice even when the heat of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> diminished. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX> was opened to the public in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">280</NUMEX>-hectare (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">700-acre</NUMEX>) Summer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palace</ENAMEX> is dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kunming Lake</ENAMEX>, which itself is subdivided into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Lake</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Lake</ENAMEX> by several causeways. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Longevity Hill</ENAMEX> rises above the north shore. Behind its peaks is a version of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beijing‚Äôs Back Lakes</ENAMEX>, created during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX>. The main strolling area is along the north shore of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kunming Lake</ENAMEX>, where the pavilions and courtyards are linked by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Corridor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chang Lang</ENAMEX>). This covered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">promenade</ENAMEX> stretches <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">777 m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,550 ft</NUMEX>) from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Halls west</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Marble Boat</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1750</TIMEX>, it consists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">273</NUMEX> crossbeam sections and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> pavilions. Nearly every exposed portion of its beams, panels, and pillars is decorated with a painted scene from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> myth, history, literature, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">geography¬†‚Äî¬†10,000</NUMEX> brightly painted panels in all.
Among the important imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> on the east side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Corridor</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> are worth viewing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Benevolent Longevity</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renshou Dian</ENAMEX>) is where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress Dowager Cixi</ENAMEX> received court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> from her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dragon Throne</ENAMEX> (which is still in place). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of Jade</ENAMEX> Ripples (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yulan Dian</ENAMEX>) is where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cixi</ENAMEX> confined her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guangxu</ENAMEX>, while she ruled in his place. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cultivating Happiness</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yile Dian</ENAMEX>) served as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress Dowager‚</ENAMEX>Äôs private viewing box for performances in the adjacent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, which was built to honor her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">60th</NUMEX> birthday. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cixi</ENAMEX> celebrated many of her birthdays at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX>, and she was especially fond of theatrical performances, in which she sometimes played a role. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> now contains some of her imperial garments, jewelry, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cosmetics</ENAMEX>, as well as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes-Benz</ENAMEX> said to be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> passenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long Corridor</ENAMEX> begins at a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Qing building</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Happiness and Longevity</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leshou Tang</ENAMEX>), where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress Dowager</ENAMEX> slept. The curtained bed, the lamps, and most of the furniture are original.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midway</ENAMEX> along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Corridor</ENAMEX> at the foot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Longevity Hill</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Dispelling Clouds</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pai Yun Dian</ENAMEX>), where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cixi</ENAMEX> held her birthday parties. This <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> now houses a collection of birthday gifts, including the portrait of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress Dowager</ENAMEX> painted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland‚Äôs Hubert Vos</ENAMEX> upon the occasion of her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">70th</NUMEX> birthday in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1905</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Corridor</ENAMEX> ends at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pavilion</ENAMEX> for Listening to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orioles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tingli Guan</ENAMEX>), where there is now a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> serving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qing</ENAMEX> dynasty imperial dishes.
Just beyond this point is the most famous (or perhaps notorious) monument in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Marble Boat</ENAMEX>, known officially as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boat of Purity and Ease</ENAMEX>. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beijingers</ENAMEX>, it is <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">China‚Äôs ‚Äúship</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Rebuilt</ENAMEX> with lavish <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> and stained glass) by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress Dowager</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1893</TIMEX>, this <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">36-m</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">118-ft</ENAMEX>) statue of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> was restored (it is said) with funds meant to shore up China‚Äôs woeful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">navy</ENAMEX>, but it was not long before <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> completely humiliated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in battles at sea. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cixi</ENAMEX> has been blamed ever since for her profligate and selfish ways, combined with her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machiavellian</ENAMEX> rise from concubine to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Empress</ENAMEX>, popularly held to be the cause of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs weakness and the fall of the last dynasty. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX> remains as visible testimony to the extravagance of the late <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX> at the expense of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs freedom and prosperity at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the 20th century</TIMEX>.
While many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Empress Dowager Cixi</ENAMEX> played such a villainous role, her Summer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palace</ENAMEX> is undoubtedly lavish enough to have launched countless tales of luxury and decadence. Even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the view of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Longevity Hill</ENAMEX> and its scores of tile-roofed pavilions and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>, enjoyed from a pleasure barge drifting across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Kunming</ENAMEX>, is a scene from a dream of old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in which emperors and empresses led lives in gardens of unimaginable splendor. Here even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bridges¬†‚Äî¬†connecting lake isles</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace shores¬†‚Äî¬†wouldn‚Äôt</ENAMEX> be out of place in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX> or Qing scroll painting, particularly the celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Seventeen-Arch Bridge</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiqi Kong Qiao</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">150 m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">492 ft</ENAMEX>) long and built of white marble.
Not far from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX> is the site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Summer Palace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yuan Ming Yuan</ENAMEX>). When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kangxi</ENAMEX> built this imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX>, it had no equal. However, after its destruction in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, it was left to decay, and the court‚Äôs attention turned to restoring the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX>. All that‚Äôs left now in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Summer Palace</ENAMEX> are some of the most haunting ruins in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, particularly in a section known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Garden of Eternal Spring</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Changchun Yuan</ENAMEX>), where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>, marble fountains, mazes, and a concert <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stand</ENAMEX> are now a broken jumble of ornately carved columns and arches. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every few years</TIMEX> there are fresh announcements that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Summer Palace</ENAMEX> will be restored to its former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">glories</ENAMEX>. For now, it provides a quiet picnic grounds amidst the ruins of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Hills</ENAMEX>
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> really wanted to escape the heat of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, they went farther west than the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX> to the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hills</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Xi Shan</ENAMEX>), romantically known <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fragrant Hills Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xiangshan Gong</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">yuan</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial</ENAMEX> villas first dotted these hillsides¬†‚Äî¬<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">†27 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">17 miles</NUMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing¬†‚Äî¬†more</ENAMEX> than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">800 years ago</TIMEX>. But it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qianlong</ENAMEX> who converted the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hills</ENAMEX> into a formal mountain retreat for the enjoyment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, complete with its own temples, lakes, gardens, and even a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX>. Late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX> is the favorite season for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, when leaves turn a fiery red. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> come to the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hills</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round for the natural beauty and historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> renowned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">temples</ENAMEX> still survive in the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hills</ENAMEX>. Near the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">park‚Äôs</NUMEX> north gate are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> great <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleeping Buddha</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wo Fo Si</ENAMEX>). In the final <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wo Fo Dian</ENAMEX>) there is a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5-m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>-ft) lacquered statue of the reclining <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> (dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1321</TIMEX>) about to attain nirvana.
Inside the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">park‚Äôs</NUMEX> north gate is an even larger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Azure Clouds</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biyun Si</ENAMEX>), which ascends the hillside. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sun Yat-sen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Republic</ENAMEX>, once lay in state here before removal to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nanjing</ENAMEX>; his hat, coat, and coffin are still at this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>. So, too, is the fascinating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luohan Hall</ENAMEX>. Luohans are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> who achieve enlightenment but choose to stay on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> to show others the way. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> luohans portrayed in this temple‚Äôs carved figures range from the ecstatic to the gruesome, from the common to the surreal. Topping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diamond Throne Pagoda</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jinggang Baozuo Ta</ENAMEX>), built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1748</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> style, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> pagodas and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stupas surrounding a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35-m</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">115-ft</ENAMEX>) white pagoda.
The most popular site in the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hills</ENAMEX> is natural: a summit known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incense Burner Peak</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xiang Lu Feng</ENAMEX>), named for the image created when fog comes sweeping over it. There is a winding path to the top known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gui Jian Chou</ENAMEX> (‚ÄúEven the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terrified‚Äù</ENAMEX>) as well as a chair lift (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX> each way). At the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">557-m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,827</NUMEX>-ft) summit there are pavilions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX>, and small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">paths</ENAMEX> into surrounding forests. There are also fine views of the lakes, temples, pavilions, and pagodas below, which can be explored upon return. On a clear day, one is tempted to linger. Here, there‚Äôs an emperor‚Äôs view to the southeast, commanding both the pavilions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX> and the skyscrapers of downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Cloud Temple</ENAMEX>
Beijing‚Äôs most active <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Daoist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bai Yun Guan</ENAMEX>, is better known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Cloud Temple</ENAMEX>. This is also the capital‚Äôs most fascinating religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>, a place of superstition and incense, mystery and spirited worship. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs leading indigenous religion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Daoism</ENAMEX> differs from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddhism</ENAMEX> (transplanted from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>) not so much in the architecture of its temples and the art of its statuary (these are often quite similar in style) as in its practices and beliefs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daoism</ENAMEX> emphasized nature, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Way</ENAMEX>, but in its organized form it relies on a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">pantheon of gods</ENAMEX>, goddesses, and supernatural icons promising miracles.
At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baiyunguan</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> features the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wind Containing Bridge</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> attempt to ensure their good fortune by striking a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX> copper bell with coins. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spring Hall for the Jade Emperor</ENAMEX>, worshippers touch the golden feet of statues representing the gods of wealth. In the side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> there are <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX> where the devout can appeal to the proper god to cure eye problems, ensure the birth of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, pass an examination, get a good job, and increase longevity. Every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these ‚Äúwishing halls‚Äù is usually jammed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>, who are often dressed in their most expensive clothes for the tour. Festivals on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and fifteenth of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lunar month</TIMEX> are especially lively times to visit. At the rear of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> there is a large rock garden, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX> where many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novice monks</ENAMEX> are trained in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Daoism</ENAMEX>.
Baiyunguan was founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">739</TIMEX> and received its present name in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1394</TIMEX>. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> date from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX>, although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yuanchen Hall</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> try to locate the deity on the zodiac of their birthday, dates from the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kublai Khan</ENAMEX>. Just south of this temple <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tianning Si Ta</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple of Heavenly Tranquillity Pagoda</ENAMEX>, built during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liao Dynasty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">907‚Äì1125</ENAMEX>), making it <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs oldest surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">58 m</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">190 ft</ENAMEX>) high and is decorated with fine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> carvings.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Pagoda Temple</ENAMEX>
Extensively renovated and enlarged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Pagoda Temple</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bai Ta Si</ENAMEX>) is renowned for its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibetan</ENAMEX>-style pagoda (usually called a dagoba or stupa). The white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pagoda</ENAMEX> at this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> is larger than the more famous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beihai Park</ENAMEX>. In fact, it is the largest of its type in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1279</TIMEX> during the reign of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kublai Khan</ENAMEX>.
The main gate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Pagoda Temple</ENAMEX> (located on the north side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fuchingmennei Dajie</ENAMEX>), the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> are new. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum houses</ENAMEX> many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> artifacts and statues discovered on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> grounds, as well as a sutra copied out by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qianlong</ENAMEX>. This rare manuscript, unearthed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>, was composed in the emperor‚Äôs own hand in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1753</TIMEX>. Beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> to the north are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> finely restored prayer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of the Great Enlightened Ones</ENAMEX> is stuffed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddhas</ENAMEX>. The white pagoda itself, rising <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">51 m</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">167 ft</ENAMEX>), is last and, like most dagobas, remains sealed, its holy treasures and relics somewhere beneath or inside the imposing structure.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pagoda Temple</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing Zoo</ENAMEX>, across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nanchang River</ENAMEX>, is one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most beautiful sights, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Five Pagoda Temple</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wu Ta Si</ENAMEX>). Its singular main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> consists of a square stone building <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">71‚ÅÑ2 m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> ft) high, its outside walls decorated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one thousand</NUMEX> niches, each containing an engraved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> is crowned with a cluster of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> elaborate towering pagodas, with stairs inside leading up to a view from the roof. The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five-pagoda</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> in style. It was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1473</TIMEX>, during the early <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ming Dynasty</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> was originally part of the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zhengjue Temple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> (built during the reign of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming Emperor Yongle</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1420s</TIMEX> and sacked by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860 and 1900</TIMEX>). On the same grounds today is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing Stone Engraving Art Museum</ENAMEX>, an open-air display of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 500</NUMEX> ancient stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">carvings</ENAMEX> and inscribed stone pillars.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bell Temple</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bell Temple</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Da Zhong Si</ENAMEX>) received its apt name in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1743</TIMEX>, when the largest bronze bell in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> was placed here. This huge bell, weighing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">34,000 kg</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">46 tons</NUMEX>) and measuring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> ft) high, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1420</TIMEX>, just as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> was finished. It is on display in its own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> at the rear of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bell Temple</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Locals</ENAMEX> often climb the stairs to the top of the big bell and drop coins through an opening for good luck, a ritual that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of pilgrims in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> followed.
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bell Temple</ENAMEX> has served as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs bell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 700</NUMEX> bells in its collection. A few of the bells are modern (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> to commemorate recent events), and some are from foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, but most are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> antiquities. Among the bells displayed in the various <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> and pavilions are some that are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4,000 years old</TIMEX>. For a small fee, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> can sound a set of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone chimes</ENAMEX> that date from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Warring States Period</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">475‚Äì221 b.c.</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art Museum</ENAMEX>
Doubling as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing Art Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zhongguo Meishuguan</ENAMEX>) is housed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanshou Temple</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple of Longevity</ENAMEX>. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, renovated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1761</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qianlong</ENAMEX>, is no longer active, it contains many old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX>, including the bell and drum <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>, which date from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1577</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress Dowager Cixi</ENAMEX> used to lodge overnight in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> on her voyage by royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">barge</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX>. The large meditation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> at the center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">temple complex</ENAMEX> is now an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art gallery</ENAMEX> containing modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> oil paintings. Side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> feature other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art</ENAMEX> exhibits, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ceramics</ENAMEX>, historic relics, and artworks and crafts for sale.
At the rear of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanshou Temple</ENAMEX> is a large rock garden with shrines to the gods of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism‚</ENAMEX>Äôs sacred mountains in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilions</ENAMEX> built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1761</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> housing a stone tablet with the engraved signature of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qianlong</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> arched gates constructed in the style of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing Zoo</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing Zoo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing Dongwu Yuan</ENAMEX>) is the creation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress Dowager Cixi</ENAMEX>, who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908</TIMEX> converted this private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ming Dynasty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garden estate</ENAMEX> into a preserve for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 700</NUMEX> exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> imported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. The entrance gate dates from the late <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX>, and many of the exhibition <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> seem nearly as old. Even the outdoor pens seem quite dated. With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 6,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> is the largest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, but despite its notable collection of giant pandas, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Siberian tigers</ENAMEX>, golden <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX>, and red-crowned cranes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> is in need of modernization. Few foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> are happy with the size and condition of the cages, although the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Panda Garden</ENAMEX>, featuring a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half-dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult pandas</ENAMEX> and twin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>, is a bit more spacious and a step in the right direction. Most of the zoo‚Äôs recent major funding has gone to the creation of the adjacent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing Aquarium</ENAMEX>, a state-of-the-art marine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> scheduled to have <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50,000 aquatic</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>.
Excursions
