



A Brief History
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has frequently been at the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> history, from the rise and fall of dynasties to the recent triumphs and tragedies at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>. Each great phase left visible marks on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, and the capital is a virtual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> devoted to the world‚Äôs oldest continuous civilization.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peking Man</ENAMEX>
The skull and bones of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prehistoric resident</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peking Man</ENAMEX>, were discovered <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 miles</NUMEX>) southwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>. This excavation at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zhoukoudian</ENAMEX>, estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000‚</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Äì690,000 years old</TIMEX>, constituted one of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> in modern paleontology, since it was the first evidence that early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Homo erectus</ENAMEX>) might have evolved in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peking Man Caves</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zhoukoudian</ENAMEX> are still a major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> tourist site, although many of the important fossils are in collections outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.
Within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> itself, there was no evidence of prehistoric settlement until the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">accidental</ENAMEX> discovery in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone Age</ENAMEX> village barely <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 km</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">half a mile</NUMEX>) from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City and Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>. The stone implements and human fossils at this site, beneath the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Oriental Plaza</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, are now on public view in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement gallery</ENAMEX>. They push the known human settlement of central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> back to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> b.c.
Capital of the Khans
There are records of a town existing at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> as early as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Zhou Dynasty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1100‚Äì771 b.c.</ENAMEX>), but the growth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> did not begin until the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tang Dynasty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">a.d. 618‚Äì907</ENAMEX>). Invaders from the north, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khitan</ENAMEX>, swept down and made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> their secondary capital, from which they controlled much of northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. This period was known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liao Dynasty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">a.d. 916‚Äì1125</ENAMEX>), but there are almost no traces of it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liao</ENAMEX> capital at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, then known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yanjing</ENAMEX>, occupied the southeast <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> of what is the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">capital</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayuan Temple</ENAMEX> the only surviving monument.
Another swarm of nomadic invaders eventually routed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khitan</ENAMEX>, establishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jin Dynasty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1115‚Äì1234</ENAMEX>) on the outskirts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> (which they renamed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zhongdu</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Capital</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> was in turn completely razed by a fresh batch of northern nomadic usurpers. They were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mongols¬†‚Äî¬†led by Genghis Khan¬†‚Äî¬†who</ENAMEX> would leave a more lasting and extensive mark on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> and all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genghis Khan</ENAMEX> laid the groundwork, gradually uniting all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> under his rule and leaving it to his famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kublai Khan</ENAMEX>, to secure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yuan Dynasty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1279‚Äì1368</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kublai Khan</ENAMEX> erected his own capital in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1279</TIMEX> on the shores of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing‚Äôs Beihai Lake</ENAMEX>, where some of his imperial treasures remain on display <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. It was to these same shores that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco Polo</ENAMEX> claimed to have journeyed at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 13th century</TIMEX>, where he won the support of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kublai Khan</ENAMEX>. He made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, then known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khanbaliq</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Khan‚Äôs Town</ENAMEX>) or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dadu</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Capital</ENAMEX>), the base for his extensive travels in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emissary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Khan</ENAMEX>. Of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 13th-century</TIMEX> capital, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco Polo</ENAMEX> wrote that ‚Äúthe whole interior of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is laid out in squares like a chessboard with such masterly precision that no description can do justice to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">it‚Äù¬†‚Äî¬†a</ENAMEX> pattern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> retains to this day.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming Period</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mongol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yuan Dynasty</ENAMEX> were eventually undone by indigenous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> who established one of the most renowned of all imperial lines, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ming Dynasty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1368‚Äì1644</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> was again razed and rebuilt, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming Emperor Yongle</ENAMEX> gave it a new name that would stick: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Capital</ENAMEX>). By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1420</TIMEX> he had finished constructing the city‚Äôs most famous surviving monument, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>. This was accompanied by other monumental projects. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Tower</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Drum Tower</ENAMEX>, and above all, the graceful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of Heaven were built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 15th century</TIMEX>. Many of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temples</ENAMEX> also date from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ming Dynasty</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ming</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> cautiously welcomed a few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuits</ENAMEX>, headed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matteo Ricci</ENAMEX>, had a profound influence not so much on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> religion (they made few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">converts</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijingers</ENAMEX>) as on science, mathematics, astronomy, art, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, and other forms of knowledge that had never before been infused with Western ideas in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Perhaps the greatest project of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX>, however, was the restoration and extension of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Great Wall</ENAMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, brick was used to finish these magnificent fortifications. It is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ming Dynasty Great Wall</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> visit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Period</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ming</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> were understandably nervous about yet another invasion from the north and took defensive measures by extending the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Wall</ENAMEX>. They were nonetheless undone by precisely what they feared most: northern invaders. This time the conquerors were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchus</ENAMEX>, who established a dynasty that proved as long-lived and as glorious as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Manchu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1644‚Äì1911</ENAMEX>) were wise enough to adopt <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> ways. They kept the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> but, unlike preceding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">dynasties</TIMEX>, did not raze it. Instead the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchus</ENAMEX> preserved and restored <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs past. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of Heaven, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beihai Lake</ENAMEX> were maintained as imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strongholds</ENAMEX>. Old temples were renovated, and the hutong neighborhoods of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard mansions</ENAMEX> were developed.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the greatest Qing emperors, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kangxi</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qianlong</ENAMEX>, maintained the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming Tombs</ENAMEX> and saw to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX>, while the last great imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress Dowager Cixi</ENAMEX>, kept the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> in splendid condition into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 20th century</TIMEX>. These and most other historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> were either preserved or created by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Qing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>, including their own imperial tombs, which rival those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX> is also celebrated for its elaboration of the artistic traditions it inherited from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ming Dynasty</ENAMEX>. What we know as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peking</ENAMEX>-style opera and still see performed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the capital became formalized under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing</ENAMEX>, although its roots (and costumes) go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX> and earlier eras. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX> were also noted for their superb ink paintings, cloisonn√© enamel work, furniture design, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">lacquerware¬†‚Äî¬†but</ENAMEX> above all for their porcelains of the ‚<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Äúfive-colors‚Äù and ‚Äúblue-and-white‚</NUMEX>Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. At the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX>, these porcelains with landscape and garden designs became all the rage in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">imitation ‚ÄúChinese‚Äù</ENAMEX> pottery began to be produced. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing</ENAMEX> continued these artistic traditions, adding increasingly rich and dense ornamentation and applying new colors, many of them clashing or gaudy.
This absorption in overly elaborate artwork, combined with heavy demands for imperial luxuries, finally coincided with a decline in the dynasty itself. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Qing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> faced a new legion of invaders, not from the north (as in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX>) but from the West, and they were unable to resist the tide.
Since the time of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Opium War</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1839‚Äì1842</ENAMEX>), Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> had been pushing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to open its doors to foreign trade. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860</TIMEX>, during the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Opium War</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> forcibly occupied <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> and exacted treaty rights. Foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> poured into the capital, taking up residence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Legation Quarter</ENAMEX>, located just southeast of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Legation Quarter</ENAMEX> was attacked by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boxers</ENAMEX>, a radical nationalist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that had the tacit support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. In retaliation for this unsuccessful attempt to expel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Westerners</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> representing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> resident in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> went on a rampage, destroying the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and even setting fire to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX>. Thereafter, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legation Quarter</ENAMEX> exercised complete control over its own affairs, becoming its own foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. Many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>-style embassy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX> of the period have survived, although all have been converted to other uses since the revolution of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warlords</ENAMEX>
China‚Äôs history of imperial rule is far older than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚Äôs</ENAMEX> reign as capital, but it was at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> that the last of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs dynasties was destined to fall. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Qing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> were overthrown in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic of China</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sun Yat-sen</ENAMEX>, was declared. A period of regional civil wars and power struggles among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival warlords</ENAMEX> ensued. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> used <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX> as the stage for their protests against <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-World War I</ENAMEX> ‚Äúunequal treaties‚Äù that favored <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, a patriotic demonstration known as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth Movement</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> was re-established as the national <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guomindang</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationalist Party</ENAMEX>), led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chiang Kai-Shek</ENAMEX>. For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> history, the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strongholds</ENAMEX>, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of Heaven, were no longer forbidden to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>.
Progress and freedom were short-lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> invaded northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> on the eve of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, seizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX> after a valiant battle at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Marco Polo Bridge</ENAMEX> (one of many new monuments added to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> occupied <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> until the war‚Äôs end in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nanjing</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs new capital under the ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationalist Party</ENAMEX>, but revolutionary change was in the air.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitalists</ENAMEX>
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 October 1949</TIMEX>, a new nation¬<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">†‚Äî¬†the People‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic of China¬†‚Äî¬†was</ENAMEX> declared from the podium facing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> was again to serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China‚Äôs</ENAMEX> capital. This new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> was indeed radically new. Led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Zedong</ENAMEX>, it was the largest communist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in the world, and it would soon begin its own program to reverse and destroy the ‚Äúfeudal‚Äù legacy of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of imperial rule.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> first initiated a popular program of reconstruction to transform and modernize the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, the ancient city walls were pulled down and the city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moat</ENAMEX> was filled in. Only a few of the venerable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> gates and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> remain standing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">China‚Äôs</ENAMEX> first subway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX> now makes a loop that retraces the foundations of the city walls, with the subway stops named for the ancient city gates. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> was substantially enlarged, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chang‚Äôan Avenue</ENAMEX> widened, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Hall of the People</ENAMEX> built, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Museum of History and the Museum of the Revolution opened¬†‚Äî¬†all in the 1950s</ENAMEX>. Old neighborhoods began to be replaced by modern brick-and-concrete highrises. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> became its own powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">municipality</ENAMEX> (not part of any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>), the seat of the new revolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cultural Revolution</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1966‚Äì1976</ENAMEX>) closed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs doors to the outside world. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> and his most radical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> shut down the nation‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> and went on a witch hunt for those alleged to harbor politically incorrect thoughts, behaviors, or backgrounds (which at times seemed to include anyone not waving <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mao‚Äôs Little Red Book</ENAMEX>). Many of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs temples and historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> were not only closed but severely damaged, all in the name of making a complete break with the feudal, superstitious past. Renovations as a result of this era of cultural destruction are not yet complete, and some ancient sites have never reopened.
Nevertheless, after the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> (whose <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> has become a much-visited modern monument to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">China‚Äôs modern ‚Äúemperor‚Äù</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> entered a period of liberal economic reform that has again transformed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>. Under ‚Äúsupreme leader‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng Xiaoping</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> opened its doors to Western investment and culture in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>.
By the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deng‚</ENAMEX>Äôs death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> was firmly reshaping itself as an international <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> in the Western mode, complete with expressways, skyscrapers, shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plazas</ENAMEX>, luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel chains</ENAMEX>, rock concerts, and state-of-the-art computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">technologies¬†‚Äî¬†not</ENAMEX> to mention rising crime rates, soaring pollution levels, increasing unemployment, and income disparities sharp enough to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> turn over in his crypt.
The skyline of the capital rises higher and higher <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and steel replace brick and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX> in the old courtyards, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars replace carts</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, and computers replace abacuses in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. Today‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> would seem to have little in common with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beihai</ENAMEX> lakeshore of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kublai Khan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco Polo</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City of the Ming</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer Palace of the Qing</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple of Confucius</ENAMEX>, or even the patriotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> has not escaped the history that shaped it, be it ancient or modern. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> can still see both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.



