



What To Do
Once a sleepy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> with little to do but sightsee by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has opened considerably to the outside world since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> have enlivened the shopping scene and given the capital its first dose of nightlife in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> is becoming a modern international <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>, but one with strong <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> characteristics that keep it an interesting and distinctive place to visit.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has some of the world‚Äôs best places to shop for Chinese-made goods and traditional arts and crafts, often with prices far below those paid in the West. The capital is renowned for its selection of silk fabrics and clothing, embroidery, pearls, jade, porcelains, cloisonn√©, lacquerware, carpets, furniture, antiques, and artwork (both contemporary and traditional).
The most popular shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wangfujing Dajie</ENAMEX> downtown, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liulichang Culture Street</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dazhalan Mall</ENAMEX> south of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Xidan Street</ENAMEX> west of city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> (the favorite of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX> are superb for strolling and window-shopping. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> stay open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> a week from <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">about 9am</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8pm</NUMEX> or later. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> is spoken in most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>. Few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> accept credit cards, so carry plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> cash. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATMs</ENAMEX> are appearing in the capital, but don‚Äôt count on finding one when you need it (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money</ENAMEX>, page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">115</NUMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> is the most crowded day of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> to shop.
You can survey the variety of goods available in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> (from crafts and souvenirs to jewelry and carpets) and determine their fair market prices by visiting the city‚Äôs most comprehensive department store for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friendship Store</ENAMEX>, located well east of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> (at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jianguomenwai Dajie</ENAMEX>).
Although small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, and large modern shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plazas</ENAMEX> carry a wide range of goods <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, the best places to find bargains are the street markets and bazaars scattered throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. These open-air markets are also the most interesting places to shop in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>.
Best Buys
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiques</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">antiques galore¬†‚Äî¬†and</ENAMEX> plenty of fakes, too. Any item created <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1795 and 1949</TIMEX> must have a red wax seal to allow export from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friendship Store</ENAMEX> are the most reliable antiques <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>, and they often provide international shipping services for purchases. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">antiques shops</ENAMEX> along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Liulichang Culture Street</ENAMEX> are worth browsing, as is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panjiayuan</ENAMEX> Market on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX>). Among the most popular antiques for sale in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> are Qing- and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX>-era furniture, porcelains, jewelry, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood carvings</ENAMEX>, screens, and scrolls.
Art. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has a number of contemporary art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wangfujing</ENAMEX> area and in some of the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> (notably the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China World and Holiday Inn Crowne Plaza</ENAMEX>). A number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> are developing international followings. Reproductions of classic and traditional landscapes and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> masterpieces are sold at most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> as well, as are low-priced painted scrolls that can be framed at home.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX> and crafts. The traditional handmade items of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, including paper kites and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, ceramic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">teapots</ENAMEX>, bamboo knickknacks, lacquerware, chopsticks, and cloisonn√© bracelets, are widely available in department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> at tourist sites. They should be quite inexpensive, particularly when purchased from streetside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Craftworkers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> are turning out an increasing number of fine ornaments aimed at foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX>; these make perfect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> presents to carry back home.
Carpets. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> carpets of silk or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> should be inspected carefully. The colors should not be fading and the threads should be fine and tightly woven. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Handmade</ENAMEX> carpets from the far western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">provinces</ENAMEX> and from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> are popular in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. Begin shopping at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friendship Store</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing Carpet Import</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Export Corporation</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong Kong Macao Center</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Ring Road East</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cashmere</ENAMEX>. Cashmere sweaters and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool creations</ENAMEX> have been popular with recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX>. Department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plazas</ENAMEX> carry a full range of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> and cashmere garments in Western sizes, well made and priced far below overseas retail markets.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chops</ENAMEX> (seals). Everyone who was anyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> had their own carved stamp, called a chop, usually a palm-sized stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> that was dipped in a special red ink. This ink stamp served as an official signature and seal. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Chops</ENAMEX> are still used widely in modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friendship Store</ENAMEX>, in the markets, and in some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master carvers</ENAMEX> can quickly create a personalized chop with the purchaser‚Äôs name engraved in any language, including <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, for an inexpensive and unique souvenir or gift.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collectibles</ENAMEX>. Nearly every open market, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk stall</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley bazaar</ENAMEX> has plenty of old collectibles for sale. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> buttons and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> posters have become highly collectible. Old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> coins, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> statues, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood carvings</ENAMEX>, and handpainted plates can all be had cheaply on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> if you bargain long and hard.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jade</ENAMEX>. China‚Äôs most prized precious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> is also quite difficult to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>. Unless you are with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>, buy only what you like at a price you can easily afford. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jade</ENAMEX> is fake. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Color</ENAMEX>, transparency, smoothness, and the skill of cutting determine the price. Check the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friendship Store</ENAMEX> first to see what you get for your money.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pearls</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gem</ENAMEX> traditionally associated with love can be an extremely good buy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hongqiao Market</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX>) has become the capital‚Äôs leading outlet for freshwater and saltwater pearls, usually sold in tassels. Prices range from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as little as 20 yuan</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over 20,000 yuan</NUMEX>. Look for uniformity in the size, shape, and color of a string of pearls. The best pearls are large and highly lustrous.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silk</ENAMEX> and embroidery. This ‚ÄúLand of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silk‚Äù</ENAMEX> has excellent selection and prices in silk fabrics and finished garments. Department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friendship Store</ENAMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel shops</ENAMEX>, and specialty silk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> carry good selections in Western sizes. Many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> also carry inexpensive embroidered goods, such as tablecloths and sheets. Try the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yuanlong Embroidery and Silk Store</ENAMEX> at the south entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of Heaven or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruifuxiang Silk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cotton Store</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dazhalan Mall</ENAMEX> off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qianmen Dajie</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tea</ENAMEX>. Packaged teas are quite affordable in the land that invented this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX>. Small <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wangfujing</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liulichang</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> are good places to shop for loose-leaf green teas and teaware. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trustworthy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jiguge Teahouse</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">132</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liulichang Dong Jie</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bichu Tea Shop</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">233</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wangfujing Dajie</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Malls</ENAMEX> and Plazas
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friendship Store</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">east Chang‚Äôan Avenue</ENAMEX> and the aging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wangfujing Department Store</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">255</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wangfujing Dajie</ENAMEX>), once purveyors of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most up-to-date fashions and top merchandise, have been superseded by the sudden eruption of huge shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> and plazas. Boutiques with an international flair, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">label outlets</ENAMEX>, specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, fast-food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarkets</ENAMEX>, department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cinemas¬†‚Äî¬†linked</ENAMEX> together by mezzanines, escalators, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass elevators¬†‚Äî¬†have</ENAMEX> all gathered under single roofs across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>. Although the prices are high by local standards and much of the merchandise is imported, careful visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> can still find bargains at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>.
Beijing‚Äôs premier mega-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Dong</ENAMEX> An <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Plaza</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">138</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wangfujing Dajie</ENAMEX>), with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> flights of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> ranging from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> supermarket and silk and clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald‚Äôs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Fog</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Xidan</ENAMEX> shopping district, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 2 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11‚ÅÑ2 miles</NUMEX>) west of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>, is working on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new massive shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plazas</ENAMEX> of its own to compete with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wangfujing‚Äôs Sun Dong</ENAMEX> An <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Plaza</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lufthansa</ENAMEX> You <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yi Shopping Center</ENAMEX> serves those staying at the international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> in northeast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Third Ring Road</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China World Trade Center‚Äôs</ENAMEX> shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX> (at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jianguomenwai Dajie</ENAMEX>) has been enlarged by the opening of more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and an ice-skating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rink</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> is also home to an Internet caf√© and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Starbucks</ENAMEX> coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>. Finally, for those who tire of shopping for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> goods, there‚Äôs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palace Hotel Shopping Arcade</ENAMEX>, the most upscale collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, with such international names as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gucci</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armani</ENAMEX>.
Markets and Bazaars
Beijing‚Äôs markets, many of them open-air spaces in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> lined with vendor‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX>, offer the most interesting shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ventures</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>. Bargaining is the rule. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, language presents no barrier to negotiations, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> should exercise patience and caution. It helps to have a notion of the market value of the merchandise by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> checking out prices in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. Street markets should have the lowest prices of all, but the initial price set by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX> is always on the high side.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silk Alley Market</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xiushui Shichang</ENAMEX>), on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jianguomenwai Dajie</ENAMEX> within a few blocks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friendship Store</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most popular clothing market. The passageways are jammed with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX>. Although silk goods are becoming scarce, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>-label sportswear, ties, and luggage are abundant and cheap if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> is willing to haggle. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yabaolu Market</ENAMEX> (known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúRussian Market‚Äù</ENAMEX>), on the northwest corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ritan Park</ENAMEX>, has a good streetside collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> and leather goods.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lido</ENAMEX> Market, across from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday Inn Lido Hotel</ENAMEX> on the way to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stalls¬†‚Äî¬†all indoors¬†‚Äî¬</ENAMEX>†carrying many of the same goods as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silk Alley</ENAMEX> Market downtown, often at better prices.
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">markets</ENAMEX> specialize in certain merchandise. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chaowai Flea Market</ENAMEX>, north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ritan Park</ENAMEX>, is known for its antiques, carvings, and furniture. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scroll Market</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xicheng District</ENAMEX> inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Ring Road North</ENAMEX>, sells handpainted scrolls, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chops</ENAMEX>, and goldfish. A bit farther north from here, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bird Market</ENAMEX> sells songbirds and ornate cages. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sanlitun District</ENAMEX> has a large wicker and bamboo market, as well as a sportswear market, amidst its caf√© and bar strip. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hongqiao Market</ENAMEX> (also known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chongwenmen Market</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmers‚Äô Market</ENAMEX>), on the northeast edge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of Heaven (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiantan</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX>, is the best place to shop for jewelry bargains, especially pearls.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panjiayuan Antique</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Curio Market</ENAMEX> (variously known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúDirt Market,‚Äù ‚ÄúGhost Market,‚Äù and ‚ÄúSunday Market‚Äù</ENAMEX>) is the most interesting to browse in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. Located <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> south of city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Third Ring Road</ENAMEX>, it goes into full swing at sunrise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> sift through wares ranging from antiques and collectibles to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ceramics</ENAMEX> and family heirlooms.
Entertainment
From traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> entertainment to modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> music, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> offers a fairly full calendar of events for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, headlined by performances of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peking Opera</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs best acrobatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troupes</ENAMEX>. Your hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">concierge</ENAMEX> or tour desk has current schedules and can book tickets for you. Check also the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English-language</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Daily</ENAMEX> or the free <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> guides published for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Month</TIMEX>, Welcome To <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, and others that are distributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and caf√©s. They list a wide range of entertainment possibilities as well as special events and concerts. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> also has several teahouse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> presenting samplers of traditional entertainment forms along with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX> or dinners. Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> has a growing number of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late-night</TIMEX> spots (some with live pop music) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">discos</ENAMEX> that welcome foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peking Opera and Acrobatics</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peking Opera</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jing Ju</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> varies little from the form it assumed during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 250 years ago</TIMEX>. The costumes, choreography, instruments, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">singing¬†‚Äî¬†all</ENAMEX> quite unique to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">China¬†‚Äî¬†might</ENAMEX> seem strange to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Westerners</ENAMEX>, but these highly stylized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> are part of a familiar tradition that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beijingers</ENAMEX> love. Other areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> have their own regional styles of opera, but <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peking Opera</ENAMEX> is definitely the most famous.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> opera becomes more comprehensible and enjoyable when the plot is known (it‚Äôs usually a historic drama or tragic love story) and when subtitles (in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>) are projected on a side-screen. It is also helpful to know that the masks, painted faces, and costumes identify each character‚Äôs social role and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>, and that the live music, with its gongs and cymbals, often functions like a film score to emphasize the action on stage.
With the closing of the centuries-old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zhengyici Theater</ENAMEX> (an opera venue since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1713</TIMEX>), the best place to take in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> of exotic opera <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>-style is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liyuan Theater</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qianmen Hotel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">175 Yong‚Äôan Lu</ENAMEX>). Here spirited excerpts from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> operas are performed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most nights</TIMEX>, with simultaneous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subtitles</ENAMEX> provided (as well as a choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX>). Other opera <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> of high repute include the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chang‚Äôan Grand Theater</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jianguomenwai Dajie</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand View Garden Theater</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancaiyun Jie</ENAMEX>). Admission prices vary widely depending on the seat location and snack or meal options, ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as little as 20 yuan</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over 200 yuan</NUMEX> for the best seat and treats in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
Acrobatics are part of most opera performances, but this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,000-year-old</TIMEX> tradition in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has produced its own highly entertaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX>. Some of the best acrobatic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. When not on an international tour, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing Acrobatic Troupe</ENAMEX> performs at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wansheng Theater</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tianqiao Market</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sichuan Acrobatic Troupe</ENAMEX> often uses the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chaoyang Theater</ENAMEX>. The most expensive venue is provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poly Plaza International Theater</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dongzhimen Nan Dajie</ENAMEX>), where the unicycling, plate-spinning, and chair-stacking receive a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>-style staging, complete with a magic show.
Teahouses
To see snatches of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs traditional performing arts in a setting appropriate for an imperial banquet, try one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs special teahouses. At these intimate dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>, decorated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX> fashion (carved wood trim, paper lanterns, and red columns), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> can enjoy local <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX> or full <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> at their tables while viewing a variety of acts on stage, including opera highlights, acrobatics, magic shows, ethnic dancing, puppetry, storytelling, and comedy.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> top teahouse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lao She Teahouse</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qianmenxi Dajie</ENAMEX>), with nightly variety shows and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tian Qiao Happy Teahouse</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">113</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tianqiao Market</ENAMEX>), with balcony seating and a staff outfitted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qing</ENAMEX> costumes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tian Hai Teahouse</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanlitun Lu</ENAMEX>) offers an even more intimate theater on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights only</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing Teahouse</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">8 Changdian</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Liulichang Culture Street</ENAMEX>) hosts traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">storytellers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every afternoon</TIMEX>.
Nightlife
Much of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs contemporary music scene is centered in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sanlitun</ENAMEX> area, a favorite of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expatriates</ENAMEX> and foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> looking for comfortable bars and late-night international caf√©s. Local <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> also frequent these spots, where the live music ranges from rock to jazz. Prices for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> (especially for imported <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>, spirits, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>) are high for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> but are about on par with those in the West. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanlitun Lu</ENAMEX> features <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several dozen</NUMEX> caf√© <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> in the space of a few blocks, some of which never close.
Among the most popular Western-style <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">caf√© bars</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frank‚</ENAMEX>Äôs Place (east of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Worker‚Äôs Stadium</ENAMEX>), an American-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> founded by an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Bull Pub</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guanghua Lu</ENAMEX>), a very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">darts</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> menu; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry J. Bean‚Äôs</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jianguomenwai Dajie</ENAMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and grill with rock bands and dancing. Local <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> pop and rock <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> can be heard in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sanlitun</ENAMEX> area at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hidden Tree</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dongdaqiao Xie Jie</ENAMEX>) or across from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kempinski Hotel</ENAMEX> at Keep In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Touch</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jiuxianqiao Dong Lu</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> even has several Western-style sports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandstand</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday Inn Lido Hotel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pit Stop</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harbour Plaza Hotel</ENAMEX>, and the immense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports City Caf√</ENAMEX>© in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloria Plaza Hotel</ENAMEX>.
For live jazz, the best bets are the CD <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Caf√© Jazz Club</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Ring Road East</ENAMEX>) on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanwei Bookstore</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fuxingmenwai Dajie</ENAMEX>) on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Beijing‚Äôs plushest jazz club¬†‚Äî¬†often</ENAMEX> attracting international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> to its piano bar¬<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">†‚Äî¬†is Aria</ENAMEX>, an upscale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and grill located in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China World Hotel</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jianguomenwai Dajie</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> of disco (which is not a dying fad in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>) have made the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hot Spot</ENAMEX> (south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jiangguang New World Hotel</ENAMEX>) the hottest dance venue in town, with stage shows and caged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> going strong <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2am</TIMEX>. Other popular disco venues include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xitucheng Lu, Haidian District</ENAMEX>), stuffed with military motifs, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poachers Inn the Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuanjiehu Park</ENAMEX>), with its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX> and stone dance floor. The most international late-night dance floor is at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hard Rock Cafe</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dongsanhuan Bei Lu</ENAMEX>), the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hamburgers</ENAMEX>, fries, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, and live (and loud) music <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nightly</TIMEX>.
Recreation and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports</ENAMEX>
Although most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to the capital do not come for outdoor pursuits or sports, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> does have a variety of recreational activities. Most international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> maintain full-service fitness <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> with exercise machines, saunas, indoor swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> such as tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> rates for non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>. The city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> are fine places for jogging, exercises, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tai chi</ENAMEX>, walking, and other <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early morning</TIMEX> workouts. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Golf</ENAMEX>, bowling, and billiards are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> most popular recreational sports.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> also offers bungee jumping (at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shidu Bungee Jumping Facility</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fangshan District</ENAMEX>), paintball (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">at Color Me Purple</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wanfangting Park</ENAMEX>), rock climbing (at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Qidagudu Climbing Club</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Xuanwu District</ENAMEX>), horseback riding (check with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Movenpick Hotel</ENAMEX>), and shooting (at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">China North Shooting Range</ENAMEX> near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Wall Badaling¬†‚Äî¬†where</ENAMEX> even <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine guns</ENAMEX> are for rent).
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Golf</ENAMEX>. Beijing‚Äôs top course is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing International Golf Club</ENAMEX>, located near the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming Tombs</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing Grand Canal Golf Club</ENAMEX>, east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, has <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>. Near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing Country Golf Club</ENAMEX> provides <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> holes. The newest championship <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX>, designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham Marsh</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Huatang International Golf</ENAMEX>. The closest course to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chaoyang Golf Club</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-hole course with a driving range. All these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> are open to the public (make reservations through your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>), and they rent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> and provide caddies. Greens fees start at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 1,000 yuan</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Bowling</ENAMEX>. Modern bowling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> enjoyed a boom in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> located in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday Inn Lido</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing International</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>. The bowling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> in the lower basement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China World Hotel</ENAMEX> has special off<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-hour</TIMEX> rates during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>.
Ice-skating. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beihai Park</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX> both offer superb outdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-skating in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX>, with skate rental at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX> on the shoreline. Indoor skating is available at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ditan Ice Arena</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ditan Park</ENAMEX> and at the underground shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> connecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Traders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China World hotels</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jianguomenwai Dajie</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> sports. Beijing‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing Ducks</ENAMEX> (basketball) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guardians</ENAMEX> (soccer), play during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Workers‚Äô Stadium</ENAMEX> in northeast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. Both have strong followings in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> know <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> by name and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> is a household name (known in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fei Ren</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúFlying Man‚Äù</ENAMEX>).
Activities for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of attractions for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and many of these can be enjoyed by visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing Zoo</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX>) has long been a prime attraction with its pandas and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX>, and next door there‚Äôs a new and elaborate attraction, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing Aquarium</ENAMEX>. At the south gate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Workers‚Äô Stadium</ENAMEX> there‚Äôs also the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Aquarium</ENAMEX>, with its <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100-m</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">328-ft</ENAMEX>) underwater <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX>. Water <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> with sluices, slides, and swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yuyuantan Water World</ENAMEX> (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yuyuantan Park</ENAMEX>, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth Ring Road East</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs largest, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tuanjiehu Manmade Seashore</ENAMEX> (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuanjiehu Park</ENAMEX>, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Ring Road East</ENAMEX>), with its artificial white-sand beach and outdoor swimming pool.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amusement</ENAMEX> and theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> are proliferating. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing Amusement Park</ENAMEX> (west side of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Longtan Lake Park</ENAMEX>) is the old-fashioned standard, with a Ferris wheel, go-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carts</ENAMEX>, and a looping roller coaster. China‚Äôs largest theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Park</ENAMEX>, is located near the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fourth Ring Road</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fangtai District</ENAMEX>. It is stocked with scale models of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> of the world‚Äôs greatest monuments, landmarks, and skylines, ranging from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sphinx</ENAMEX>. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Ethnic Culture Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beichan Lu</ENAMEX>, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fourth Ring Road</ENAMEX>) costumed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> live in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">model</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> and put on cultural performances.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> are also entertained by the special effects and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> sets assembled at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Studios</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henderson Center</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jianguomenwai Dajie</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> of miniature golf gather for a round at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kaite Mini-Golf</ENAMEX> (north entrance, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ritan Park</ENAMEX>). An indoor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX> with games and slides for younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fundazzle</ENAMEX>, is located near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Workers‚Äô Stadium</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gonrentiyucahng Lu</ENAMEX>, and a chance for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to learn such crafts as paper-making, embroidery, and pottery is provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Five Colours Earth Craft Center</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dongzhimen Nanlu</ENAMEX>, near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poly Plaza</ENAMEX>).
Chances are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will have the most fun while touring with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs celebrated outdoor attractions: running up and down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Wall</ENAMEX>, paddling rowboats at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Behai Park</ENAMEX>, passing secret messages inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echo Wall</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of Heaven, or just strolling the exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of the capital‚Äôs new and old neighborhoods.



