



A Brief History
This remote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of islands remained unnamed until it was spotted by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">navigator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Berm√</ENAMEX>∫dez in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1503</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only a few years later</TIMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> map showed ‚ÄúLa <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>.‚Äù It was also called the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúIsles of Devils‚</ENAMEX>Äù because early navigators were terrified of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda‚</ENAMEX>Äôs reefs and celebrated their salvation when they had passed safely by. Despite benign conditions and ample <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, there were few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, and those who landed did so usually because they were shipwrecked. One was the anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailor</ENAMEX> who carved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the date 1543</TIMEX> on a rock on the south coast, now known as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish Rock</ENAMEX>. He also inscribed a cross and a pair of letters, perhaps his initials or those of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea Venture</ENAMEX> 
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1606</TIMEX> James I granted a charter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Company</ENAMEX> to establish the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamestown</ENAMEX> in the king‚Äôs honor. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years later</TIMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> contingent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> set sail from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plymouth</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Admiral</ENAMEX> Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Somers</ENAMEX>. Less than halfway across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> ran into a vicious storm. The flagship <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX>, called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea Venture</ENAMEX>, was separated from the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">convoy</ENAMEX> and eventually snagged on the reefs just east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28 July 1609</TIMEX>.
Miraculously, all aboard were ferried to shore. It turned out that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> was an ideal place to be stranded. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than a year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Somers</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> had built new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> from local cedar and timber salvaged from the remains of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea Venture</ENAMEX>. Leaving behind <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Somers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> resumed their journey westward and finally landed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamestown</ENAMEX>, only to be greeted by a shock: <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>, starvation, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> attacks had drastically decimated the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Somers</ENAMEX> set sail almost immediately, headed back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>. He knew that it could provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamestown</ENAMEX> with enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> to save them from further hardship. Unfortunately, he died trying to organize the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>-Jamestown lifeline. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> was shipped back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> but his heart was buried in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> he would later be credited with founding.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King James</ENAMEX> added the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> to the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Company Charter</ENAMEX>, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring of 1612 more than 50</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX> were sent out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plough</ENAMEX> to join <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX> who had volunteered to hold the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">fort</ENAMEX>. Defenses were built and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. George‚Äôs</ENAMEX> was established at the east end of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>, near the spot where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea Venture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">castaways</ENAMEX> had first landed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda Company</ENAMEX> was then created to administer the island.
News of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> settlement agitated the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>. After all, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spaniard</ENAMEX> had discovered (and given his name to) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip III</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> was urged by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> to act immediately to force the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> out. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> were dispatched with orders to evaluate the situation. As they approached the island, the small <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> created a number of ruses to convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> was well defended; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">salvos</ENAMEX> fired from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cannon</ENAMEX> went across the bay. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> fell for the ploy and fled, grossly overestimating the strength of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garrison</ENAMEX>, which couldn‚Äôt have mustered a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> shot at that time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bermuda‚Äôs Britishness</ENAMEX> was affirmed.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Growing Colony</ENAMEX>
Progress was swift during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first few years</TIMEX> of the colony‚Äôs existence. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1619</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congregation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Peter‚Äôs Church</ENAMEX> moved into a permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda‚Äôs parliament</ENAMEX> met in an enclosure still visible amid the pews. But it was soon decided to separate the secular from the religious, and a new government building went up. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda‚Äôs</ENAMEX> first stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>, is still standing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. George‚Äôs</ENAMEX>.
An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">surveyor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Norwood</ENAMEX>, undertook a study of the terrain, dividing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> into the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> ‚Äútribes‚Äù that are the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">parishes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">counties</ENAMEX>) of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and the origin of the numerous ‚ÄúTribe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roads‚Äù</ENAMEX> still to be seen across the island. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">parishes</ENAMEX>, all but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. George‚</ENAMEX>Äôs were named after prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> in the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda Company</ENAMEX>. 
During this period local money was minted, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúHog‚Äù</ENAMEX> money after the wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> on the reverse side; it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Britain‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> colonial currency. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> was to be the economic base for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>, whose major <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> was tobacco. In reality, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> could never compete with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crops</ENAMEX> produced in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, but it began to develop a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation system</ENAMEX>, including the importation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> labor. The slaves were treated a bit better than were those on islands farther south, and slavery was finally abolished in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1834</TIMEX>. The initial centuries of enforced settlement, followed by emancipation and the ensuing years of equality, have produced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bermuda‚</ENAMEX>Äôs modern biracial society.
When agriculture failed to be profitable, the ingenious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> looked for other ways to make a living. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bermuda</ENAMEX> sits astride the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX> migration route, and because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">motherland</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> demanded (and paid well for) the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>, the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> went into the whaling business. Once the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX> were good enough seamen to land <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whales</ENAMEX>, it was perhaps only natural that they might turn their skills to another historical marine tradition: piracy. The practice evolved modestly, perhaps even legally, from the salvaging (called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúwrecking‚Äù</ENAMEX>) of treasure found on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> grounded on the local reefs. From there it was easy to make the transition to taking goods by subterfuge or by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. Smuggling was so commonplace that it passed almost unnoticed.
Changing Loyalties
Isolated from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than 5,300 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,300 miles</NUMEX>) in an age of slow communications, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> sometimes found itself out of step with developments in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1649</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">islanders</ENAMEX> were appalled to learn of the execution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles I</ENAMEX> and the proclamation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cromwell‚Äôs Commonwealth</ENAMEX>. They later rejoiced when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles II</ENAMEX> was restored to the throne in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1660</TIMEX>.
Another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era ended in 1684</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda Company</ENAMEX> lost its charter. After a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> legal battle, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> became a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> with a degree of self-government. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> appointed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> to act as the crown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> (this is still the system <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>). The most difficult test of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda‚</ENAMEX>Äôs loyalties came when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> rose in rebellion against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George III</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London</ENAMEX> forbade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> to trade with or otherwise support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Washington‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX>. This was a heartbreaking decree for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">islanders</ENAMEX> to obey in light of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda‚Äôs</ENAMEX> close personal and family ties with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> also provided a strong rationale for helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> received most of its grain from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX>. Simply put, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> needed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX> needed gunpowder.
On a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dark night</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-August 1775</TIMEX>, several <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> sailed into the dark <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tobacco Bay</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fort St. Catherine</ENAMEX> and, in a daring and dangerous raid, stole <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">100 kegs of gunpowder</NUMEX> from the main ordnance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. Once safely on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ammunition</ENAMEX> made its way to the rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. To this day nobody knows if this was part of an orchestrated campaign or simply a spur-of-the-moment action by local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sympathizers</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> got its grain. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> were horrified but could find no conclusive proof of guilt. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tuckers</ENAMEX>, a prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> with many connections to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX>, were the prime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>. Not all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermudians</ENAMEX>, however, were sympathetic to the rebel cause, as privateers continued to capture and ransack <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibraltar</ENAMEX> of the West
With the loss of its naval <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> began to appreciate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda‚</ENAMEX>Äôs strategic importance. They wanted to create a ‚ÄúGibraltar of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West‚Äù</ENAMEX> and set about building a large naval <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dockyard</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland Island</ENAMEX>, at the opposite end of the archipelago from the main population center of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. George‚Äôs.</ENAMEX> The addition of this important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> shifted the center of communications in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>, prompting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> to transfer the capital from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. George‚</ENAMEX>Äôs to the hitherto undistinguished village of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Traditionalists</ENAMEX> were furious.
Starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1824</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> sent convicts to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> to supplement the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> labor working on the dockyard project. At any given time there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well over 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> employed in the development of the outpost‚Äôs military potential. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellow</ENAMEX> fever, dysentery, and scurvy killed a sizable proportion of these unfortunates, who were crammed into filthy floating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> (called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúhulks‚Äù</ENAMEX>) during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hours</TIMEX> they weren‚Äôt working. These hulks were used until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1863</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slavery</ENAMEX> had been abolished in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> more than a quarter-century before the outbreak of the American <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, yet islanders‚Äô sympathies lay with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> remained officially neutral and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> were forbidden from taking part in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostilities</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermudians</ENAMEX> pitched in to help supply <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and goods to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> cause against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. George‚Äôs Harbour</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penno‚Äôs Wharf</ENAMEX> were working at full capacity to unload cargoes that were then transferred onto blockade-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runners</ENAMEX>. These long, slim <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX> were specially designed to outrun the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> navy‚Äôs picket <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>. They made their way to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wilmington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, the closest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>. Here they would take on a new cargo of cotton¬†‚Äî¬†a most profitable ballast that increased in value tenfold by the time it was delivered to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. George‚</ENAMEX>Äôs boomed during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> seethed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> laid down his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865</TIMEX>, it was as if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>, too, had lost a war.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> that followed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda‚</ENAMEX>Äôs fortunes picked up as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> steamships began to arrive on a regular basis. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1883</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX>) arrived on a lengthy visit en route to her new home farther north, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor General</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>. She extolled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> to those in her upper-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> circles, and wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> began to arrive soon thereafter. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> was a well-known <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> destination for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princess Hotel</ENAMEX> was opened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1885</TIMEX> to commemorate the visit.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">More Wars</ENAMEX>
At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the twentieth century</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Boer War</ENAMEX> (the struggle between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>) sent shock waves as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Boer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> were shipped to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison camps</ENAMEX> were established on half-a-dozen islands in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Sound</ENAMEX>. After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boers</ENAMEX> lost the war, many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> chose to remain in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> rather than accept a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British South Africa</ENAMEX>.
During <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermudian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> fought in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> while others joined resident <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in defending the islands. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> submarines aggravated the supply problem and threatened <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> stopping in the islands to refuel for the remainder of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> crossing. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> entered the conflict, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">White‚Äôs Island</ENAMEX>, just opposite the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX> waterfront, was leased to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. It was a small-scale preview of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military presence that would be established in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.
Between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> world wars, tourism became a prime economic factor, and luxury cruise liners began regular runs between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>. Resort <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> were built to attract <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> escaping the northern <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> (and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition</ENAMEX> laws against alcoholic beverages).
When war broke out in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda‚</ENAMEX>Äôs growing tourist industry all but collapsed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> were commandeered to carry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> or become floating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, and the waters around the islands were infested with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> submarines. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bermuda</ENAMEX> played an important role in intelligence. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basements</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermudiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> analyzed communications intercepted between the western hemisphere and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. Mail quietly removed from refueling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> was steamed open and tested for microdots and invisible codes, an important contribution to the struggle against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Axis</ENAMEX> spying activity. The big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> stayed in business by serving as billets for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX> and civilian war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.
Just as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> M15 intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> were arriving in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1940</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Lend-Lease Act</ENAMEX> was negotiated between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>. Under a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">99-year</TIMEX> lease, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> acquired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one-tenth</NUMEX> of the land area of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> for the development of naval and air <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX>, modernizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">defenses</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Britain‚Äôs ‚ÄúGibraltar</ENAMEX> of the West.‚Äù
Changing Times
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, the centuries-old links with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> began to change. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúImperial‚Äù coffers</ENAMEX> were empty, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> swiftly began to contract, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> were pulled out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">174 years</TIMEX>. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> changes also began to revolutionize the old way of life. The motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> was introduced, bringing about the demise of the horse-drawn <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriage</ENAMEX> and eventually causing the bankruptcy of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda Railway</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1950s</ENAMEX> saw racial segregation end in the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> (although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> were not integrated until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, a new constitution was adopted to make self-government more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> and effective; elections were won by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Bermuda Party</ENAMEX>. Then suddenly, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> was expelled from the ‚ÄúSterling area,‚Äù and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> chose to ally its currency to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> dollar. 
These abrupt and far-reaching changes on an island proud of its traditional ways brought strain and conflict. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riots</ENAMEX> broke out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> had to be called in to restore order. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years later</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Sharples</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> were assassinated. When the alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassins</ENAMEX> were executed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, more riots ensued.
However, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> pulled back from the brink of social chaos and began to return to its peaceful and law-abiding ways. With progressive taxation for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> enjoyed one of the highest standards of living in the world. Where whaling and piracy were once important industries, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> now looked to the less exciting but more predictable earnings from tourism, insurance, and banking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> the number of so-called exempt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> more than doubled, and they now compete with tourism as the major contributor to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda‚</ENAMEX>Äôs balance-of<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-payments‚Äô</NUMEX> surplus.
The political status quo under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Bermuda Party</ENAMEX> continued until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1998</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive Labour Party</ENAMEX>) won an unexpected landslide victory in the general elections. This not only surprised the old school but ushered in a new era full of opportunity for development as the island keeps up with a rapidly changing world. Challenges include environmental and housing issues as well as problems of unemployment, unknown in modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the final years of the 20th century</TIMEX>. Positive long-term solutions will ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> continues to enjoy the wealth, security, and comfort it has created for itself.



