



What to Do
We provide local <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> phone numbers for many of the activities mentioned in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>. When calling from outside the islands, remember to dial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda‚</ENAMEX>Äôs own area code (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">441</ENAMEX>) before the seven-digit number. 
Recreation and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda</ENAMEX> is an ideal vacation destination for outdoor activities. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Summer</ENAMEX> brings warm (but not hot) weather and warm sea temperatures, making it ideal for diving, snorkeling, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> sports. On land, you can fill your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis and golf</ENAMEX> along with long walks and beach activities. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>, the sea temperature makes it a little too cold for diving, but many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> still enjoy swimming in waters warmer than at home, and all land activities are thoroughly enjoyable with the addition of a jacket or sweater. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda Tourist Board</ENAMEX> produces <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Bermuda¬†‚Äî¬†What</ENAMEX> to Do, a comprehensive brochure with contact information and prices on a range of sporting activities.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda</ENAMEX> is known as a golfer‚Äôs paradise and has a greater concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> than in any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the world. It‚Äôs not only the quantity that makes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> great but also the quality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, many created by the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> in the world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX> and fairways are kept in pristine condition. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> are challenging, and the hills and coastline also help to create links reminiscent of those in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Scotland¬†‚Äî¬</ENAMEX>†but with much better weather. 
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda‚Äôs</ENAMEX> championship <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> are world famous, but all are engrossing. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> have courses on their own grounds, but all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and guesthouses can arrange an introduction to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> you‚Äôd like to play. Be sure to have them phone ahead to set the starting time. Here is a brief survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, from west to east:
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Port Royal Golf Course</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southampton Parish</ENAMEX>): <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6,411 yards</NUMEX>, par <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">71</TIMEX>. Government-owned and open to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Trent Jones</ENAMEX> course dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A couple of fairways</TIMEX> cling to clifftops over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>, adding thrills to some impressively serious golf.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princess Golf Club</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southampton Parish</ENAMEX>): <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,684 yards</NUMEX>, par <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX> executive course. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gibb‚Äôs Hill</ENAMEX> lighthouse overhead is only one of the sights on this 18-hole par-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> course alongside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southampton Princess Hotel</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Riddell‚Äôs Bay Golf and Country Club</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warwick Parish</ENAMEX>): <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5,414 yards</NUMEX>, par <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hilly and windy</ENAMEX>, with narrow fairways. The first hole, at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">418 yards</NUMEX>, par <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda‚</ENAMEX>Äôs toughest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">starter</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belmont Hotel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beach Club</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warwick Parish</ENAMEX>): <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5,777 yards</NUMEX>, par <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX>. All very challenging, with tight fairways, elevated <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX>, blind <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shots</ENAMEX>, and headwinds on steep headlands.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean View Golf</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Country Club</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devonshire Parish</ENAMEX>): <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> holes, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,956 yards</NUMEX>, par <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>. Government-owned and open to the public. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean View</ENAMEX>, formerly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Queen‚Äôs Park</ENAMEX>, is right in the center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main Island</ENAMEX> and overlooks the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">north</ENAMEX> coast.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid Ocean Club</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tucker‚Äôs Town</ENAMEX>): <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6,547 yards</NUMEX>, par <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">71</TIMEX>. The name is often mentioned when the pros discuss the greatest golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> in the world. With its big <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX> and awesome obstacles, this is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda‚</ENAMEX>Äôs longest and most thrillingly beautiful course. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Home</ENAMEX> run <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe Ruth</ENAMEX> couldn‚Äôt clear <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mangrove Lake</ENAMEX>, the big wet problem on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 5th</TIMEX> hole; he lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> balls.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Harbour Golf Club</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton Parish</ENAMEX>): <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6,445 yards</NUMEX>, par <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">71</TIMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid Ocean</ENAMEX>, its next-door <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Harbour</ENAMEX> shows the skill of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Trent Jones</ENAMEX>. From the elevated first tee, the panorama of green land, blue-green harbor, and dark blue sea stirs the heart. At <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only 312 yards</NUMEX>, this par <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> starts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> with confidence, but beautiful complications quickly follow.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. George‚Äôs Golf Club</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. George‚Äôs Parish</ENAMEX>): <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4,502 yards</NUMEX>, par <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68</TIMEX>. It adjoins the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Club Med St. George‚Äôs Cove Village</ENAMEX> (under new ownership and renovation at present, and due to open in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>), overlooking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fort St. Catherine</ENAMEX>.
Walking
The old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Railway Trail</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda‚</ENAMEX>Äôs premier walkway, with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> of safe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">paths</ENAMEX> through the heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> and along some of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prettiest</ENAMEX> stretches of coastline. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda Department of Tourism</ENAMEX> has issued a booklet guide for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, with maps showing the main features of the route. 
Another area for safe and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">picturesque</ENAMEX> walking is along the sand dunes behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Shore</ENAMEX> beaches. These link the main public beaches (from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Warwick Long Bay</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horseshoe Bay</ENAMEX>). They also provide access to secret coves. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> in any of the beach parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX> along the south coast to reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">paths</ENAMEX>. 
For a personal touch, there are a number of guides who provide guided walks full of interesting details of local history. Contact <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda Lectures</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Tours</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">234-4082</TIMEX>; fax <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">238-2773</ENAMEX>) for further details or to arrange a custom itinerary.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water Sports</ENAMEX>
With many shallow lagoons, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> is a great place for windsurfing, jet skiing, pedalos, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">aqua-cycling</ENAMEX>. Most large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> will have some equipment for hire. If they don‚Äôt have what you need, contact <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blue Waters Divers and Watersports</ENAMEX>, which has comprehensive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Somerset Bridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Elbow Beach</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marriott Castle Harbour Resort</ENAMEX>. You can reach them at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.O. Box SN 165</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southampton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SN BX</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">234-1034</TIMEX>; fax. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">234-3561</TIMEX>; website <www.divebermuda.com>. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parasailing</ENAMEX> is also available, but please make sure that you are fully insured before taking to the air. Many policies exclude this popular activity.
Diving and Snorkeling
The diving and snorkeling opportunities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> are many and varied. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> temperature ranges from 17¬∞C (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">62¬∞F</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> to a warm 28¬∞C (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">83¬∞F</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>. The clear waters in the western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>, with numerous reefs and rocky outcrops, offer an ideal habitat for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many hundreds</NUMEX> of species of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> along with healthy coral for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parrot fish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">angel fish</ENAMEX>, and huge, gentle groupers. Deeper water supports such <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX>. 
The shallow bays and rocky inlets around the coast are ideal snorkeling territory. Visibility can reach <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 60 m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 200</NUMEX> ft) since there is very little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water pollution</ENAMEX> here and the reefs offer protection against the rolling waves of the outer ocean. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> will have snorkeling equipment that you can rent to explore close to shore. If you want to snorkel out in the large shallow reefs on the northern side of the island, there are a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> offering <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full-day</TIMEX> trips with equipment included. One is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barefoot Cruises</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">236-3498</ENAMEX>); another is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse James Cruises</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">296-5801</ENAMEX>).
Bermuda‚Äôs reefs provide excellent dive sites either in the shallows or on the ocean side walls that drop steeply into the colder, deeper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> that have foundered on reefs in the waters off <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> have left over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">365</NUMEX> wrecks to explore. Even the scant remains of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea Venture</ENAMEX> (which sank in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1609</TIMEX>) can be located and identified. Others are far more exciting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divers</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harrington Sound</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Shore reef</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX>, and the wreck of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vixen</ENAMEX> (just off <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somerset Long Bay</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somerset Island</ENAMEX>). 
There are a number of dive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> that provide transport to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> and experienced and qualified dive masters to assist. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fantasea Bermuda</ENAMEX> offers diving instruction and accompanied dives as well as introductory sessions (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Darrel‚Äôs Wharf, 1 Harbour Road, Paget PG 01</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">236-0102</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">888-DO-A-DIVE</ENAMEX> toll-free in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>; fax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">236-8926</TIMEX>; website <www.fantasea.bm>). In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nautilus Diving</ENAMEX> offers instruction and introductory sessions (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">295-9485</TIMEX>; fax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">234-5180</TIMEX>; website <www.bermuda.bm/nautilus>). Remember to bring your dive certificate, as you will be allowed to rent equipment and dive only if you can prove your competence.
If you wish to learn to dive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>, there are a number of dive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> that offer training to professional levels. All are affiliated with one of the major certifying bodies, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PADI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professional Association of Diving Instructors</ENAMEX>) being the most common. The basic qualification¬<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">†‚Äî¬†the Open Water Certificate¬†‚Äî¬</ENAMEX>†takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> to complete. This will allow you to dive with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> to a depth of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">60‚ÄÇft</ENAMEX>), which opens many dive sites in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> to you. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Water Divers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watersports</ENAMEX> offers a certification program. They have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> locations around the island (write to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.O. Box SN 165</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southampton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SN BX</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">234-1034</TIMEX>; fax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">234-3561</TIMEX>; website <www.divebermuda.com>).
For those who would like to experience the underwater environment at first hand but don‚Äôt want to dive or can‚Äôt swim, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that operate a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúhelmet diving‚</ENAMEX>Äù system. Walk on the sandy sea bottom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 21‚ÅÑ2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8 ft</ENAMEX>) under the surface wearing a helmet that supplies a constant supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX>. Here you can explore shallow reefs and watch the marine life swim right by. All tours are supervised by guides. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Hartley‚</ENAMEX>Äôs Under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea Adventures</ENAMEX> operates from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watford Bridge Ferry Dock</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somerset</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10am and 1:30pm</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">234-2861</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda Bell Diving</ENAMEX> is located in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Flatts Village</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">292-4434</TIMEX>; fax <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">295-7235</ENAMEX>). 
Fishing and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sport Fishing</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> are teeming with fish <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> round. This is especially true during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer months</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> is on the path of many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">migratory species</ENAMEX>. Sport fishing is hugely popular and can be arranged at a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> around the island. The local guides are especially experienced and helpful.
The deepwater sounds are where the big fish such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marlin</ENAMEX>, sailfish, barracuda, and tuna run. These can be found all around the outer reef, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> local help is needed to pinpoint the best spots, weather, water conditions, and times of year for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish species</ENAMEX>. Reef fishing by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> offers the opportunity to catch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">amberjack</ENAMEX>, snapper, and chub. Fishing from the coastline beaches and docks can be just as exciting, with bonefish, barracuda for sport, and snapper for eating. 
Sport fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> can be rented at most major marinas. Prices vary, but a full day‚Äôs rental of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $400 and $500</NUMEX>. Half-day rentals are also available. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Young Charter Fishing</ENAMEX> offers private or split trips sailing from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somerset</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">234-1832</TIMEX>; fax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">234-2930</TIMEX>; website <www.Bermuda.bm/sportfishing>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eureka Fishing Ltd.</ENAMEX> operates a large-capacity party fishing boat, with per-person rates (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">296-5414</TIMEX>; fax <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">295-3620</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sailboat Tours</ENAMEX>
If you don‚Äôt sail yourself, this is a great way to see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, including the many small islands lying just off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamilton Harbour</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. George‚Äôs Harbour</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hayward‚Äôs Cruises</ENAMEX> departs from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton Harbour</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">292-8652</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator Sports</ENAMEX>
Bermudians are a particularly sociable yet competitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who take enthusiastically to sports. There are many important sporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leagues</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> whose competitions bring out the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
The game of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">cricket</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda‚</ENAMEX>Äôs life blood, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cup Match</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premier</ENAMEX> sporting¬<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">†‚Äî¬†and social¬†‚Äî¬†event</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. The whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is in a holiday mood when the event is held in late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early August</TIMEX>, and most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> close. Everyone‚Äôs attention focuses on enjoying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. You are not just watching the match; you are watching a society at play.
Bermuda‚Äôs maritime heritage can be seen most clearly in the many regattas and ocean races held during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>. Local <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> dinghies, with white sails unfurled, cut through the azure waters. Large sleek <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sailboats</ENAMEX> ply the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> in an ocean-going race at least once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>, and there is nothing quite like watching these beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX> arrive in harbor (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX>). Large crowds gather in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX> to welcome winner and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> alike.
There are also frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>, tennis, and rugby tournaments. Road races, carting, fun runs, triathlons, and marathons are all regular activities, and many of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda‚</ENAMEX>Äôs sporting associations hold invitationals or open tournaments. If you have a special sporting interest, it would be worthwhile contacting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda Department of Tourism</ENAMEX> for specific information. 
Entertainment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotels</ENAMEX> and resorts will of course have regular shows and performances in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, some quite spectacular. Nightlife outside the hotel and resort scene is concentrated in caf√©s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX> in the main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nightclubs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">discos</ENAMEX> are mainly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX>.
Local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> shows reflect such <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermudian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> traditions as steelband music, calypso, goombay, reggae, and limbo dancing, among others. There is also a thriving local rock ‚Äòn‚Äô roll scene.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter season</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November through March</TIMEX>), nightlife can be much quieter. But the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bermuda Arts Festival</ENAMEX> takes up the slack starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> with a series of concerts, opera, plays, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art</ENAMEX> exhibits, and other cultural events featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> from around the world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Festival</ENAMEX> is extremely popular with native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermudians</ENAMEX>, which means many performances sell out immediately. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Office</ENAMEX> has information, or you can contact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda Festival Ltd.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">295-1291</TIMEX>; fax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">295-7403</TIMEX>; website <www.bermudafestival.com>).
Watching Ceremonies
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda</ENAMEX> has a full series of ceremonial activities throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer months</TIMEX>, all based on the traditions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British ‚Äúpomp</ENAMEX> and circumstance.‚Äù Such events as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Opening of Parliament, the Beat Retreat Ceremony, and the ‚ÄúPeppercorn‚Äù Ceremony</ENAMEX> are colorful, exciting, and rich in history. They also bring out the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, and attending makes you feel as though you are a part of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bermudian</ENAMEX> society.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda</ENAMEX> is not a duty-free island. In fact, since there is no income tax for the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, charging duty on imported goods is one way for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to raise funds. Duty varies on the type of goods but is always included in the price. However, there is no sales tax at all in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>, so here is your opportunity to save a little.
Tax-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> will claim to save you up to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> on prices back home, but this is not universal. It is always important to do some research at home before you arrive so that you can compare prices. Some goods are only a little cheaper in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>, but you might want a ‚Äúreal‚Äù bargain.
In many ways, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> is still a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX> of fine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> goods, although the range of merchandise is definitely expanding. Bermudian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> have always bought directly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> rather than through <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">middlemen</ENAMEX>, which has traditionally resulted in a cheaper price than you would find at home. However, government-imposed import duty means that prices might not be as advantageous as they once were. The key to tax-free shopping in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> today is quality, not price.
There is a comprehensive range of quality luxury goods on sale in the major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> on the island. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Front Street in Hamilton</ENAMEX> is a shopper‚Äôs delight, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> offer a helpful and not overpowering sales service. You can browse here in a relaxed, unpressured atmosphere.
The best in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crystal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porcelain tableware</ENAMEX>, silver cutlery, and jewelry can be found, and savings can be made by discerning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> on such names as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waterford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wedgwood, Baccarat</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Doulton</ENAMEX>. Other popular imports from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Isles</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> tweed, cashmere, and genuine tartans.
The oldest department store is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trimingham‚Äôs</ENAMEX>, which has a comprehensive range of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> goods such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">perfume</ENAMEX> and clothing, but other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> act as exclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> for certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> (for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bluck‚Äôs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cooper‚</ENAMEX>Äôs specialize in china and crystal). 
Bermuda‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> sell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and silver jewelry and gemstones such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamonds</ENAMEX>, sapphires, and emeralds set in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>. There are also unusual and rare <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and silver coins recovered from treasures found on the seabed and mounted in gold to be worn as pendants or brooches. A comprehensive range of watches by names such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolex</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breitling</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tag Heuer</ENAMEX> are also available, along with fragrances from around the world. 
Art and Handicrafts
Painting. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> create watercolor images of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>, and their bright harbor scenes or elegant details of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cottages</ENAMEX> will bring back many happy memories of your trip. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Swan</ENAMEX> depicts <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bermudian</ENAMEX> architecture in minimalist fashion, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carol Holding</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Stuart</ENAMEX> paint a more literal picture. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronnie Chameau</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> who works with watercolor, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay</ENAMEX>, and dried grass to create a range of beautiful Bermudian art. She has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trimingham</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX>.
Sculpture. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desmond Fountain</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bermudian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sculptor</ENAMEX> whose work can be seen all over the island. The impression of Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Somers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ordnance Island</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. George‚</ENAMEX>Äôs is his most noted work, but he also accepts commissions to produce beautiful life-sized <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> and smaller pieces. He has a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southampton Princess Hotel</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galleries</ENAMEX>. Visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts Centre</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Naval Dockyard</ENAMEX> to view a range of styles. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. George‚Äôs</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bridge House Art Gallery</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Craft Shop</ENAMEX> (on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King Street</ENAMEX>) has a range of work and represents <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windjammer Gallery</ENAMEX> (on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King Street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX>) has a comprehensive selection of pieces by local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodwork</ENAMEX>. Bermudian <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cedar</ENAMEX> has been used to construct and decorate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, and public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 300 years</TIMEX> and makes a fitting souvenir. Able wood turners now create bowls and carvings that bring out the beauty of the grain. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cedar</ENAMEX> is now rare, other woods are also used.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ceramics</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda Pottery</ENAMEX> (at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Naval Dockyard</ENAMEX>) produces a number of patterns, several with island themes.
Glass. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda Glass Blowing Studio</ENAMEX> (at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailey‚Äôs Bay</ENAMEX>) melds the skill of the glassblower and the heat of the furnace to produce a range of articles such as plates, small <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, and beautiful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">decorations</ENAMEX>.
Clothing
If you don‚Äôt feel like packing for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>, take an empty bag and buy your holiday wardrobe when you arrive in the islands. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Front Street</ENAMEX> department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX> have a full range of fashion items from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and there are many independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX> with ready-to-wear collections. And as in any other tourist destination, there are plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> selling beachwear and T-shirts galore.
Collectibles
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">sea</ENAMEX> has played an important role in the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>, and there is a range of nautical-themed items to purchase. Propellers, brass plates, and displays of nautical knots will remind you of the regatta or ocean yacht race.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> and colonial legacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>, plus a natural tendency for most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bermudian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> in the past never to throw anything away, means that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is a treasure trove of collectibles. Many items found their way over from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, so old tins, buttons, bottles, and items of china and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX> are numerous. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX> and on the roadside as you travel around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> where you can lose yourself for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> searching for that little piece of the past to take <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with you.
Food
The mild climate and abundant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> help to produce some interesting and tasty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foodstuffs</ENAMEX> to take home. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bermuda honey</ENAMEX> has a distinctive taste and is sold at many small roadside vegetable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marmalade</ENAMEX> and preserves have been made for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> to prolong food supplies for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">islanders</ENAMEX>, and you can choose from a wide range of flavors.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liquor</ENAMEX>
Dealing in alcohol and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX> is one of the longest-standing trades in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>, and you will find the finest products from around the world. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> is duty-free only if bought to take off the island, not when purchased for consumption on the island. You will not be allowed to take these purchases with you when you leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, but they will be delivered to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> for you to collect just before you leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>. 
Prices for brands that you have at home might not be cheaper than at your local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, so please undertake some research before you leave for your trip.
Activities for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children</ENAMEX>
There‚Äôs nothing that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> like better than a sandy beach and the sea; they can play for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> in the shallows or build sandcastles on the shore. Most of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> have clean, safe beaches with good <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. 
Always remember to cover youngsters‚Äô skin with a suitable <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">sunscreen</ENAMEX> and to limit their time in the sun for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first few days</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> has very clear air, resulting in more of the damaging rays reaching the surface. Also make sure they are well supervised whenever they are near the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. 
Some large hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> will offer special programs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Some might even have a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can make new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the whole day</TIMEX> in pursuit of such activities as face painting. Also be aware that certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> have an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>-only policy or few <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> specifically for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Always research the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> available at any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> before you make a reservation. 
For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart</ENAMEX>
Below are some attractions that are ideal for younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and locations).
Carriage rides. An exciting way to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamilton¬†‚Äî¬†and</ENAMEX> to be seen by everyone in town.
Ferry rides. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúLandlubbers‚Äù</ENAMEX> will have fun going across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton Bay</ENAMEX>, through the shallow waters, past small islands, and into the tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">harbors</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beat Retreat Ceremony</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> are fascinated by the sound of the drums and bagpipes and by the colorful uniforms. Expect them to march all the way back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deliverance</ENAMEX>. Set them loose to explore this fascinating replica of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Admiral Somers</ENAMEX> and his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shipwreck victims</ENAMEX>. It is almost small enough to be a play ship.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aquarium</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> are fascinating (look for the huge moray eel, which is not for the squeamish), but the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> exhibits are also fun. Talking parrots, peacocks in full display, and cute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lemurs</ENAMEX> will always win hearts.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Caves</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> will be awestruck by both the size and the beauty of this underground cavern. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Devil‚Äôs Hole</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Feeding sharks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX> is great fun, and because the hole is round and small, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> can get pretty close to the action. Just make sure that they don‚Äôt become bait!
Historical re-enactments. In <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King‚Äôs Square</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. George‚Äôs</ENAMEX>, the dunking stools and stocks show that being grounded isn‚Äôt the worst punishment in the world.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolphin Quest</ENAMEX> (at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southampton Princess Hotel</ENAMEX>). Touching and caring for these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">magical creatures</ENAMEX> are activities that every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> will relish. 
Helmet diving. A safe option for those too young to dive or snorkel, as well as a wonderful opportunity to experience the underwater environment at close <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX>.



