



Where to Go
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX> is so compact that it‚Äôs perfect for walking. You can stroll through Downtown in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> and explore a number of distinct neighborhoods: the cobbled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beacon Hill</ENAMEX>, the jumble of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> in the financial district, or the Victorian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back Bay</ENAMEX>. To get your bearings, start with the panoramic view from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Hancock Observatory</ENAMEX> or take a fun trolley tour hopping on and off as you go. If you have limited time, you may want to stick to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Freedom Trail</ENAMEX>, but otherwise get out and explore the neighborhoods. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Details</ENAMEX> of the main sights are given on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX>.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Common</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beacon Hill</ENAMEX>,and The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Esplanade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Common</ENAMEX>
The oldest public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston‚</ENAMEX>Äôs historical, spiritual, and geographical heart. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> settler <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William Blackstone</ENAMEX> sold the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">48-acre</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19-hectare</NUMEX>) parcel of land to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1634</TIMEX>. It served variously as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow pasture</ENAMEX> (until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1830</TIMEX>), drill field, and meeting place. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> regulars camped here. The stocks also stood here and many were hanged on the gallows too. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX>-roofed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Park Street Station</ENAMEX>, which was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1897</TIMEX>, stands at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common</ENAMEX> and is the country‚Äôs oldest subway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>.
Today <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bostonians</ENAMEX> inevitably seem to wind up on the Common. Businesspeople stride along the red brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">paths</ENAMEX>, office workers enjoy a picnic lunch, the elderly sun themselves on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> benches, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> read, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> gather by the bandstand and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War Soldiers and Sailors Monument</ENAMEX>. On a hot day, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> play under the fountain at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frog Pond</ENAMEX> (without <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">frogs nowadays</ENAMEX> and once said to be a place for dunking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witches</ENAMEX>). As <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> approaches, tennis, volleyball, and softball get going.
The adjacent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Public Garden</ENAMEX> is far prettier than the Common. Still supported entirely by private donations, the country‚Äôs original botanical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garden</ENAMEX> boasts a wonderful selection of ornamental flowerbeds, rare <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, and lush <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX>. Weeping willows hang over the lagoon, around which, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, you can take a soporific little tour on a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Swan Boat</ENAMEX>, pedaled by a strapping young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> sitting at the rear. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>, hardy skaters replace the swans.
The garden‚Äôs quirky sculptures and little fountains merit exploration. The most beguiling is the bronze Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mallard</ENAMEX> followed by her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight ducklings</TIMEX> (near the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beacon Street</ENAMEX> entrance), a tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Robert McCloskey‚Äôs Make Way for Ducklings</ENAMEX>, a famous children‚Äôs tale (on sale in all local bookshops). It relates the traumas of rearing a family of ducklings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gilded dome</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massachusetts State House</ENAMEX> glistens above the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> at the northern corner of the Common. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Revere</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Adams</ENAMEX> laid the cornerstone in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1785</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Bulfinch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Capitol</ENAMEX>, designed the original core which was completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1798</TIMEX>. In front of the neoclassical fa√ßade stand several statues including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Hutchinson</ENAMEX>, who left the intolerant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quaker Mary Dyer</ENAMEX> who was hung for her unorthodox views, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX> striding in front of the western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>.
Inside, history is expressed everywhere. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doric Hall</ENAMEX> displays portraits and statues of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX>. Murals of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revolutionary</ENAMEX> events line <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nurses‚Äô Hall</ENAMEX>, which features a moving sculpture of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> ministering to a wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>. The heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> lies <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives Chamber</ENAMEX> in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúsacred cod‚Äù</ENAMEX> hangs as it has since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1895</TIMEX>, a reminder of the city‚Äôs humble beginnings as a fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX>. Opposite, the impressive domed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Chamber</ENAMEX> is lined with busts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lafayette</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, and others.
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beacon Hill</ENAMEX>
Behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most desirable residential neighborhood has the air of a somnolent village, insulated from the traffic and vulgarity of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> still a preserve of the old-monied who occupy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Revival</ENAMEX>, and Victorian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> that have stoops, boot-scrapers, and wrought iron railings.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX> so many leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> lived here that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> became known as <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúThe Athens of the United States</ENAMEX>.‚Äù On <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chestnut Street</ENAMEX> alone, there lived <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Parkman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin Booth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Ward Howe</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Singer Sargent</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louisa May Alcott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nathaniel Hawthorne</ENAMEX> resided on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pinckney Street</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beacon Street</ENAMEX> which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Wendell Holmes</ENAMEX> dubbed ‚Äúthe sunny <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> that holds the sifted few‚Äù boasted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Prescott</ENAMEX>. At number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beacon</ENAMEX>, stop at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Athenaeum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">227-0270</TIMEX>; guided tours <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3pm</TIMEX>; reservations needed), a haven for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> since it was established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1807</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750,000</NUMEX>-volume collection is amazing, but so too is the interior of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1849</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, which is exquisitely furnished with antiques, busts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin Franklin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Webster</ENAMEX>, and others, and several paintings by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Singer Sargent</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert Stuart</ENAMEX>. Farther along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beacon</ENAMEX> at number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Gray Otis</ENAMEX> died in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulfinch</ENAMEX> designed for him. Don‚Äôt miss the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Louisburg Square</ENAMEX> surrounded by some of the finest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Revival</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols House</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Vernon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Street</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">227-6993</ENAMEX>, open for guided tours <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">May‚ÄìOctober Tuesday‚ÄìSaturday</ENAMEX>, noon‚<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Äì5pm</TIMEX>; February‚ÄìApril and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">November‚</ENAMEX>ÄìDecember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> noon‚<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Äì5pm</ENAMEX>), offers a chance to view the interior of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> attributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulfinch</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> are exactly as they were when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose Standish Nichols</ENAMEX>, a noted landscape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>. Furnishings include <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Flemish</ENAMEX> tapestries, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX> rugs, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> art. Don‚Äôt overlook <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acorn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Street¬†‚Äî¬†the</ENAMEX> prettiest of them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">all¬†‚Äî¬†a cobbled lane</ENAMEX> so narrow that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> can‚Äôt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> here to spoil a photographer‚Äôs picture. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Street</ENAMEX> serves as the community‚Äôs main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and as a magnet for serious antique <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX>. Also note the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Charles Street Meeting House</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Harriet Tubman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sojourner Truth</ENAMEX>, and other abolitionists preached.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Joy Street</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African Meeting House</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX>) and to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">141</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cambridge Street</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Gray Otis House</ENAMEX> (guided tours <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wednesday‚ÄìSunday 11am‚Äì4pm</ENAMEX>), the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulfinch</ENAMEX> designed for prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beacon Hill</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otis</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The 19th-century</TIMEX> furnishings are opulent and surprisingly brilliantly colored.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Esplanade</ENAMEX>
Explore westwards from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Charles Street</ENAMEX>, and you‚Äôll come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Esplanade</ENAMEX>, a long narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Charles River</ENAMEX>. Here <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bostonians</ENAMEX> enjoy jogging, walking, cycling, in-line skating, or just watching the river life. The much-loved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> Pops <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orchestra</ENAMEX> performs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art Deco Hatch Memorial Shell</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 4th of July</TIMEX> performance is a knockout (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84</NUMEX>).
Along the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Downtown Freedom trail to Downtown Crossing</ENAMEX>
From <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brimstone Corner to Filene‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> bordering the eastern side of the common is filled with historical imprints and some of the city‚Äôs major architectural highlights, which are great when viewed from the harbor (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Street Church</ENAMEX> stands on a site whose nickname comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brimstone Corner</ENAMEX> (some say for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiery sermons</ENAMEX> delivered by such figures as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Ward Beecher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Lloyd Garrison</ENAMEX>, who delivered his first anti-slavery speech here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1829</TIMEX>, others because gunpowder was kept in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1812 War</ENAMEX>). Built on the site of a granary in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1809</TIMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">church‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most beautiful feature is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">217</NUMEX>-ft- (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">66-m-</NUMEX>) tall triple-tiered steeple, based on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Wren</ENAMEX> design.
The adjacent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Granary Burying Ground</ENAMEX> contains the graves of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Hancock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Revere</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Adams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Otis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Boston Massacre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Treat Paine</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Boston Massacre trial</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Faneuil</ENAMEX>. A map near the entrance locates the gravestones of the famous. Note the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">headstones</ENAMEX> carved with skull and crossbones or winged death‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> motifs. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> headstones have been moved to accommodate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> and the lawnmower, so they may not mark accurately where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">remains</ENAMEX> lie; furthermore, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple of dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> may be interred under each stone given that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> are buried here.
Continue northward along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tremont Street</ENAMEX> to the squat, granite <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King‚Äôs Chapel</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thursday‚</ENAMEX>Äì <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday 9am‚Äì4pm</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only 9am‚Äì4pm</TIMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican</ENAMEX> place of worship in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, it stands on land taken by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andros</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial ground</ENAMEX> next door: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puritans</ENAMEX> refused to sell any land that would be used to benefit a denomination that had persecuted them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants worshiped</ENAMEX> here until the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX> caused a split in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congregation</ENAMEX> and placed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in jeopardy. After the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX> it became the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Unitarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, even while it retained much of the ritual and musical tradition of the earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> (frequent lunchtime and other concerts are given). The magnificent interior, one of the finest examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> architecture in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>, has lavishly upholstered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pews¬†‚Äî¬†especially the governor‚Äôs¬†‚Äî¬†gilt crown</ENAMEX> and miters on the organ case, the oldest pulpit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, and a bell cast by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Revere</ENAMEX> that was tolled at his death.
Adjacent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King‚Äôs Chapel Burial Ground</ENAMEX>, is the city‚Äôs oldest and holds many historical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Winthrop</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Dawes</ENAMEX>, who rode with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Revere</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Pain</ENAMEX>, the model for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hawthorne‚Äôs Hester Prynne in The Scarlet Letter</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Bulfinch</ENAMEX> is buried under the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel</ENAMEX> itself.
Turn down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">School Street</ENAMEX>, to the mosaic plaque outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old City Hall</ENAMEX> commemorating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Public Latin School</ENAMEX>, which was founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1635</TIMEX>, the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Franklin</ENAMEX> was an early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pupil</ENAMEX>, and his statue stands in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> here. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Latin</ENAMEX> is now in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fenway</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> there still have to study <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beaux Arts City Hall</ENAMEX> has been replaced by nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Center</ENAMEX>. It is now home to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maison Henri</ENAMEX>, a highly recommended <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>.
Back on the corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tremont Street</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omni Parker House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> (the oldest continually operating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>) has been associated with much of the city‚Äôs political and social history since it opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1854</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX> announced his candidacy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press Room</ENAMEX> and to this day the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> is still a quintessential politician‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Literary Club</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine Club</ENAMEX> met here gathering such figures as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Henry Dana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Greenleaf Whittier</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Russell Lowell</ENAMEX>, and others. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX> was founded here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1857</TIMEX>. Here too, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ho Chi Minh</ENAMEX> worked in the kitchens around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm X</ENAMEX>, who was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Roxbury</ENAMEX>, worked as a busboy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX>.
At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, the lovely red-brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gambrel</ENAMEX> roof was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1718</TIMEX> as an apothecary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> on the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Hutchinson‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX> it became a literary light when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ticknor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fields</ENAMEX>, the publisher of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emerson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Longfellow</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thoreau</ENAMEX> operated here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1832 to 1865</TIMEX> and when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX> was the most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe Corner Bookstore</ENAMEX> sells memorabilia and souvenirs associated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Across the street stands a moving monument to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> who fled starvation and oppression crossing ‚Äúthe bowl of tears‚Äù to seek a better life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>.
Diagonally opposite, stands the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old South Meeting House</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1729</TIMEX>). Here on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 December</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1773</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX> came to protest the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> tax. They listened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Adams</ENAMEX> and then marched down to the docks and dumped <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">123,000 pounds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> into the harbor (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Franklin</ENAMEX> was baptized here, and black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Wheatley</ENAMEX> worshiped here. During the occupation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> desecrated the church ripping out the pews and using it as a riding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it‚Äôs been restored and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> can enjoy an audio presentation about the great controversies that have been aired here.
Continue up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Washington Street</ENAMEX>, into the heart of the Downtown shopping area (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX>). Here the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Freedom Trail</ENAMEX> doubles back on itself to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old State House</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1713</TIMEX>), a red-brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> with a wedding cake bell <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>. The surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> dwarf it. It was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Government‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and also served as the merchants‚Äô exchange and after the revolution as the state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">capitol</ENAMEX>. Here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Otis</ENAMEX> argued against the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Writs of Assistance; the Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> was read from the balcony on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 July</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX>. The gold <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX> and silver unicorn above, symbols of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> crown, are replicas of originals that were destroyed that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">same day</TIMEX>. Inside, displays and historical artifacts relate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston‚Äôs Revolutionary</ENAMEX> history. Other exhibits concentrate on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> events, like the first attempt to integrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1848</TIMEX>.
It‚Äôs easy to miss the circle of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> in a traffic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old State House</ENAMEX> marking the site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Boston Massacre</ENAMEX>. Here on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 5, 1770</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, taunted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX>, fired on an angry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crispus Attucks</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, who was black. The massacre aided the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revolutionary</ENAMEX> cause by creating its first martyrs and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">propagandists</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Revere</ENAMEX>, who made an engraving of the event, used it to their advantage.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">city‚Äôs malls</ENAMEX> now outshine the shopping district of Downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Crossing</ENAMEX> (around the crossroads of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>), but here you‚Äôll discover long-established department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Macy‚Äôs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Filene‚Äôs.</ENAMEX> It‚Äôs hard to imagine the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pedestrians</ENAMEX>-only <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Washington Street</ENAMEX> joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old State House</ENAMEX> south to the neck of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shawmut</ENAMEX> peninsula before the landfills were created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>. A few quaint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> are hidden down side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX>, as is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke-Ober</ENAMEX> (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winter Place</ENAMEX>), which has served traditional fare to well-heeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a century</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Center</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faneuil Hall</ENAMEX>
This is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston‚</ENAMEX>Äôs commercial and financial heart, but it‚Äôs far from being an homogeneous district: It incorporates the austere <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Center</ENAMEX> and the lively <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faneuil Hall</ENAMEX> Marketplace.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Center</ENAMEX>
Little good can be said about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Center</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs monolithic, dreary, and soulless. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has attempted to enliven the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> by adding a garden with terraces, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pools</ENAMEX>, and niches where music is performed, but there‚Äôs still little reason to visit, except to see the enormous <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Steaming Kettle</ENAMEX> on the south side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX> above the door of the eponymous coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>. Commissioned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tea Company</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1873</TIMEX>, it is an appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landmark</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> so closely linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>. Its capacity is printed on its side: <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">227 gallons</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> quarts, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> pint, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> gills (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">some 868 liters</NUMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faneuil Hall</ENAMEX> Marketplace
Annually <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> come to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faneuil Hall</ENAMEX>, the great ‚ÄúCradle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberty‚Äù</ENAMEX> and marketplace. It‚Äôs very commercial, but very alluring and one of the most successful restorations anywhere.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huguenot</ENAMEX> merchant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Faneuil</ENAMEX> (pronounced fannel, fan‚Äôl or funnel), gave it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1742</TIMEX>. The original, consisting of a town hall above and a market below was burned down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1762</TIMEX>, but was swiftly rebuilt. Here on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> floor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boston‚</ENAMEX>Äôs great orators raised their voices against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> tyranny, against slavery, and female oppression. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> still used for meetings and assemblies. The vast painting behind the stage shows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Webster</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Calhoun</ENAMEX> arguing over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>. On the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> floor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of the Ancient</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Honorable Artillery Company</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1637</TIMEX>, displays historic flags, paintings, and military memorabilia (open <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monday‚ÄìFriday</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9am‚Äì5pm</ENAMEX>). The building‚Äôs most legendary feature is the grasshopper weathervane. No one knows really why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tinsmith</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shem Drowne</ENAMEX> chose the grasshopper motif, although some say it symbolizes good fortune. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1805</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Bulfinch</ENAMEX> enlarged the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>.
Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fanueil Hall</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quincy</ENAMEX> market <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> fill with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, who come to feast on chowder, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">deli sandwiches</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX>, and an array of ethnic cuisines. They also come to shop at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX>, the flower market, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, to watch the street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entertainers</ENAMEX> and to sample the nightlife. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in particular draws folks¬<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">†‚Äî¬†Durgin Park</ENAMEX>, which offers <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX>, communal dining, and tough no-nonsense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitresses</ENAMEX>. When they were built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1826</TIMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> stood on the waterfront. Older <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bostonians</ENAMEX> can still recall the stench of rancid meat emanating from them on a hot summer‚Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> and the gradual decay of the area before they were restored in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackstone Block</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Holocaust Memorial</ENAMEX>
A neon sign northeast of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX>, beckons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union Oyster House</ENAMEX> which opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1826</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackstone Block</ENAMEX>, a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">red-brick buildings</ENAMEX> separated by narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> that dates to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1713</TIMEX>. Even if you don‚Äôt intend to eat here, peer in the window at the oysters and clams being shucked at the raw bar (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> serves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 4,000</NUMEX> oysters on a busy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>).
In front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackstone</ENAMEX> block the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Holocaust Memorial</ENAMEX> with its <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six</NUMEX> glass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> placed above a smoldering chamber recall the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> who died. Also look out for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Stone</ENAMEX> set in the wall of a gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Marshall Street</ENAMEX>. It was once used to grind paint from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pigments</ENAMEX>, and was put here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1737</TIMEX> as a distance marker.
Don‚Äôt miss the colorful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> and vegetable market that takes place at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haymarket</ENAMEX>, just behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackstone Block</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North End</ENAMEX> and Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">River</ENAMEX> to Charlestown
An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> Festa
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North End</ENAMEX> with its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">caf√©s</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and vibrant street festivals is one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most entrancing neighborhoods.
Before the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX>, royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and other wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> lived here, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX> it became a crowded slum as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">immigrants¬†‚Äî¬†Irish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Italian¬†‚Äî¬†poured</ENAMEX> into the district. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">titans</ENAMEX> got their start here on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanover Street¬†‚Äî¬†Eben Jordan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. H. Macy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúHoney Fitz</ENAMEX>,‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose Kennedy</ENAMEX>, was born on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ferry Street</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> took hold in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX> and made the area the lovable, close-knit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> in aprons still feel free to loll outside in the evenings.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanover Street</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North End‚</ENAMEX>Äôs commercial backbone lined with caf√©s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> frequented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> evenings <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> gather for a liqueur and gelati at the cavernous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caff√® Vittoria</ENAMEX> at number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">296</NUMEX>. Examine the walls for splendid black-and-white photographs of the area.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salem Street</ENAMEX>, just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanover</ENAMEX>, is another atmospheric street lined with wonderful delicatessens redolent with the scents of fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheeses</ENAMEX>, sausages, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pasta</ENAMEX>, newsagents selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">La Gazzetta</ENAMEX> dello <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sport</ENAMEX>, and such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bakeries</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bova</ENAMEX>, selling first-rate cakes and pastries at number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">134</NUMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historical Sights</ENAMEX>
The clapboard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul Revere House</ENAMEX>, tucked into pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Square</ENAMEX>, is the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, dating to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1680</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Revere</ENAMEX> purchased it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1770</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">¬£213</NUMEX>, a sizable sum for an artisan. The exterior is notable for its diamond pane windows, deep second-story overhang, and massive chimneys. Inside, it‚Äôs furnished with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX> pieces, but only a few letters and engravings recall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revere‚</ENAMEX>Äôs life here.
Boat builder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathaniel Hichborn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revere‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, lived in what is now the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pierce-Hichborn House</ENAMEX>, one of the city‚Äôs earliest brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Georgians</ENAMEX> built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1711</TIMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most days</TIMEX>, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> guided tours (details available from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul Revere House</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">523-2338</ENAMEX> for more information).
Back on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hanover Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Stephen‚Äôs Church</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1804</TIMEX>), is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston‚</ENAMEX>Äôs only remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulfinch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. It began as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congregationalist Church</ENAMEX> but since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1862</TIMEX> has served the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic Irish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose Kennedy</ENAMEX>, baptized his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> here. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> looks down what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prado</ENAMEX>, officially named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Revere Mall</ENAMEX>. The equestrian statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Revere</ENAMEX>, set against the steeple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old North Church</ENAMEX> rising out of the foliage, is one of the most photographed sights in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Locals chat on the stone benches of the promenade, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> inspect the bronze plaques on the brick walls that pay tribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North End‚</ENAMEX>Äôs famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old North Church</ENAMEX> (properly known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christ Church</ENAMEX>) is the city‚Äôs most beloved. Here on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 April, 1775</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sexton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Newman</ENAMEX> climbed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> and hung the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lanterns (‚Äúone</ENAMEX>, if by land, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, if by sea‚Äù) warning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Concord</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> troop movements. The lanterns are lit on the eve of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriot‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day each year</TIMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>). Modeled on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Wren‚</ENAMEX>Äôs designs it was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1723</TIMEX>. The steeple was added in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1740</TIMEX> and has toppled several times. The interior contains enclosed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pews</ENAMEX> with brass nameplates of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who worshiped here, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reveres</ENAMEX>. Numerous memorials around the walls recall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> who died in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tories</ENAMEX> who fled the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
The last <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Freedom Trail</ENAMEX> stop in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North End</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Copp‚Äôs Hill Burying Ground</ENAMEX>, which has a fine view across the river to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charlestown</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sexton Robert Newman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cotton Mather</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Hall</ENAMEX>, a free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">black</ENAMEX> who founded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro Freemasons</ENAMEX>, are all buried here. Note too the pockmarks on some of the headstones caused by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> who used them for target <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle of Bunker Hill</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> west down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commercial</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Causeway</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, and you will soon reach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Station</ENAMEX> and the site of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston Garden</ENAMEX>, the beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bruins ice hockey</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtics</ENAMEX> basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FleetCenter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">624-1000</ENAMEX> for information on events) has now replaced it.
Charlestown
Across the river, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Charlestown Navy Yard</ENAMEX> has played a major role in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston‚Äôs</ENAMEX> history for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly two hundred years</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to the indomitable <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúOld Ironsides,‚Äù</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.S. Constitution</ENAMEX>, a war ship that was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1797</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North End</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$302,718</NUMEX>. During her naval career, she won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> battles, captured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX>, and was undefeated. Her most notable triumphs occurred during the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War of 1812</ENAMEX> when she vanquished the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Guerriere</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java, Cyane</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levant</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailor</ENAMEX> gave her the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúOld Ironsides</ENAMEX>,‚Äù as cannon balls skimmed off her copper sheathed gunwales and he marveled at her apparent indestructibility. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> you can go aboard to see the decks. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every July 4th</TIMEX> she fires a salute and is taken out on a short cruise. You can also visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> destroyer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. Cassin Young</ENAMEX> and take guided tours of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Yard</ENAMEX> conducted by the park <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rangers</ENAMEX>. At the adjacent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution Museum</ENAMEX> you can computer skipper the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> through some of her famous battles and trace the route she took on her round the world trade mission in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1844</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exhibits</ENAMEX> also show how horrendous were the living conditions endured by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX>.
Nearby, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">220</NUMEX>-ft- (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">67- m-</NUMEX>) tall tapering granite obelisk, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bunker Hill Monument</ENAMEX> commemorates the first battle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 June</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1775¬†‚Äî¬</NUMEX>†a hollow victory for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> who suffered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,000</NUMEX> casualties against <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">400 to 600</TIMEX> for the colonials. Despite the name it actually stands on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Breed‚Äôs Hill</ENAMEX>, the site of the colonial redoubt in the battle. At its base is a swashbuckling statue by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Wetmore Storey</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colonel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prescott</ENAMEX>, who gave the famous order: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúDon‚Äôt fire ‚</ENAMEX>Äôtil you see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> of their eyes.‚Äù There are informative models depicting the battle‚Äôs progress as well as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musket</ENAMEX>-firing demonstrations. You can climb the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">294</NUMEX> spiral steps to an enclosed deck, which has great views. A multimedia presentation at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">The Bunker Hill Pavilion</ENAMEX> re-enacts the battle.
To reach <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlestown</ENAMEX>: walk along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Freedom Trail</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">roughly</NUMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15-minute</TIMEX> walk from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Copp‚Äôs Hill</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Yard</ENAMEX>) or take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orange Line</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community College</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bunker Hill Monument</ENAMEX>), or else take the water <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shuttle</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Long Wharf</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Financial District</ENAMEX> and Chinatown
State <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Street</ENAMEX> originally linked the wharves to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old State House</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it is a commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> boasting the showy glass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stock Exchange Building</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">53 Exchange</ENAMEX> Place), which features a monumental marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">staircase</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">foyer</ENAMEX>. Another ostentatious marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">atrium foyer</ENAMEX> marks number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX>. At the harbor end stands the bizarre <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Custom House Tower</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX> that was added to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Revival</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple base</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1913</TIMEX>.
For a good look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Downtown‚</ENAMEX>Äôs architecture, go to the green triangle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Office Square</ENAMEX>. Stepped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Deco‚</ENAMEX>Äìstyle wall decorations make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Telephone Building</ENAMEX> on the southern edge of the square <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most arresting. The lobby‚<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Äôs 360</NUMEX>-degree mural celebrates the proletarian history of the telephone. You can also pop in to a little room off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> that replicates the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attic room</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Bell</ENAMEX> on nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Court Street</ENAMEX>. It was from there that he <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> transmitted sounds electrically over a wire in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1875</TIMEX> (open <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monday‚ÄìFriday</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30am‚Äì5pm</TIMEX>).
There are said to be over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chinatown</ENAMEX>, the crowded <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">blocks</ENAMEX> bordered by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kneeland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Essex</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Expressway</ENAMEX>. Even if you don‚Äôt intend to eat here, you might enjoy visiting some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> jewelry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bakeries</ENAMEX>, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> that feature pagoda-topped telephone boxes. It‚Äôs small compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Francisco‚</ENAMEX>Äôs sprawling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chinatowns</ENAMEX>, so don‚Äôt bother unless you‚Äôre really interested.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waterfront</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fort Point Channel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wharves</ENAMEX> reach out into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boston Harbor</ENAMEX> from Downtown and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North End</ENAMEX> like the fingers on a hand. Once this was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> busiest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, with clippers jostling for space. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> after a long period of decline, the area has revived and the granite <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouses</ENAMEX> have been renovated into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> sailed home from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Long Wharf</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> you can sail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harbor Islands</ENAMEX>, take a cruise around the harbor, or just sit and admire the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX> at anchor.
On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Wharf</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Aquarium</ENAMEX> is one of the best anywhere. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centerpiece</ENAMEX> is a giant <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200,000-gallon</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank</ENAMEX> containing a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-ft- (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7-m-</ENAMEX>) deep coral reef filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX>, sea <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> times a day, scuba <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divers</ENAMEX> go in to feed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, a fascinating spectacle to watch. Ramps circle the tank so that you can walk around the whole thing. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 70</NUMEX> exhibit tanks make up the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aquarium</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>. They are categorized as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> or fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and feature <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> inhabiting different marine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">climates</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cold</ENAMEX> and temperate to tropical. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> can see the life forms found in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt marsh</ENAMEX>, a mangrove swamp, or along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> seashore. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> love the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Touch Tide Pool</ENAMEX> where they can handle crabs and starfish. Other perennial favorites are the penguins, the sea otters, and the sea <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX>, who provide entertainment in the theater. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">aquarium</ENAMEX> is currently undergoing an expansion that will triple its size. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">West Wing</ENAMEX> containing a large outdoor seal exhibit, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> of exhibits, plus <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">visitor facilities</ENAMEX> opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. A large-format <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> will open in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> and the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East Wing</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>.
To the south <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rowes Wharf</ENAMEX> hosts many different cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> and also anchors the luxurious <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boston Harbor Hotel</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fort Point Channel</ENAMEX> divides Downtown from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Boston</ENAMEX> (confusingly to the east) and here, docked by one of the rusty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beaver</ENAMEX> II looks anachronistic. In a way it is, for it‚Äôs a replica of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriots</ENAMEX>, dressed as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>, boarded and from which they dumped <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">342 chests</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>. Built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX> it sailed across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bicentennial</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Tea Party Ship and Museum</ENAMEX> invites you to explore the decks and hold and to join the costumed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in tossing a bale of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> over the side. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> on the small, adjacent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX> explains the historical background. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> does a brisk trade in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> towels, mugs, and, of course, packets of the precious leaves. 
A superb <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> stands across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fort Point Channel</ENAMEX> marked by a whimsical giant milk bottle, which serves <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children‚Äôs Museum</ENAMEX> is both a vast <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX> and a stimulating learning <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. The buzz words here are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúhands on‚Äù</ENAMEX>: There are strange sculptures to climb over, bubbles to make, and hopscotch to play in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kid‚Äôs Bridge¬†‚Äî¬†a</ENAMEX> reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston‚</ENAMEX>Äôs multiculturalism. The most original part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> is an entire <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>, and tatami <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, which have authentic scents, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Teen Tokyo</ENAMEX>, where you can ride the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX> and take up the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sumo Challenge</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cruises</ENAMEX> and Looking For Leviathans
On a fine day, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> trip in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boston Harbor</ENAMEX> is idyllic. The rectangular, circular, and pyramidal shapes of the downtown rooflines are etched magnificently against the skyline. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is bobbing with yachts, speedboats, tugs, and fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>, while a constant stream of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> descends onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">waterside runways</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the world‚Äôs busiest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>.
As you reach the outer harbor, the urban scenery fades, and a jumble of indecipherable green lumps appear. These are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> tiny islands that constitute The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harbor Islands</ENAMEX>. Gulls hover over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lobster pots</ENAMEX> or perch on rocky outcrops; channel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">markers</ENAMEX> float on the surface and small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lighthouses</ENAMEX> appear on the horizon.
There‚Äôs not that much to do or see on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> islands that make up <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boston Harbor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islands State Park</ENAMEX>, but an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> spent here offers gentle strolls, picnics, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>-watching¬†‚Äî¬†a welcome respite from urban frenzy. From <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-October</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boston Harbor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cruise Company</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">723-7800</ENAMEX>) operates a ferry from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Long Wharf</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georges Island</ENAMEX>, the core of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fort Warren</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>-shaped fortress in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> were incarcerated during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX> occupies most of the island. It‚Äôs an atmospheric and spooky place, with old gun emplacements, lookout posts, and chilly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX>.
You can also visit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">islands¬†‚Äî¬†Peddocks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lovells, Bumpkin, Gallops</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Grape¬†‚Äî¬†on</ENAMEX> a free water-shuttle service from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georges Island</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July to Labor Day</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lovells</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> with a designated swimming area. For details on camping, see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most exciting experiences you can have in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX>-watching. From <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> through to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, literally <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of sightseeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> scattered along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> coast <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> out to an area known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stellwagen Bank</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whales</ENAMEX> stock up on plankton and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> before migrating to warmer <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> climes. If you sail from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gloucester</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Provincetown</ENAMEX>, which are closer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX>, you will spend less time getting there and more time actually looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whales</ENAMEX>. For details of sightseeing and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX>-watching trips, see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">111</NUMEX>.
Humpbacks are most commonly spotted, but you might also spy the larger fin <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whales</ENAMEX> (which measure up to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">80-ft or 24-m</NUMEX> in length¬†‚Äî¬†the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> biggest species after blue <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whales</ENAMEX>) and swift, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-ft</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9-m</ENAMEX>) -long minkes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôre</ENAMEX> almost certain to glimpse a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX>. In fact, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> you may see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as forty</NUMEX>. (You are more likely to see greater numbers if the weather is poor; take seasickness medicine before boarding.)
When the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">guide¬†‚Äî¬†who</ENAMEX> is usually a well-qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">naturalist¬†‚Äî¬†makes</ENAMEX> a sighting, everyone rushes to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>, causing it to lurch suddenly. The boat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> off toward the telltale sign of the spume of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, and then suddenly, there it is: a silvery flank virtually underneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>. A flick of a tail or fluke, and it‚Äôs gone. If you are very lucky, you may see the rare spectacle of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale breaching</ENAMEX>, heaving its entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. At times, it seems as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whales</ENAMEX> themselves are doing the watching, when they approach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>, swimming underneath them, and staring up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. 
Back <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay</ENAMEX> and The Fenway
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the 19th-century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> ended at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Common</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back Bay</ENAMEX> was just a polluted tidal flat. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX>, however, an immense landfill project transformed it into the city‚Äôs most fashionable residential and commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district</ENAMEX> to which the well-to-do moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beacon Hill</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South End</ENAMEX>.
In contrast to the tangled maze of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> of the ‚Äúold‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back Bay</ENAMEX> was meticulously planned in regimented lines inspired by the boulevards of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. The residential <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">district North</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Boylston Street</ENAMEX> contains some of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> architecture in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churches</ENAMEX> and Skyscrapers
From the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Public Garden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Boylston Street</ENAMEX> leads into the commercial section of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back Bay</ENAMEX>. Follow it a short way to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Copley Square</ENAMEX>, a popular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> focal point for concerts, and a place where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> splash in the fountain. Here a feast of contrasting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> competes for your attention.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleek</ENAMEX>, blue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Hancock Tower</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New England‚</ENAMEX>Äôs tallest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, rises on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> are knife-edge thin, and from certain vantage points it seems as if the building virtually disappears. When it was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> it was a disaster because the glass blew out, so every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sheet</ENAMEX> had to be replaced. If the weather is fine, pay a visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Observatory</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">60th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>. There‚Äôs no better way to get to grips with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston‚</ENAMEX>Äôs peculiar topography. A model of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1775</TIMEX> brings <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> just how much of the present land was under water at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> feared that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> would eclipse one of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity Church</ENAMEX>, but the beauty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hobson Richardson‚</ENAMEX>Äôs masterpiece now reflected in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tower‚Äôs glass</ENAMEX>, has only been enhanced. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> has been named by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIA</ENAMEX> one of the nation‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> best <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1877</TIMEX> when it was consecrated, it cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750,000</NUMEX>. For that amount the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioners</ENAMEX> purchased the great stained glass windows by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John LaFarge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Burne-Jones</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Morris</ENAMEX> in addition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> itself. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> has had some colorful preachers too from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Parker</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips Brooks</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">O Little Town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX>, and a prodigious gourmet, who also loved the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX>, billiards, and fly-fishing. Ironically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hancock</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> enriched the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> won <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.6 million</NUMEX> in a suit against its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> for damage caused during construction.
On the other side of the square the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Public Library</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1895</TIMEX>), the oldest free municipal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> in the world), is well worth visiting. The grand <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> has several decorative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">highlights¬†‚Äî¬†the bronze</ENAMEX> doors by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Chester French</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dartmouth</ENAMEX> entrance, the double marble staircase graced with murals by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puvis de Chavannes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin Austin Abbey</ENAMEX>, and on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Singer Sargent</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson Building</ENAMEX> was added in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> and now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> holds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than six million</NUMEX> books stored on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">65 miles</NUMEX> of shelves.
Copley Place, on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Huntington Avenue</ENAMEX>, is a large shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>, anchored by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two 1,000</NUMEX>-room <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred-plus</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>. A walkway connects it to the graceless <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudential Center</ENAMEX>, from which the famous amphibious <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> leave on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boston Duck Tours</ENAMEX>. After touring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, go up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Top of The Hub</ENAMEX> bar-restaurant and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skywalk</ENAMEX> (open <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monday‚ÄìFriday</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">10am‚Äì7pm</ENAMEX>) great vantage points from which to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock Tower</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skywalk</ENAMEX> is quieter and more spacious than the neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">observatory</ENAMEX>, though the views are less impressive.
A little farther along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Huntington Avenue</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Science World Headquarters</ENAMEX> may not sound enticing (and indeed, the austerity of the administration <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> around a vast reflecting pool makes a somber first impression). Still, the huge basilica of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Church of Christ, Scientist</ENAMEX>, a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX>-style church enveloping the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Church</ENAMEX> is an amazing edifice. It can hold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX>; its tiered seating makes it more like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> than a place of worship. The organ, which is the focal point of the space, contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,595</NUMEX> pipes covering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> octaves.
Except for quotations on the walls from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Testament</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Science</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Baker Eddy</ENAMEX>, there‚Äôs no decoration. Some stained glass windows are found in the older <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, which also contains <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Baker Eddy‚</ENAMEX>Äôs chair. She only addressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congregation</ENAMEX> twice, as she wished to avoid any personal idolatry. A guided tour is highly recommended (you can only visit the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> by joining a tour).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Science</ENAMEX> publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, adjacent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> an interesting phenomenon, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mapparium</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-ft</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9m</NUMEX>)-wide glass globe, made of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">608 stained</NUMEX> glass panels that are lit from outside by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> lights. You can stand on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> in the middle of the sphere and study this dramatic object created by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chester Lindsay Churchill</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1932 and 1935</TIMEX> (it shows the national borders as they were then).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chic</ENAMEX> and the Victorian
A stroll along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Newbury Street¬†‚Äî¬†the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">city‚Äôs</ENAMEX> most expensive real <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">estate¬†‚Äî¬</ENAMEX>†is the most civilized and congenial of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> experiences. This is where the chic and the conservative come to furnish their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> with art and antiques, wrap their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> in designer fashion, have their hair styled in upmarket salons, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, dine, and drink iced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee al fresco</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>. Image and appearance take center stage here, both in the showcase windows and the personas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> looking at them. Every <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">display¬†‚Äî¬†whether</ENAMEX> of fine art, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">fashion¬†‚Äî¬†is</ENAMEX> worth a picture. Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> exhibit works by major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice the</ENAMEX> architecture as well: At the end of the converted carriage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, the less genteel eastern end gives way to series of alternate classic bow- and flat-fronted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">townhouses</ENAMEX>.
Take a detour along the way down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, alphabetically arranged from A to H, starting at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Public Garden</ENAMEX> (they‚Äôre named after <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>). In between the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX>, look out for the narrow, arrow-straight service <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> that form the entranceway to the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">servants‚Äô quarters</ENAMEX> at the backs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. The strip which is lined with elms and runs down the spine of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonwealth Avenue</ENAMEX> is the perfect vantage point on which to stand back and gaze at the ornate Victorian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> built in a range of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">styles¬†‚Äî¬†French</ENAMEX> Second <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian Gothic</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance Revival</ENAMEX>. Detour to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKim Mead & White</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Andrew</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hereford Street</ENAMEX> and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that housed the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Farmer Cooking School</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hereford Street</ENAMEX>. You can get a wonderful sense of life in a Victorian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back Bay</ENAMEX> home at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibson House</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">137 Beacon Street</ENAMEX>, (open for tours <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">May‚ÄìOctober</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wednesday‚</ENAMEX>ÄìSunday at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 2</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3pm</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends the rest of the year</TIMEX>). The contents of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">house¬†‚Äî¬†imported</ENAMEX> carpets, plush <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ottomans¬†‚Äî¬</ENAMEX>†are the fascinating and colorful legacy of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibsons</ENAMEX>, who lived here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1860 to 1954</TIMEX>.
Fenway
Come to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fenway</ENAMEX> to enjoy the city‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> superb art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, located close to the meandering tract of ponds, reeds, and meadows of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back Bay Fens</ENAMEX>, and to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX> in action at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fenway Park</ENAMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenmore Square</ENAMEX>, pinpointed from afar by a massive neon CITGO sign, is a congested intersection of fast-food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, frequented by local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> and university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Fine Arts</ENAMEX> (or MFA) contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most important art collections in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">There‚Äôs much¬†‚Äî¬†too much¬†‚Äî¬†to</ENAMEX> absorb in one visit, so choose particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> or take a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Highlights Tour leaflet</ENAMEX> and pick out just a few works. For example, the museum‚Äôs outstanding collections of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> works include <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> armor, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Javanese statue gods</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai Buddhas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX>. There are first-rate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mummies</ENAMEX> and early sculptures, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nubian</ENAMEX> statues and stelae. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> feature a full cupboard of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Revere</ENAMEX>, and his portrait (among many others) by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Singleton Copley</ENAMEX>, who was probably Boston‚Äôs best-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. The complete pantheon of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> art is represented¬†‚Äî¬†from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> landscape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX>. The most overwhelming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> are those exhibiting works by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monets, Millet‚Äôs The Sower, Renoir‚Äôs Dance at Bougival</ENAMEX>, and works by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C√©zanne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toulouse-Lautrec</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Gogh</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">There‚Äôs</ENAMEX> also a great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum shop</ENAMEX>, a caf√©, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>.
Nothing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> can match the beauty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum</ENAMEX>. Modeled on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Venetian loggia</ENAMEX>, the cloister, delicate arches, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salmon</ENAMEX>-pink marble walls enclose a stunning, atmospheric space lined with mosaic and filled with foliage and classical statuary. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabella Gardner</ENAMEX> created <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fenway Court</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903</TIMEX> to hold her outstanding collection of art. A flamboyant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>, her unconventional ways scandalized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Brahmins</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> occasion. Her portrait by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Singer Sargent</ENAMEX> (in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic Room</ENAMEX>) captures her individuality and her eccentricity lives on in her will, which stipulates that all of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> pieces on display in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> must be left exactly where they are. This decree is qualified by the condition that were anything to change, the museum‚Äôs contents would be sold off, with the proceeds going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs an extraordinary place filled with great art works which are displayed idiosyncratically in often (for the time) innovative ways. It‚Äôs more a personal home than a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> and the works are often poorly lit and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cursorily</ENAMEX> labeled. Each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> displays art of a particular artist¬<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">†‚Äî¬†Titian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Veronese¬†‚Äî¬†or style¬†‚Äî¬†Dutch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX>, or early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Night Out</ENAMEX> withthe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX>
Leave the car behind and experience being crushed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> in a trolley on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MBTA Green Line</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenmore</ENAMEX>. Constructed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fenway Park</ENAMEX> is the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballpark</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The quirky, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">irregularly</ENAMEX> shaped arena boasts real, manicured <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> and a towering wall that is nicknamed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Green Monster</ENAMEX> for its scale and color. This is an intimate place, so even those who are standing at the back will be close to the action. If you‚Äôre not familiar with baseball‚Äôs finer points, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> in the friendly, vociferous, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34,000</NUMEX>-strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> would love to talk you through them. In a low-scoring game dominated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX>, you might wonder what the fuss is about. Feel the fever generated by a slick double play or a home run, and you could be hooked. For tickets, see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay Village</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South End</ENAMEX>
The few blocks of tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay Village</ENAMEX> lie well hidden in between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater District</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back Bay</ENAMEX>, around <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Winchester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melrose</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fayette</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. It feels somewhat like a toy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">village¬†‚Äî¬†a</ENAMEX> miniature, flat version of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beacon Hill¬</ENAMEX>†‚Äî¬†with similar red-brick and black-shuttered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes lining sidewalks</ENAMEX> that are shaded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and lit by old-fashioned street lamps. These were the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> of artisans, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brahmins</ENAMEX>, and are less precious, devoid of cornices and fancy wrought iron. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marsh of Back Bay</ENAMEX> was filled in during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1860s</TIMEX>, water flooded into this area, forcing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> to be raised on pilings.
Take <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tremont Street</ENAMEX> south and cross over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massachusetts Turnpike</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South End</ENAMEX>. Come if only to savor <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (or more) of its great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, a clutch of chic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bistros</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tremont Street</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clarendon</ENAMEX>. Like so much of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South End</ENAMEX> began as a landfill project, but it soon lost out in desirability to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back Bay</ENAMEX>. A multi-ethnic mix of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Indian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is also home to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston‚</ENAMEX>Äôs largest gay community. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">districts¬</ENAMEX>†‚Äî¬†to the south of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shawmut Avenue</ENAMEX>, for example¬†‚Äî¬†are best avoided. In others, though, you will come across bright community murals and perhaps a reggae <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> playing in a local <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>.
The neighborhood boasts (justifiably) a fine concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> terraced <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX>. Bow brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, their steep stoops (or steps) framed with scrolled black railings, are set off by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, the finest examples being <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union Park Square</ENAMEX>, situated just off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tremont Street</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Concord</ENAMEX> squares both farther to the south.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dorchester</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica Plain</ENAMEX>
Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> suburbs might not claim any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúmust see‚Äù sights</ENAMEX>, if you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and are confident about finding your way around with a good map, there is a variety of intriguing places to explore.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Boston</ENAMEX>, referred to as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Southie</ENAMEX>, is in fact (rather confusingly) situated east of Downtown. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Home</ENAMEX> to such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flanagan‚Äôs Supermarket</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shannon Tavern</ENAMEX> on its main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">thoroughfare</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East Broadway</ENAMEX>, it‚Äôs thoroughly and proudly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>. In fact, it was the flashpoint for protests and riots during the busing controversy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. Follow the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> past its old wooden and brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Independence</ENAMEX>, which stands at the very mouth of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boston Inner Harbor</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">fort</ENAMEX> is rarely open, but join the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> who settle down in the surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> with deck chairs and binoculars to watch the nautical and aeronautical activity.
Your next <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">stop</ENAMEX> could well be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dorchester Heights</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-tiered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> of marble standing on a hill. From here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX> trained his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">artillery</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and succeeded in frightening <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> into evacuating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>. (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>).
Follow the waterfront south to the extraordinary, stark white <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I. M. Pei</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John F. Kennedy Library</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>. Enter via the brilliantly lit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">atrium</ENAMEX> with glorious bayfront view. See the introductory film and then look at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> exhibits that trace the career of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX> using rare film and television footage, documents, and personal memorabilia. You can watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy/Nixon</ENAMEX> debate again, revisit the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">67-day 1960</TIMEX> campaign and see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Cronkite</ENAMEX> reading the results. Other exhibits highlight the accomplishments of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,000 days¬†‚Äî¬</NUMEX>†the resolution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cuban Missile Crisis</ENAMEX>, the founding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corp</ENAMEX>, the launching of the space program, and the support for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Rights</ENAMEX>. The film footage of the assassination still shocks and appalls. The quotation that follows ‚ÄúA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> may die, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> may rise and fall, but an idea lives on‚Äù though reminds us of an earlier political time when visionary ideas mattered more than gossip to the media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">111</NUMEX> for details of boat trips from Downtown).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Park</ENAMEX> lies close by to the west. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoo</ENAMEX> (open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> Monday‚ÄìFriday, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">10am‚Äì4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pm</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">10‚Äì5pm</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, and holidays; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">10am‚Äì5pm</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">10am‚Äì6pm</NUMEX> respectively in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>), a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">75-acre</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30-hectare</NUMEX>) area with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, is part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. The showpieces are the new lion exhibit, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow leopard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cheetah</ENAMEX> exhibits, and an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> tropical rain forest, which is complete with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX> and warthogs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Park</ENAMEX> was the jewel in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emerald Necklace</ENAMEX>, the last in a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7-mile</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11-km</NUMEX>) network of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Law Olmsted</ENAMEX> that run all the way from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Common</ENAMEX>.
West of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Franklin Park</ENAMEX>, lies the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">265-acre</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">107-hectare</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Arboretum</ENAMEX>. Each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">shrubs</ENAMEX>, and vines, is labeled clearly with its common and scientific name. Spring is a wonderful time to visit when the lilacs, rhododendron, and magnolia are in bloom; the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">130</NUMEX> different maples put on a blazing show in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX>.
Before returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, make a final stop in affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brookline</ENAMEX> (actually a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>), once home to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olmsted</ENAMEX>. The modest wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">83</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beals Street</ENAMEX> (property of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Park Service</ENAMEX>, open <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10am‚Äì4:30pm</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-May‚ÄìOctober</TIMEX>) is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">John F. Kennedy National Historic Site</ENAMEX>. He was born and lived here until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age four</TIMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose</ENAMEX>, had it restored, and furnished it with family pieces.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cambridge</ENAMEX>
Although it‚Äôs only separated from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> by a river and a few subway stops, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> is a distinct <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with a distinct outlook. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> dominated by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America‚</ENAMEX>Äôs leading academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>, and although there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> should begin by exploring life around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Square</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Square</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Square</ENAMEX> itself is unkempt. What makes it special is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. This is a place where everyone just hangs out, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> conversing in sententious tones, to punks in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leather</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> in well-pressed suits. Street performers¬†‚Äî¬†fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jugglers</ENAMEX>, puppeteers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trapeze artists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joni Mitchell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Chapman</ENAMEX> both performed here)¬†‚Äî¬†pull big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX>, notably on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> evenings.
There are numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">caf√©s</ENAMEX> and bookshops (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX>) in which to while away <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours</TIMEX>. Buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> from the global selection at Out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Town News</ENAMEX> in the center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> itself (the name also refers to all the surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>), and settle down at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Au Bon Pain caf√©</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs the place for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>-watching, and for a couple of dollars you can also test your skills against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> chess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maestro</ENAMEX>.
Among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University</ENAMEX> is the oldest (founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1636</TIMEX> as a training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ground</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">puritan ministers</ENAMEX>), and the richest, and has produced numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize winners</ENAMEX>.
From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Square</ENAMEX> enter the gates into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Yard</ENAMEX>, the oldest part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>. Here is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollis Hall</ENAMEX> attended by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emerson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thoreau</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massachusetts Hall</ENAMEX> attended by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Adams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. H. Richardson‚Äôs Sever Hall</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Bulfinch‚Äôs Stoughton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Halls</ENAMEX>. Note the statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Harvard</ENAMEX>, labeled as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> and dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1638</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> called the statue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Lies</ENAMEX> because it isn‚Äôt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Harvard</ENAMEX>, but only a student model; he wasn‚Äôt the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>, only the first benefactor, who donated his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX>-book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>; and the date is wrong (it should be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1636</TIMEX>). So much for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard‚</ENAMEX>Äôs motto: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veritas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latin for ‚ÄúTruth.</ENAMEX>‚Äù
