



What to Do
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> come to see the nation‚Äôs many excellent historic and cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, including the imperial treasures. But there is much else of interest in this vast land to make the journey truly enjoyable. You will of course want to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> at least a few souvenirs, and you will have opportunities to attend presentations of an incredible range of performing arts. It will not be difficult to fill your moments of leisure with memorable activities that will make your trip last well after you return <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
After watching coachloads of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> clamoring to buy souvenirs at every stop, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> to the oases of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Xinjiang</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> have opened <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> wherever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> go. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friendship Stores</ENAMEX>, found in all significant tourist locations, make for easy shopping. They are essentially for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> only, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salespeople</ENAMEX> speak <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> languages and usually have all the patience in the world for repetitive queries. Foreign money may be changed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX>, and some credit cards are accepted.
But more adventurous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> might stumble across the same items in a neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. There the scene is less relaxed and the language problem might daunt you, but at least you‚Äôll be able to catch a glimpse of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> consumer society.
In many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, arts and crafts department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> showcase the output of local artisans. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiques</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> specialize in old pottery, jewelry, carvings, and calligraphy, as well as high-quality <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">reproductions</ENAMEX>.
Since the distribution system is unpredictable, old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hands</ENAMEX> say you shouldn‚Äôt take a chance: if you find something you like, buy it, for it might not be on sale anywhere else. Prices are as marked; do not try to bargain.
What to Buy
Bargains are rare, but there‚Äôs much to buy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, and markets. Here‚Äôs an alphabetically organized listing to start you on your rounds.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiques</ENAMEX>. From fossils to ancient coins, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> customs regulations prohibit the export of any cultural relics except those marked with special wax seals; and only fairly recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> are given the seal. Even so, browsing is fascinating. Remember that many knowledgeable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> will have preceded you. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> here peg prices to international levels.
Bamboo products. In the southern regions where bamboo grows, cottage industries turn out bamboo <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> boxes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, flutes, chopsticks, walking sticks, and furniture.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brocades</ENAMEX> and silk. Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Han Dynasty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has been exporting delicate silk fabrics in brilliant colors. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX> you can buy inexpensive raw silk by the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX> or exquisite brocades, as well as silk scarves, ties, and blouses.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronzeware</ENAMEX>. Modern versions of traditional hotpots are useful in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, as are bronze <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX>, plates, and vases (often engraved with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">intricate dragon</ENAMEX> or floral designs).
Carpets and rugs. Luxurious and colorful, oriental rugs of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> or silk are a tempting buy. The big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> catering to foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> arrange for shipping.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porcelain</ENAMEX>). Reproductions of classical designs or modern teapots, cups, plates, and vases. Shrewd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> point out that price tags always indicate the excellence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porcelain</ENAMEX> (and of cloisonne ware, too). In the line of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> text before the actual price, look for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> symbols for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the numerals 1, 2</TIMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> horizontal lines), meaning <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> class. If there‚Äôs no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> at all, it means <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chopsticks</ENAMEX>. Now that you‚Äôre becoming familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> cooking, you might want to collect the appropriate utensils. Elaborate chopsticks are sold in their own fitted carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cases¬†‚Äî¬†handy</ENAMEX> for a picnic or an emergency.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cloisonne</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">don‚Äôt</ENAMEX> claim to have invented this type of enamelware, but they have been doing it very well for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several hundred years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cloisonne</ENAMEX> is applied to plates, vases, and other items.
Ethnic novelties. Artisans from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs ethnic minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> produce a good share of exotica: ornaments and figurines, ceremonial knives and swords, skullcaps and other headgear, colorful dresses and shirts, and shaggy sheepskin coats.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hangzhou</ENAMEX> alone manufactures <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> per year, most of them for export. They come in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> varieties, but the best known folding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> are made of fragrant sandalwood or black paper.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figurines</ENAMEX>. Ceramic polychrome figurines of historic or legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personages</ENAMEX> are popular, as are little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, with the panda the most sought after.
Furniture. Boxwood, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mahogany</ENAMEX>, or bamboo screens, chairs, and chests with elaborately carved designs re-create the atmosphere of old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Shipping abroad can be arranged.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furs</ENAMEX>. Glossy sable or marten coats are often displayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friendship Stores</ENAMEX>. The styling might not be the latest fashion, but the price tag could make all the difference.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ginseng</ENAMEX>. The all-purpose <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> medicinal <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">herb</ENAMEX> is becoming well known in the West as a tonic. Small doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ginseng</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> are claimed to be the secret of enduring vitality.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herbs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX>. Every market has stands selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fragrant spices</ENAMEX>. Look above all for varieties particular to the region; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chongqing</ENAMEX>, for instance, you might buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sichuan</ENAMEX> dried peppers. A few fen will buy an exotic gift, especially welcome when the herbs or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX> are unknown or unavailable at home.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX>. Carvings of remarkable intricacy are a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> specialty. But only an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> can distinguish between a genuine tusk and substitute <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>. Obtaining real ivory, of course, means the slaughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> almost all import of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ivory products</ENAMEX> has been banned. If in doubt, check with your consulate <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jade</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the hardest of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX>, jade has intrigued the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 3,000 years</TIMEX>. Even if you don‚Äôt believe in its mystic powers, jade‚Äôs aesthetic appeal cannot be denied.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kites</ENAMEX>. In windy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> and many other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, high-flying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kites</ENAMEX> are a favorite of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and others. The designs are colorful, original, and elaborate.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacquerware</ENAMEX>. Numerous layers of lacquer, individually polished, are applied to trays, cups, vases, and boxes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacquer</ENAMEX> also makes the ideal finish for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX>, since the material resists boiling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luggage</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> answer to the problem of excessive buying might be to buy additional luggage to carry your souvenirs home. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> make good, cheap, sturdy suitcases of all sizes. Or you can pick up a local imitation of a Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> attach√© case.
Musical instruments. Such <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> musical instruments as violin, guitar, flute, and pipa (a plucked stringed instrument) are well made and usually well priced.
Paintings. Squadrons of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> copy the traditional drawings and paintings by hand. A lengthy scroll can take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as long as ten days</TIMEX> to complete, brushstroke by brushstroke, with the details of a landscape intended to be viewed in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX>, not all at once. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artists</ENAMEX> also produce original meditations on venerable themes. The scrolls have the advantage of being already rolled up for packing.
Paper art. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, who invented paper, are thought to have devised the decorative art of paper cutting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 2,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>. With great skill, scissors-wielding paper cutters produce intricate scenes suitable for framing.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rubbings</ENAMEX> and reproductions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> rubbings of inscriptions from ancient temples, or of classical calligraphy on stone pillars, make popular (and portable) souvenirs. In some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> you will find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> selling reproductions of their most famous archaeological exhibits (for example, the flying <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lanzhou</ENAMEX>). Tiny facsimiles of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Xi‚Äôan warriors</ENAMEX> are now available in many parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seals</ENAMEX>. These ink stamps (also called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúchops‚Äù</ENAMEX>) are the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> substitute for handwritten signatures. You can have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> carved just for you, with your name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">incised¬†‚Äî¬†perhaps</ENAMEX> in ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block characters¬†‚Äî¬†in soapstone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX>, jade, or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ivory</ENAMEX>.
Souvenirs. In any local department store or street market you‚Äôre likely to come across some very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> inspirations: acupuncture charts and dolls, those ubiquitous thermos flasks, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> mugs with lids, padded jackets, posters, and so on.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tea</ENAMEX>. A collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teas</ENAMEX> (black, green, semi-fermented, and flower-petal) makes an inexpensive, useful, and long-lasting souvenir. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tea</ENAMEX> is frequently packaged in special, artistically decorated containers.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toys</ENAMEX>. Cheap and unusual children‚Äôs toys, from cuddly <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> to mechanical games, are being manufactured in increasing numbers in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolens</ENAMEX>. An unexpected bargain is cashmere sweaters, in all styles and colors. Other woolens, too, can be economical, good-quality purchases.
Entertainment
After a grueling day of sightseeing, you might not be too disappointed to discover that an evening‚Äôs entertainment starts and ends early. Nightlife stays on a high cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, far removed from the nightclub scene of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> performances combine amusement with edification in a glittering package few Western impresarios could afford to mount.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> hospitably assume that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> can‚Äôt bear more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about ten minutes</TIMEX> of traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> opera. You might, indeed, find the voices shrill and the mannerisms maddening (many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> seem to spend most of the time fussing with their sleeves, which can unroll to the floor). So you should not mind if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> rushes you out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> into the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early evening</TIMEX> traffic.
But if you persevere, you will begin to understand what the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> see in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this age-old</TIMEX> art form. If you fail, you‚Äôve still enjoyed the splendid costumes and makeup, the acrobatics that enliven some regional versions, and the experience of being in a theater surrounded by local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Peking opera is the version most familiar to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Westerners</ENAMEX>, but other regions have their own variants.
If possible, familiarize yourself with the plot in advance. Ideologically uplifting operas were the only ones permitted during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cultural Revolution</ENAMEX>; classical stories were banned. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> both classical and modern works are presented. If you have an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interpreter</ENAMEX> at hand, you‚Äôll understand why some scenes animate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> and others don‚Äôt. The words of the songs are projected onto screens alongside the proscenium <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch</ENAMEX> to clarify the nuances of a tonal language set to music. Apart from the set pieces, most of the music is percussive and serves to support and reflect the action and mood.
Props are minimal and the action is subtle: an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> closes an invisible door with a mime gesture, and anyone walking with a riding <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> must be understood to be mounted on a horse. But the heroic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> couldn‚Äôt ever be mistaken for the snarling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puppets</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Acrobats</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folklore Groups</ENAMEX> 
Popular with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shadow</ENAMEX> play (a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,000-year-old</TIMEX> art form) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dramatizes</ENAMEX> familiar legends. The two-dimensional puppets, manipulated behind a silk screen, can jump and fly, giving the colorful silhouettes an advantage over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> opera. The busy puppeteers give voice to their characters, often in song. Professional and amateur shadow-play <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troupes</ENAMEX> also put on shows with marionettes.
The so-called acrobatic shows, staged for tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, are more fun than you might expect. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trapeze artists</ENAMEX>, of course, are first-class, and so are the contortionists and human pyramid acts. But they also throw in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jugglers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magicians</ENAMEX> and even comics, and you don‚Äôt have to understand a word to join in the laughter.
Typically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúChinese folklore‚Äù</ENAMEX> performances are organized especially for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. Shows feature the costumes, songs, and dances of the national minority groups¬†‚Äî¬†often as foreign to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> as they are to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> from abroad. These evenings are usually uplifting and not very long.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concerts and Ballet</ENAMEX>
During the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cultural Revolution</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tchaikovsky</ENAMEX> were banned and many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> banished to the countryside for ‚Äúre-education.‚Äù So if you go to a concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, you‚Äôll sense the drama of recovery from mad xenophobia. This needn‚Äôt obscure the fact that some professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> haven‚Äôt yet reached world standards. But the enthusiasm of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> is exciting in itself.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballet</ENAMEX>, a vehicle for ideological indoctrination during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s and 1970s</TIMEX>, is much less restricted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Folk legends</ENAMEX> are often a source of inspiration, and classical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> works are sometimes performed, with elaborate costumes, sets, and lighting effects.
And a Nightcap
With varying degrees of success, the tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> try to meet foreigners‚Äô demands for a quiet place to have a drink and a chat. Only the newest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> that were built with international cooperation contain bars reminiscent of those in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. The others are likely to be quaint rather than cozy.



