



Where to Go
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> most-visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and sights in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, described in detail in this section, are arranged in alphabetical order. This conveniently puts the capital, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, first. The names of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> are given in official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinyin</ENAMEX> spelling. (To the right of each place name, we also provide the spelling by which it was known in the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade-Giles</ENAMEX> system of romanization: for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚ÄúPeking‚Äù</ENAMEX> instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúBeijing</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX>) The authentic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> for each place name are provided in a list at the back of this guide along with pronunciation guides (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">251</NUMEX>). At the end of this extended gazetteer, we provide ‚ÄúBriefings‚Äù on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> additional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and sights that are less frequently visited on typical tours.
Planning Your Trip
Choosing an itinerary can be a difficult task, for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is too big to be covered in any reasonable amount of time. An excessively hasty week might take in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming Tombs</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Wall</ENAMEX>; the archaeological marvels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xi‚Äôan</ENAMEX>; the romantic scenery of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guilin</ENAMEX>; and a glimpse of bustling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guangzhou</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canton</ENAMEX>). This sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">trip¬†‚Äî¬†though</ENAMEX> you leap around more often than is convenient¬†‚Äî¬†takes you to the top attractions.
Less taxing would be a week in and around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX>, emphasizing the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">charms</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wuxi, Suzhou</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hangzhou</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> are on the historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Canal</ENAMEX>.
If you go inland, you can still take the celebrated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> trip between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wuhan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chongqing</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yangzi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yangtze) River gorges</ENAMEX> (before they are swallowed up by a massive dam project to be completed after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2009</TIMEX>), and from there fly to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guangzhou</ENAMEX> for sightseeing, shopping, and gourmet dining.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silk Road</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> fly from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xi‚</ENAMEX>Äôan to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urumqi</ENAMEX> in the far west, returning via the exotic desert oases of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turpan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dunhuang</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> cave treasures and camel rides to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX>-locked lakes.
Another western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> adventure is a visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yunnan Province</ENAMEX>, whose capital, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kunming</ENAMEX>, is home to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of most of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚Äôs</ENAMEX> minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kunming</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone Forest</ENAMEX>, a natural monument of bizarre formations, and to the northwest, near the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> border, the dazzling minority <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dali</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lijiang</ENAMEX>. 
If you prefer to stay close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, the better part of a varied week could profitably be spent investigating the carvings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> caves near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Datong</ENAMEX>, visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mongolian</ENAMEX> lands of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hohhot</ENAMEX>, and viewing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">temples</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chengde</ENAMEX>.
Any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of these week-long <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX> can be combined for a fortnight‚Äôs touring. The most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">itineraries</ENAMEX> invariably include <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xi‚Äôan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guilin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX>, each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> providing a glimpse of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> past and present.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peking</ENAMEX>)
A visit to the medieval and modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is an exhausting though rewarding round of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, temples and monuments, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stores¬†‚Äî¬†a jolting</ENAMEX> juxtaposition of imperial pomp and contemporary energy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over 12 million</NUMEX>, but it is spread over a huge area calculated at a staggering <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">16,800 square km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 6,500 square miles</NUMEX>). Many neighborhoods are lined with old hutongs (alleyways) alongside traditional <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>- and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard houses</ENAMEX>, where life has changed little since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX>. Around the corner from these fast-disappearing cozy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> are new housing projects, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, modern shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plazas</ENAMEX>, and open-air markets. This is a metropolis in the throes of modernization.
Mostly the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is flat, which is a mercy for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> who bicycle to work in the world‚Äôs most unlikely <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">rush hour</TIMEX>, a chaos of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> than you‚Äôve seen in your whole life. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> took the unthinkable step of actually banning <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Xisidonglu</ENAMEX>, where bicycle flow had reached <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> per minute.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Middle Ages</TIMEX>, the emperors decided to do something about the capital‚Äôs unrelieved flatness. They ordered hills to be artificially constructed just north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> so they could go up and, in total privacy, enjoy a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> breeze and a bird‚Äôs-eye view over the curved tile roofs of their imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>. Try it yourself, perhaps at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dawn</TIMEX>, when a thin haze drapes itself over the pavilions, redefining yet softening the features of this storybook skyline. You‚Äôll see why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperors</ENAMEX> wanted it all for themselves.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> in History
Not far from the present-day suburbs of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> was the habitat of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peking Man</ENAMEX>, the startling <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anthropological</ENAMEX> discovery of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cave</ENAMEX> near the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zhoukoudian</ENAMEX> held the skull of a small-brained but upright ancestor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX> who lived <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> are still sifting for the bones, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> can tour the dig themselves.
Recent excavations in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> show that it was inhabited over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20,000 years ago</TIMEX>, but the place made little stir until the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warring States</ENAMEX> period (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> centuries b.c.) when, known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jicheng</ENAMEX>, it became the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom of Yan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renamed Yanjing</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> served as capital for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Liao Dynasty in the tenth century a.d. The Jin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chin</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynasty</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 12th century</TIMEX> called it <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Zhongdu (‚ÄúCentral Capital‚Äù</ENAMEX>) and built an imperial palace as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lugou Bridge</ENAMEX>; known abroad as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚ÄúMarco Polo Bridge</ENAMEX>,‚Äù it is still in use.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genghis Khan‚Äôs Mongol</ENAMEX> armies leveled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zhongdu</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 13th century</TIMEX>, then rebuilt it under the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dadu (‚ÄúGreat Capital‚Äù</ENAMEX>). By the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco Polo</ENAMEX> arrived, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> outshone the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ming Dynasty</ENAMEX> transferred most of the imperial pomp south to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nanjing</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 14th century</TIMEX>. Predictably, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dadu</ENAMEX> received yet another name, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beiping (‚ÄúNorthern Peace‚Äù</ENAMEX>) but had to wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 50 years</TIMEX> to win back its imperial status and a fresh name. This one¬<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">†‚Äî¬†Beijing (‚ÄúNorthern Capital‚Äù)¬†‚Äî¬†is</ENAMEX> still around. So, happily, are the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ming</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> and temples.
At the beginning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> prospered. New <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> and gardens were laid out and scholarship flourished. But during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Boxer Rebellion of 1900</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> wrought havoc in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in retaliation for the siege of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX>. This was only the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of many crises which were to rock <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>: the fall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> world wars, and civil war. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> became the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">People‚Äôs Republic of China</ENAMEX>.
Sightseeing
The historic heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> consists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> concentric <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, rectangular and symmetrical, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fourth¬†‚Äî¬†Outer City¬†‚Äî¬</ENAMEX>†to the south. Most of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> of walls that protected each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> have been lost to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúprogress,‚Äù but the innermost, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>, still glitters behind its original fortifications.
The elegance of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> plan, basically <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">700 years old</TIMEX>, has never been surpassed. A precise north-south axis links the main elements, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Tower</ENAMEX> all the way to the gate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Outer City</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 miles</NUMEX>) to the south. At the center of it all is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>, imperial heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle Kingdom</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> 
Called the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX> on earth, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> covers <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 hectares</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 acres</NUMEX>) in the very center of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> was the center of world attention during the student demonstrations of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> and their tragic aftermath. In contrast, it is now the site of frequent festivities, with magnificent flower displays and sparkling fountains.
At the time of the emperors, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about one-fourth</NUMEX> its present size. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old</TIMEX>, less expansive square <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Zedong</ENAMEX> first raised the flag of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 October 1949</TIMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 October 1999</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People‚Äôs Republic</ENAMEX> celebrated its golden anniversary, each of the square‚Äôs concrete blocks freshly replaced by stately <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">granite</ENAMEX>. 
The newest building on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>, called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Zedong Memorial Hall</ENAMEX>, contains the embalmed body of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People‚Äôs Republic</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its first 27 years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum</ENAMEX>, which is bigger than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lenin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Moscow‚Äôs Red Square</ENAMEX>, is open to a procession of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, who are allowed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a few minutes</TIMEX> inside. A grandiose building on the west side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Hall of the People</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renmin Dahuitang</ENAMEX>), erected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>, is the meeting place of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National People‚Äôs Congress</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Hall</ENAMEX> offers tours. At the heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monument to the People‚Äôs Heroes</ENAMEX>, a granite obelisk where the democracy movement was headquartered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. 
Far across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard museums</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> cover the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Chinese History</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9,000</NUMEX> items from prehistoric fossils to breathtaking pottery and bronzes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of the Chinese Revolution</ENAMEX> houses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> documents and displays. The explanations are in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> only, but you can buy an illustrated guide in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> from the bookstall to the left of the entrance. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX> across <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Changan Avenue</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> (and leading to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>) is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heavenly Peace</ENAMEX>, with its famous portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX>. Atop this formidable stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> is a rostrum for reviewing parades, and behind it a massive wooden gate-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> with a double roof. The original <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">gate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> was rebuilt in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1651</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tourists</ENAMEX> are now allowed to survey the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> from atop the gate, a vantage point once reserved for emperors and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gu Gong</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> is too sprawling a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> for strolling around, so you can forget the sort of browsing that some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> offer. Among several exceptions, though, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>. Here you will find <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than 72 hectares</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">175 acres</NUMEX>) of grandeur, with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>, courtyards, and gardens. It is a walled rectangular island within a massive moat wide enough for naval engagements.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>, so described because it was off-limits to ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 500 years</TIMEX>, is now called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palace Museum</ENAMEX>. Designed to contain the auspicious number of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9,999</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, its scale is overwhelming and leaves many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> bewildered. Built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years 1406‚Äì1420</TIMEX>, it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> emperors for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly seven centuries</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tourists</ENAMEX> normally enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> from the south, after a long walk along a cobbled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roadway</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heavenly Peace</ENAMEX>. The main entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meridian Gate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wumen</ENAMEX>), was designed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 15th century</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> used the left portal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the imperial family the right. Next comes another ceremonial gate, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Harmony</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taihemen</ENAMEX>), first erected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1420</TIMEX>. A pair of monumental bronze <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX> stand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>.
Beyond this powerful defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> stands <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs supreme ensemble of ancient architecture. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> and foremost is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Great Harmony</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taihedian</ENAMEX>), popularly called the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚ÄúHall of the Imperial Throne</ENAMEX>.‚Äù This is the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> and one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most beautiful wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX>. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing</ENAMEX> dynasties this was the tallest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>; by law no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> could rise higher. (Counting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hall‚Äôs upswept roof decorations</ENAMEX>, that meant the limit was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately 371‚ÅÑ2 m</TIMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">123</NUMEX> ft.) Inside, on a raised <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúSon of Heaven‚</ENAMEX>Äù sat on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dragon Throne</ENAMEX> surrounded by symbols of longevity and power and cowering acolytes, all covered in a fog of incense. To the tune of gongs and chimes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> knelt to kowtow <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> times.
Less formal occasions took place in the smaller, golden-roofed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Central Harmony</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zhonghedian</ENAMEX>), behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Great Harmony</ENAMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> in this series, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Preserving Harmony</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baohedian</ENAMEX>), was used, among other things, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> examinations, which were the world‚Äôs first civil-service tests. Behind this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>, in the center of a stairway, is a ramp full of sculptured dragons carved from a single slab of marble weighing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than 200 tons</NUMEX>. It was reserved for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">emperor‚Äôs sedan</ENAMEX> chair. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX> worked to pull the block to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">site</ENAMEX> from the quarry <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">48 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 miles</NUMEX>) away; ingeniously, the operation was scheduled for deepest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> so that the load could be slid along specially iced <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>.
From here to the north, the density of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> increases markedly as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> passes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outer Court</ENAMEX> (where official business was conducted) to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> and pavilions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inner Court</ENAMEX> (where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>, the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> lived). Many of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> are now used to display the artwork and more prosaic belongings of the emperors. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Clocks and Hall of Jewelry</ENAMEX>, collections of gifts to the emperors, are worth a detour to the right, as is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nine-Dragon Screen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jiulongbi</ENAMEX>), carved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1775</TIMEX>.
The rear (northern) section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> contains the pavilions where the imperial family resided and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ends</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial Gardens</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yuhuayuan</ENAMEX>), with magnificent stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rockeries</ENAMEX>, site of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Daoist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> that dates back to the completion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> itself under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX> emperors in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1420</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks</ENAMEX>
Just north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, along the main imperial axis, is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jingshan Park</ENAMEX>, better known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coal Hill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meishan</ENAMEX>). The highest point of old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, the hill was created from earth that was removed to form the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moat system</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>. Each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> artificial peaks was provided with a romantically designed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-tiered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pavilion</ENAMEX> of Ten <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thousand Springs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanchunting</ENAMEX>), on the middle peak, offers an inspiring view over the glistening rooftops of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial City</ENAMEX>, with the modern capital beyond.
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beihai Park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX>, has been a beauty spot for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Its lake, which young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> now explore in rented rowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>, was created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 12th century</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">graceful Bridge</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eternal Peace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yonganqiao</ENAMEX>) leads to an artificial island <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> in circumference with a long covered corridor that sweeps along the northern shore. On a hill in the center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">isle</ENAMEX> is situated a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibetan</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Dagoba</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baita</ENAMEX>), at the back of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yongan Temple</ENAMEX>. In springtime the dagoba seems to burst from waves of green leaves. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> and fall, this is the most beautiful and lively <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> to stroll through in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple of Heaven Park</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiantan Park</ENAMEX>, known to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heaven Park</ENAMEX>, is the biggest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, celebrated for its assembly of thrilling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15th-century</TIMEX> architecture. The highlight is the circular, blue tile-roofed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hall of Prayer for Good Harvest</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qiniandian</ENAMEX>). This marvel of geometry, art, and engineering, built without a single nail, measures <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">371‚ÅÑ2 m</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">123 ft</ENAMEX>) to the gilded orb on its topmost roof. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1889</TIMEX> the masterpiece was struck by lightning and burned almost to the ground. Fortunately, the ruin was quickly restored to its original, resplendent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> was carried here in a procession in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first lunar month of each year</TIMEX> to pray for a bountiful harvest. The floor plan of the hall provides the key to the building‚Äôs function. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> central columns represent the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX>; then come <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concentric</ENAMEX> rings of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> columns each, representing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the months</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the dozen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-hour</TIMEX> periods into which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> was divided; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> hardwood pillars symbolize the constellations.
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> can no longer enter this monument, its colorful interiors can still be glimpsed from outside. Other attractions at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Round Altar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haunqiutan</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echo Wall</ENAMEX>, where whispered secrets ricochet and are mysteriously magnified, crossing an immense <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>, without benefit of modern technology. 
Top Temples
Beijing‚Äôs most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lamasery</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Palace of Harmony</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yonghegong</ENAMEX>), popularly known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama Temple</ENAMEX>. It was originally the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> who became the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yongzheng</ENAMEX>. The stately <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> of wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, has been painstakingly restored. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> recalls <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> efforts to unify <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mongolia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>.
Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and down a narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama Temple</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most serene place of worship, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple of Confucius</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kongzimiao</ENAMEX>), with statues and stone tablets honoring the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage</ENAMEX>.
Other temples of significant interest and variety are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bell Temple</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dazhongsi</ENAMEX>), with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs leading collection of antique bells; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Pagoda</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baitasi</ENAMEX>), with its newly renovated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibetan</ENAMEX> stupa, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs largest; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Five Pagoda Temple</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wutasi</ENAMEX>), decorated with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>-influenced sculptures; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Clouds Daoist Temple</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baiyuanguan</ENAMEX>), where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beijingers</ENAMEX> of all ages <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> in to pray for good fortune at a variety of most unusual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX>.
An <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Observatory, a Zoo</ENAMEX>, and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aquarium</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient Beijing Observatory</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guguanxiangtai</ENAMEX>), built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1442</TIMEX>, stands atop a remnant of the old city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> on the busiest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jianguomenwaidajie</ENAMEX>). Many of the bronze instruments, sundials, and sextants on display inside and on the roof of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">observatory</ENAMEX> were gifts from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jesuit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> who lived in the capital during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX>.
China‚Äôs largest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX>, in the northwestern sector of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, now includes a separate indoor-outdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> for its lovable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> pandas. The older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> (dating back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> Manchurian <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yaks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow leopards</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">P√®re David‚Äôs deer</ENAMEX>, known to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúquadruple unlikeness‚Äù</ENAMEX> (sibuxiang) because it has characteristics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX>, the reindeer, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ox</ENAMEX>, and the donkey. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> is popular with local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, but most foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> find the facilities too antiquated and its conditions poor.
Rather than upgrade its aged <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing Zoo</ENAMEX> has just opened the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing Aquarium</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs largest, on adjacent property. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Home</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, the huge conch-shaped facility features a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúTouch Tidepool</ENAMEX>,‚Äù sea mammal shows, and some of the world‚Äôs largest acrylic viewing panels.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hutongs</ENAMEX> and Courtyards
Growing in popularity in the face of extinction by bulldozer, the hutongs (traditional alleyways) and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard houses</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> are worth a visit. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every year these old</TIMEX> neighborhoods are reduced as the capital relentlessly reconstructs itself, but it‚Äôs still possible to book a guided pedicab tour of the hutongs. Wandering the backstreets in the old lake district north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beihai Park</ENAMEX>, these pedicab caravans make stops at the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Drum Tower</ENAMEX> for panoramic views, at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Prince Gong‚Äôs Palace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gongwangfu</ENAMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> and sometimes opera in a lavish grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming Dynasty</ENAMEX> estate, and at a typical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard home</ENAMEX> in a hutong neighborhood for a chance to meet and talk with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>.
If time allows for further exploration of these old neighborhoods, poke around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qianhai</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houhai</ENAMEX> lakes for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> markets. Here you‚Äôll find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Songqingling Guzhu</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Soong Ching-ling</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sun Yat-sen</ENAMEX>), who lived in this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard mansion</ENAMEX> after the revolution. It is now a family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Districts</ENAMEX>
Some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs few walkable areas are its chief shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and markets. Wangfujing, running north a few blocks east of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>, is the capital‚Äôs primary shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, lined with upscale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX> and glittering shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plazas</ENAMEX>, although a few venerable arts and crafts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>, and old department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> still survive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Liulichang Street</ENAMEX> has been restored to its <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ming Dynasty</ENAMEX> appearance and is a shopper‚Äôs delight. Liulichang, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing‚</ENAMEX>Äôs premier antiques market, extends eastward into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dazhalan Street</ENAMEX>, a pedestrian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> famous for silk and jewelry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>.
Outdoor markets, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> must bargain at length, are another walking adventure. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silk Alley</ENAMEX>, the most famous and most overpriced, specializes in designer fashions. More clothes and furs are found at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yabao Market</ENAMEX>, near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ritan Park</ENAMEX> (popularly known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Market</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hongxiao Market</ENAMEX>, near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of Heaven, features clothing, crafts, and freshwater pearls. The most colorful market is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panjiayuan</ENAMEX> (know as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dirt Market</ENAMEX>), starting at sunrise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Sunday</TIMEX>, with its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX> of collectibles, antiques, family treasures, tomb art, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibetan</ENAMEX> rugs, furniture, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> memorabilia.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summer Palace</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> name for this convergence of natural and man-made beauty is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Yiheyuan¬†‚Äî¬†the ‚ÄúPark of Nurtured Harmony</ENAMEX>.‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreigners</ENAMEX> call this <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">280-hectare</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">700-acre</NUMEX>) imperial estate the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX>. In actual fact, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">250-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>, pavilions, temples, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> occupy only a small part of the dreamily landscaped area. By far the largest feature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kunming Lake</ENAMEX>.
Contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> wax indignant that, under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX>, funds appropriated for the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">navy</ENAMEX> were, in fact, siphoned off to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yiheyuan</ENAMEX> an increasingly luxurious private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. Perhaps the most astonishing of the items on which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress Dowager Cixi</ENAMEX> squandered the naval budget is a double-decker <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Marble Boat</ENAMEX> beached at the edge of the lake. You can view this monument to royal folly, but you can no longer board it.
Among the outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Joyful Longevity</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leshoutang</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Seventeen-Arch Bridge</ENAMEX>, but the most magnificent structure is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Corridor</ENAMEX>, a wooden gallery <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">728 m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> a mile) in length. This covered way, which is interrupted by octagonal pavilions, is decorated with landscape paintings and depictions of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legends</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs like a long, unfolding wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scroll</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Cathay</ENAMEX>, a lakeside <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> recording all that was once the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle Kingdom</ENAMEX>. 
Not far from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summer Palace</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Summer Palace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yuanmingyuan</ENAMEX>), once the emperor‚Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> retreat. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> razed most of the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, including a complex modeled after <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Versailles</ENAMEX>. The ghostly ruins make an idyllic picnic ground.
Excursions from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Wall</ENAMEX>
It‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 80 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 miles</NUMEX>) from the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> northwest to the most visited stretch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Wall</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Badaling</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The trip</ENAMEX> telescopes history, from the modern capital through the outskirts where donkey <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carts</ENAMEX> and cargo<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-</ENAMEX>carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX> share the road, past <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> where nothing seems to have changed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>, to a harsh mountain range where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly one million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> walled in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>. Like all the real wonders of the world, this one is more awesome when visited in person than it is in any film or book.
The first elements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall system</ENAMEX> were built <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, but the expansion and consolidation of the project near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> began under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ming Dynasty</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 14th century</TIMEX>. The serpentine stone bulwark and elevated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanlichangcheng¬†‚Äî¬†‚ÄúThe Wall Ten Thousand Li Long‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 6,000 km/3,700 miles</NUMEX>).
The restored section of the wall at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Badaling</ENAMEX>, undulating up the unexpectedly steep hillsides, can be a test of a tourist‚Äôs endurance. It is far steeper and more formidable than it looks in any tourist brochure. Out of breath, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> exchange sympathetic smiles along the way as they ascend to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or another of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>. If you walk far enough west, you come upon unrestored sections of the wall at the edge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gobi Desert</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Badaling</ENAMEX> section is often overcrowded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other sections now provide relatively easy access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Wall</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mutianyu</ENAMEX>, as beautiful as the section at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Badaling</ENAMEX> but a little less steep, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Wall</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simatai</ENAMEX>, more distant from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> than other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> but virtually unrestored. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simatai</ENAMEX> is the least crowded and most original of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Great Wall sites</ENAMEX>. Although it too has a cable-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concession</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simatai</ENAMEX> bills itself as ‚Äúthe most dangerous section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Wall</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming Tombs</ENAMEX>
On the way to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Wall</ENAMEX> is the peaceful valley the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX> emperors chose as their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial ground</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1407</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yongle</ENAMEX> ordered a search for a suitable burial place with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">auspicious ‚Äúwind</ENAMEX> and water‚Äù conditions, as well as appropriate grandeur. This site proved so perfect that all but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the succeeding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> were entombed in the same valley.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sacred Way</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming Tombs</ENAMEX> begins at a great marble gateway <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than four centuries old</TIMEX>. Beyond this is the main gate with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> archways; the middle arch was used only once in each <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">reign¬†‚Äî¬</ENAMEX>†for the delivery of the emperor‚Äôs remains to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX>. Then comes the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Avenue of the Animals</ENAMEX>, which is lined with massive statues of real and mythical <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX>.
The largest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Changling</ENAMEX>) belonged to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yongle</ENAMEX> himself. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Eminent Favors</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lingendian</ENAMEX>) is among the largest wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> gilded pillars supporting the coffered ceiling were fashioned from a huge tree that took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than five years</TIMEX> to ship here from southwest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ninety</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> steps take you down below ground level to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dingling</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanli</ENAMEX>, whose reigned from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1573 to 1620</TIMEX>). It took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> to build this underground <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>. Most of the regalia and artifacts on display, including the red wooden coffin containers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial vault</ENAMEX>, are copies of the items discovered during excavations in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Qing</ENAMEX> Tombs
While many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming Tombs</ENAMEX> find the site crowded and uninspiring, there is a fascinating alternative. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Qing Tombs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dongqingling</ENAMEX>) mimic the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX> architecture but are grander and more effectively restored. They are also more than twice as far from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">125 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">78 miles</NUMEX>) to the east on slow but interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> tombs open to view, those of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchu</ENAMEX> emperors, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qianlong</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kangxi</ENAMEX>, are impressive, and that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress Dowager Cixi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1835‚Äì1911</ENAMEX>) is as elaborate as it is strange.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Changsha</ENAMEX>
If you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Changsha</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, you will arrive at the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> biggest railway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, a distinction quite out of proportion to the amount of rail traffic or the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. The explanation is that, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legions</ENAMEX> of pilgrims converged on this provincial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> in search of the roots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Zedong</ENAMEX>. Now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> has faded in glory, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX> are uncrowded and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Changsha</ENAMEX> has returned to its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age-old</TIMEX> role as a rather prosaic regional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of trade and culture. However, the surrounding fertile countryside is attractive, the spicy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hunan</ENAMEX> cuisine is worth trying, the scenic mountain areas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> are outstanding, and the archaeological displays are stunning.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hunan Province</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Changsha</ENAMEX> lies along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Xiang River</ENAMEX>, a wide and often turbulent stream that flows into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yangzi</ENAMEX>. The long thin strip of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange Island</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juzizhou</ENAMEX>), rich in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oranges</ENAMEX> among other <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX>, bisects the river and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 20th century</TIMEX> was home to a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX>. From the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> at the southern tip there is an engrossing view of sampans, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">barge trains</ENAMEX>, and passenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>. On the far side of the river, fragrant forests climb the slopes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yuelu Hill</ENAMEX>, a favorite escape from the subtropical heat of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the evergreen <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> in the mountainside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lushan Temple</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,700</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> on top (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yunlugong</ENAMEX>) affords a fine panorama.
For most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> the prime attraction of the region is found in the northeast part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hunan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Provincial Museum</ENAMEX>, with its renowned relics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Han Dynasty</ENAMEX>, including silks, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ceramics</ENAMEX>, and lacquerware of unbelievable sophistication, as well as alluring figurines and musical instruments. All these artifacts survived because they were buried in coffins within coffins in subterranean royal tombs. These beautiful wooden boxes come from the royal graves at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mawangdui</ENAMEX>, as does the museum‚Äôs show-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stopper</ENAMEX>: the remarkably well-preserved silk-wrapped mummy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marquis of Dai‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tohou</ENAMEX>, who died at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 50</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">186 b.c. Nearly 2,200 years later</TIMEX>, her hair is still on her head and her expression is unchanged from the moment of her last breath.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tourists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Changsha</ENAMEX> are sometimes taken to visit the local embroidery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs handicraft tradition has flourished for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,000 years</TIMEX>. Staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> paint original designs, usually of landscapes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, which the artisans reproduce stitch by microscopic stitch in colorful silk. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> here are proudest of the double-faced embroidery, with a different picture on each side.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Changsha</ENAMEX> also features sites linked with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> and the revolution. Foremost is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunan‚Äôs</ENAMEX> first <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Teachers‚Äô Training School</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diyishifan</ENAMEX>). Reconstructed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, it resembles a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arcades</ENAMEX> and gardens. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cultural Revolution</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> thronged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, for this is where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Zedong</ENAMEX> studied from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1913 to 1918</TIMEX> and later taught. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> desks where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> sat and the crowded <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dormitory</ENAMEX> where he slept under a mosquito net are on view.
Since the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">100th</NUMEX> anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mao‚</ENAMEX>Äôs birth (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1893</TIMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> have been to the village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaoshan, Mao‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> by bus from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Changsha</ENAMEX>. The principal sights are the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> where he was born, quite roomy by local standards, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> with all the exhibits in duplicate, filling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mirror-image wings designed to double the crowd capacity.
Excursions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hunan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Outdoor enthusiasts</ENAMEX> and independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> might have time to explore <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most spectacular natural attractions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Heng Mountain</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hengshannan</ENAMEX>, also called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nanyue</ENAMEX>), one of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">China‚Äôs Five Sacred Mountains</ENAMEX> in the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daoist pantheon</ENAMEX>, is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">112 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">70 miles</NUMEX>) south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Changsha</ENAMEX>. Its temples, monasteries, and misty vistas are well worth a day‚Äôs hike. Wulingyuan, a large nature preserve better known to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhangjiajie</ENAMEX>, is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">350 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">217 miles</NUMEX>) west of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Changsha</ENAMEX>. Known as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúChina‚Äôs Yellowstone</ENAMEX>,‚Äù this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNESCO</ENAMEX> World Heritage Site is a remote <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> of spectacular and uncanny quartz labyrinths and pinnacles, massive limestone caves, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">white-water rapids</ENAMEX>, steep hiking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX>, and minority <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chengde</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jehol</ENAMEX>)
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> the trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chengde</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 250 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">150 miles</NUMEX>) northeast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, might well be one of the prettiest anywhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Fertile fields alternate with stony hills, miraculously <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">sprouting trees</ENAMEX>, and wildflowers. In the hamlets along the way, trim <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> are roofed with thatch or traditional tile with winged projections. In the fields, the labor is done mostly by hand, and when <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are not available, even the heavy plowing is done by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in harness. Chengde itself looks, at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance, like any other northern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, but the dreariness is interspersed with beautifully sited old temples and an imperial pleasure-ground big enough to be protected by a wall <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 miles</NUMEX>) long.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> and gardens of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chengde</ENAMEX> provided summertime escape for the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing Dynasty</ENAMEX>, beginning with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kangxi</ENAMEX>, who created the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>, lakes, and hunting grounds here as a second summer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1703</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kangxi</ENAMEX> called these royal parklands <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bishushanzhuang, or ‚ÄúMountain Villa for Escaping the Summer Heat</ENAMEX>.‚Äù Indeed, its altitude¬†‚Äî¬†at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 350 m</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,100</NUMEX> ft) above sea level¬†‚Äî¬†provides relief from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> heat, as do the surrounding mountains, forests, and rivers.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> enter this royal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> at the ceremonial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lizheng Gate</ENAMEX>, flanked by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">marble lions</ENAMEX>. The old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> and royal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> now serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>. Among the exhibits are bows and arrows and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flintlocks</ENAMEX>, rare jade and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porcelain</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedan</ENAMEX> chairs in which the emperors were transported all the way from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">emperor‚Äôs bedroom</ENAMEX> is located in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Refreshing Mist-Veiled Waters Pavilion</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> and courtyards are eminently regal, yet they also inspire a feeling of relaxation appropriate to the setting. The plain wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corridors</ENAMEX> connecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> contrast with the illustrated passageways of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing‚Äôs Summer Palace</ENAMEX>, which occupies but half the space of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chengde</ENAMEX> retreat. 
The landscape beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace compound</ENAMEX> features many of the romantic elements of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> tradition: interconnected lakes and lotus ponds, forests, causeways and arched <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>, ornate pavilions, and towering pagodas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tower of Mist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rain</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yanyulou</ENAMEX>), a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lakeside pavilion</ENAMEX> in the southern style, was favored by emperors for its foggy views resembling those of an old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> painting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tourists</ENAMEX> can cross the lakes in hand-poled ferryboats or drift at their own pace in a rowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX> of the lakes there are hiking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Garden of Ten Thousand Trees</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanahuyuan</ENAMEX>), where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qianlong</ENAMEX> gave an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1793</TIMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to set foot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macartney</ENAMEX>. The meeting did not go well.
Beyond the wall surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> and its gardens rise the exotic roofs of the Eight <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outer Temples</ENAMEX>, built by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1713 and 1779</TIMEX> to honor and influence <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kazakhs</ENAMEX>, and other northern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>. All are open to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> grandest temples are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> in style. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Sumera Longevity</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Happiness Temple</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xumifushoumiao</ENAMEX>) is a copy of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Panchen Lama‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shigatse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>. The high red walls surround a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> with a roof gilded in a ton of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">A mile</NUMEX> east, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Potala Temple</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Putuozongshengmiao</ENAMEX>), the largest at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chengde</ENAMEX>, evokes the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dalai Lama‚Äôs Potala Palace</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lhasa</ENAMEX> and is so steep a climb (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">164</NUMEX> steps) that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedan</ENAMEX>-chair <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> do a brisk trade with weary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chengdu</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chengtu</ENAMEX>)
Balmy and often misty weather keeps <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chengdu</ENAMEX> green and full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers year ‚Äòround</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs the climate in which bamboo thrives, and bamboo is the staple of the giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">panda</ENAMEX>. The best place to spot these cuddly-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX> in something resembling the wilds is at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Research</ENAMEX> Base of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant Panda Breeding</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7 miles</NUMEX>) northeast of downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chengdu</ENAMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pandas</ENAMEX> have free run of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">some 30 hectares</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">80 acres</NUMEX>) of bamboo groves. There‚Äôs a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panda museum</ENAMEX> here, too. In closer confines, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chengdu Zoo</ENAMEX> has more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> pandas (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a dozen</NUMEX>) than does any other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> in the world. The thin bamboo stalks they find so delicious are grown right in the grounds. Because they are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> of this attraction, the giant pandas are assigned high-ceilinged, spacious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cages</ENAMEX> and outdoor play areas.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chengdu</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sichuan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Szechuan</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Province</ENAMEX>, the natural habitat for eighty percent of the world‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> giant pandas. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chengdu</ENAMEX> has other attractions as well, some of them historical, some of them spiritual, and some of them edible.
At the time of the era of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Three Kingdoms</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chengdu</ENAMEX> was capital of the feudal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom of Shu</ENAMEX>, and politics, not pandas, was the prime attraction. The principal monument from that era is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquis Wu</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wuhouci</ENAMEX>), a complex of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> and gardens in the southern suburbs built to commemorate the kingdom‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>. Known in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">a.d. 181‚Äì234</ENAMEX>) as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhugeliang</ENAMEX>, he was posthumously ennobled for his role in unifying the region and developing its economy and culture. In the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>, built in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tang Dynasty</ENAMEX>, there are gilt statues of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zhugeliang</ENAMEX>, his son, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX>; the latter died in battle at the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilgrims</ENAMEX> are drawn to another of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chengdu‚</ENAMEX>Äôs historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, the thatched cottage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dufu</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dufucaotang</ENAMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> at the spot where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tang Dynasty</ENAMEX> lived in exile from the capital for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dufu</ENAMEX> (formerly spelled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tufu</ENAMEX>) lived from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">712 to 770</TIMEX> and wrote <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,400</NUMEX> poems, many of them regarded as the greatest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">canon</ENAMEX>.
Chengdu‚Äôs most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Daoist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qingyanggong (‚ÄúGreen Goat Temple‚Äù</ENAMEX>), is a lively, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garish complex</ENAMEX> where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bronze ‚Äúgood luck‚Äù goats</ENAMEX> at the main altar have been rubbed smooth by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worshippers</ENAMEX> seeking their fortunes. Not far away is the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chan</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sichuan</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1,300-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wenshu Temple</ENAMEX>, which maintains its own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of woodcarvers as well as a vegetarian restaurant and outdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teahouse</ENAMEX>. 
Chengdu‚Äôs largest and most renowned religious monument, located <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">28 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">17 miles</NUMEX>) north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Divine Light Monastery</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baoguangsi</ENAMEX>). The most photographed element of this vast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> is the stupa, a slightly crooked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>-level pagoda. It was built of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> at the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tang Dynasty</ENAMEX>, replacing an ancient wooden pagoda on the same spot. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> are filled with works of art, including <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> sculptures, religious and landscape paintings, and examples of many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of calligraphy. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> larger-than-life-sized statues of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚ÄúAncestor Garden</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">‚Äù</ENAMEX> formerly reserved for retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monks</ENAMEX>, has been appropriated for the use of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> only¬†‚Äî¬†as a tearoom.
By long tradition, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chengdu</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs preeminent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of teahouses. Many still operate along the north <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jin (‚ÄúBrocade‚Äù) River</ENAMEX>, serving covered cups of flower <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Customers</ENAMEX> linger at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> tables, watching trinket <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> and pipe and tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesmen</ENAMEX> ply their trade along the river promenade.
Another restful spot is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">River Viewing Pavilion</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wangjianglou</ENAMEX>), in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> along the south <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jin River</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 100</NUMEX> kinds of bamboo grow here. As in other traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chengdu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, there are pavilions and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>, rock gardens, ponds, and shady <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">paths</ENAMEX>. River viewing of a different type is recommended at the site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dujiangyan Irrigation System</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">57 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35 miles</NUMEX>) northwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chengdu</ENAMEX>. This ambitious irrigation and flood-control project, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third century</TIMEX> b.c., is still in use. The lush hills along the shore provide a poetic setting for an engineering wonder.
In the center of town some neighborhoods retain a medieval look. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shophouses</ENAMEX>, some sagging with age, line the narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. They have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> on the ground floor and living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX> above, with wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">balconies</ENAMEX> and distinctive carved designs. But ‚Äúprogress‚Äù is inevitable. On the site of the ancient viceroy‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>, in the very center of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chengdu</ENAMEX>, stands a heavy, columned socialist-realist <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>; a giant statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Zedong</ENAMEX> graces the entrance. The edifice is now a department store. In the main hall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> are inspired by portraits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Engels</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>. A special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> catering to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> features such local specialties as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shu</ENAMEX> embroidery, toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pandas</ENAMEX> (made of rabbit fur), pottery, and bamboo ware.
By way of local color, you shouldn‚Äôt turn down a chance to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sichuan Opera</ENAMEX>. To make things more challenging, it‚Äôs all sung in the local dialect, but you can just relax and watch the spectacle of mime, dance, and acrobatics. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Backstage tours</ENAMEX> are arranged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> by private tour <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sichuan</ENAMEX> cuisine, one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> cooking, produces such imaginative creations as ‚Äúabalone and chrysanthemums,<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äù ‚Äúpeonies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX>,‚Äù and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äústewed bear‚Äôs trotters</ENAMEX> in brown <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX>.‚Äù One of the most famous dishes, mapo dofu, consists of beancurd infused with chili peppers in a manner that numbs the tongue upon impact. 
For the more adventurous, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chengdu</ENAMEX> is the gateway to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Buddha</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leshan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Emei</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">136</NUMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chongqing</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chungking</ENAMEX>)
Although the city‚Äôs history goes back <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chongqing</ENAMEX> was never a cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, and it isn‚Äôt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. It cannot offer spectacular temples, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>, or archaeological sites. Rather, it is a place to see the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life of a major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and to begin some outstanding excursions on the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yangzi River</ENAMEX>.
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qin Dynasty</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third century</TIMEX> b.c., the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of the dreamily named <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom of Ba</ENAMEX>. Its present name (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chongqing means ‚ÄúDouble Jubilation‚Äù</ENAMEX>) dates from the medieval period, commemorating a lucky streak in the life of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX>. Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> it was spelled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chungking</ENAMEX>, by which name the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was best known in the West as the political and military capital of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nationalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939 to 1945</TIMEX>, the wartime redoubt of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chiang Kai-shek</ENAMEX>.
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chongqing</ENAMEX> is physically located in subtropical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sichuan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Szechuan</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Province</ENAMEX>, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1997</TIMEX> it has been an autonomous governmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> (as are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tianjin</ENAMEX>), with a staggering metropolitan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 30 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Set on a promontory where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yangzi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jialing</ENAMEX> rivers converge, this starkly industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of smokestacks is crucial to transportation and commerce in southwest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. It presides over the portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yangzi</ENAMEX> upstream from the massive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Gorges Dam</ENAMEX> project, which sometime <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the years 2009 and 2013</TIMEX> will create an immense reservoir and drown the most scenic section of the river. 
The sightseeing you remember best might be the lively free market lining the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of steps that descend higgledy-piggledy from the hills of central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chongqing</ENAMEX> to the river. Hustling, bustling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants hawk</ENAMEX> the rich harvest of the surrounding farming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>: cabbages and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oranges</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> and live <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> (they are weighed while flapping), river <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and squirming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eels</ENAMEX>, and table after table of the most fragrant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX> and hole-in-the-wall caf√©s heat up the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">city‚Äôs number-one dish</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sichuan</ENAMEX> hotpot.
Leading down to the river‚Äôs edge, the steep stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stairway</ENAMEX> known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chaotianmen</ENAMEX>), which appears not to have been cleaned since the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ming Dynasty</ENAMEX>, is treacherously overlaid with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX> and muck, so wear your safest shoes and walk with care. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happily</ENAMEX>, at the bottom of this long descent there is a terminal for the funicular that returns you to the top of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, which is so <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hilly</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX> are almost unknown.
Sights worth seeing in town include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chongqing People‚Äôs Hall</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX> to serve as a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX>-seat conference <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> and hotel. It blends the styles of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qing</ENAMEX> dynasties with the needs of a modern conference <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chongqing Museum</ENAMEX>, while poorly-lit and aging, does contain a collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dinosaur eggs</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two 3,000-year-old</TIMEX> wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> that, suspended from the cliffs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yangzi</ENAMEX>, served as caskets for nobles in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ba Kingdom</ENAMEX>. Perhaps the liveliest sight in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chongqing</ENAMEX> is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1,000-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luohan Temple</ENAMEX>, where blind fortune-tellers and devoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> converge from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dawn to dusk</TIMEX>. 
In the domain of darker political history, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nationalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> are open as monuments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revolutionary</ENAMEX> cause. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chiang Kai-shek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Criminal Acts Exhibition Hall</ENAMEX> (so goes the catchy title) includes cells and torture <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX>. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> are not usually shown around unless they specifically <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">request it.</ENAMEX> This is largely in deference to the sensitivities of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, who are blamed for collusion with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nationalists</ENAMEX> in the excesses of their anticommunist struggle.
Because of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Chongqing‚Äôs notoriously torrid summer weather¬†‚Äî¬†it‚Äôs</ENAMEX> known as one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúovens‚Äù of China¬†‚Äî¬†hills</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> are a very welcome refuge here. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Loquat Hill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pipashan</ENAMEX>), the city‚Äôs highest spot, has gardens, a teahouse (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hongxing</ENAMEX>), and some splendid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panoramas</ENAMEX>. The Northern and Southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hot Springs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beiwenquan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nanwenquan</ENAMEX>) are also popular gathering places, with well-kept public gardens. A typical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chongqing</ENAMEX> method of escaping the heat is to take refuge in a cool cave. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> air raids, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">air-raid shelters</ENAMEX> were dug into the mountains here, and some have been turned into caf√©s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>.
Even in the heat of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, however, the most popular dish remains the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sichuan</ENAMEX> hotpot, a bowl of seething <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oils</ENAMEX> into which the diner dips and boils to perfection a selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meats</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>, and beancurd, much like fighting fire with fire.
Excursions from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chongqing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yangzi River Cruise</ENAMEX>
China‚Äôs most exciting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> trip is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yangzi River</ENAMEX> cruise through the spectacular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Gorges</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanxia</ENAMEX>). It takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least three days</TIMEX> to go downriver from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chongqing</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wuhan</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as many as five days</TIMEX> in the reverse direction, bucking the considerable tide. Until relatively recently the trip was considered an extended, risky adventure. The most awesome scenery is concentrated between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sichuan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baidi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nanjin Pass</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hubei Province</ENAMEX>. The sight of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yangzi</ENAMEX> water rushing between the sheer walls and evocative rock formations never fails to stir the traveler‚Äôs spirit. 
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National People‚Äôs Congress</ENAMEX> passed a resolution to launch the massive <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Three Gorges Hydropower</ENAMEX> Project, including the construction of a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dam</ENAMEX> and a reservoir, slated for completion sometime after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2009</TIMEX>, which will submerge the most scenic sections of the river. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tourists</ENAMEX> can choose between ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> passenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> or more deluxe luxury cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> that cater to overseas <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">river boats</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> use lack frills, amenities, and guides. The luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX> charge much more but offer a good range of tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX>, including decent meals. Often reserved in part for package tours, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> are also open to independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>, and staterooms can even be booked in advance overseas with such lines as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Cruises</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dazu Stone Sculptures</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs great artistic wonders, rated on par with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mogao Caves</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silk Road</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dunhuang</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> sculptural treasure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dazu</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> northwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chongqing</ENAMEX> was so inaccessible in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> times that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many thousands</NUMEX> of statues were never exposed to pillage. Today, it still takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> to cover the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">112 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">70 miles</NUMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chongqing</ENAMEX>, even via the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chengyu Expressway</ENAMEX>.
The stone carvings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dazu</ENAMEX> were begun late in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tang Dynasty</ENAMEX>; the work lasted well into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Song</ENAMEX> period, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX> is their central theme, there are also sculptures representing historical and human-interest subjects.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Hill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beishan</ENAMEX>), situated <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only a couple of kilometers</NUMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dazu</ENAMEX>, begins with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> and a big, animated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>. The wide, rocky valley below is filled with sculpture; every inch of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> seems to have been carved. Among the perfectly preserved figures in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúThe Wheel of the Universe‚Äù in Grotto 136</ENAMEX> are the statues of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> holy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bodhisattvas Manjusri</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samatabhadra</ENAMEX>, who triumphed over evil. Helping to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Hill</ENAMEX> an overwhelming experience is the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilgrims</ENAMEX> who still call upon these ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX>. 
Even more magnificent is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Treasure Peak</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baodingshan</ENAMEX>). Its sculptures are located in a natural arc of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Buddha Crescent</ENAMEX>, carved over a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70-year</TIMEX> span by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> monks during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Song Dynasty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1127‚Äì1279</ENAMEX>). The biggest single work, an immense reclining <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha 29 m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX> ft) long, is surrounded by the infinitely smaller statues of lifelike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX>. Whereas grotto sculpture in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is usually laid out more or less spontaneously, the caves here were apparently all planned to the last detail before the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> was chipped, thus eliminating any repetition. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dazu</ENAMEX> represents the last great period of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> cave sculpture in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, and a long day‚Äôs journey out and back from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chongqing</ENAMEX> to this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone crescent</ENAMEX> is unforgettable. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dali</ENAMEX>
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yunnan Province</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 250 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">155 miles</NUMEX>) northwest of its capital <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kunming</ENAMEX> along the historic <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Burma Road route</ENAMEX>, is the scenic village of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dali</ENAMEX>, a favorite of independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">backpackers</ENAMEX>. The surroundings could hardly be more spectacular, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erhai (‚ÄúEar Sea‚Äù</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> to the east and the steep <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cangshan</ENAMEX> mountain range to the west. Best of all are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dali</ENAMEX>, mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX>, outgoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who treat Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> with wonderful hospitality.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, capital of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bai Autonomous Region</ENAMEX>, has sections of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">medieval wall</ENAMEX> with formal gates on the north and south ends. Within the walls are a few intersecting main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> whose tile-roofed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> now serve as souvenir <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, private travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, hostels, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">and¬†‚Äî¬†above all¬†‚Äî¬†small</ENAMEX>, intimate, friendly caf√©s serving a truly international mix of inexpensive dishes.
The caf√© life in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dali</ENAMEX> is one of its chief delights. Caf√©s are perfect spots to wile away the sunny <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> or to meet local <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as well as other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>. Perhaps the most famous of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of caf√©s is Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Son‚Äôs Cultural Exchange Caf√©</ENAMEX>, run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Li</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heliyi</ENAMEX>), the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bai</ENAMEX> in history to go abroad. His autobiography, on sale at his caf√©, is an epic soap opera.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dali</ENAMEX> also has sights and attractions well worth attending to when the caf√© and bistro scene begins to pale. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Erhai Lake</ENAMEX> is a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-minute</TIMEX> walk from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, and its main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caicun</ENAMEX>, is a maze of unpaved <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. Ferries cross the lake to even more remote <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> dedicated to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guanyin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> of mercy) on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Putuo Island</ENAMEX>. Any of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of local travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> can quickly arrange an excursion to lakeside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>, including the market at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wase</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> popular diversion is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> outdoor market at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaping</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> up the eucalyptus-lined road by minibus from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dali</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs a vast market of country wares, batik, and horse-trading, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> dressed in their traditional bright Bai jackets, tunics, and plumed caps.
The chief monument at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dali</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Three Pagodas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santasi</ENAMEX>), founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">825</TIMEX>. The tallest of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>, all sealed up, rises to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> tiers. The complex is ringed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX>, many of them selling specimens of the local marble. There are also temples and pagodas in the steep foothills of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cangshan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Mountain</ENAMEX>) range. Although seldom open, they provide the perfect ornaments for a day‚Äôs hike from vista to vista over this long, narrow valley that reaches west to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>.
While young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventurous travelers</ENAMEX> still flock to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dali</ENAMEX>, the opening of several new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> away has brought this exquisite little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> Shangri-La within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any visitor‚</TIMEX>Äôs reach.
As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dali</ENAMEX> is discovered by more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> are heading out into even more remote regions of northwestern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yunnan</ENAMEX>. Particularly recommended is the village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lijiang</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">150 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">95 miles</NUMEX>) north of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dali</ENAMEX>, under the shadow of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5,500-m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18,000</NUMEX>-ft) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jade Dragon Snow Mountain</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yulong Xue Shan</ENAMEX>). The old-town section, recently restored after a serious earthquake, is even more quaint than downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dali</ENAMEX>, the local <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Naxi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are warm and open, and the nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">monasteries</ENAMEX> are intriguing.
From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lijiang</ENAMEX>, one can journey still farther into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs ultimate outback, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leaping Tiger Gorge</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xutiaoxia</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lugu Lake</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sichuan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> borders.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Datong</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tatung</ENAMEX>)
It takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about seven hours</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> to reach <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Datong</ENAMEX>, to the west in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanxi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shansi</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Province</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The trip</ENAMEX>, through some gorgeous mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, is a favorite of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> who are drawn to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Datong</ENAMEX> to see the quaint steam locomotives still at work in the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs richest coal-mining region. Coal was the logical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> for the long <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> to the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Datong</ENAMEX> became the major steam <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">locomotive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Datong Locomotive Works</ENAMEX> could turn out a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">locomotive</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every working day</TIMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> now makes diesel engines only, but it is open for tours, highlighted by a ride on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the old steam locomotives.
