



Where to Go
In planning your trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>, you can, according to your interests, divide your time between several quite different itineraries. However, for nearly everyone visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayas</ENAMEX>, whether experienced from the comfort of a hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX>, from the seat of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, or from along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX>, are at the heart of a visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> to the mountains are the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, temples, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu Valley</ENAMEX>. Nowhere else on earth is there anything else quite like the valley‚Äôs architectural legacy, a fact recognized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unesco</ENAMEX> in declaring much of the valley a cultural World Heritage Site to be cherished and protected for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>.
Although they are so close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> as almost to be suburbs, the sister <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhaktapur</ENAMEX> each have a distinct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and unique attractions. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">300 years</TIMEX>, until forcibly united in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 18th century</TIMEX>, they were separate kingdoms with related, but not always friendly, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malla</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>.
Within and beyond the valley are many more sights worth taking in on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trips, including viewpoints on the valley‚Äôs rim from where you can see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayas</ENAMEX> at sunrise and sunset, particularly recommended if you are not planning to go trekking.
For many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, trekking is the main purpose of a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. The special section on trekking gives hints and tips on what to expect, what to take along, the dangers to avoid, and a brief description of the more popular treks (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX>).
However, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> is not all mountains. Down in the lowland forests there are several national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, including the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Royal Chitwan National Park</ENAMEX>, where rhinos, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of species of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> can be spotted. Accommodations at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Chitwan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Bardia</ENAMEX> national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> range from the truly rustic to the luxuriously rustic.
Reservations for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, jungle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lodges</ENAMEX>, and flights to and within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> can be hard to confirm in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the busiest seasons</TIMEX> if you wait too long. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning</ENAMEX> is important, but so is flexibility. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> should allow a few extra <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> for contingencies; perhaps a flight cancelled by weather in the mountains or just your on-the-spot realization that there‚Äôs more to do and see than you expected.
The question of where to begin is easy: exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, capital and gateway to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>
The sights, sounds, and smells of old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> bombard the senses. The center of the capital is a kaleidoscope of golden rooftops, multicolored costumes, steep temple steps layered with wares like market shelves, country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> hawking produce spread on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, sari-draped <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">matrons</ENAMEX> placing flower petals on altars to grimacing gods, the sudden eruption of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">herd</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX> across your path, the scent of marigold garlands and of dumplings fried in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>, the constant jangling of bicycle bells and rickshaw horns. It‚Äôs all too much to take in at once.
Begin with an organized tour of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> or engage a guide through a travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. Sort out the main features and then return on your own for a closer, calmer look. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Streets don‚</ENAMEX>Äôt have actual names but are instead referred to by the name of the neighborhood through which they are passing, thus <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> change name about every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> in some parts of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Luckily, throughout old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, there are now signposts to let you know what neighborhood or square you are in, so with the help of a good map you can orient yourself by a few major landmarks. Finding hidden gems down narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> and dark <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> is one of the great rewards of exploring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> on foot. Organized tours rarely penetrate these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corners</ENAMEX>. Assuming a minimum of stops for shopping, the following walking tour will take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a very full half day</TIMEX>.
The best way to start this walking tour is to get a cycle rickshaw or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> to take you to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Durbar Square</ENAMEX>. Don‚Äôt get too concerned if you seem to be following a very roundabout route; one-way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> often make getting from point A to point B in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> a circuitous experience.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Licchavi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> founded the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kantipur</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the eighth century</TIMEX> and laid the foundations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanuman Dhoka Durbar</ENAMEX>, the palace which gives this area its name. The present <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX> was begun by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malla</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1500s</TIMEX> and enlarged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prithvi Narayan Shah</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1768</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building stands</ENAMEX> in the heart of a living <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malla</ENAMEX> dynasty architecture.
Flanking the brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> with its broad-lintelled, latticed windows and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> is the raised brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basantapur Chowk</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">royal elephants</ENAMEX> were once kept and where curio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> now spread their wares. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚ÄúFreak Street</ENAMEX>,‚Äù leading off this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>, was once the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hub</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kathmandu‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX> scene. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it is still lined with cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and guest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> full of local handicrafts and jewelry. Freak Street is no longer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu‚Äôs</ENAMEX> hub for the backpacking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>; today‚Äôs budget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> seem to be willing to spend a bit more than their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie predecessors</ENAMEX> did.
At the far end of this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza stands</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kumari Bahal</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of the living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX>, which was built for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kumari</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1757</TIMEX> and is guarded by painted <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX> with long wavy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX>-style hair. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three-story</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> can be visited and, if enough rupees are collected, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kumari</ENAMEX> herself may appear briefly at a beautifully carved upstairs window.
Directly across from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kumari Bahal</ENAMEX> stands the incongruous white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grecian</ENAMEX> facade of a palace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> that was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandra Shumshere</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rana</ENAMEX> responsible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singha Durbar</ENAMEX> and many of the city‚Äôs neoclassical edifices.
Continue past the high pagoda <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vishnu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, guarded by a splendid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kneeling</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garuda</ENAMEX>, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kasthamandap</ENAMEX>. The word, which means ‚ÄúHouse of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wood</ENAMEX>,‚Äù may have given <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> its name. This <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is a rather squat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> said to have been made from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>. Inside, pigeons peck at <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice grains</ENAMEX> left as offerings to an image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorakhnath</ENAMEX> that is encrusted with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carmine powder</ENAMEX>.
To <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kasthamandap</ENAMEX> is a small, shiny, brass-roofed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> dedicated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>-headed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hindu god Ganesh</ENAMEX>. A procession of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> line up here in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> to make offerings to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ganesh</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worshippers</ENAMEX> will touch a pillar of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> or reach up to sound the bells hanging from the low roof. Ringing bells at temples is a way of telling the god to pay attention to a prayer.
Turning back into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durbar Square</ENAMEX>, climb the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> steep steps of the central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maju Deval</ENAMEX> pagoda to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva</ENAMEX> for a view over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> and its surrounding temples. The broad steps are a favorite spot for reading and loafing in the sun. From this vantage point you can enjoy the charming sight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parvati</ENAMEX> in painted wood looking amiably out of an upper window of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">adjoining house</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>. Just beyond is the great bell, which used to be rung to call the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> for important announcements, and, a little further along, a pair of huge drums. The drums are now thumped once a year to mark the sacrifices of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water buffalo</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dasain festival</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>.
There are something like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> temples and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX>, great and small, in the immediate vicinity of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hanuman Dhoka Palace</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>, which now serves primarily as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, takes its name from the red-cloaked figure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey god Hanuman</ENAMEX> that stands to the left of the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace entrance</ENAMEX>. This stone statue was erected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1672</TIMEX> and stands atop a squat pillar. The statue‚Äôs face is entirely obscured by red paste that is smeared on by worshippers. Tour guides say the red paste is to spare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanuman</ENAMEX> the sight of the goings-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">on¬†‚Äî¬†more acrobatic</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">erotic¬†‚Äî¬†carved</ENAMEX> on the struts of the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaganath Temple</ENAMEX> opposite.
When this bit of mythology is related, it immediately sends tour groups trotting across to see what is forbidden to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey god</ENAMEX>. Some say the carvings are there for protection, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> of lightning is a virgin who would not come near anything so shocking. The erotica is probably best explained, however, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nepal‚Äôs ubiquitous Shiva lingams</ENAMEX> (phalluses) and the female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">yoni symbols</ENAMEX>, as an expression of the creative energy in male-female relations and the pleasure principles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tantrism</ENAMEX>.
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace wall</ENAMEX> beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanuman</ENAMEX> statue and protected by a wooden fence is a poem etched in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> languages dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 January 1664</TIMEX>. It is attributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Pratap Malla</ENAMEX>, reputed to be a great linguist.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> itself is still used for the coronation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> and for observance of religious rituals by the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Like most other national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> it opens at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30am</TIMEX> and is closed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX>. Just inside the entrance is a remarkable sculpture (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1673</TIMEX>) in black stone of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vishnu</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Narsimha</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>, disembowelling the demon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haranyakashipu</ENAMEX> with the relish of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workman</ENAMEX> opening his lunchbox.
The inner <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nasal Chowk</ENAMEX>, is one of the few that can be visited. It has curious and fine carved struts as well as door ornamentation. Binoculars are great for isolating such works of art from their busy surroundings and for appreciating the details of craftsmanship.
From here you can climb to the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Basantapur Tower</ENAMEX> and look down on the rooftops of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Kathmandu</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> houses a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribhuvan, Mahendra</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birendra</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> is like a walk-in scrapbook, with framed snapshots, newspaper clippings, and memorabilia, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">King Tribhuvan‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">goldfish tank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycle</ENAMEX>, and record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX>.
Back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durbar Square</ENAMEX>, pigeons swirl constantly around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kathmandu‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most colorful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kala</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>) Bhairav. This is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva</ENAMEX> in his ‚Äúdestroyer‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX>, fanged and bedecked with skulls. The image acted as a sort of ancient lie detector, as it was said that anyone failing to tell the truth before it would bleed to death. Suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> were brought here to force them to confess. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate</ENAMEX>-faced god is quite gaily decorated in hues of red, yellow, and blue, and his round, white-circled eyes look more startled than fierce. Nearby, behind a screened window, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seto</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bhairav</ENAMEX>, a gold-lacquered face through which beer spurts for scrambling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indra Jatra</ENAMEX>.
Adjoining the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> is the magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> dedicated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1564</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahendra Malla</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taleju</ENAMEX>. Only the royal family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prays</ENAMEX> here. It is enclosed by a wall with a gaudy gate that is opened to the public once a year during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dasain festival</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-tiered brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pagoda</ENAMEX> has gilded roofing, is topped by a golden bell-shaped cupola, and is decorated under the eaves by a fringe of wind chimes. It stands on a raised <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>, its profile stately against the sky.
Beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taleju</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> begins a famous narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">diagonal street</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, open-air markets, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX> most typical of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Kathmandu</ENAMEX>. It is so crowded with humanity, on foot and on assorted wheels, and is crammed with so many fascinating things for sale, that one risks overlooking the significant monuments along the way.
At the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indra Chowk</ENAMEX> junction, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dragon-lions</ENAMEX> snarl beside the unusual stairway entrance to the many-hued and balconied <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akash Bhairav</ENAMEX>, housing a silver <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bhairav</ENAMEX> image brought out on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">feast days</TIMEX>. At the next junction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kel Tole</ENAMEX>, a modest gateway on the left leads to the important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seto Machendranath Temple</ENAMEX>. An example of the fusion of religions prevalent in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>, the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> to this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bodhisattva</ENAMEX> is encircled by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> prayer wheels, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> images are mounted on pedestals. Within the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>, you‚Äôll spot a traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> statue that was placed here during the rule of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranas</ENAMEX>.
The next major junction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asan Tole</ENAMEX>, is larger and even busier than the ones preceding. Here is the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> market and collection point for porters looking for jobs. You have to thread your way through heaps of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> sold by farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> sitting cross-legged on the ground, all the while <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">side-stepping cows</ENAMEX> browsing on vegetable leaves.
Almost overwhelmed by this swirl of activity, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annapurna Temple</ENAMEX> in the right-hand corner gleams with burnished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX>. The metal belt hanging over the roof is a pataka, a sort of hot-line to speed prayers heavenwards. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> contains a kailash, a silver pot symbolizing wealth, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annapurna</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva‚Äôs Parvati</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> of abundance.
From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asan Tole</ENAMEX> make a sharp left into the back-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, past <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, and continue until the next main intersection. On your left, in the wall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corner house</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of nails have been hammered into a piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> under a small image of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vaisha Dev</ENAMEX>, the toothache god. In case this remedy doesn‚Äôt ease the pain, several <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX> and denture <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> have set up close by.
Turn right at this intersection, and then left where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX> flank a passage leading to a striking white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> stupa in a large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>. This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kathesimbhu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-17th century</TIMEX> in the style of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swayambhunath</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>) as a service to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX> physically unable to climb up to that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">hilltop</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX>. There are several masterpieces of sculpture here, as well as a bahal, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX>, one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> tucked away in courtyards of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
At this point, continuing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thahiti Tole</ENAMEX>, where there is another small stupa, you can walk north to the main intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thamel, Kathmandu‚</ENAMEX>Äôs lively, fast-spreading <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for budget-conscious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. Guest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, curio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX>, rug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, trekking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, bicycle and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> rental <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX>, and bookshops line the way. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guest houses</ENAMEX> have pleasant gardens, and most are clean and quite inexpensive, though in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> more expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> have also opened in this neighborhood. Many low-budget guest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> have bulletin boards where trekkers leave messages for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> or advertise for trekking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companions</ENAMEX>.
From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thamel‚</ENAMEX>Äôs center you can return to your starting point by heading right, or east, to a roundabout. Back in the modern part of town you come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser Library</ENAMEX>. This has nothing to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> emperors, but was built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field-Marshal Kaiser</ENAMEX> (a distortion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX> name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kesar</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shumshere Rana</ENAMEX>. The tall <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> surrounding this building, which also houses part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ministry of Education</ENAMEX>, are the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> roost of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> of large fruit <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bats</ENAMEX> that trade places at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dusk</TIMEX> with flocks of crows. Inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> there are old photos of assorted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ranas</ENAMEX>, smartly dressed in tweed suits, neckties, and polished boots, posing atop the huge rhinos and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers they‚Äôve slain</ENAMEX>.
The royal family lives in the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Narayanhiti Palace</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, behind <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">flagpoles</ENAMEX> bearing the world‚Äôs only non-rectangular national flag. (Nepal‚Äôs is made of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> superimposed triangular pennants with sun and moon emblems.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace stands</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the wide <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durbar Marg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX> leading south. Here are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> and travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency offices</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, quality <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hotels¬†‚Äî¬†the</ENAMEX> opposite pole of tourism from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thamel</ENAMEX>. Veer right at the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Durbar Marg</ENAMEX> to reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rani Pokhari</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen‚Äôs Pond</ENAMEX>).
In the middle of this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> basin of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, connected to the shore of the pond by a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>, stands a small white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shiva</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> on an island. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> is only opened once a year, and for this reason, the entire pond is surrounded by a substantial fence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rani Pokhari</ENAMEX> lies at the northern end of a large open space that divides the old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> from the newer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX>. This space includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ratna Park</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tundikhel</ENAMEX> parade ground, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> can sometimes be seen. Toward the south end of the open space is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bhimsen Tower</ENAMEX>, a useful landmark visible from many parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>.
From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rani Pokhari</ENAMEX>, carefully cross the wide <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX> known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kantipath</ENAMEX>, which is lined with numerous public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, including a hospital and former <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranas</ENAMEX>. Today this is one of the most congested <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, and the exhaust fumes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">tuk-tuks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> can be overwhelming. Once across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX>, you can dive back into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Kathmandu</ENAMEX> and within a block reach <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Asan Tole</ENAMEX>, through which you passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> and from where you can retrace your steps back to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Durbar Square</ENAMEX>. Alternatively, you can head north up Kantipath, take the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> left and then, after a bit of zigging and zagging, take the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> right to find yourself heading back into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thamel</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathmandu Environs</ENAMEX>
Crowning a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">hilltop</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 3 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 miles</NUMEX>) west of the city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,000-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swayambhunath</ENAMEX> can be seen from all over the valley. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> can take you almost to the very top of the hill, but it is more interesting to follow the pilgrims‚Äô route and climb the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">365</NUMEX> steps that lead up through a wooded <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX>. The lower stairs are lined with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> selling small, carved mani <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> (prayer stones) made for the tourist market. Higher up, the stairs become much steeper and are lined with stone statues of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>.
At the summit is one of the oldest stupas in the world, an immense white mound surmounted by a golden <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">cube</NUMEX>, on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of which are the astonishing all-seeing eyes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>. Above this rises a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> diminishing golden disks symbolizing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> steps to enlightenment, then a golden royal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">parasol</ENAMEX> topped by a bell-shaped crown. Strings of prayer flags stretch from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tower‚Äôs pinnacle</ENAMEX>, and around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of small prayer wheels. While pilgrims circumambulate the stupa, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, and pigeons clamber about and forage for scraps of food offerings in small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">altars</ENAMEX> set in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>.
The typical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX> mix of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hinduism</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX> is almost immediately in evidence. At the top of the stairs stands a huge dorje, the tantric thunderbolt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX>. To the left of this (remember to walk clockwise around the stupa) rise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two shikara</TIMEX>-style votive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">deities</ENAMEX>. On the side of the stupa opposite the stairs is a very popular pagoda <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hariti Devi</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> who protects against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">smallpox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">children‚Äôs diseases</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, too, has <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> prayer wheels around it, worn shiny by the hands of the devout.
Adjacent to this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, within a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX> to prevent their theft, are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> images alternately described as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Tara</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green Tara</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> deities) and as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ganga</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamuna</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">deities</ENAMEX>). A bronze <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacock</ENAMEX> accompanies these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> figures. There is a small forest of white chaitya <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX> behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hariti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Devi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, and a porch to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side where pilgrims congregate to prepare meals in offering for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX>.
On the north side of the stupa, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> is open to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4pm</TIMEX> the monks can be observed at prayer, blowing the groaning horns and banging drums and cymbals in a red and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold chapel</ENAMEX>. At sunset, when the burnished gold atop the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stupa</ENAMEX> begins to glow with a warm buttery light, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX> surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swayambhunath</ENAMEX> offers a fine view over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu Valley</ENAMEX>.
On the road back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, stop at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Museum</ENAMEX> to admire its small but select collection of art and artifacts. Here are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Licchavi</ENAMEX> stone reliefs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parvati</ENAMEX> from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixth centuries</TIMEX>, the classical period of sculpture. Figures are slimmer and more graceful than the more common balloon-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">breasted</NUMEX> models of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mallas</ENAMEX>. A lovely <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighth-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birth</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> is curiously reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> nativity scenes. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bhairav</ENAMEX> urn and a comical terra-cotta <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ganesh</ENAMEX> are noteworthy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">There‚Äôs</ENAMEX> also a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> that holds a collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> iconography. The historical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> is filled with ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, including a leather cannon that must have given <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunners</ENAMEX> a few anxious moments.
Pashupatinath, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 miles</NUMEX>) northeast of old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, is dedicated to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva</ENAMEX> in his incarnation as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pashupati</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lord of the Animals</ENAMEX>. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pashupati</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron deity</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pashupatinath</ENAMEX>, located on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bagmati River</ENAMEX> near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, is one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nepal‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most sacred sites. The great temple <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> can only be entered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hindus</ENAMEX>, but views of a huge gilded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nandi</ENAMEX> (a bull <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times life size) and massive embossed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> doors can be had from just outside the front gate. From a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> that links the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> with terraces on the far side of the river, you can look down on the funeral <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">‚Äúghats‚Äù</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX> are cremated atop piles of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">straw</ENAMEX>. There is usually a cremation in progress on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX> by the river, and though it seems macabre, there are always <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> shooting pictures and videos of the proceedings. When the cremation is completed, the ashes are scattered in the shallow waters of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bagmati</ENAMEX>, which is regarded as holy because it is a tributary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ganges</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">river</ENAMEX> is also where on many occasions during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX> take ritual purification <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX>.
Boudhanath, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 miles</NUMEX>) northeast of the city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, is the valley‚Äôs second important stupa and is similar in many ways to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swayambhunath</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, constructed around <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">a.d. 500</ENAMEX>, is encircled by monasteries, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, and lodges for pilgrims. It cannot be seen fully until you enter its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">precincts</ENAMEX> through a narrow passage from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. Then it looms above you, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">38 m</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">125 ft</ENAMEX>) high, streamers of prayer flags fluttering gaily against the sky. It is possible to reach terraces around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> by climbing a staircase guarded by painted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-bearing stone <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX>. The all-seeing eyes here seem genuinely penetrating, almost glowering above the whitewashed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX>. The question mark ‚Äúnose‚Äù is actually the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX> numeral <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, meaning the only way to enlightenment is by following the rules of conduct laid down by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boudhanath</ENAMEX> has attracted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monks</ENAMEX> and pilgrims for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>, and over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sherpa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> has grown in this area. Many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you will see circumambulating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boudhanath</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetans</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nepalis</ENAMEX>, and those with long braids and wild costumes are usually <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetans</ENAMEX> who have only recently arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>. Also keep an eye out for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilgrims</ENAMEX> who prostrate themselves repeatedly as they circle the stupa.
Where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swayambhunath</ENAMEX> is cluttered with monuments in different styles, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boudhanath</ENAMEX> there are no other temples to distract pilgrims. There are, however, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> specializing in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antiques</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> souvenirs. Pilgrims coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>, as well as local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, supply the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> that ring the stupa with the city‚Äôs best selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antiques</ENAMEX>. There are also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> filled with bronze <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> statuary, silver ornaments, prayer wheels, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass ‚</ENAMEX>Äúsinging bowls.‚Äù
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lalitpur</ENAMEX>)
Although it was once an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patan</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> separate from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> in name only. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bagmati River</ENAMEX> runs between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, but there is little to distinguish <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of the river from the other. At least, that‚Äôs how it seems as you cross the bridge between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and pass through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulchowk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kupondole</ENAMEX> sections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> are home to modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of numerous international aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and other non-governmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> (NGOs), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> of many expatriots from around the world. However, beyond modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patan</ENAMEX> lies the old part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, where traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Newari</ENAMEX> craftsmanship is readily apparent. Here it is easy to see why this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lalitpur</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beautiful City</ENAMEX>).
Here, on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Patan‚Äôs Durbar Square</ENAMEX>, stands the valley‚Äôs greatest concentration of major temples and historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. Among these are the red brick <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Palace</ENAMEX>, which now houses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patan Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nepal‚</ENAMEX>Äôs finest and most modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>), and, facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> across the narrow brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> temples of different styles and sizes.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Palace</ENAMEX> consists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> courtyards and contains several temples. The first entrance into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> leads into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sundari Chowk</ENAMEX>, which encloses a glorious royal tub, entered by steps and encrusted with intricate sculptures. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank</ENAMEX> is encircled by small sculptured deities and coiled <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX>. In the next <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mul Chowk</ENAMEX>, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> outstanding examples of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Newari</ENAMEX> metalwork, tall bronze reliefs of the goddesses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ganga</ENAMEX> (standing on a crocodile) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamuna</ENAMEX> (standing on a tortoise). Over the door, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Surya</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo</ENAMEX>-like sun god, rides in a chariot drawn by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">prancing horses</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> rarely seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX> art.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> entry is one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">square‚Äôs masterpieces¬†‚Äî¬</ENAMEX>†the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Gate</ENAMEX>. Above this gilded door can be seen images of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consort</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parvati</ENAMEX>. Through the gateway lies the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patan Museum</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> an impressive collection of art and artifacts from throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nepal‚</ENAMEX>Äôs history.
Opposite the door to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sundari Chowk</ENAMEX> stands a stone <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Krishna</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> built in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> shikara style. Beside this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> is a huge bell that has no rope (its clapper is swung by hand). To the right of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, on a tall column, is a gilded image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoganarendra Malla</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1684‚Äì1705</ENAMEX>) seated on a throne, unperturbed by a hooded cobra hovering over him. Atop this cobra is a bronze bird like those found on the corners of temple roofs. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> once told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that as long as such <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> did not fly away, his spirit would remain in the valley.
Of the many temples across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durbar Square</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Palace</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krishna Mandir</ENAMEX>, located opposite the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Gate</ENAMEX> and built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siddhi Narsimha Malla</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1636</TIMEX>, is the most unusual and impressive. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> is of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moghul</ENAMEX> inspiration and, unusual for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>, is constructed entirely of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>. Its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> lower stories have a remarkable carved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">frieze</ENAMEX> representing scenes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mahabharata</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramayana</ENAMEX> epics. This kind of story-telling was an important way to perpetuate legends for illiterate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX>, like comic books in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>. A gilded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garuda</ENAMEX>, in his usual namaste pose, kneels on a pillar before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>.
To the right of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krishna Mandir</ENAMEX> stands <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the pagoda</TIMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva Temple</ENAMEX>, which has erotic carvings at the base of its roof struts. Beyond is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhimsen Temple</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pagoda</ENAMEX> dedicated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX> god of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> (dear to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newari</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopkeepers</ENAMEX>). To the left of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krishna Mandir</ENAMEX> stands the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charnarayan Temple</ENAMEX>, which is believed to be the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> and which also has erotic carvings on its roof struts.
Leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> on the lane that begins at the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhimsen Temple</ENAMEX> and following the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> around to the right will bring you to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Temple</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kwa Bahal</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 11th century</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">painted lions</ENAMEX> mark the entrance. Inside, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> surrounds a sunken <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> with an exquisite golden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, backed by a pagoda temple decorated with episodes from the life of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>. Flanking the steps leading to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> and standing on statues of tortoises are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bronze elephants</ENAMEX> with praying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">riders</ENAMEX> on their backs. On the upturned roof corners of the shimmering golden <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> stand bronze <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>.
From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Temple</ENAMEX>, continue descending the narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lane</ENAMEX> and you will come to temple complex dominated by a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five-tiered pagoda</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kumbheshwar Temple</ENAMEX>, which is dedicated to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva</ENAMEX> and dates to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1392</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> ponds in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> compound are said to be fed by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> from the holy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gosainkund Lake</ENAMEX> high in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayas</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX> come to bathe in these ponds beneath a richly ornamented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva</ENAMEX> lingam.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patan</ENAMEX> lead to a succession of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-hidden temples and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX> of great beauty and interest. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most impressive of these is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mahaboudha</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thousand Buddhas</ENAMEX>, which was erected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX>. Designed after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bodh Gaya</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> reached enlightenment, this soaring <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">spire</ENAMEX> boasts an image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> on each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of its bricks. Extensively damaged during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1934 earthquake</ENAMEX>, it was later reconstructed.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patan</ENAMEX> passes an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ashoka</ENAMEX> stupa (one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patan</ENAMEX>) and brings you to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jawalakhel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibetan Cooperative</ENAMEX>. Founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> assistance for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> makes and sells carpets. In surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> the process of carding, washing, spinning, and dyeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX>, then weaving the carpets, can be followed from start to finish. Quality of carpets is judged by the number of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">knots per square inch</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80</TIMEX>, or (superlative) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>. Profits of the cooperative go to support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapped</ENAMEX> and aged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>.
At the nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patan Industrial Estate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newari</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craftsmen</ENAMEX> can be watched carving windows and door frames for reconstruction projects or boxes for the tourist trade. They use the same tools and methods as their ancestors, and demonstrate the same skills. So do the bronze-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, who cast figurines by the ancient ‚Äúlost wax‚Äù method. These artisans are not faking antiques; they are continuing traditions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhaktapur</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhadgaon</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhaktapur</ENAMEX> lies <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">16 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 miles</NUMEX>) east of the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhaktapur</ENAMEX> means ‚ÄúCity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devotees,‚Äù</ENAMEX> and this could today be taken to mean devotion to the old ways, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhaktapur</ENAMEX> is even more medieval than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Kathmandu</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patan</ENAMEX>. Exploring its narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, you‚Äôll come upon squares filled with pottery drying in the sun and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">potters</ENAMEX> working at their hand-spun wheels, weavers at their looms, and wood-carvers at work on window frames. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artists</ENAMEX> with the finest of brushes paint the minutely detailed religious paintings called thangkas. These are widely sold, but the best come from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bhaktapur</ENAMEX>. Newari <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> also still work the fields that come right to the city‚Äôs edge.
Bhaktapur‚Äôs treasures are many, and if time permits you will be amply rewarded by allowing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two half</NUMEX>-days to wandering through its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX>.
If this city‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durbar Square</ENAMEX> seems less crowded than those in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, it‚Äôs because it was most affected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1934 earthquake</ENAMEX>. Empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX> still show where temples once stood. Others have been painstakingly restored in an on-going cooperation between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, making use of the undiminished skills of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craftsmen</ENAMEX>.
At the center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Palace</ENAMEX>, founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 15th century</TIMEX> and better known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Palace of 55 Windows</ENAMEX>. From atop a pillar, a statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bhupatindra Malla</ENAMEX>, who embellished the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX>, looks down onto the glorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sun Dhoka</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Gate</ENAMEX>, which serves as entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>. The gateway, created at the height of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Malla</ENAMEX> development in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1753</TIMEX>, surpasses anything of its kind in the valley. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>-armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> in the center of the torana is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taleju</ENAMEX>, pulling the hair of a demon beneath a pot-bellied <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garuda</ENAMEX>, assorted writhing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX>, and cavorting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>. The gate is topped with the double pennants from which the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> national flag is derived.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taleju Temple</ENAMEX>, which is located through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Gate</ENAMEX> at the far end of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> courtyards, is closed to non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hindus</ENAMEX>, but you can admire the carving on its door and get a peek past the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendant soldier</ENAMEX> to the ornate interior.
The art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> adjoining the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Palace of 55 Windows</ENAMEX> contains a collection of antique thangkas and sculpture in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> and stone. At the far end of the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">shikara</TIMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Durga Temple</ENAMEX>, interesting for the pairs of animals guarding the stairs.
A short <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> descending from the far corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>, behind a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15th-century</TIMEX> replica of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pashupatinath</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>), leads to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taumadi Tole</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> is dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhaktapur‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most famous monument, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nyatapola Temple</ENAMEX>, which was consecrated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1702</TIMEX> and is both the valley‚Äôs tallest temple and one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three five</NUMEX>-tiered pagodas in the valley. The pagoda‚<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Äôs 108</NUMEX> painted struts support the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> tiled roofs. Beginning with a pair of burly, mustachioed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malla</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestlers</ENAMEX>, the staircase leading up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> is lined with animal guardians; at each ascending level, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> times stronger than those on the level below. This sequence would indicate that the temple‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupant</ENAMEX>, the tantric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siddhi Laxmi</ENAMEX>, is extremely powerful.
Facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cafe Nyatapola</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">balconies</ENAMEX> from which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diners</ENAMEX> can admire the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nyatapola Temple</ENAMEX> and take in the market activities on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> below. Also on this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhairavnath Temple</ENAMEX>. This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bhairav</ENAMEX> idol that is paraded through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhaktapur</ENAMEX> in a chariot during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">New Year‚Äôs Bisket festival</ENAMEX>.
Duck through a low passage between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> to find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Til Mahadev Narayan Temple</ENAMEX>. It stands in an un-touristy rubble-filled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> where there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> washing, goats looking out of upstairs windows, and, behind a grill in a small kiosk, a lingam much venerated by older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, who keep it covered with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>.
Bhaktapur expanded over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> from a nucleus around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tachupal Tole</ENAMEX>, reached by a walk from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nyatapola Temple</ENAMEX> through narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> full of unfamiliar merchandise: the lengths of red yarn are sold to be plaited in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">women‚Äôs hair</ENAMEX>; the gray cannonballs are homemade <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap</ENAMEX>, the conical yellowish cigarettes are bidi, the cheapest tobacco, and can be bought singly. There will be heaps of orange <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">turmeric</ENAMEX>, cardamom, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ginger</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX>, and bundles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dried fish</ENAMEX>, looking like twigs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> offer to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mix lime</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX> of nuts and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> in a fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">betel</ENAMEX>-leaf packet for chewing. Bigger leaves stuck together with bamboo toothpicks are sold as plates for temple offerings.
Many of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tachupal Tole</ENAMEX> have been very carefully restored. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one end</TIMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dattatreya Temple</ENAMEX>, used impartially by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestlers</ENAMEX>, symbolic of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malla</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strongman</ENAMEX>, flank the open porch of this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>, and a gilded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garuda</ENAMEX> kneels on a column above. In an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> just off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> is the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peacock Window</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intricately carved wood</ENAMEX>; the window is part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pujari Math</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">priest‚Äôs house</ENAMEX> that now houses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Woodworking Museum</ENAMEX>.
KathmanduValley
Just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> away from the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, life goes on as it has for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> in the rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> of the valley. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of driveable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> is less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years old</TIMEX>. Before that there were few <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. In the valley, at least the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> of principal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> is paved and accessible by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> and bus, though the slower pace of walking or cycling is the most pleasant way to enter this world where time seems to have stopped.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farmland</ENAMEX> begins at the very edge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, and the fields are full of activity whatever the season. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX> needs lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, so the paddy (the shoots are grown from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX>) is transplanted when the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> rains flood the fields. This is a job for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, who work in lines to space the young <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> in neat rows. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> forms a green velvety blanket, then turns golden in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX> when it ripens and is harvested. This brings out the whole valley in force, everyone bending low with small sickles to cut the stalks, then stacking these in sheaves for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> or thatch after the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> is threshed. Then the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grain</ENAMEX> is dried in the sun, covering the squares and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>, and is winnowed by tossing it in the air from round trays. Fields of yellow <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mustard</ENAMEX> are grown for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil-seed</ENAMEX>. Wheat is planted as a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> in the paddies, and garden plots supply <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">maize</ENAMEX>, chilies, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>.
Another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> is bricks. The topsoil is neatly set aside, the clay beneath is dug out for brick-making, and the fertile black <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> is then replaced. Bricks fired on the spot are the valley‚Äôs main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> material.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ruminative buffalo</ENAMEX> pulls plows and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carts</ENAMEX>, then wallows in the mud of a village pond. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Chickens</ENAMEX> run in and out of doorways and often may be seen peering out from roosts on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> floor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. Under the eaves, bundles of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">maize</ENAMEX> hang to dry along with large cucumbers. Pumpkin vines climb over rooftops.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dakshinkali</ENAMEX> (a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45-minute</TIMEX> drive from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> to the southern end of the valley), when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of pilgrims bring <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> and goats to sacrifice to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kali</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacrifices</ENAMEX> also take place on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> is at the bottom of a shady glen by a brook. Carrying their offerings by the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">feet</NUMEX> (incidentally, only male <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> may be sacrificed), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> form a line on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> on the other. The altar where the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> will be spilled is out of sight, behind a wall where a loudspeaker screeches hymns to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kali</ENAMEX>. Under a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>, a cauldron bubbles. Decapitated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fowl</ENAMEX> are chucked in to speed the plucking and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX> are seared to remove the hair. The offal is thrown into the stream.
Along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, barbecues convert the sacrifices into lunch. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">picnickers</ENAMEX> say they‚Äôre doing the animal a favor, giving it a chance of a better reincarnation. A thriving souvenir market lines the path to the parking lot.
On the way back toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, the village of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pharping</ENAMEX> deserves a stop. It has many beautifully carved windows in mud brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> that are gently crumbling away. A path leads uphill to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monasteries</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bajra Yogini</ENAMEX>, a local deity, guarded by bronze <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX>.
Beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pharping</ENAMEX> and just off the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> lies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chobar Gorge</ENAMEX>, through which flows the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bagmati River</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legend</ENAMEX> holds that this gorge was created by the saber of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manjushri</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>). It is indeed scarcely wider than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> slash, crossed by a miniature iron suspension <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> brought from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> and portered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the turn of the century</TIMEX>. Below, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jal Binayak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ganesh</ENAMEX> stands by the rocks where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> do laundry and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> dive, while a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral ghat</ENAMEX> stands mercifully downstream from these activities. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> here, you‚Äôll see what appears to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star of David</ENAMEX>. This is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">emblem</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> superimposed triangles, the up-pointing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> denoting the male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, the other the female. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bronze rat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ganesh‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX>, fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, looking like a dachshund. A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cement</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> belching smoke is a regrettable addition to this corner of the valley.
Off the road back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> lies the valley‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> most important <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kirtipur</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Prithvi Narayan Shah</ENAMEX> had difficulty conquering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirtipur</ENAMEX>, whose site atop a ridge with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two high</NUMEX> points made it virtually impregnable. When he finally succeeded, after a prolonged siege and heavy losses, he punished the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> by cutting off the noses and lips of all men¬†‚Äî¬†except those who played wind instruments.
In the middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bagh Bhairav Temple</ENAMEX>, under the eaves of which are swords and shields from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th-century</TIMEX> siege. From the restored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uma Maheshwar Temple</ENAMEX> at the highest point, there is a fine view of the valley and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stone <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> with spikes on their backs to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> from playing mahout. Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will probably be found playing ‚ÄúGoats and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tigers</ENAMEX>,‚Äù a favorite national game that can be marked out in chalk on the ground and played with pebbles, or on attractive brass boards with carved pieces. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Girls</ENAMEX> like to play jacks with pebbles as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popular</ENAMEX>, too, is the game of caroms, played by flicking checkers on a square <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> with corner pockets.
The highest peak on the valley‚Äôs rim is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pulchowki</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,762</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9,062 ft</NUMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half-day</TIMEX> trip beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patan</ENAMEX> through verdant scenery rising to the attractive village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godavari</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulchowki</ENAMEX> is gravel or worse much of the way, and is only driveable during the dry season. The hiking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX> takes a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX>, passing through rhododendrons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">orchids</ENAMEX>, and laurel. At the top, the breathtaking mountain view on a clear morning sweeps from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everest</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annapurnas</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godavari‚Äôs Royal Botanical Gardens</ENAMEX> at the foot of the mountain has an orchid collection, lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, and a brook. It is a favorite haunt of bulbuls, babblers, and minivets, as well as those who understand this language¬†‚Äî¬†bird-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> species of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterfly</ENAMEX> have been identified here, and as many different <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>.
Other country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> running south from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patan</ENAMEX> pass <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>- and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-story narrow brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> bunched close together in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Newari</ENAMEX> fashion. A stroll through any of these hamlets, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bungamati, Thecho</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapagaon</ENAMEX>, will provide intimate glimpses of country life. Stroll with care, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">however¬†‚Äî¬†the</ENAMEX> back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">paths</ENAMEX> are heavily fertilized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> as well as by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.
Thimi, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bhaktapur</ENAMEX>, is where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">papier-m√</ENAMEX>¢ch√© masks are made and sold. On this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, too, are attractive pottery flowerpots in the shape of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX>. Thimi‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> often become open-air kilns, when pots are fired beneath smoldering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice straw</ENAMEX>. Festivals in these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>, if you can find the right <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">day and hour</TIMEX>, are even more riotous and welcoming than those in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> north from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> leads <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 miles</NUMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Budhanilkantha</ENAMEX>, and a giant statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vishnu</ENAMEX> reclining on a bed of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX>. Carved from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> and set in a sunken <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tank</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5-m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>-ft) image dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the seventh century</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Legend</ENAMEX> has it that as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vishnu</ENAMEX> floated partly submerged in the primeval ocean, a lotus grew out of his navel, issuing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brahma</ENAMEX>, whose sole task was to create the world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> cannot visit this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX>, as to look upon what is considered to be an image of himself, an incarnation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vishnu</ENAMEX>, would be a forecast of death. On festival <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> worshippers blanket the statue with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>. Beyond is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shivapuri Watershed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wildlife Preserve</ENAMEX>, good place for a day hike.
If there is any one spot outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> that is a must, it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Changu Narayan</ENAMEX>. The oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> in the valley and unquestionably one of the most interesting, it sits on an isolated hilltop <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few miles</NUMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhaktapur</ENAMEX> and just south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sankhu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. The drive from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhaktapur</ENAMEX> cuts across paddies and climbs past thickets of bamboo to the ridge top. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A misty morning</TIMEX> makes the scene even more evocative of the past.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> is in the center of a walled enclosure, with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">treasury</ENAMEX> of small sculptures and shrines dotted about. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of several masterpieces dedicated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vishnu</ENAMEX> is a broken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighth-century</TIMEX> stone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Licchavi</ENAMEX> work. There is a lovely <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifth-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garuda</ENAMEX>, and near it, on a memorial pillar, the earliest historical document in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>, an inscription of the same period concerning the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Licchavi King Manadeva</ENAMEX>. Doors, niches, struts, and cornices are superbly decorated, yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> and compound retain a human dimension and are not overwhelming.
Beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>
While there is plenty to see within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu Valley</ENAMEX>, beyond the valley lies a different, more natural, and less polluted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>.
Nagarkot, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dhulikhel</ENAMEX>, and Kodari
From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, short trips to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">valley</ENAMEX> rim make it possible for those with limited time to see the high mountains at sunrise or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">sunset</ENAMEX>.
Nagarkot, which stands on the crest of a ridge at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,195</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7,200 ft</NUMEX>), is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about an hour‚Äôs</NUMEX> drive from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhaktapur</ENAMEX> and one of the best places in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> area for viewing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayas</ENAMEX>. From this aerie on the rim of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu Valley</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">322 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 miles</NUMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayas</ENAMEX> stretch out before you in an immense wall of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. Although there are excellent views from the many lodges and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> here, the view is even better from a nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">observation tower</ENAMEX>, which can be reached in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour‚</TIMEX>Äôs walk from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nagarkot</ENAMEX>. From this observation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>, it is possible to see as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Everest</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> come for the sunrise or sunset on the mountains, and though the weather is often at its clearest in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early morning</TIMEX>, low clouds and fog often obstruct the view.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> area‚Äôs other popular mountain-viewing spot is the village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dhulikhel</ENAMEX>, which has a view very similar to that from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nagarkot</ENAMEX> and is a bit easier to reach, since it is on the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>. This highway passes through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banepa</ENAMEX>, where you can turn off to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panauti</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> here have great artistic and historic importance and for this reason have become the focus of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>-funded restoration project. Today, this out-of-the-way village offers a fascinating glimpse into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu Valley‚</ENAMEX>Äôs small-town life. Dhulikhel, on the other hand, is strictly about mountain views. Here there are several attractive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with tropical gardens, that cater to visitors hoping to catch a glimpse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayas</ENAMEX> at sunrise or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">sunset</ENAMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dawn and dusk</TIMEX>, the otherwise perfectly spectacular mountains are made just that much more breathtaking as they are painted in shades of lavender and pink by the rising and setting sun.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dhulikhel</ENAMEX> drops precipitously, then turns up the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sun Kosi River</ENAMEX> gorge toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> border. After the hot-spring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tatopani</ENAMEX>, the walls of the gorge draw closer and closer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> (landslides often close the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>) until the customs post at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodari</ENAMEX> is reached. Although it is sometimes possible to enter <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> at this border crossing, it is much easier to fly from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lhasa</ENAMEX> and then travel overland back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. To make such a trip you will need either a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> visa or a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>-tour permit for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX> and Gorkha
Some <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">124 miles</NUMEX>) west of the capital by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX> by air, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX> is a major staging point for treks and one of the fastest-growing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Almost as spectacular as the flight to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everest</ENAMEX>, the air route to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> in the opposite direction, paralleling the high mountains toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Annapurna</ENAMEX>. Below, all signs of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> disappear, and it is clear how difficult road-building is in this tortuous terrain. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">900 m</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,000 ft</NUMEX>), is almost tropical, with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX>, papayas, and poinsettias growing in gardens. The contrast makes the stunning views of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX>-capped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Machhapuchhare</TIMEX>, the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúFish Tail‚</ENAMEX>Äù peak dubbed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúNepalese Matterhorn</ENAMEX>,‚Äù all the more marvelous.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pokhara</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phewa Lake</ENAMEX>, has the best views for the least expended energy of any location in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakeside</ENAMEX> neighborhood, jammed with cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, is where most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Westerners congregate</ENAMEX> to rent <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX>, shop for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> wares that are sometimes cheaper here than in the capital, and drink cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, there are several luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, and one of these, on the lake itself, is reached by a hand-drawn ferry. This is a starting and ending point for trekkers, and as such is filled with a mix of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in anxious anticipation of their impending adventure and those who have recently returned from exhausting treks. Everyone seems content to fill up on cakes and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pies</ENAMEX>. Day hikes are a popular activity here, with the most popular hike being that to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarangkot</ENAMEX> to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dhaulagiri</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annapurnas</ENAMEX> from the viewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>. Other good walks include a visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> refugee <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tashiling</ENAMEX> and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Stupa</ENAMEX> atop the forested hill on the south side of the lake. You can also take a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> out on the lake or walk to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Devin‚Äôs Fall</ENAMEX>, where a river disappears underground into a steamy hole. While most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> look on this as a staging point for a trek, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX> is such a beautiful spot that it can be quite enough just to relax and enjoy the mountain scenery in the warm sunshine.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> follows the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Seti River</ENAMEX> for much of the way. A side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> makes it easy to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gorkha</ENAMEX>, ancestral seat of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Shah dynasty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> from which the unification of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> was begun. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prithvi Narayan Shah‚</ENAMEX>Äôs large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> here has been restored by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>-carvers, and you can climb for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX> up to the stronghold, which is now inhabited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>. Looking out of a window onto the panorama of high mountains and wave upon wave of rolling hills, one can imagine the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> saying to himself ‚ÄúThis must be my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>.‚Äù In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> Maoist activity in the area has limited the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gorkha</ENAMEX>.
Chitwan, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lumbini</ENAMEX>, and the Terai
Chitwan, ‚ÄúHeart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jungle‚</ENAMEX>Äù in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX>, is a tropical forest on the southern border with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. This is the haunt of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bengal tiger</ENAMEX>, of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> of the world‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of rare <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-horned rhinos, and of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 400</NUMEX> species of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amazingly</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>-back at the jungle‚Äôs edge you can see the snowcapped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Himalayas</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less than 160 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 miles</NUMEX>) away and looming like a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foam</ENAMEX>-crested wave. (No <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on earth has such a great range in altitude, from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">150 m/500 ft to the 8,848 m/29,028 ft</NUMEX> summit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everest</ENAMEX>.) And this pristine wildlife reserve is within easy reach by air and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>.
Once the private hunting ground of royalty and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chitwan</ENAMEX> became a national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> and has been designated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unesco</ENAMEX> as a World Heritage Site. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Chitwan National Park</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">932 sq km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">358 sq miles</NUMEX>) of magnificent <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">trees¬†‚Äî¬†the</ENAMEX> tall hardwood sal, the kapok ‚Äúsilk-cotton‚<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Äù tree</ENAMEX>, and the flame-of- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the</NUMEX>-forest with their spectacular crimson <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, plus ferns, bamboo, and huge vines that choke trees to death like pythons. And there are real pythons, too. White-ruffed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">langur monkeys leap</ENAMEX> and swing in the treetops, sending flights of green <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parakeets screeching</ENAMEX>. In open glades, peacocks preen, and shy, tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">barking deer</ENAMEX>, no taller than the peacocks, race away at an intruder‚Äôs approach. It‚Äôs a magical environment.
The best way to see the wildlife, and certainly the most fun, is swaying atop a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">silently padding elephant</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX> grass along the several rivers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> is so tall that only from an elephant‚Äôs back can you spot rhinos, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX>, most of which are used to seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> and do not run from them. With luck, you‚Äôll see a leopard draped <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">indolently</ENAMEX> on a tree <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>, and perhaps a stately <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sambar stag</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>, the gaur, the world‚Äôs largest wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ox</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6 ft</ENAMEX>) high at the shoulder, comes out of its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hideaway</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Siwalik Hills</ENAMEX> on the park‚Äôs southern edge in search of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX>. Spotted <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX>, sloth bear, giant flying squirrels, and civet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> are among the other mammals the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> may see.
There are several jungle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lodges</ENAMEX> and tented <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> within the park‚Äôs boundaries, and from any of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> there is a very high likelihood that you will see rhinos and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tigers</ENAMEX>, leopards, and sloth <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bears</ENAMEX> are a bit more elusive. All of these lodges, and even some outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, have their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> and nature guides. On a stay at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these lodges, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half day</TIMEX> is usually spent in dug-out canoes searching for endangered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gharials</ENAMEX>, a narrow jawed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>-eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crocodile</ENAMEX>, and their flesh-eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX>, the huge marsh muggers. However, these canoe rides actually focus on the more visible bird life along the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">river banks¬†‚Äî¬†egrets</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX>, storks, kingfishers, eagles, and scores of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fascinating birds</ENAMEX>. The rare, almost sightless <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gangetic dolphin</ENAMEX> may even come up for a blow alongside your canoe if you are extremely lucky. At day‚Äôs end, lodge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> compare notes around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> during a stay, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> from a nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tharu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> will perform their traditional martial arts-like stick dance.
Along the park boundary and especially at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sauraha</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park headquarters</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of lodges and inexpensive guest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> cater to budget-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Elephant rides</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">jeep tours</ENAMEX>, and canoe trips can all be arranged at the park entrance, where an interesting interpretive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> provides a history of the area and information about its ecology. One is reminded that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>, during a safari arranged for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Viceroy of India</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> took part in a hunt that bagged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> rhinos, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> leopards. Today, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> are stationed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> to keep out poachers.
Package tours, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three nights</TIMEX> in or near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, are widely offered by travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>. You can fly to an airstrip near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX>, go by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about six hours</TIMEX>, or spend a day or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> paddling the rapids of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Trisuli River</ENAMEX> en route.
Travel by road provides a glimpse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terai</ENAMEX>, an extension of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ganges Plain</ENAMEX>. This well-watered farming zone stretches the length of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on its southern border with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only about 40 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 miles</NUMEX>) wide, but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nepal‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> lives here, producing much of the nation‚Äôs food.
A visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lumbini</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gautama Buddha</ENAMEX>, can also be made in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about three hours</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chitwan</ENAMEX>. (There are also flights from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bhairawa</ENAMEX>, the nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airfield</ENAMEX>, with a bus service to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lumbini.</ENAMEX>) The story goes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddha‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> gave birth to him under a tree in a garden at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lumbini</ENAMEX>, unable to get back in time to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>, some <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12 miles</NUMEX>) away. Marking the spot is a pillar commemorating the visit in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">250 b.c.</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashoka</ENAMEX>, a zealous convert to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> pilgrims from all over the world come to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lumbini</ENAMEX>, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> the site has been developed into an international cultural and religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> with several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> temples built by the world‚Äôs various <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
Although few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> stray from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX>-Chitwan focal points, it is possible to see something of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">undeveloped</NUMEX> west without walking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> to get there. There are now several lodges at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Royal Bardia National Park</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Karnali River</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> was created specifically as a preserve for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX>, which, with a little luck, can be seen here more easily than at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chitwan National Park</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Elephant rides</ENAMEX>, jungle walks and drives, river rafting, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>-watching keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> busy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karnali</ENAMEX> gorge above <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chisopani</ENAMEX> is especially beautiful and is noted for the size of the fighting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mahseer</ENAMEX> carp taken by sport <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX>.



