



What to Do
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outdoor Activities and Sports</ENAMEX>
Trekking
There is nothing to compare with the experience of hiking through a world without automobiles. This is just the experience to be had trekking in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX>, life unfolds at a slower pace, unaffected by Y2K <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bugs</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">dot-com</ENAMEX> stocks. It is the chance to leave behind the hurried and harried pace of today‚Äôs modern world that makes trekking in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> such a memorable experience. The fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nation‚Äôs trails</ENAMEX> wander among the highest mountains on earth and pass through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> of numerous ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> only adds to what is in effect a step (make that many, many steps) back in time.
It‚Äôs difficult for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> to grasp that not only is most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> still beyond the reach of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, but that there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up in those hills as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mountain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> take you to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>, not to wilderness as they would in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alps</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rockies</ENAMEX>, and just about every village <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> seems to have several lodges offering refreshments, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, and lodging. In fact, on the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annapurna Circuit</ENAMEX> it seems in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> that every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is a lodge, and even where there are no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> there are sometimes lodges. What this means for trekkers is that there are plenty of options for lodge-to-lodge treks. However, for the full trekking experience, nothing can substitute for the fully-catered tenting trek, which is patterned on the first Everest expeditions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>.
Planning and Preparation
There are basically <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> styles of trekking. You can book through a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that will plan your itinerary and provide everything: from down jackets, sleeping bags, and food and drink to sirdar (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">porters</ENAMEX> who will set up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX> at campsites. Alternatively, you can hire a guide and/or porter and do a lodge-to-lodge trek, which involves very little planning and allows you to do your hiking with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only a light</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX> on your back. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">last¬†‚Äî¬†and cheapest¬†‚Äî</ENAMEX> alternative is to carry your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX> and strike out with a good trekking guidebook but no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> or porter. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who opt for this latter type of trek stay in the numerous and increasingly more comfortable trailside lodges that can be found on the major trekking routes. By staying in lodges, you avoid having to carry a tent, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, or cooking gear. A luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trek</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> category might cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> or more per day per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. Hiring a guide and porter will lower your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> costs to somewhere around <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>, while going it alone (meaning without a guide, as trekking without any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> should not be attempted) can be done for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $10</NUMEX> a day.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> are the most popular trekking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> because they are warm and sunny, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> are dry after the monsoon. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> is good for low-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">treks</ENAMEX>, though it will be getting cold at higher altitudes. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter months</TIMEX> bring the clearest skies. Spring comes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March and April</TIMEX>, when rhododendrons and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> set the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">forests ablaze</ENAMEX> with color. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> the skies gradually become hazy and there are light <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rains</ENAMEX>, which can make flights to starting points unpredictable. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> it is hot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX>, the high peaks are rarely visible, and humidity mounts until the weather breaks in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, with the onset of the monsoon. Trails during the monsoon are muddy, slippery, and leech-ridden, which makes trekking between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June and October</TIMEX> a miserable experience. It is possible to fly to higher elevations where <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">leeches</ENAMEX> are less of a problem, but the rainclouds make mountain flights particularly dangerous.
Deciding where to go will depend on the time available and your physical condition. Serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trekkers</ENAMEX> usually plan on spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two to three weeks</TIMEX> or more on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five days</TIMEX> to a week is about the minimum to have a fair sampling of trekking life (though only after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> do you get your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äútrail legs‚Äù</ENAMEX>). Shorter outings around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu Valley</ENAMEX> or the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">‚ÄúRoyal Trek‚Äô‚</ENAMEX>Äô out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX> (which was followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX>) afford great mountain views in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> and are not to be disdained.
Once your route is decided, you‚Äôll need to get a national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> or conservation area permit (depending on where you are trekking). These are obtainable at special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX> (or, for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional</NUMEX> charge, through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX> trekking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>).
When you receive your recommended immunizations (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX>), you should have a physical as well. Also, you‚Äôll enjoy your trek much more if, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> prior to hitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX>, you pursue a structured athletic training program. Walking or jogging <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several miles</NUMEX> a day is good (and even better if you‚Äôve got some hills or stairs to climb); the stair machines at fitness <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> are also useful for developing your quadriceps (thigh muscles).
Renting equipment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> is easy. There are numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">outfitters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thamel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX> offering a wide variety of new and used hiking, camping, and mountaineering gear. However, keep in mind that there is no substitute for your own tried-and-true equipment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trekking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> should be seen as a place to pick up things you might have forgotten, since rental jackets and sleeping bags are not always in the best condition. A deposit will be required for rentals. Also keep in mind that much of the new name-brand outdoor gear for sale in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> is actually counterfeit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">label</ENAMEX> may say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lowe</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Face</ENAMEX>, but don‚Äôt count on the item being genuine.
Several excellent guidebooks to trekking in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> are available. Also, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX> there are numerous trekking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that can help you plan your trip. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trekking companions</ENAMEX> and recommendations of guides and porters, consult notice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu‚Äôs Thamel</ENAMEX> neighborhood or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pokhara‚Äôs Lakeside</ENAMEX> neighborhood.
On the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Trail</ENAMEX>
Trekking isn‚Äôt mountain climbing, but it also isn‚Äôt just a stroll in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> walking, with lots of uphills and downhills. Almost anyone can go trekking, though a trek is definitely more enjoyable if you‚Äôre reasonably fit. Sure there are lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> on the trail who seem to be here merely for the challenge, but you‚Äôll also come across <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of the less physically fit, including school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> from the international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> and organized senior citizens‚Äô treks, going happily along at their own pace.
As you hike, whether with a fully loaded backpack or just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a light daypack</NUMEX>, you can‚Äôt help marveling at the burdens that porters carry in their dokos (baskets). Everything not made or grown in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> has to he packed in on the backs of wiry, barefoot porters, who carry loads of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as much as 60 kg</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">130 pounds</NUMEX>). Even more amazing is the fact that these baskets have no shoulder straps but only tump lines (forehead straps). You may notice that going downhill, porters take short steps on the balls of their feet with their knees bent. Do the same and you‚Äôll avoid the common complaint of ‚Äútrekker‚Äôs knee.‚Äù
Along the way you‚Äôll see hill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working their terraced fields of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">maize</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">barley</ENAMEX>, buckwheat, millet, and, in the high country, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffaloes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX> are milked, and millet is threshed by pounding the stalks on the threshing floor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls troop</ENAMEX> to and from water taps with their water jars, while small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> slung in baskets under the thatched eaves of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>-walled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Grain</ENAMEX> is taken to water-driven <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX> for grinding, or in some cases is ground between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> flat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> or pounded in a mortar by a foot-operated rocker-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam pestle</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> numerous hydroelectric projects throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annapurna</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Solu-Khumbu</ENAMEX> regions have brought moderately reliable electricity to remote <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>. However, this electricity is usually only available for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours in the evening</TIMEX>. With electricity available, it is now possible to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> (via satellite dish) from a remote lodge many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">days‚Äô</ENAMEX> walk from the nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>.
If you are trekking in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Annapurna</ENAMEX> region, you will at times have to give way to caravans of ponies, mules, and donkeys crowned with red and white yak-tail plumes. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Khumbu</ENAMEX> region, it will be caravans of yaks themselves (or yak-cow cross breeds) carrying the packs. Give the yaks a wide berth, and always stay on the uphill side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX> as they pass.
There are many exciting moments: you look way up at a towering white cloud and discover that there‚Äôs a mountain emerging from the top of it; you inch across a swaying bridge of planks hung from cables over a churning river; or there‚Äôs a booming sound, and high on a mountain face an avalanche appears to roll along in slow motion as it roars down <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousands of feet</NUMEX>. And there‚Äôs delight in bathing your hot feet in a shady brook, or stretching out for a break on a rock <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> where porters rest their packs.
The first sight of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Everest</ENAMEX> close up can never be forgotten. It‚Äôs the top of the world! But the towering tooth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ama Dablam</ENAMEX> above the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thyangboche Monastery</ENAMEX>, the forked fishtail summit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machhapuchhare</ENAMEX>, the solid block of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dhaulagiri</ENAMEX>, the tent-shaped black rock atop <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annapurna II</ENAMEX>, and the gleaming white of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Langtang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gauri Shankar</ENAMEX>, as well as other peaks whose names you‚Äôll never know, each have their own awesome quality. A mighty power and grandeur emanates from these great mountains, holy to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who live in their shadow.
Whether you‚Äôre trekking on your own or on an organized camping excursion, you‚Äôll want to have a good contour map. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>, distances on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX> are measured not in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles or kilometers</NUMEX> but in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> from place to place. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Trekking</ENAMEX> routes often wind in and out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">gorges</ENAMEX> and deep river valleys, which involves much ascending and descending of steep <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX>, often stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">staircases</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> that seem close on the map may actually be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of climbing apart.
A typical day on an organized camping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trek</ENAMEX> begins around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6am</TIMEX> with a mug of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> outside your tent as the first rays of sun hit the high peaks above you. Breakfast might be a bowl of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porridge</ENAMEX> or toast and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>. After a bit of a wash-up from a basin of warm <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, you‚Äôll be on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7am</TIMEX>. No need to worry about packing up the tent or cleaning the breakfast dishes: that‚Äôs what you‚Äôve hired the porters to do.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porters</ENAMEX> stop for their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> real meal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">day¬†‚Äî¬†rice</ENAMEX> and lentils¬†‚Äî¬†between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 and 11am</TIMEX>, and consequently, trekkers can also expect to eat lunch fairly early, usually on the edge of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> or at a scenic vista. After a bit of exploration in the area, there will be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few more hours</TIMEX> of hiking before calling it quits for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3pm</TIMEX>, once again usually in an interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>. The porters will then busy themselves with setting up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, usually in a designated campground, and preparing the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening meal</TIMEX>. The sun often goes behind the mountains early, and supper always follows soon after sunset, usually around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6pm</TIMEX>. With only kerosene lamps to keep away the dark, exhausted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trekkers</ENAMEX> usually head for bed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9pm</TIMEX>.
For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trekkers</ENAMEX> doing a lodge-to-lodge trek, the day‚Äôs schedule is slightly different. There is usually no ‚Äúbed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>,‚Äù but there might be a wide range of choices for breakfast (many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lodges</ENAMEX> now have electric ovens, and fresh baked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">breads</ENAMEX> and rolls are all the rage).
If trekking with a porter, it is wise to get as early a start as possible, since your porter will want to stop for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch around 10 or 11am</TIMEX>. Also, the later you stop for lunch, the longer you will usually have to wait for a meal, since trailside lodges usually have dal bhat (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> and lentils) ready shortly after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10am</TIMEX>. Stop any later than this and they‚Äôll have to make yours from scratch, which can easily take an hour or more. Rest breaks along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX> are often at lodges, where <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a cup</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk tea</ENAMEX> or hot lemon provide a bit of welcome rehydration.
During the main trekking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX>, it is wise to stop for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day between 2 and 3pm</TIMEX>. Stop any later than that and you risk finding the best lodges completely full. After spreading out your sleeping bag in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, you should put in an order for dinner, specifying when you would like it served. Although the presence of electricity in many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> along the main trekking routes means that trekkers often stay up later than in the past, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are so exhausted after a day of trekking that they head for bed around 9pm anyway.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the few unpleasant aspects of trekking is the prevalence of begging along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX>. In almost every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village trekkers</ENAMEX> enter, they are almost immediately greeted by sometimes very insistent (even belligerent) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> shouting out ‚Äúone pen, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> rupee, one sweet.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äô‚Äô Trekkers</ENAMEX> are urged not to give in to their insistent demands; this begging is due to trekkers in the past indiscriminately handing out gifts to the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> often grow up to depend on more sophisticated forms of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">begging ¬†‚Äî¬†when</ENAMEX> you stop for a glass of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> or a soft <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX>, you may be asked to make a donation to a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>-building <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX>. You‚Äôll be shown a notebook full of the names of previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> and the amounts they donated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> also likely be asked to perform emergency first aid on local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villagers</ENAMEX>, but aside from putting a bandage and disinfectant on someone‚Äôs cut, you may just want to direct the injured and infirm to the nearest health post, unless you have a medical background, can adequately diagnose the problem, and have the appropriate remedy handy.
Staying properly hydrated is perhaps the most difficult thing on a trek. Carry a canteen and some iodine or a two-stage water filter (one that iodizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>), and try to drink <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> quarts (liters) of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> a day to avoid dehydration. Alternatively, taking lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> breaks and ordering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> by the pot rather than just by the glass will help to keep plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquids</ENAMEX> in you. Avoid buying the bottled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> sold along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX>. The plastic bottles this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> comes in have become the most prevalent form of litter along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, and to make things even worse, they are sometimes just refilled from a nearby water tap and resold to unsuspecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trekkers</ENAMEX>.
If you are on an organized trek, carry plenty of small rupee notes in case you want to buy some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>, or some other snack or souvenir along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX>. If you are doing a lodge-to-lodge trek, carry plenty of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 50</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> rupee notes.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popular</ENAMEX> Treks
Solu-Khumbu: the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Everest region</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> days‚<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Äì3 weeks</TIMEX>). The shortest possible trek for a close view of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Everest</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sherpa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sagarmatha National Park</ENAMEX> is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-day</TIMEX> dash with round-trip flights between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukla</ENAMEX>. The trail goes up the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dudh Kosi river valley</ENAMEX> through lovely woodlands with an overnight at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phakding</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jorsale</ENAMEX>. The next night is at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Namche Bazaar</ENAMEX>, where there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherpa</ENAMEX> market on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX>. Return is by the same route with an added <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukla</ENAMEX> to be on hand for one of the (often cancelled) <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early morning</TIMEX> flights back.
Add <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> for the interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">switchback</ENAMEX> walk from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Namche</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thyangboche Monastery</ENAMEX> and back, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten days</TIMEX> for the circuit that goes on to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pheriche, Lobuje, Gorak Shep</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kala Patar</ENAMEX> for one of the greatest of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Himalayan</ENAMEX> views. It is also possible to continue on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Everest Base Camp</ENAMEX> area at an exhausting <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5,360 m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">17,586 ft</NUMEX>), although there is not much to see at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base camp</ENAMEX> (no view of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everest</ENAMEX>). Add <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another week</TIMEX> (for a total of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 to 21 days</TIMEX>) if you hike in from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiri</ENAMEX> (reachable from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> by bus or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX>) and then fly out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukla</ENAMEX>. Add yet another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 days</TIMEX> if you walk back out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiri</ENAMEX>.
Around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annapurna</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1‚Äì3</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>). Fly to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ghandruk</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dhampus</ENAMEX>. This route provides superb views of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macchapuchhare</ENAMEX>, the spectacular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fishtail Peak</ENAMEX>. Continue to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ghorapani</ENAMEX>, which sits high above the valley of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kali Gandaki River</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Separating Dhaulagiri</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Annapurna 1</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kali Gandaki</ENAMEX> forms the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">world‚Äôs deepest valley</ENAMEX>. Return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five to six days</TIMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poon Hill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birethanti</ENAMEX>. Or add <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten days</TIMEX> round-trip and continue from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghorapani</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tatopani</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muktinath</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thakali</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> along the old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX>-trade route to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>.
Add <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days</TIMEX> round-trip from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghandruk</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Annapurna Sanctuary</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,960 m</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,990</NUMEX> ft) on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX> that leads up the valley of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modi Khola</ENAMEX>. The circuit around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annapurna</ENAMEX> takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 days</TIMEX>, and includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jomosom</ENAMEX> route, a stretch of arid <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northern Himalaya</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mustang</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5,416-m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17,770</NUMEX>-ft) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thorong La</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thorong Pass</ENAMEX>).
Langtang, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gosainkund</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helambu</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1‚Äì2</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>). From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, take a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or bus up the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Trisuli River valley</ENAMEX> (an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> in itself) to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dhunche</ENAMEX>, the entrance to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Langtang National Park</ENAMEX> (there is a small fee to enter, so keep the ticket: it may be requested en route). Making overnight stops at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syabru, Chongong</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Langtang Village</ENAMEX>, you reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Langtang Valley</ENAMEX>, where there are lodges and campsites near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyanjin Gompa</ENAMEX> (at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,800 m/12,467 ft</NUMEX>) and also a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> set up with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> aid. From here you can explore the yak pastures and glaciers beneath snowy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Langtang Lirung</ENAMEX>. An alternative route leads past the sacred <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Gosainkund</ENAMEX> lakes to link with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helambu</ENAMEX> circuit for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a two-week</TIMEX> trek.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Helambu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX> begins at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sundarijal</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> ride from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, rises through forests to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pati Bhanjyang</ENAMEX>, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three more days</TIMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malemchigaon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarke Gyang</ENAMEX>. The return can be via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dhunche</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sundarijal</ENAMEX>, depending on how long a bus ride you wish to endure at the end of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trek</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trekking Tips</ENAMEX>
Good hiking boots are the most important equipment for trekkers. Although some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trek in running shoes and even flip-flops (and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">porters</ENAMEX> go barefoot), it is advisable to wear sturdy hiking boots with lug soles and especially solid ankle support. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> pair of athletic shoes or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">river sandals</ENAMEX> can be packed for changing into at day‚Äôs end. A light pair of sock liners covered by heavier woolen socks or a pair of high-tech sweat-wicking sports socks make for comfort going up- and downhill. Be sure to have a roll of moleskin or adhesive plaster to put on your heels or other friction spots before blisters form, and to make a cushioned pad around any blister. Tight pants, such as blue jeans, can make for very uncomfortable climbing. Looser pants, shorts, or, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, a calf-length loose skirt (such skirts are widely sold in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX>) are recommended. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> also need extra socks (keep a dry pair separate for putting on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the end of the day</TIMEX>), a couple of changes of pants and shirts, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> sweater or synthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fleece</ENAMEX> jacket, and a down jacket.
Take a flashlight (torch), binoculars, sun hat and sunscreen, sunglasses, water bottle, and pocket <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX>. In your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">backpack</ENAMEX> carry a first-aid kit with disinfectant, gauze pads and adhesive tape, elastic bandage (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ace Bandage</ENAMEX>) for sprains, insect repellent, tincture of iodine to sterilize <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> drops to a liter), throat lozenges, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspirin</ENAMEX>, a small pair of scissors, safety pins, and a thermometer. Get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> to prescribe a treatment for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diarrhea</ENAMEX> and a wide-spectrum <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibiotic</ENAMEX>. You may be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many days</TIMEX> from the nearest medical care and will have to doctor yourself and possibly others.
Be aware of the symptoms of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Acute Mountain Sickness</ENAMEX> (AMS), which can become lethal suddenly. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayan Rescue Association</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jyatha Street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thamel</ENAMEX>) advises that headache and breathlessness at any altitude above <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,800 m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6,000 ft</NUMEX>) may be a sign of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMS</ENAMEX>. At altitudes above <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,000 m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10,000 ft</NUMEX>), ascents should not exceed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">300 m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,000 ft</NUMEX>) a day, or a day of rest and acclimatization should be taken before continuing. If symptoms persist, it is essential to descend as quickly as possible, even if it‚<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Äôs night</TIMEX>. Results will be dramatic. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMS</ENAMEX> can hit anyone, even the most fit.
There are few telephones or radios from which messages may be sent in the mountains or where medical help can be found. Find out where these may be on your route. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helicopters</ENAMEX> may be chartered from various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> at the princely sum of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $2000</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX>, payable in advance. It can take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as much as 24 hours</TIMEX>, including time for the message to get through, for a rescue to be arranged. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porters</ENAMEX> can also carry a sick or injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
Register with your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> and let them know where you‚Äôre going and when, and do not trek alone; find a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> through a trekking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or by posting a notice on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the many bulletin boards in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thamel</ENAMEX>.
White-Water Rafting
For <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart</ENAMEX>-in-the-mouth thrills it is hard to beat white-water rafting on the tumultuous snow-fed rivers of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. Although trekking is still the favored outdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> here, rafting is a close <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rafting</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> come specifically to paddle this country‚Äôs challenging waters, which roar through some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">world‚Äôs deepest gorges</ENAMEX>. The knowledge that even the best rafters sometimes capsize in these currents keeps the adrenaline flowing as fast as the river.
Although there are some easy floats on the lowland rivers, the majority of rafting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> is on Class III through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Class‚ÄÇV</ENAMEX> waters, not ideal for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neophytes</ENAMEX>. However, plenty of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-timers do get out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> during their stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. Rafts usually carry <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> plus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> guides, and the typical rafting trip includes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> spent camping on the riverbank, with the rafting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> setting up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and preparing all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX>. Rafters spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX> before lunch riding the rapids and enjoying the spectacular scenery, followed by a leisurely lunch (often with a fire to warm shivering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>). After lunch, it‚Äôs more rapids and scenery before stopping early enough to set up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>.
The most popular rafting excursions are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>- and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX> trips down the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Trisuli River</ENAMEX>, which empties out of the hills not far from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Chitwan National Park</ENAMEX>, and thus is favored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> heading there in search of rhinos and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bears</ENAMEX>. This river consists primarily of Class III and Class <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV rapids</ENAMEX>, becoming gentler the farther down the river you get. Although rafting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will tell you that you don‚Äôt need any experience to raft this river, a boatload of inexperienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paddlers</ENAMEX> can easily have problems. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trisuli</ENAMEX> parallels the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terai</ENAMEX>, this is not a wilderness trip.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seti</ENAMEX>, which flows from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX> to merge with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trisuli</ENAMEX>, is an easier river, perfect for beginners. This river offers <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Class II</ENAMEX> and Class III rapids, but because there is no road alongside the river, it has more of a remote feel. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> even has a deluxe lodge along this river, so its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> don‚Äôt have to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> out during an overnight trip. Trips down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seti</ENAMEX> usually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last three days</TIMEX>.
Expedition-level rivers include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karnali</ENAMEX>, which requires a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX> trek just to reach the put-in point, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sun Kosi</ENAMEX>, which involves <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8 days</TIMEX> on the river. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Expert paddlers head</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhote Kosi</ENAMEX>, which is almost non-stop Class V rapids. In the past the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kali Gandaki</ENAMEX> was very popular, but much of the best whitewater on this river has now been flooded beneath the waters behind a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dam</ENAMEX>.
Important things to keep in mind include picking a reliable rafting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that uses new self-baling rafts and that provides good helmets and life jackets. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Himalayan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> are cold, be sure to wear thermal underwear or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> (some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> provide wetsuits as well) since you will be soaking wet for most of your trip (your minimal gear gets stuffed in a water-tight barrel). Old sneakers or rafting sandals with good straps are ideal footwear.
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outdoor Activities and Sports</ENAMEX>
Fishing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fishermen</ENAMEX> can get a good fight out of the mahseer, a giant <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">river carp</ENAMEX> weighing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up to 40 kg</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">90 pounds</NUMEX>), found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karnali, Gandaki</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sun Kosi</ENAMEX> rivers.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf/Swimming/Tennis</ENAMEX>. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two nine</NUMEX>-hole golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>, one near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dusit Thani Fulbari Resort Hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX>. Golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> can be rented at both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>. All the five-star <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> have swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> and most have tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>.
Mountain biking. Mountain-bike tours are available through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kathmandu‚Äôs Thamel</ENAMEX> neighborhood and in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pokhara‚Äôs Lakeside</ENAMEX> neighborhood. It is possible to rent first-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX>, and tours of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">anywhere from half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> are available. An accompanying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">van</ENAMEX> carries camping gear and luggage.
Pony trekking. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX> there are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that offer pony rides, both day trips and overnight rides.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
What to Buy
Bring a spare lightweight bag (or plan to buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> here; <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">they‚Äôre</ENAMEX> quite inexpensive) to hold all the gifts you won‚Äôt be able to resist buying in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. There is something for everyone on your list.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiques</ENAMEX>. The export of religious antiquities from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> is prohibited. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Authentic Nepali</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antiques</ENAMEX> are increasingly rare, and are therefore quite expensive. They are subject to customs restrictions, so get a certificate from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> and, if you are at all in doubt, also from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Antiquities</ENAMEX> to avoid confiscation of your purchase upon departure.
Carpets. Hand-woven wool carpets, many of them made by the large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugee community</ENAMEX>, are the single best shopping value in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. Carpets of a size that can easily be transported <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in checked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">luggage</ENAMEX> are readily available.
Clothing. Offerings include embroidered T-shirts, cotton dresses, knitted wool sweaters, socks, and mittens, and velvet jesters‚Äô hats. Imitation outdoor gear sporting fake labels is not a good buy; it tends to fall apart quickly.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khukuris</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ornate</ENAMEX>, curved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gurkha</ENAMEX> knives.
Jewelry is made with semi-precious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tibet¬†‚Äî¬†turquoise</ENAMEX>, coral, amethyst, amber, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">garnets¬†‚Äî¬†set</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> bracelets and amulets.
Masks. Grimacing papier-m√¢ch√© demon faces from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thimi</ENAMEX> and carved wooden masks from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are generally made strictly for the tourist trade.
Metal housewares include <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX> and brass water pots, water <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX>, cups, and other common household items. Sometimes old pieces are available.
Shawls are made of fine, feather-light cashmere and pashmina. Watch out for synthetic ones, which aren‚Äôt as warm.
Statuettes of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">deities</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bronze</ENAMEX> or carved in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>.
Tibetan artifacts range from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX> prayer wheels to cups made from human skulls to long copper horns, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>-lined wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> bowls, fur hats, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">brass ‚Äúsinging bowls‚Äù</ENAMEX> that resonate when their rim is rubbed in a circular motion.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thangkas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minutely</ENAMEX> detailed paintings on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> religious themes or representing the ‚Äúwheel of life‚Äù are hand-painted by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Newari</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>.
Bargaining is expected and even a modest show of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> will usually bring a small discount quickly. Serious, drawn-out bargaining can earn substantial reductions. Competition among street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> is stiff, but it is worth remembering that most of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> are relatively poor, and spending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX> to extract <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few rupees</NUMEX> discount is perhaps not the best use of your time. Don‚Äôt expect <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopkeepers</ENAMEX> to bargain much at all.
Where to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shop</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> in the area around <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kathmandu‚Äôs Durbar Square</ENAMEX> will give you a good idea of the variety and prices available. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basantapur Chowk</ENAMEX>, as well as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace wall</ENAMEX> facing the temples in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>, the khukuris, prayer wheels, figurines, and grotesque masks are spread on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pavement</ENAMEX> for your inspection. Around the walled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taleju</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, thangka paintings are displayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX>.
The crowded, narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> leading diagonally from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Durbar Square</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indra Chowk</ENAMEX> is the main shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nepalis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX> selling topis, the jaunty, colored caps worn by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in the valley, as well as the black ones that are a must for civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>. All sorts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass pots</ENAMEX> are heaped in doorways. Knit sweaters and small rugs hang like laundry overhead. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indra Chowk</ENAMEX> is the center for blankets, shawls, and sari fabrics. Thamel, however, is ground <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> for curio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbar Marg</ENAMEX> leading to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Narayanhiti Palace</ENAMEX> has, in addition to the street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, a number of good jewelry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> selling interesting earrings and bangles. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tibetan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antiques</ENAMEX> can be found here, but be prepared for high prices.
On the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> that leads from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patan</ENAMEX> there are several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> selling handicrafts from different parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Most of these have been set up by international aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> to directly benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> of the handicrafts, usually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> from rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>, and many of them are operated as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cooperatives</ENAMEX>. Among the most popular items in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> are hand-made paper products (including notecards and notebooks) made with the bark of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> of daphne <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is often block-printed, as are fabrics used for everything from placemats to dresses.
The best place for carpets with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, or contemporary designs is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugee</ENAMEX> cooperative in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jawalakhel</ENAMEX> on the outskirts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patan</ENAMEX>. You can watch them being made here; the prices are fixed and shipment can be arranged on the spot. On the farther side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patan</ENAMEX> is the ‚ÄúPatan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial Estate</ENAMEX>,‚Äù a complex of artisans‚Äô workshops and salesrooms where you can see bronze figurines being cast by the ‚Äúlost wax‚Äù method and then delicately finished by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. Here, too, are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woodcarvers</ENAMEX> who still preserve the skills that created the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple decorations</ENAMEX> and ornamental windows of the valley.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhaktapur</ENAMEX> is the place for thangkas and other paintings. Thimi <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> is where many of the masks are made and where interesting pottery, including flower pots in the shape of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX>, is sold.
Festivals
With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major religions, a multitude of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gods</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> calendars, and many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> with their different traditions, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> enjoys a profusion of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX>. Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> erupts in colorful festivals that sometimes stretch over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. These occasions are usually rooted in a rich mixture of fact, legend, and ancient seasonal observances. In a land where <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> toil can be hard and diversions few, festivals bring a combination of solace, gaiety, and confirmation of family ties, plus a bid for good fortune.
Almost all the festivals are moveable feasts, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Passover</TIMEX>, because they are based on the phases of the moon. In addition, some only begin when astrologers declare the auspicious moment. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birendra‚</ENAMEX>Äôs coronation was delayed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than two years</TIMEX>, until the numbers of his age, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> were all lucky ones. This uncertainty makes it impossible to pinpoint far in advance the dates and times of most festivals. Nevertheless, because there are so many, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> can count on some festival taking place during his stay.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the greatest fall during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the peak tourist season</TIMEX>, which extends from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early October</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dasain</ENAMEX> is the most important, comparable to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. It lasts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten days</TIMEX> and is followed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks later</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tihar</ENAMEX>, the festival of lights. The latter includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Newari New Year‚Äôs Day</ENAMEX>. The official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Year‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX> falls on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 April</TIMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherpa</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX>, which follows the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> calendar, is in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>.
Dasain honors the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tiger</ENAMEX>-riding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durga</ENAMEX> and her defeat of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">buffalo</ENAMEX>-demon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahisasura</ENAMEX>, a feat symbolic of good defeating evil. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This holiday</TIMEX>, which follows the monsoon, is a time for renewal, including scrubbing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, wearing new clothes, and taking purification <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX> by starlight at different river locations, followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> visits with puja offerings of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, colored <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">powders</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>. All over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> fly kites during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dasain</ENAMEX>, and primitive wooden Ferris wheels or swings suspended from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> stout bamboo poles are set up on the outskirts of every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. The message carried skywards is ‚ÄúNo more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>, please.‚Äù
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">barley seeds</ENAMEX> are planted in a special pot in every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">barley sprouts</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>, the shoots are worn in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX> or behind the ear. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventh day</TIMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phulpati</ENAMEX>, the feast of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, when a bundle of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> bound with red ribbon is carried <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">72 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">45 miles</NUMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> from the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shah dynasty at Gorkha</ENAMEX>. It is borne to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hanuman Dhoka Palace</ENAMEX> in a procession of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>, costumed and masked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX>, and bands. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldiers</ENAMEX> dressed in the uniforms of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gurkhas</ENAMEX> blaze away with muzzle-loading <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">muskets</ENAMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durga</ENAMEX> is also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kali</ENAMEX>, who thirsts for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. On the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dasain</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX>, and young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">buffalo</ENAMEX> are sacrificed, soaking temples in gore. If you see a taxi with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> on its wheels, don‚Äôt be alarmed; it should actually be extra safe to ride in. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Motorists</ENAMEX> daub the blood of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sacrificed fowl</ENAMEX> on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kali/Durga‚</ENAMEX>Äôs protection. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Nepal Airlines</ENAMEX> get this treatment.
You can photograph the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-chopping in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kot Courtyard</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Durbar Square</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX> and bullocks are sacrificed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> units <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all morning</TIMEX> long, as well as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace wall</ENAMEX> facing the temples in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>. Burly young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> are expected to dispatch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> with a single stroke of the heavy khora <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX>, as the big drum thumps and martial music is played before the massed flags of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regiments</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kot Courtyard</ENAMEX>, incidentally, is where the first Rana engineered the massacre of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> nobles, clearing the path to power in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1846</TIMEX>.
On the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> day of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dasain</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">members exchange</ENAMEX> visits and feast. Visits to work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> are also obligatory. Government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">functionaries</ENAMEX>, in their uniform of white leggings and black jacket and cap, go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> to receive the tika from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> also line the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>, waiting <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> to receive the king‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blessing</ENAMEX>.
There is still a celebratory feeling in the air <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks later</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tihar</ENAMEX>, also called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deepawali</ENAMEX>, is celebrated. This festival of lights honors <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lakshmi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> of wealth. The story is that in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dark nights</TIMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX> new moon, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakshmi</ENAMEX> orbits the earth aboard her <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">owl</ENAMEX>. She will reward with prosperity those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> below that have been made tidy and show lights burning on the doorstep. This is a time for non-stop gambling games, often held on a street-corner or in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> compound, with all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> hoping for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakshmi‚Äôs</ENAMEX> favor. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Shops</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> mark a red <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">path</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, through their doors, to the building‚Äôs money-box. Small <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay oil</ENAMEX> lamps are also set out to welcome the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX>. Elsewhere, strings of electric lights blaze <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the five-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">festival</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> go from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to house singing songs and receiving gifts. All sorts of tinsel garlands, fancy lamps, fireworks, and decorations are sold in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.
During <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tihar</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">successive days</TIMEX>, crows, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> are honored by giving them treats to eat and garlands to wear. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cats</ENAMEX>, by the way, are considered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unlucky</ENAMEX> and are rarely seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>.) On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fifth day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> are honored by their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>, who deck them with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, place the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">tika</ENAMEX> dot on their forehead, and tie a good-luck thread around their left wrists.
Bisket, the official <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>, prompts a wild celebration in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bhaktapur</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four days</TIMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> representing different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> have a tug of war over a chariot containing symbols of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kali</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhairav</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> keep the chariot in their district and parade it through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next several days</TIMEX>, fuelled by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice liquor</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 April</TIMEX>, a huge pole, decorated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX> and garlands and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">streamers</ENAMEX> representing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX>, is erected in a field on the outskirts.
Why snakes? Well, it seems that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX> of bygone years required a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> because each morning her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> was found dead. Finally a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> took on the job, and after satisfying the princess he hid himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword bared</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX> issued from the princess‚Äôs nostrils, ready to kill. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> hacked them up and lived happily ever after with the princess¬†‚Äî¬†no questions asked. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, the king, ordered the pole with snake streamers to be erected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> in commemoration. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> tug of war takes place on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Year‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, when the pole is pulled by opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> until it comes crashing down.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indra Jatra</ENAMEX> is an important festival, usually falling in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early September</TIMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this</TIMEX> week-long observance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kumari</ENAMEX> is drawn through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> on her chariot and receives the homage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>. Ritual dances are staged in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durbar Square</ENAMEX>, which is jam-packed at this time, the steps of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vishnu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> being reserved for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> decked out in their finest. On <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last evening</TIMEX>, the screen is removed from the face of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Bhairav</ENAMEX> mask and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> squirts from his mouth to the jostling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> beneath.
Patan‚Äôs big blow-out, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late April</TIMEX>, is in honor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red Machendra</ENAMEX>, a god sacred to both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX> and probably of very ancient origin among valley animists. The festival involves dragging a huge chariot across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and sometimes takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> before culminating in the display of a jeweled vest, about which, needless to say, another complicated legend exists. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathmandu‚Äôs White Machendra</ENAMEX> gets his chariot ride <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month earlier</TIMEX>.
Holi, when a kind of maypole with streamers is put up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basantapur</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chowk</ENAMEX> next to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kathmandu‚</ENAMEX>Äôs old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">royal palace</ENAMEX> and crowds throw colored <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">powders</ENAMEX> and water bags at each other, comes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">March‚ÄìApril</ENAMEX>, the merriment encouraged by the full moon. Gaijatra, the festival of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> and departed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>, is another light-hearted celebration. Departed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> who hold onto the tails of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> are believed to receive assistance in entering heaven. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> dressed as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clowns</ENAMEX> dance in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, and much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> is consumed, especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bhaktapur</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> after the death of a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nepalis</ENAMEX> wear white in mourning. White candles also are used at the time of death.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Trekkers</ENAMEX> who reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thyangboche Monastery</ENAMEX> above <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Namche Bazaar</ENAMEX> on the full-moon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day of November</TIMEX> will be privileged to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> monks‚Äô masked dance ceremony, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mani Rimdu</ENAMEX>. A similar dance takes place on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May‚</ENAMEX>ÄìJune full moon. Sherpas celebrate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> with singing, dancing, and the consumption of chhang, the local home-brewed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice beer</ENAMEX>.
Entertainment
In a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with more yaks than TV sets and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">temples</ENAMEX> for every movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, singing and dancing at religious festivals and family celebrations are a main source of entertainment. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokhara</ENAMEX>, Western-style entertainment is confined to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> congregate. These are frequented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> and hip young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nepalis</ENAMEX>. Bars are officially required to close at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10pm</TIMEX>. In rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>, where electricity is limited, everyone, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, is in bed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9pm</TIMEX>.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúcultural shows‚Äù</ENAMEX> that present traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX> music and dancing (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummers</ENAMEX> are especially talented) are staged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nightly</TIMEX> at several luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and upscale <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. These performances feature harvest dances, wedding dances, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>-man <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rituals</ENAMEX>, and singing with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan or Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">overtones</ENAMEX>. There are also performances by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Everest Cultural Society</ENAMEX> in a hall adjoining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel de l‚ÄôAnnapurna</ENAMEX>, and by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Himalchuli Cultural Group</ENAMEX> at its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> just north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel Manaslu</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lazimpat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX>.
Similar shows are also staged at several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pokhara‚Äôs Lakeside</ENAMEX> neighborhood. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Chitwan National Park</ENAMEX> lodges, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tharu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villagers</ENAMEX> perform traditional stick dances in the evenings.
You can sometimes hear singing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kathmandu‚Äôs Seto Machendranath</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asan Tole</ENAMEX> and at other temples around the old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the evenings. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> you may be serenaded by young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with musical instruments. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are gaines, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buskers</ENAMEX>, who expect a tip. They‚Äôre working, not begging.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> also has several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Casino Nepal</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Soaltee Crowne Plaza Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casino Everest</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everest Hotel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casino Royale</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel Yak & Yeti</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casino Anna</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel de l‚ÄôAnnapurna.</ENAMEX> All of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> are off limits to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nepalis</ENAMEX>, who are nonetheless fanatical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX> at cards, particularly during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dasain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tihar</ENAMEX> festivals. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clientele</ENAMEX> consists primarily of rich <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> who fill the gaming tables and slot-machine jungles. A free taxi ride back to your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> is provided at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casino Royale</ENAMEX> is housed in a former <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> and is the most impressive of the city‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>.



