



A Brief HistorY
The early history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> is a mixture of fact and myth; religious lore is associated with virtually every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landmark</ENAMEX> and event. Actually, so intertwined are legend and history that it is often impossible to determine where fact leaves off and legend begins. The prime example of this commingling of fact and fiction involves the origin of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu Valley</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legend</ENAMEX> holds that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu Valley</ENAMEX> was once a vast lake, upon which floated a giant lotus flower, from which emanated the light of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swayambhu</ENAMEX>, the primordial <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">god</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manjushri</ENAMEX> came to view this light, he was unable to get close enough for a good look, so he took his great <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> and slashed through the mountains surrounding the valley to release the waters of the lake. (That is the myth. The fact, according to geologists, is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu Valley</ENAMEX> was indeed once a lake, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">valley‚Äôs waters</ENAMEX> now drain through the narrow cleft of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chobar Gorge</ENAMEX>, which was most likely created by a large earthquake.)
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> side effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manjushri‚</ENAMEX>Äôs draining of the lake was that the snake gods called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nagas</ENAMEX>, which lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, were left with no place to live. So, once again Manjushri interceded and created a pond for them to live in. This pond still exists <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> not far from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chobar Gorge</ENAMEX>. However, elsewhere around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, there are other stagnant ponds from which rise statues of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nagas</ENAMEX>; these ponds, too, are dedicated to the snake gods.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unity and Fragmentation</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Licchavi</ENAMEX> dynasty, of high-caste <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> origin, ruled in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu Valley</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a.d. 330 to 700</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Manadeva</ENAMEX> I (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">a.d. 462‚Äì505</ENAMEX>) shook off the domination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India Gupta</ENAMEX> emperors and extended his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kosi River</ENAMEX> in the east to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gandaki River</ENAMEX> in the west and from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terai</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Himalayan</ENAMEX> passes. A great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of this line, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amsuvarna</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">609‚Äì621</ENAMEX>), married his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bhrikuti</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Srongtsen Gampo</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">640</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhrikuti</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> converted <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Srongtsen Gampo to Buddhism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhrikuti</ENAMEX> is venerated as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúGreen Tara‚Äù</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúWhite Tara</ENAMEX>.‚Äù Their images are prominent in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepalese Buddhist</ENAMEX> art. Commercial and cultural links with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>, and through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, were strengthened at this time.
More reliable records come with the next major dynasty, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malla</ENAMEX>, who were established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 1200</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strongman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ari Malla</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malla</ENAMEX> came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of several waves of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fugitives</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 11th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> invasion of northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. Many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> were nobles of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chetri</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior caste</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rajasthan</ENAMEX>; forging new feudal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>, they were responsible for reinforcing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hinduism</ENAMEX> at the expense of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu Valley</ENAMEX> itself was raided in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1336</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengal</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> he destroyed both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> temples and statues, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swayambhunath</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pashupatinath</ENAMEX>. These great <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX> were later rebuilt and expanded into their present magnificence.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Malla</ENAMEX> period saw completion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nepal‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most important <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>, temples, and works of art. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mallas</ENAMEX> became fragmented upon the death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1482</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yaksha Malla</ENAMEX>, who divided his lands amongst his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three centuries</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> city-states side by side in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">valley¬†‚Äî¬†Kantipur</ENAMEX> (now known as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lalitpur</ENAMEX> (now known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patan</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bhaktapur</ENAMEX> (also sometimes called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhadgaon</ENAMEX>), along with their hinterlands.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unification</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Nepalese</ENAMEX> history really begins with the arrival of a dynamic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> bent on unifying the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prithvi Narayan Shah, ‚ÄúThe Great,‚Äù</ENAMEX> was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1723</TIMEX>, in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> generation of a line of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">princes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gorkha</ENAMEX>, a hill <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> whose lands adjoined those of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> to the east. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malla</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Shah princes</ENAMEX> had fled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajasthan</ENAMEX> rather than convert to Islam.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prithvi Narayan Shah</ENAMEX> captured <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1768</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bhaktapur</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX>. Before his death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1775</TIMEX> he had brought under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> rule all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mahakali River</ENAMEX> in the west to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sikkim</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darjeeling</ENAMEX> in the east. During the reign of his son, under a regent, the borders were pushed further north and west, provoking reactions from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British East India Company</ENAMEX>, the power to the south.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1814</TIMEX> but were repulsed by the king‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Gorkha¬†‚Äî¬†thus</ENAMEX> earning all subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX> fighting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúGurkhas‚Äù</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> were more successful on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> attempt in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1816</TIMEX>, forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> to give up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sikkim, Darjeeling</ENAMEX>, and some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> to the far west. The peace treaty signed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segauli</ENAMEX> established <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepal‚Äôs</ENAMEX> borders pretty much as they are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. It also allowed a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> to set up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, the first Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX>.
Rise of the Ranas
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1846</TIMEX>, during the course of an unsavory palace intrigue involving an unsolved murder, meddling by the queen, and the massacre of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 100</NUMEX> high-ranking court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> who had been lured to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace courtyard</ENAMEX>, the instigator of these events became the power behind the throne. He was an ambitious and unscrupulous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29-year-old</TIMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jung Bahadur Rana</ENAMEX>. Before long he had exiled the king, replaced him with the youthful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crown prince</ENAMEX>, and arranged to have himself and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> made hereditary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime ministers</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranas</ENAMEX> were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">104 years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> remained, but had only ceremonial power. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranas</ENAMEX> kept the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> completely insulated from the outside world; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> weren‚Äôt allowed in and few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepalis</ENAMEX> could go out. Calling themselves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Maharajahs</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime ministers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> built <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX>, usually in an incongruous neoclassical style. The huge white <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singha Durbar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,700</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, far more than the king‚Äôs. Reconstructed after a fire in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, it serves <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> secretariat and meeting place of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranas</ENAMEX> also made a few modern improvements, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">works</ENAMEX> for the capital, a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50-km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">29-mile</NUMEX>) narrow-gauge <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">railway</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terai</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>. There were not many driveable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, however, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranas‚</ENAMEX>Äô new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolls-Royces</ENAMEX> were brought to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu</ENAMEX> in pieces, either on frames carried by big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of porters or on the ropeway, a lift that carried freight from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hetauda</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terai</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mahabharat</ENAMEX> range. Outside the valley, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> slumbered on, for all intents and purposes still in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Middle Ages</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Times</ENAMEX>
When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> became independent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>, pressure for change mounted within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tribhuvan</ENAMEX> pretended he was going on a shooting picnic and managed to escape to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. An uprising spread against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohan Shumshere Rana</ENAMEX> resigned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Tribhuvan</ENAMEX> returned, a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> constitution for the monarchy was installed, and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> were allowed into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Everest</ENAMEX> was conquered.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Mahendra</ENAMEX> acceded to the throne on the death of his father <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tribhuvan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>. After an experiment with elections and parliamentary democracy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahendra</ENAMEX> abolished the constitution in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> and instituted the system of ‚Äúpanchayat democracy.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Road-building</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> construction progressed during his reign.
After <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birendra</ENAMEX> became sovereign in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1972¬†‚Äî¬†tenth</NUMEX> in the line of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Shah rulers</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prithvi</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Great¬†‚Äî¬†a</ENAMEX> referendum in which all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepalis</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> were eligible to vote confirmed the popular preference for the panchayat system over a return to multi-party democracy. However, there was still some unrest regarding the issue. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> deferred to demands expressed in student demonstrations by making the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> directly elected, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> responsible to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> as well as to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, in the wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> Union‚Äôs collapse, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nepalis</ENAMEX> once again took to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> to demand an end to the panchayat system. After sometimes bloody protests and under pressure from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India‚Äôs Congress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birendra</ENAMEX> finally conceded to allow political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and the kingdom‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> truly democratic elections were held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> won a plurality of seats in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>. However, without a majority, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communists</ENAMEX> were forced to form a coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and in fact elections since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> have repeatedly ended in coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> being formed. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> have proved highly ineffectual in running the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1990s</TIMEX> there was growing discontent with the entire democratic process. There was also a growing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Maoist</ENAMEX> uprising taking place in the central hills of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> have made great efforts to develop <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal‚</ENAMEX>Äôs rather sparse natural resources. A number of hydro-electric <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dams</ENAMEX> have been built (or are being built), <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> are being extended, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and health posts are multiplying. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progress</ENAMEX>, however, is offset by steep increases in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
At the same time, almost total dependency on firewood for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> has deforested the heavily populated middle mountain ranges and led to erosion, landslides, and loss of soil for agriculture. Without trees to absorb the moisture, monsoon rains run off rapidly, swelling the rivers and causing severe floods downstream in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangladesh</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourism</ENAMEX> is now the most important source of foreign exchange in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. It has grown from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few thousand</NUMEX> adventurous souls <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years ago</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 300,000</NUMEX> visitors a year, and it provides income for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nepalis</ENAMEX> in mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> as well as for those in urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and construction jobs. The influx of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> has added to pressures on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Himalayan</ENAMEX> environment, but it hasn‚Äôt spoiled the friendliness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nepalis</ENAMEX>, surely among the most welcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on earth.
Religions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>
With <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> professing to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hindus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> claims to be the only officially <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> on earth. While this is essentially true, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hinduism</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu Valley</ENAMEX> and other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle Hills</ENAMEX> is inextricably interwoven with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nepal‚</ENAMEX>Äôs unique form of pantheistic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX>. In the higher elevations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayas</ENAMEX>, among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> origin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX> is the dominant religion. Overlay both of these religions with a strong dose of animism, and you have a thoroughly inscrutable religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">milieu</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhists</ENAMEX> worship at the same temples, and rocks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, and waterfalls take on mystical importance. However, whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu or Buddhist</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> live their religion on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis and can be seen worshipping at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX> and temples throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and night. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saturdays</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> head off to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> temples may take the pagoda form, but all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>-style stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shikara tower</ENAMEX> temples are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> and all the white <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX>-like stupas are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX>. The small trail-side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX> in the high mountains, called chortens, are also <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX>, and often surrounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> carved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Om</ENAMEX> mani <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">padme hum incantation¬†‚Äî¬† ‚ÄúHail</ENAMEX>, jewel in the flower of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lotus</ENAMEX>.‚Äù Small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stupas</ENAMEX> found around <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temples</ENAMEX> and known as chaityas are erected to hold relics or in memory of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
Hinduism
Rather than a formal ‚Äúchurch,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Hinduism</ENAMEX> is a guide to a virtuous life and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> for social relationships. It originated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 4,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aryan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> who migrated to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> from the vicinity of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">present-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> revered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of nature personified by innumerable gods and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddesses</ENAMEX> whose activities and moral guidelines are chronicled in prayers, hymns, and poetic sacred epics of great antiquity.
At the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hinduism</ENAMEX> is belief in a life essence and a common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>, atman, which all living things share, and in reincarnation, the soul‚Äôs rebirth after death in another form. What the next form will be depends on the sum of a person‚Äôs actions in his previous life, his karma. Following rituals such as taking purifying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX>, making offerings to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">gods</ENAMEX>, and honoring them in festivals will lead to reincarnation in a higher form. The highest form is liberation from the nuisance of repeated rebirth in this imperfect world.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temples</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> are dedicated to the great <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">gods Vishnu and Shiva</ENAMEX> or their consorts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>. Over the doorway of each of these temples is a semicircular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> called a torana with images of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> god¬<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">†‚Äî¬†this</ENAMEX> will help you identify who‚Äôs who.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vishnu</ENAMEX> is the preserver of life; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shiva</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">destroyer</ENAMEX> whose destruction makes new beginnings possible. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu ‚Äútrinity‚Äù</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brahma</ENAMEX>, whose only task was to create the world. All this would be simple enough but for the fact that the gods have appeared on earth in different incarnations, or avatars, with different names, forms, and natures. Some even assimilate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> and primitive, non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> local deities. If you are confused, join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">club¬†‚Äî¬†so</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>.
Vishnu, for example, can be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Narayan</ENAMEX>, floating on the primeval ocean or lying on a bed of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX>. He is also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rama</ENAMEX>, the model <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramayana</ENAMEX> epic, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krishna</ENAMEX>, a lusty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> who is the central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhagavad Gita</ENAMEX>, a section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mahabharata</ENAMEX> epic. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rama</ENAMEX>, he usually carries a bow and arrows. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krishna</ENAMEX>, he is usually depicted with a blue face, an after-effect of swallowing a poison that threatened the world, and is often represented playing a flute or sporting with the milkmaids he seduced. As himself <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vishnu</ENAMEX> is shown with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, holding a lotus, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, a conch <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shell</ENAMEX>, and a disk, often seated on a snake, symbolizing eternity. Vishnu may appear in art as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, a tortoise, a boar, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwarf</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> avatars. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX>, according to some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hindus</ENAMEX>, was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>. His <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> incarnation, to rescue the world from evil by destroying it and beginning a new cycle, is due <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 540,000 years from now</TIMEX>. 
Shiva, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pashupati</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lord</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guardian</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. He has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,008</NUMEX> names in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sanskrit</ENAMEX> literature. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahadev</ENAMEX>, he is lord of reproduction represented by the lingam, a phallus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX> often appearing in his temples as a stump of stone rising from the female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX>, a disk called the yoni. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva</ENAMEX> is also lord of learning and dance. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bloodthirsty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bhairav</ENAMEX>, fanged and festooned with skulls, he destroys at will. But he also destroys ignorance and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">misfortunes¬†‚Äî¬†the</ENAMEX> reason he is the symbol of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Nepal Airlines</ENAMEX>. A statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nandi</ENAMEX>, the bull, and a trident sign mark the temples of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> of these gods also have numerous names and attributes. Lakshmi, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vishnu‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, was created from ocean foam, like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Venus</ENAMEX>, and is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> of good fortune and beauty. Shiva‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parvati</ENAMEX>, also called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Annapurna</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>. She, too, has various aspects. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kali</ENAMEX>, she is horrible to look at, with a long tongue and staring eyes, and is kept satisfied by the blood of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sacrificed animals</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durga</ENAMEX>, she is fierce, riding a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tiger</ENAMEX> and brandishing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parvati</ENAMEX> also has more benevolent aspects, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taleju</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron deity</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nepali</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">royal family</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devi</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parvati</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>-headed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ganesh</ENAMEX>, easily the most popular of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> because he is capable of assuring the success of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other often-represented deities are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanuman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey god</ENAMEX> and helper of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rama</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garuda</ENAMEX>, the winged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">birdman</ENAMEX> who carries <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vishnu</ENAMEX>. He regularly appears kneeling before temples to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">palms</ENAMEX> joined together in the traditional namaste gesture of greeting and homage.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepalis</ENAMEX> begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> by making an offering to a god or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> whose favor they seek. This act, called puja, may consist of placing a small dish of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grains</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX>, or flower petals at an altar in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, or a tree, stone, or other place sacred to the spirits. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> or respected family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> may place a tika, a dot of red paste, on a worshipper‚Äôs forehead, the spot where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam</ENAMEX> of enlightenment is thought to emanate from.
Buddhism
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siddhartha Gautama</ENAMEX> was born a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> in the line of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sakya</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixth century</TIMEX> b.c., near <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">present-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lumbini</ENAMEX>. As a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> he was sheltered from the harsh realities of life, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> he saw a sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, then an aged blind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and finally a body being carried to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial</ENAMEX>. Profoundly shaken, he left his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and became a wandering beggar, searching for the meaning of existence. But the life of an ascetic and the wisdom of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> did not satisfy his quest. Finally, seated in meditation beneath a pipal <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bodh Gaya</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">‚ÄúFour Noble Truths‚Äù</ENAMEX> were revealed to him. He became the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Enlightened One</ENAMEX>, and embarked on travels to spread his beliefs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> never claimed to be divine and in fact emphasized that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> could by their own efforts follow his path to enlightenment and the blissful state of nirvana, release from the cycle of repeated births and deaths. His ‚ÄúFour <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noble Truths‚</ENAMEX>Äù are: all life is suffering; suffering is caused by desires; desires can be suppressed; and the way to become free of desires is to follow <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> ‚<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Äúright‚Äù principles¬†‚Äî¬†the Eightfold Path</ENAMEX>. These are right views, right intentions, right speech, right conduct, right livelihood, right effort, right mindfulness, and right contemplation.
After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddha‚</ENAMEX>Äôs death at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 80</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX> eventually split into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main lines, those who strictly followed his teachings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theravada</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hinayana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sri Lanka</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX>, and those who allowed new interpretations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mahayana Buddhists of China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mahayana</ENAMEX> allowed worship of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> and recognized other holy figures as well. These include a number of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhas</ENAMEX>, to be approached for favor through meditation, and saint-like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bodhisattvas</ENAMEX> who achieved enlightenment but remained active to help humankind find the right path. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bodhisattavas</ENAMEX> often seem to blend with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gods</ENAMEX> and resemble them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bodhisattvas Lokeswara, Manjushri</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machendra</ENAMEX> are especially popular with both religions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kathmandu Valley</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> is influenced by elements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tantrism</ENAMEX>, techniques to speed up enlightenment. These include learning physical and mental control through yoga exercises, and also prayer and meditation rituals such as repeating certain phrases, or mantras, and concentrating on geometric designs called mandalas. Prayer wheels (which hold a scroll covered with prayers) and flags multiply the power of prayer by adding to devotion the energy of movement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tantrism</ENAMEX> is also the source of the male and female symbols of the thunderbolt (vajra, also called dorje) and the bell (ghanta), usually present in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> ceremonies, and of the system of lamas or high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>, who are held to be reincarnations of holy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.



