
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER: Authoritarian and Aristocratic</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Marjorie</ENAMEX>,

            At the risk of letting you lure me into a very old argument, I'd say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> for ill. Not great ill, and not unmixed ill, but ill--mostly in
that she helped establish the modern social compact under which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> trade
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX> (or, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> puts it, " 'freedom' ") for security. The balance sheet
gets complicated if you think, as I do, that a lot of her most noble goals
(such as racial integration) would have happened anyway, and consider that a
lot of her least noble ones (such as disarmament on the verge of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>)
were never achieved.

            What tips the balance for me is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> was a far more authoritarian
figure than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> lets on. Granted, paternalism was in the air. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX>, too,
urged that we "treat the jobless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> resented it when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> compared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> and treats all
complaints about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>'s dictatorial ambitions as cynical rabble-rousing
meant to protect private interests. Maybe at times. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Freidel</ENAMEX> says
that, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX> that saw the rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX>, fears of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>
as an elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>--while ultimately misplaced--were understandable, even
healthy, in a democracy. He adds that during the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hundred Days</ENAMEX>, "Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>
lamented that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> lacked a benevolent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> to force through
reforms."

            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Ninety percent</NUMEX> of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> do is self-actualization. Some make
things better, some make things worse, most do both--but that's a secondary
project. And that's why I don't exactly fault <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> for her bad luck in
ruling in good times, which makes a lot of her rhetoric, as you say,
inappropriate. She would have been more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>-like during a depression and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> would have been more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>-like during a boom.

            What makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s growing love of power so fascinating--and
troublesome--is that it had to be wielded with either extreme ingenuousness or
extreme disingenuousness, and it's hard to figure out which. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s
instincts were aristocratic. She ushered in (or, more accurately, restored) an
era in which political power was seized not through backroom deals and
exchanges of money but through cause-based kudos-accumulation. The fact that
she gave to charity the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> she made as a radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> does not, to my mind,
exempt her from the charge of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gingrichian</ENAMEX> buck-raking.

            You cannot lament, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> does, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s stingy attitude toward the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s neglected and rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" without asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> to open up her
own books. You cannot carp, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> did, about privileges of race and gender
without begging the question of your own megaprivileges: land, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">connections</ENAMEX>, fame, not to mention having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> who's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The
latifundium on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Astor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morgan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> enlisted to
bankroll her schemes, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newport</ENAMEX> (to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> was
hardly, pace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>, dragged kicking and screaming), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and
charity connections that allowed her Val-Kill furniture <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to break
even--what would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> have been without them?

            As for money, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> said, "If you could give it all where it would do the
most good that would be grand but we can't always do that!" I'm with her, I'm
with her! But the moment she berates the "privilege" of those who couldn't
afford to make a down payment on her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">carriage house</ENAMEX>, or invokes the "greed" of
those making <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">125 percent</NUMEX> of the mean per capita income, I'm with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hick</ENAMEX>, who said
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> during a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> dinner, "God damn it--none of us ought to be
wearing velvet dinner gowns <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>."

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
