
   
   
      
         
            Short End of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Stick</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hick</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Chris</ENAMEX>,

            Thanks for your excellent recap of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>, Volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . I'd probably
quarrel with some of your emphases--and certainly with the strength of that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adjective</ENAMEX>, "irresponsible." I did think you unfair in characterizing it as
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Whig History</ENAMEX> for the PC era, full of paeans to same-sex love," and so on. You
especially underrate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s careful narrative of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>'s emotional life, in
suggesting that her bio is given to "sweeping generalizations about emotional
needs."

            But you touched unerringly on all the elements of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>'s life that give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s
work its fascination. I found her portrait of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> marriage in most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> rich, in other ways frustrating. She's definitely broken new ground in
establishing how thoroughly bifurcated their extended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">circle/Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s circle, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>'s place (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warm Springs</ENAMEX>)/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s places
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Val-Kill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campobello</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>'s surrogate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy Mercer</ENAMEX> and Missy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LeHand</ENAMEX>)/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s surrogate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> (one-time state trooper and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller and Lorena Hickok</ENAMEX>). That the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roosevelts</ENAMEX> managed to keep all these plates
in the air, while also raising <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and sharing the presidency of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, is just another big reminder that any one marriage is a stranger
and more mysterious land than an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> can possibly know.

            That it wasn't easy is suggested by the jealousies that bordered their
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">arrangements: Woe</ENAMEX> betide anyone (with the possible exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Howe</ENAMEX>) who
tried to befriend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> equally. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>--even the
lesbian ones--occasionally made the mistake of falling for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>'s easy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">charms</ENAMEX>. In Volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> wonderfully described <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickerman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Cook</ENAMEX>, as beginning a "slow slide toward that dangerous
abyss they considered neutrality." But this leads me to what I found a bit
frustrating. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> by no means ignores what was difficult about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>
marriage, but I think she minimizes it, or rather that her awareness of it
seems to come and go. On the one hand, she writes that

            
                in relation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> still occupied a lonely sphere which
echoed the isolation of her childhood. Beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Family</ENAMEX>'s jolly facade,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> endured a lifelong sense of exclusion that represented for her an ongoing
humiliation regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>'s domain.
            

             But in between such acknowledgments that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>'s independent life began as an
accommodation to the deep pain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>'s philandering caused her, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> tends to
present their domestic life as a settled, deeply fond, mutually beneficial
arrangement. I'm sure that there's realism in this portrait--a long marriage is
never all amity or all its opposite. But somehow I thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> didn't
manage to keep the mixedness of it in focus as well in this volume as
she did in the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            Is this because it's so hard to admit that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s strengths came in part
from being married to an impossible (in the marital sense) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> did a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> job in Volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> of demonstrating how flawed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> was as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>; how he relinquished all control to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and absented himself
from the brutal conflicts that resulted between <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grrrrrr</ENAMEX>. But it isn't very satisfying to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt</ENAMEX> became a
great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> mostly by making the best of a bad business, is it?

            I'm entirely fascinated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hickok</ENAMEX> material in this volume. You're right
that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hick</ENAMEX>" is a sympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--and in many ways a sad <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> is
entirely hip to the irony of their relationship: Just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> was coming to
the full command of her own powers, poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hick</ENAMEX> (who quit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> over the
conflict of interest posed by her personal ties to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>) was pining away over
having given up the career that had lifted her out of poverty and brought her
every good thing in her life up to the time she met <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>. It's ugly to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>'s
rather <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-like collusion in this process; with her advantages of class and
marriage, she couldn't begin to imagine what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hick</ENAMEX> had sacrificed for her.

            I didn't find it paradoxical that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> insists on the centrality of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s lesbianism. And actually, "insists" is not the right word. What she
does is assume the centrality of it, for the most part, and leave the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> to puzzle out what it means. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> made quite a canny--and
possibly political--decision to be so matter-of-fact about the lesbianism of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s circle. It leaves us <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to grapple with our own reactions.
( You mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> was tooling around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> on vacation in an open
convertible with her lesbian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>? And she got away with it? Isn't that kind
of... wild?? )

            Some other things I'd like to touch on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>: Did the bifurcated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> do a disservice in providing a model for later
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">administrations</ENAMEX>, in which poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX> and the halt
were insidiously sentimentalized as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s work? (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Bush</ENAMEX>.) And of
course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> parallel ... but we'll need at least a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">whole day</TIMEX> just for
that. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> for good, as I definitely believe, then
why does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> drive me mad?

            Best,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Marjorie</ENAMEX>

            P.S.: A personal aside: Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allusion</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Browder</ENAMEX> fell wide of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">polemical</ENAMEX> mark with me, because I actually lived next door to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Browder</ENAMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> math <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">granddaughter Julie</ENAMEX> was my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. So I knew <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Browder</ENAMEX> as a somewhat gloomy
but kind old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gent</ENAMEX> who took a daily constitutional up the block to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>
street, where he would buy me and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX> a package of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hostess</ENAMEX> cupcakes--the
orange-flavored ones, with icing squiggles on top.

             

             

         
      
   
