
   
   
      
         
            For the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Greater Glory of ER</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marjorie</ENAMEX>,

            That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s greatness was reactive
strikes me as her saving grace. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> could have been--at times was--a
dangerous mix of patrician self-importance, self-delusion, and imperiousness.
Your casting of her manipulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hick</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-like," for instance, was on
the mark. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> is persuasive that their love affair was rich and rewarding over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. But at the outset, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> took as her model not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloomsbury</ENAMEX> (sexual
partnership among equals, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">blah-blah-blah</ENAMEX>) but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> and her dissolute male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> (having your way with the help).

            Much of her do-goodery--e.g., her
snotty refusal to let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> elevator <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> practice their trade ("I
know how to run an elevator!"), her firing of all the white <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> help on the
dubious belief that white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can always find work--had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> to do with the
objects of her "solicitude" and everything to do with the greater glory of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt</ENAMEX>. What makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> admirable, and lovable to some, is that
her political ambitions did not arise purely from such a project of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">self-aggrandizement.</ENAMEX> They were at least in part the reaction of a decent and
thwarted person tacking out in search of love and eminence. I can't agree that
she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> for good, but she seems to have been a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.

            Most differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s
standing and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s arise from the origins of their respective
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> consciences. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> says, as she does at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point in Volume
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , "There is nothing more exciting than building a new social order," why
don't we reply, as we have to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>: Who the hell elected you? And why does
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Lasch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New Radicalism in America</ENAMEX> --the classic
indictment of the self-interest of the "concerned" classes, which excoriates
progressive paternalism from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Addams</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>--leave a
big hole where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> should be, giving her a free pass? Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>, in
her own patrician way, had behind her the authority of what our grandparents
called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">School</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hard Knocks</ENAMEX>. (And our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> had far more awareness
than we grant them that such Knocks could be emotional ones.) Her ambitions are
the product of difficult and humiliating intercourse with humanity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, by
contrast, is a cosseted suburbanite with a project for getting famous. Her
ambitions come undiluted from her own fantasy life.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s most visible outward
advantages over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) a sense of humor and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) a willingness to do
hard, painful work. In my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> I ran across a great book of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Arno</ENAMEX>
cartoons from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> that would make you laugh till
you cried. Except for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. It showed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX> with their flashlight-helmets
staring off into the distance, and one was saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look</ENAMEX>! It's Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>."
What's so funny about that? I wondered. After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> did go down in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mines</ENAMEX>. I think what was funny to contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> was a) the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>-like
ubiquity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt</ENAMEX> and b) the unthinkability of a wealthy lady
getting her clothes dirty in a dangerous place. They're stunts, but courageous
and spirited enough ones to earn you the ear of the public. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> frightens
us because she feels no need to do any of that earning.

            As an account of the blossoming of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>--emotional, sexual, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>, political, and otherwise--this is a
splendid biography. But as a political history? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> implies that--at the
height of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>'s terror, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after a planned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ukrainian</ENAMEX> famine that was
arguably a genocide--those who disagreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther Lape</ENAMEX>'s quest
for diplomatic recognition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> were rustic lunkheads to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
And I have a favorite passage from Volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , concerning the difficulty
in passing a constitutional amendment to ban child labor:

            
               State ratification was
blocked by shrieks of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bolshevism</ENAMEX>: Various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church groups</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of public
health, public education, and all public improvements protested the amendment
as a government intrusion into the "freedom" of family
life.
            

            The equation of anti-communism and
opposition to "all public improvements" is bad. But the sneer-quotes around
freedom take the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>. None of this sinks the book. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s ideology is
kind of like the weather in a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>: After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> you learn to
dress for it, and you can enjoy the sights without paying it much mind. Still,
I'll stick with my characterization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> as "irresponsible."

            Best,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chris</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
