
   
   
      
         
            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eleanor's Nanny State Really So Bad</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Chris</ENAMEX>,

            I don't see how we can say that the good things <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> was involved in (e.g.,
civil rights) would have happened just fine without her, but she must take a
huge share of the blame for the invention of the nanny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> (like all
do-gooders motivated by the perilous business of noblesse oblige) might have
had her authoritarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leanings</ENAMEX>, but the point is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> wasn't a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>, and neither was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>, who--whatever she may have mused aloud at
the start of the New Deal--never got half the loaf she wanted.

            What she did get was a chance to rally and embolden the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> inside
the New Deal who shared her belief that its benefits ought to extend to
everyone, including "negroes," and to give some lasting symbolic weight to the
civil rights movement. Symbolic weight isn't nothing in this case: No one can
say how much it ultimately meant that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> had lunch on the patio of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter White</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX>, but it meant something for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s first hostess to say that there was no reason a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> shouldn't
eat with her, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, as her equal. If she hadn't broken that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>,
who would have? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bess</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamie</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>? Civil rights would always be a cause that
moved by symbolic advances, and the fact is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> took down more than
her fair share of bricks from the edifice of respectable racism. And she did
it, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> makes clear, in spite of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and upbringing, which she saw
past only with great difficulty.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C'mon</ENAMEX>, don't you love the scene from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Conference on Human</ENAMEX>
Welfare? It's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull Connor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connor</ENAMEX> has insisted
that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> sit in segregated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>, upon entering, takes
her place among the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> ask her to move, she
stands and moves her chair to a spot between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sections--where she plants
her chair <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> for the remainder of the conference. What's a little aristo
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dis</NUMEX>)ingenuousness, held up against such brave improvisation? (I know, you're
going to tell me that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Conference on Human Welfare</ENAMEX> was full of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com-symps.</ENAMEX> But so did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> tell me that!)

            Besides, let's say I grant you that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> is responsible (in part) for the
nanny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. I still can't grant you that this is a bad thing. I know we don't
want to get lured into this old argument, but still, which part of the New Deal
did you hate? Was it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLRB</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>? Putting my grandfather
to work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civilian Conservation Corps</ENAMEX>? I know, I know (or at least I think
I know): We're talking about a spectrum here, in which some freedom is
traded for some security, and reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> like me and reasonable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> like you simply differ on where the appropriate balance is
reached. But where <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> are concerned, I think the burden's on a
conservative to explain whether and why the New Deal should have halted short
of where it did.

            Finally, you really lost me on that last curve--about Gingrichian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buck</ENAMEX>-raking, and rich old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> inveighing against the greed of others. Why
isn't it better to make a lot of money you give to charity than to make a lot
of shady money you give to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX>? Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>'s money made her modestly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypocritical</ENAMEX> in preaching against the greed and privilege of others, but it
strikes me as unfair to seize on this as a reason to disqualify her as having
done any good. ( It's not that I have reasonable objections to what you did;
it's the way you did it, or who you were as you did it ... ) Would it have
been more virtuous of her to while away the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> polishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">china</ENAMEX>? May only the poor object to the treatment of the poor?

            But I'm very grateful to you for the word "latifundium." I had to look it
up.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Marjorie</ENAMEX>

             

         
      
   
