
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>: Full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cap</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' steady circumvention
of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> budget-balancing caps. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with a story the others run inside: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s imminent recommendation that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> revoke rules it passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> requiring all oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to include
an oxygenate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">additive</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX>, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s grounds that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">additive</ENAMEX>, a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carcinogen</ENAMEX>, while promoting cleaner combustion, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">polluting groundwater.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with the latest on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Yosemite</ENAMEX> murders: the apparent confession by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
which led with that story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, goes instead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> heat wave
that has killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>. Most of the dead, the story says high
up, were sick and elderly, but the story's very last sentence reveals that two
were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> left in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead explains that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s main tack for nominally obeying
the budget caps while proposing both a tax cut and more money for key domestic
programs is to declare monies actually going for routine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> expenses to be
"emergency" funding, which the caps don't constrain. Some recent examples of
such "emergencies": medical services for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> and the census. The paper
calls this a "backdoor method."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead points out that in the past, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> has defended the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">additives</ENAMEX> against those fearing health risks. But, the paper adds, newer car engines can
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon monoxide</ENAMEX> emissions without oxygenates. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says substances
are now showing up in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> "supplies." (Which are
what, exactly? Does this mean in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of our drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> or not?)
One break: The most dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">additive</ENAMEX> smells so bad when it's present in
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> refuse to drink it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yosemite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>, a wilderness <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buff</ENAMEX> who had been
previously questioned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> and then dropped, gave a full account
of the murders of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to a top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> adds that in
a jailhouse interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, he told a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> that he had dreamed
about killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> had previously hidden evidence
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> but had also written them an anonymous letter leading them
to a body they couldn't find.

            The up-tick in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> continues as the LAT fronts and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> stuffs the news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislature</ENAMEX> visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knesset</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, becoming the highest ranking
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> to do so. (A trip of but <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8.5 miles</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> informs.) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece mentions that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wing members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s parliament
"did a little pro forma heckling" but otherwise, "barely a peep of protest
could be heard." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story gives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those heckling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX>
several paragraphs and quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his heckles, leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> with an
impression of more discord.

            The papers report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> it is pledging an
additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 million</NUMEX> in humanitarian assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, thus raising the
total <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> commitment there to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800 million</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> piece of perspective missing
from all the stories: None mention the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign aid budget, or
the amounts of humanitarian aid this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has sent to say, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.J. Dionne</ENAMEX>'s column on the tax-cut debate trots out an
important fact: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> pay more in payroll taxes than
in income taxes. In other words, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who have benefited least from the
upswing in salaries or the stock market also benefit least from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
tax stance. An important piece in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> makes a similar
point about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s beloved estate-tax cut. Citing an article out
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in the policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notes</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> noted that
under current law, only the wealthiest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> even pay estate
tax, and the average tax rate on estates of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $600,000 and $1 million</NUMEX> is
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX>. Not to mention that the tax's floor moves up to an estate value of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.5 million</NUMEX> if there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> involved, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.4 million</NUMEX> if there's a
farm. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> question about the piece: Why did it run on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>?

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front pictures of the aftermath of
the looting and arson rampage that wound up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Woodstock '99</NUMEX>. The accounts in both papers steer pretty
clear of sociological explanations--the only reason for the anomie that's
discussed seems to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX> bottles of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 pretzels</NUMEX>. And there's no
discussion of the total dollar amount of the damage. This is not the standard
newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> regarding riots. Does the once-over lightly have anything to
do with the festival's virtually all white attendance?

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> notes that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s recent reprise of three
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year-old</TIMEX> stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skylab</ENAMEX>, none of the stories gave the same weight for
the space <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>. Although the letter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> was being critical of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, the episode probably left him with an improved appreciation of their
job: He notes that finding out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skylab</ENAMEX>'s weight took him <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> phone calls.

         
      
   
