
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cranky Achievement</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Marjorie</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanche Wiesen Cook</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> volumes into an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt</ENAMEX> biography that
will stretch to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of pages. Its worldview is cranky and at times
irresponsible. Its subject is a busybody. And yet these books are a real
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">achievement</ENAMEX>. They leave no doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> deserves a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William Manchester</ENAMEX> to
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston Churchill</ENAMEX> or, for that matter, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Freidel</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>.

            A recap: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt</ENAMEX> is born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1884</TIMEX>, orphaned early. Her mother lives
just long enough to inculcate in her (unjustifiably) a sense of her own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">awkwardness</ENAMEX>. Her beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, is a kind-hearted drunk who
dies at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX>, hounded to the grave by a sadistic and mentally warped elder
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, who (perhaps smarting at having been outshone by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott</ENAMEX> in his youth)
slanders him in public, fleeces him out of his money, turns his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> against
him, and seeks to get him institutionalized. That <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy</ENAMEX>, becomes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX>. (OK ... so that's more my opinion than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> attends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allenswood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie Souvestre</ENAMEX>'s radical girls' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>, a vaguely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sapphic</ENAMEX> environment where she learns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> languages and much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poetry</ENAMEX>, and blossoms. No room for that back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX>, once she marries her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cousin Franklin Delano Roosevelt</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> comes under the thumb of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">passive</ENAMEX>-aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nurse Ratched</ENAMEX>-cum-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>), who
uses the family finances to stay Top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woman</ENAMEX> in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s life.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> is bound for glory: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant secretary</ENAMEX> of the
Navy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1913-1921</TIMEX>, vice presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1920</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929-32</TIMEX>, then
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>. He's also, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cook</ENAMEX>'s nice phrase "a flirt, a bottom-pincher,
and a knee-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX>." When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> discovers love letters from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy Mercer</ENAMEX> while
unpacking his trunk, she offers him his "freedom." If that's a euphemism for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">divorce</ENAMEX>, he declines. If it means freedom tout <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> , he accepts.

            So does she. And in a strange way, after an initial frost, their marriage
grows more tender as it grows more distant. (Let's talk more about this.) He
veers into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s world of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and, once he's stricken with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">polio</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">spa</ENAMEX> he starts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warm Springs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ga.</ENAMEX> She becomes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agitator</ENAMEX>--trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, suffrage, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> backrooms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s bombshell
is her assertion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>, throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, was in a
passionate lesbian relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorena Hickok</ENAMEX>. "Hick" is a
deeply sympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--from a broken Midwestern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, she knows not only
real breadline-and-boardinghouse poverty but also opera and poetry. She's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boswell/Eckermann</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s eyes and ears.

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> is too immersed in her life of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s activism
to change. But she adapts so skillfully that no one quite realizes it. She
continues with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>-building, starts a column ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Day</ENAMEX>"), and grapples
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s race problem. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hick</ENAMEX>'s influence, she occupies herself with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poor</ENAMEX> of all sexes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> social circles, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> policy
circles, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> agendas. But while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s agenda looks
separatist--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>-only press conferences, an attempt to avert <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>
through a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lysistrata</ENAMEX> -style "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s strike for peace"--it also succeeds
in grafting onto <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> new blocs of the
hitherto-disenfranchised without which the New Deal would be impracticable. The
only shameful note: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s seeming indifference to the plight of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>.

            This is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Whig History</ENAMEX> for the PC era, full of paeans to same-sex love,
sweeping generalizations about emotional needs, attacks on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">present-day</TIMEX> lack of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">civility</ENAMEX>, and you-go-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>!-type interjections. Such history brings strengths:
Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s first allegiance is to feminism (more specifically, to gay
rights), she is not dug in on most of the political and economic questions that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">divide FDR</ENAMEX>'s hagiographers from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX>. She thus shows the elitist,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paternalist</ENAMEX> (and shallow) roots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>'s progressivism, his tendency to
compromise, the personalism of his program. (I'd make the case that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> had
more in common with him than it appears.) It also brings weaknesses: This is
radical history, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s description of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-World War I</ENAMEX> race riots, of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wobblies</ENAMEX>' agitation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>, of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1930s</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>communism (which she calls
a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Red Scare</ENAMEX>"), could have been written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Browder</ENAMEX>.

            Sorry to run on. These are excellent books to be read with extreme caution.
I'm puzzled that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> at once urges that we study <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> in her own right, yet
so "privileges" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these first five years</TIMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. I'm
bothered that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cook</ENAMEX> uses the old leftist trick of praising her subject's
visionary radicalism, and then condemning as alarmist fabricators those who
recognize but don't like it. (A particular paradox: In insisting on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s
lesbianism as central, she follows the lack of circumspection of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>'s
contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX> , not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>.) I wonder if rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-actualization</ENAMEX> provides a useful model for legislation to help poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.
I'm also curious about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> would compare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--since she is constantly inviting 1990s comparisons. But I'm most
curious about what you think.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
