
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox Goes Soft</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>

            Watching a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> replay <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s press conference
(click here to watch it; click here to
read a transcript), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> was struck by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX>'s comfort and
ease. Here's a sample <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>:

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: Another question about the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>. Aside from asking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Bush</ENAMEX> to come forward and give specifics on the issues that you mentioned,
could you tell us what you find objectionable about his trying to present a new
moderate face for his party just like you did for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>? And could you
tell us whether you're worried whether he will figure out how the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
can occupy the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics?
               

               A: No.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: Do you have any hints?

               A: No, no, I don't think I'll answer those questions.

               [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Laughter</ENAMEX>.]

               
                  I will say. I will--no, look, let me say again I wouldn't even agree with
the characterization you gave of my first answer. When I ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, the first thing I did was tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> what I thought was
going on in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and what I would do. And if you remember, the late
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tsongas</ENAMEX> and I were actually almost ridiculed at the time because
we both put out these very detailed plans of what we would do. If you go back
and get one of those plans now, you'll see that virtually everything we said
we'd do, we did do, except for the things we tried to do and were defeated
on.
               

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s relaxed press posture seemed strikingly reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>, whose image has been all over the tube these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few days</TIMEX> in
the sad aftermath of his son's death. Chatterbox, who's had trouble looking at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> on TV for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a year</TIMEX>, found himself .. liking the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. What's that all about?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has a hypothesis: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is easier to like when his
popularity ratings go down.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roper Center</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Presidential Job Performance</ENAMEX> Web site, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> enjoyed his
highest-ever job approval--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73 percent</NUMEX>--during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December of last year and January</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February of this year</TIMEX>. This, of course, was the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
impeachment and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s bad behavior throughout the Flytrap
scandal--especially his smug refusal to confess to perjury during the
impeachment proceedings--made him easy to despise. And yet (no doubt largely
because congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were overplaying their hand), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> gave
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> more support than had ever been enjoyed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>
(personal best: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67 percent</NUMEX>) or even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> (personal best: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX>
percent--mass adulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> being a largely retrospective
phenomenon). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also hit <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early in 1998</TIMEX>, right after Flytrap
broke. In that instance, the public was probably expressing disapproval of the
press.

            As the impeachment drama dissipated, though, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the press
started to lay off, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s approval rating dropped. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, it's been
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 50 and 60 percent</NUMEX>. That isn't bad, and it certainly isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
absolute lowest approval rating as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>---that would be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s popularity dropped on several occasions to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37 percent</NUMEX>.
Interestingly, this was a period when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> felt more enthusiastic
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s presidency than he has ever felt since. Still, in the vast
sweep of history, a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 to 60 percent</NUMEX> approval rating isn't particularly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>--it's about where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s lowest job-approval rating
sat. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s approval rating is higher than the rating for his
policies (an ass-backward situation, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s view, since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-the-person is usually much easier to hate than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policymaker</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s explanation for this at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s press
conference, which seemed a bit of a reach, was: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> think things are going
well, but they want a change in policy ... particularly in a dynamic time where
things are changing, you should want continued change."

            But back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s newfound likability. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> knows what you're
thinking: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> always like to take popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down, and they're trained to sympathize with underdogs ("afflict the
comfortable, comfort the afflicted"). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will grant that some of this
crude psychology may be at work.

            But part of it was also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s performance. He just seemed more
relaxed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>--less of a snake-oil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>, less apt to be pissed-off by
rude questions, more willing to hit back, but in a good-natured way, and more
confident about his own achievements. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s primary message--don't let the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> spend the surplus on tax cuts--didn't seem all that urgent, since
it's not clear that even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have a majority to do
that. But for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> felt himself thinking,
possibly against his better judgment, that maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wasn't such a bad guy
after all.

         
      
   
