
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Glass Ceiling</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>'s hiring of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carly Fiorina</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX> is one of the
few unequivocally good things to happen anywhere in the world--okay, how about
"in the upper reaches of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>"--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent months</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H-P</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiorina</ENAMEX>'s arrival will bring some much-needed new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> into a somewhat tired
and overly bureaucratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, as well as a welcome emphasis on Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commerce</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiorina</ENAMEX>, who had had a stellar career at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX>, the hiring means
that she'll get a shot at running a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before she could
have expected to get the top job at her old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. And for the rest of us, at
least the rest of us who worry about who's running <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> business, it's
excellent finally to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman CEO</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>.

            Unfortunately, though not surprisingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiorina</ENAMEX> has taken pains to downplay
the last fact. It's understandable that she doesn't want it to look as if she
was hired because she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (although the fact that she'd be worried
about anyone thinking that in a world in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> of the Fortune 500
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is somewhat astonishing). So we'll stipulate that
she was not hired because she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. She was hired because she's a
managerial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX> who helped transform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX> from a staid spin-off of AT&T
into a prototypical bleeding-edge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. But that doesn't mean that the fact
that she is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is therefore irrelevant.

            The irony is that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiorina</ENAMEX> says things like "there really is not a glass
ceiling anymore," she's simultaneously making too much and too little of her
own accomplishment. She's making too much of it because of her implicit
argument that her ascension has smashed the ceiling. But the reality is that
most doors into the executive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> are still not open to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and those that
are have been opened only through struggle. Something like <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> of all
top executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX> are still held by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. There are lots of reasons for
that, of course, and most of them have to do with broader social realities and
not with corporate prejudice. But the old-boys' network is not a myth, and it
still takes a conscious effort on the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and hiring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committees</ENAMEX> to promote <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. (It may be telling, in fact, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have done a much better job in this regard.) It's hardly a
coincidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX>, which has a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women executives</ENAMEX> in
positions of real authority, was the first Dow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> ever to hire a female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>. Under outgoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lew Platt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H-P</ENAMEX> has emphasized diversity. Which, again,
doesn't mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiorina</ENAMEX> wasn't the right choice. It just means that there's
an institutional environment that allowed that choice to be made.

            On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiorina</ENAMEX> is making too little of her accomplishment
because she's downplaying just how talented she had to be to rise as fast as
she has and to overcome all the lingering prejudices against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women executives</ENAMEX>,
especially in the old-line technology industry. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Needless</ENAMEX> to say, any time a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> downplays her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>, it's nice, but still ...) It's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">major-leaguer</ENAMEX> had to be exceptional, because a merely
good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> wouldn't have been able to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of what they didn't want
to be convinced of, namely, that black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> could play. In some ways, in
fact, you could say that major league <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> wasn't really integrated until
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Red Sox</ENAMEX>--the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to integrate--signed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pumpsie Green</ENAMEX>, a
mediocre-hitting utility <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infielder</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> start being run by the
female equivalents of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pumpsie</ENAMEX>--as most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> currently are by the male
equivalents--then we'll know that the glass ceiling is really gone.

            Of course, in theory the market should already have taken care of this.
Discrimination is economically irrational, which means that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> which
discriminate against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> should feel the pain in reduced competitiveness. But
we know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> do discriminate even when it costs them. As my friend
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Devlin</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tulane University</ENAMEX>, points out, after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>
most industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> fired the women <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, even though
they would work for less than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, in order to restore the status quo that had
prevailed before the war.

            In any case, when it comes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> market in particular, it's difficult
to decide what constitutes "rationality" because the selection process is so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">personalized</ENAMEX> and because the criteria for what constitutes a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> are so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ill-defined</ENAMEX>. As the sky-high pay for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> compared with their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> demonstrates, the insular nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">directors</ENAMEX> means that purely economic considerations do not always prevail. And
in that sense, worrying too much about why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiorina</ENAMEX> was hired is fruitless.
What's important is that she was hired and that if she's successful she'll make
it easier for those after her. Even, or rather especially, those who are more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pumpsie Green</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Robinson</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
