
   
   
      
         
            No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Props For California</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead is that despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>'s nominal administrative control, it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberation Army</ENAMEX> that's truly in charge of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Davis</ENAMEX>' decision not to fight in
the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to establish <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Prop. 187</ENAMEX>, the state ballot measure that passed
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, cracking down on illegal immigration. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>' stance means, says the
paper, that both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">187</TIMEX> as a whole and most of its individual provisions will
never become law. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes with a fresh survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>
that seems to show that insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> procedures are inimical to efficient
patient care. The survey also gets front-page coverage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and
space inside everywhere else. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the explosion in special funding
provisions (a k a "pork") that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> has attached to
the spending bills currently under consideration in order to gain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>'
votes for them.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Hedges</ENAMEX>, filing from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX>, gets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> on record saying that they're running things now and
gets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to admit they can't do much about it. The problem is that,
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,100</NUMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> planned for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 156</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> are
there yet, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in the area haven't been able to close the gap.
Indeed, the weapons turnover program they are administering is almost
universally flouted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hedges</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shakedowns</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX>
are the order of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, and he describes the confiscation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> furniture
merchant's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and the theft of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> worth of his inventory. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hedges</ENAMEX> spots
some of it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> at the office building occupied by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-appointed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> deal means the end of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">187</NUMEX>
provisions calling for denying illegals access to social services and public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and those requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>, and public health
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to turn them in. All that will remain are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> laws aimed at stopping
the false document market in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. All this for an initiative that, notes
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, won the approval of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 60 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>.

            Basically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> survey indicated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> who took it
aren't all that thrilled with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">601</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">365</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> says it was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,053 docs</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">768</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>),
but their attitudes are nuanced. For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> noted that they are
frequently able to reverse an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurer</ENAMEX>'s initial decision to deny a course of
treatment, and they admit that the rise of managed care has probably led to an
upswing in preventive medicine. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> headline is a wry one: HMOs
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PERFORM BEST FOR THE HEALTHY, DOCTORS SAY</ENAMEX>. Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> headline (in the
online edition at least) mentions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> were surveyed too.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Responsive Politics</ENAMEX>' assessment of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> in lobbying. Total lobbying expenditures for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> were
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> higher than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX>, with the total number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>
percent over that time span. Top influence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spender</ENAMEX>? The insurance industry.

            The WP fronts a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s ruling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> cannot
stop the pharmaceutical industry from encouraging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> to prescribe
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> for unapproved "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-label</ENAMEX>" uses. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> ruled that to do
otherwise would be to violate the constitutional protection of commercial
speech.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> are investigating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> rapes at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Woodstock '99</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also produces several festival <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX> who come on
the record by name to say that they saw or saw evidence of rapes, some of them
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang rapes</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> adds that one of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> also described a woman
having her clothes ripped off her while she was "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>-surfing" over the mosh
pit. An experienced concert safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> expresses the bottom line: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What</ENAMEX>
would not be allowed on public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> is allowed at concerts."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's business section front page reports that after several failed
attempts at settlement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> is again focused on seeking a break-up of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have approached at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> leading investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> recently, requesting detailed break-up
analysis. Interestingly, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> declined, out of fear about the business
impact of appearing allied with the interventionist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>.

            A letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> carefully rehearses some facts
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> military compensation that are routinely overlooked by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> notes that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, attended college and
graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for free, and that given the tax advantages of a military
salary, his pay of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$54</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">792</NUMEX> is actually equivalent to a civilian salary of just
under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$94,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. A key tax advantage the letter-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> mentions is almost
never in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Military</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> can usually avoid paying state taxes.
Many military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> have had some training in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> for instance,
and remain constructive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of such low- or no-tax <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>
thereafter.

         
      
   
