
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Repairing China</ENAMEX>

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with the first high-level encounter between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>--a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch</TIMEX> meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreign minister</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diplomacy</ENAMEX> also leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , which stuffs the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> meeting, but
goes with the impromptu talks between new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">P.M.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> and the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abdelaziz Bouteflika</ENAMEX>; and between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassan</ENAMEX>, a story the
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> run inside. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with a story also fronted by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the arrest of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yosemite National Park</ENAMEX> murder of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">naturalist</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> is saying is also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> murder
there of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s luncheon with her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
counterpart is a hopeful lift in what has been a difficult patch with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
especially given that it resulted in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> announcing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
will meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX>, a nice change
from just after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombing, when, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> wouldn't
take a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> phone call. A key ingredient in the upswing is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>
emphasized that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> doesn't endorse <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>'s recent attempts to depart
from the "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>" policy. The only real difference between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> accounts
is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> stresses remaining strains in the relationship a bit
more, noting this in the big type of its headline, and also mentions the
spurning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s requests for renewed visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> naval
vessels and for resuming talks regarding the nonproliferation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mass</ENAMEX> destruction.

            The LAT fronts the follow-on to a story the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> led with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> agreed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to normalize trade relations, thus marking
the real end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says both sides were "ecstatic." The
paper says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> don't anticipate much trouble in gaining
congressional approval.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager reports that because so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> now have personal experience with the difficulties posed by aging,
infirm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>, the issue of how to help alleviate the cost
of long-term care for the elderly and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled</ENAMEX> is at last becoming part of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' agenda. "Until you've gone through something, you don't really
understand it," is how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gephardt</ENAMEX> explains the change to the
Times . Hmmm ... so maybe what this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> also needs is for more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> to have family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who can't get drug rehabilitation treatment
or day care or who end up on the wrong end of a handgun.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page feature notes a way
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is bucking the general trend against affirmative action: The
business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that certifies minority ownership of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> is likely to
drop its definition from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51 percent</NUMEX> ownership by minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group members</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
percent. The story notes two overriding factors behind the trend: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Corporations</ENAMEX> are slashing their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> down to a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX>, which
would, under the present rules, automatically exclude virtually all
minority-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the clout of minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> has grown
and therefore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> want to be able to undertake <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) without losing the
chance to establish a minority-friendly track record. But isn't this sort of
like becoming more attractive to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> by weakening the definition of
profitability?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ex-Reagan</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Korb</ENAMEX> points out in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed
that the vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> to deny money to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> doesn't, despite many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">headlines</ENAMEX>, actually kill the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. That's because, he explains, the money that
was turned down was only for producing the first block of aircraft <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 billion</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> and D for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was left untouched, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Korb</ENAMEX> notes that
this sort of pot has been used in the past to resuscitate killed or virtually
killed aircraft such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Osprey</ENAMEX> tilt rotor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aircraft</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> want to really kill a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>, they need, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Korb</ENAMEX> points
out, to do what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Cheney</ENAMEX> did to bury (the
runaway-expensive) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A-12</TIMEX>--take away all its funding.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's recent addition of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> is starting to
pay off. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s column from her gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> an inside look at how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> failed to cover a demonstration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A</ENAMEX>: When one
of the protest's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> called, he was transferred <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times and then
apparently none of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> faxes he sent got through. The sole <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> at the paper, an intern, knew in advance of the demonstration, but
assumed the city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> would already know about it. Just getting the snafu story
out there will make both the paper and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> more aware of what needs to
be done to avoid this sort of mistake in the future.

            Back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's account of the arrest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> in the Yosemite
cases. His crucial misstep appears to have been a profound failure to blend in.
He was "arrested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, fully clothed, at a nudist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> near
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
