
   
   
      
         
            Weatherbox

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> regards 
                  Slate
                as a near-flawless source of
news and commentary, it does tend to neglect an important aspect of life: the
weather. Not once has 
                  Slate
                ever run the headline, "Whew!
It's a Scorcher!" or posted, in the middle of a cold-weather snap, a photograph
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> orange covered with frost. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incidentally, Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has long
suspected the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> keeps on file a single photograph of a frost-covered orange
and uses it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>. How would anyone know the difference?)

            These thoughts are inspired by the current miserable heat wave. It's a
scorcher! According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> of record on the subject
of weather, it's supposed to be upward of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 degrees</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Plains</ENAMEX>
and in parts of the southeast and southwest. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's incomprehensible-but-gripping "radar movie" of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">continental United States</ENAMEX>.) As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> draws to a close, "hottest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> are being broken left and right, making it harder and harder to
pooh-pooh evidence that greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">gasses</ENAMEX> are warming the planet. However,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> isn't really interested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in expounding on the terrifying menace
of global warming. (It's too hot.) Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> finds himself wondering:
How hot can it get? As is usually the case when interesting questions are
raised, the answer can be found on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>--in this case, by consulting the
National
(popularly known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOAA</ENAMEX> and pronounced exactly like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s last
name).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has always felt that the usual way temperature records are
expressed--by comparing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s temperature in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Topeka</ENAMEX> to the temperature in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Topeka</ENAMEX> on this same exact day in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">previous years</TIMEX>--is a bit of a cheat.
With <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">365 days in a year</TIMEX>, and a limited database of temperatures recorded in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Topeka</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">previous years</TIMEX>, you've got a pretty decent chance of breaking
weather records pretty frequently. No doubt there are serious scientific
reasons for recording all-time temperature highs this way, but a nonscientific
reason may be that it makes it easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weather authorities</ENAMEX> to soothe an
aggrieved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>: There, there. You're right. Nobody's ever had to endure
what you're enduring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> . But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> wants to know: What's the
hottest it's ever been, anywhere ?

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOAA</ENAMEX>, the hottest it's ever been, anywhere on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>, at least as
far as we know, was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">136 degrees Fahrenheit</NUMEX>. That was the temperature recorded
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Azizia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 13, 1922</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-hottest it's ever
been, anywhere, was right here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, when it hit <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">134 degrees</NUMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Greenland Ranch</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Death Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10, 1913</TIMEX>. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-hottest it's ever been, anywhere, was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tirat Tsvi</ENAMEX>, in what would
soon be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">129 degrees</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21, 1942</TIMEX>. (The coldest it's ever
been, anywhere, interestingly, was recorded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 23, 1983</TIMEX>--when it hit
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">minus 129 degrees</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vostok</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Antarctica</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOAA</ENAMEX> also has hottest-ever data for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firsters</ENAMEX> who only really care
about how hot it gets in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On the "Temperature Extremes</ENAMEX>" page, go to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">All-Time Temperature Maximums</ENAMEX>
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>" and click on "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDF</ENAMEX>].") As previously stated, the hottest day in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10, 1913</TIMEX>, when it hit <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">134 degrees</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Death Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX> The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-hottest day in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29, 1994</TIMEX>, when it hit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">128</NUMEX>
degrees in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Havasu City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">125 degrees Fahrenheit</NUMEX> (the
third-highest temperature ever recorded in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laughlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nev.</ENAMEX> The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-hottest day in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 27, 1994</TIMEX>--presumably the same
heat wave--when it hit <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">122 degrees</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Waste Isolation Pilot Plant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>. (Chatterbox assumes the temperature had nothing to do with the
radioactivity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WIPP</ENAMEX>'s contents.) The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-hottest and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-hottest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> would seem to support the theory that global warming is making the
planet, or at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, much hotter.

            Probably the data isn't perfect. Can it really be true that the hottest
temperature ever recorded in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 degrees</NUMEX> (on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 27, 1931</TIMEX>)?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has never been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> but was under the impression it had a warm
climate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> would also like to take this opportunity to implore pedants
not to write in and point out that during earlier geological eras the worldwide
climate was vastly different from what it's been during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last century</TIMEX> (which
is about as far back as record-keeping goes). Still, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOAA</ENAMEX> statistics do
seem to show that, hot as it is, we should all stop bitching and get back to
work. It's been hotter.

         
      
   
