
   
   
      
         
            Blame <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster</ENAMEX>, Not the MPAA

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Film Critics Association</ENAMEX>
condemned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motion Picture Academy of America</ENAMEX> for refusing to grant Stanley
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> an R rating without a bunch of ludicrous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digital</ENAMEX> alterations during a ritualized orgy. Yippee: another occasion for
bashing the ratings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. I saw the picture before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fig leaves</ENAMEX> were applied
and the sequence in question was no more erotic than dental surgery--but that's
neither here nor there.

            My point is that the film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are blaming the wrong party. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>
in this scenario are not the anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fuddy-duddies</ENAMEX> who sit on the ratings
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> but the sanctimonious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypocrites</ENAMEX> who preside over some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
largest video and media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>. These are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who treat any film rated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NC-17</ENAMEX> as leprous. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NC-17</ENAMEX> was originally meant to eliminate the porn-related
stigma that came with the earlier <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> rating. But the very same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> that
refused to carry ads for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> films refuse to carry ads for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NC-17</ENAMEX> films. With a
film held hostage by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster et al.</ENAMEX>, any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> with, say, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> on the line feels compelled to hack at their movie and play
footsie with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX> until they get their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R.</ENAMEX>

            Take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster</ENAMEX>, which prides itself on being a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> video <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>." A
stroll through the aisles will take you past displays of such wholesome fare as
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Meat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cleaver Massacre</ENAMEX> , as well as innumerable soft-core made-for-video
serial-killer-stalking-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>-in-lingerie flicks. You have to wonder
whose family the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> caters to--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mansons</ENAMEX>? But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster</ENAMEX> and other
such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfits</ENAMEX> have, with the help of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX>, given themselves a veneer of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">righteousness</ENAMEX> while trafficking in the same kind of sleaze as every other
entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX>. That's capitalism.

            In a column for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Variety</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> argues that a new rating,
A--something between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NC-17</ENAMEX>--would allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> to see the original
cuts of movies such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> and would "provide a category for
adult films that would be acceptable to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> and advertising
outlets." He goes on: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theaters</ENAMEX> would not shun them. Everybody understands the
concept of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>-only category. And because <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NC-17</ENAMEX> would remain in business,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> would remain free to discriminate against
it."

            I wish I could support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebert</ENAMEX>'s suggestion but I'm not so sure that A would
work. Wasn't that the purpose of NC-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> to begin with? And does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebert</ENAMEX> really
trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX> to distinguish between films that have artistic merit and those
that don't? Eyes 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wide Shut</ENAMEX> might be a no-brainer because of the
Kubrick imprimatur, but what about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">South Park: Bigger</ENAMEX>, Longer &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uncut</ENAMEX> (a title whose second meaning allegedly passed straight over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX>)? Before cuts for its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>, there were allegedly lines about sex with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Almighty</ENAMEX>. A or NC-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>? How long before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster</ENAMEX> and those big newspaper
chains announce that they won't be carrying ads for A films?

            The larger issue is what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX>'s distinctions say about our culture. In
its press release, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angles Critics Association</ENAMEX> notes the disturbing
"double standard the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX> continues to maintain when it comes to sexual and
violent movie content ... The PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> rated movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild Wild West</ENAMEX> , for
example, opens with a 'humorous' decapitation, and the PG rated movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wars: Episode 1--The Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> , contains numerous violent deaths." I'm
fond of citing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Brooks</ENAMEX>' experience in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost in America</ENAMEX>
because it so gorgeously encapsulates the issue. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX> gave the film an R
rating because of a scene in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist babbles</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Hagerty</ENAMEX>) that he wants to "fuck" her over her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> desk. That's
unacceptable, said the ratings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, because "fuck" is used in a "sexual
context." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> pointed out that if the character, instead of saying, "I want
to fuck you over this desk" had said, "I want to fuck you over with this
desk," the film could have gone out with a PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>.

            But if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX> is puritanically intolerant of sex, it also has peculiar
notions of "acceptable" violence. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> who frequently tangled with the
ratings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> told me an instructive story. He did some research on fistfights
and discovered that a lot of them last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> punch: In real life, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s
nose gets broken and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s hand gets broken. There's a lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. I once watched a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> get his nose broken in a (brief) fistfight and
it remains one of the most ghastly things I've ever seen. Now, let's pretend I
want to film such a fight for the purposes of making violence realistically
horrible--so that anyone who sees it will think twice about getting into a
fight. I put in the sound of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage</ENAMEX> being crunched and show the bright red
blood pouring out of someone's nose, and I give you a close up of the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s broken fingers beginning to swell. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agony</ENAMEX>, right? And very likely--if I
do my job correctly--an NC-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>. Too explicit for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Now let's pretend I
decide to restage that fight and make it painless--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> punches back and forth,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popeye</ENAMEX>-style, with no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> walking away unblemished. That's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>. The lesson for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> is that violence is funny and bloodless and without
real consequences.

            It really won't matter if it's PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NC-17</ENAMEX>, or even A until we figure
out just what it is that we wish to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from . The next step
is to ask ourselves what's wrong with a cinema exclusively for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>--and why
we can't seem to keep from stigmatizing it.

         
      
   
