
   
   
      
         
            In a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Graveyard Spiral of Whimsy</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Cynthia</ENAMEX>,

            As long as we're talking about cyber protocol, allow me to grouse about why
computers constantly have to tell us more about their own internal activities
than anybody wants to know. Just signing on to check my e-mail gives me the
impression I might be inadvertently launching a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialing"</ENAMEX>,
"Communicating at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28,800</NUMEX> bauds," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Starting PPP</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Authenticating</ENAMEX>," all of this
ending up in an inscrutable "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Status</ENAMEX>" box with graphs and blinking lights and
various pronouncements whose urgent meanings no human could ever know.

            I'm with you on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">MacArthur Park"</ENAMEX>; I'm with you on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crimson and Clover</ENAMEX>"; but
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Convoy</ENAMEX>" is one of those songs, like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Battle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Tie Me</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Kangaroo Down</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sport</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Please Mister Custer</ENAMEX>," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Brennan</ENAMEX>'s
unforgettable talking rendition of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Epic Ride</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John H. Glenn"</ENAMEX> (it's on
the flip side of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Rivers"</ENAMEX>), that I'm just going to give a pass to.

            This is our last exchange for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>, right? From this distance, our
discussions seem to have started out on a suitably high and somber note with
the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX>, but our ephemeral natures soon got the better of
us. Before we could move on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> tax cut, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> banking
crisis, or the fate of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, we found ourselves--to use a phrase from this
unfortunate week--in a "graveyard spiral" of whimsy. And it is only with a
great effort of will that I now refrain from referring you to my new favorite
publication, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beer Frame</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Inconspicuous Consumption</ENAMEX> ,
and its article on the superiority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hydrox</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oreo</ENAMEX>, its salute to
products with "edible spokescharacters" like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pillsbury Doughboy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tuna, and Slim Jim</ENAMEX>, and finally its definitive history of the styptic
pencil ("styptic," proclaims the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, "is such an excellent word"). If you
can top that for meaninglessness, you are welcome to try. In the meantime, it
should be stated for the record that your own book on the history of the
abortion wars is a marvel of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> and you should not necessarily be judged
by the lowbrow online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you've been keeping <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all week</TIMEX>.

            With lard in my pocket (yeccch),
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
