
   
   
      
         
            Not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avant Guard</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX> news diversity breaks out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, with nobody's lead on anybody else's
front. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s planning of an extensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>-run monitoring
system for protecting government computers and those in the private sector from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hackers</ENAMEX>. (The extensive story is virtually an exclusive, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> running a brief dispatch on the same
subject.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the announcement that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley Clark</ENAMEX> will be leaving his post earlier than anticipated.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s decision upholding
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>'s right to attend civil trials. The ruling came in connection with
the bitter lawsuit between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX> and his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> Sondra
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX>, in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, citing the need to keep the jury free of reporting
about the case, banned the public and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> from case proceedings in which
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> was not present. Several media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> pursued an appeal, arguing
among other things, that some of the legal battles that have had the most
impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' lives have been fought in civil cases. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , affirmed the public's right of access
to criminal trials many times, no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high court</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has ever, before
now, done the same on the civil side. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s approval of the first new anti-flu <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>,
an inhalant. Optimally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> will cut the length of a flu bout by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
percent, and significantly reduce the chances of escalation into a severe
case.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lead waits until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">11th</NUMEX> paragraph to inform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> computer monitoring <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX> will be in place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. That's after the
jump--too late in the story. By the way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says it got its computer
scoop when a civil liberties <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (not identified by the paper), concerned
about the project's potential for abusive intrusion, provided an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> memo on
the project. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hmm</ENAMEX> ... wonder if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has a policy against accepting
such materials if they're the product of a hack ...

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> was "abruptly informed" that he will be
leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next April</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year earlier</TIMEX> than expected, and
connects the departure to tension between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> war, marked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s repeated requests for more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and equipment
than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> was planning to provide. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , in its
inside story, credits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , but does something the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
doesn't--reminds the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX> was once in line to become
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX> but had to step aside "because of a blemish in
his personal life." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Lady</ENAMEX> won't show any more leg than that though,
deigning not to remind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> just what the zit was.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s whimsical campaign countervisit
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>. Playing along with the joke was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Huckabee</ENAMEX>, who
is quoted as saying of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy G.</ENAMEX>: "He's never been here before, he's never worked
here, he's never lived here. Today, he will be announcing his candidacy for
some significant major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs its piece on the
episode deep inside.

            On its front, the WP takes its swing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air National Guard</ENAMEX> career of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. The story says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Guard</ENAMEX> was famous for string pulling for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> of the influential,
noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Bentsen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was inducted into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANG</ENAMEX> at about the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time GWB</ENAMEX> was. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> can be dinged for not quite remembering who
suggested he apply to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>--he says it was unspecified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, not his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> can be dinged for not mentioning that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> got
to this story <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>" page reports that the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> is
likely to pass a bill the would prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, filmmakers, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">songwriters</ENAMEX>
from making unauthorized use of the images of dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The bill would
withhold this particular piece of poetic license from everybody but ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's "Tax Report" runs a nugget that says a lot about the
growth of this economy. The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with adjusted gross incomes of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> or more in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> for which stats are available) was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">142,556</NUMEX>, nearly double the total for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. (Of course, after taxes, not all
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX>, but on the other hand there are many net-worth
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX> who make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than a million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports inside that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> has
announced its intent to conduct a yearlong boycott of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> major networks
over its dissatisfaction concerning the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">under</NUMEX>-representation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latinos</ENAMEX> on
television. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> makes up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, but less than
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> of television's lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. It's more than a little puzzling
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , with a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in its coverage area, a
paper that has recently given over quite a bit of front-page space to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>'
complaints about their sparse television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">presence</ENAMEX>, runs the story on Page
12.

         
      
   
