
   
   
      
         
            Not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denny Less</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> lead
with a story that's been cooking for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>: passage of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$792 billion</NUMEX> tax cut by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX>. The bill would pare personal income tax rates by
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 10 years</TIMEX>, reduce the "marriage penalty" and the
highest rate on capital gains from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent to 15 percent</NUMEX>, and repeal the tax
on health insurance and large inheritances. The papers concur that the plan has
zilch chance of actually becoming law--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has already promised
not to sign it--and that it merely represents an opening gambit in the upcoming
back-and-forth over what to do with the surplus.

            The reports agree that this a key victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denny Hastert</ENAMEX>,
who cajoled his fractious and narrow majority--including a cadre of moderates
skittish about using so much of the surplus for tax cuts--into supporting the
legislation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX> wooed party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> by agreeing to postpone the tax cut
if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s interest rate on the national debt climbs (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> call
this stipulation a sham; no one understands how it would actually work, and it
is unlikely to survive in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's ticktock account of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX>'s vote campaign proposes that the bill ultimately passed because "just
about every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> wants <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX> to succeed." After the bill scored enough
votes to win, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> cheered, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX>! Coach! Coach!"

            The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire"</ENAMEX> column ticks off the legislation's many
concessions to special interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Investmentmeister Warren Buffett</ENAMEX>
persuaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kerrey</ENAMEX> to up the limit on how many bequeathed publicly
traded shares a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> can own in a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, while Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Dunn</ENAMEX> worked on behalf of retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> to ensure that their
incentives to build in shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> wouldn't be taxed heavily.

            All papers front the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s ban of the spiritual organization
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX> (sometimes known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Dafa</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Followers</ENAMEX> are, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ,
largely "middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who practice a form of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> breathing exercises
and meditation," but they are organized enough to engineer what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> calls "the largest expression of public discontent with the
government since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1989</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> protests." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> waits
until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">22nd</NUMEX> paragraph of its story to explain why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> is so spooked by
the mystics: Similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> destabilized the last imperial dynasty, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
fears that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX> could organize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s huge numbers of newly laid-off
state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX>'s estimated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> make it a close <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> in membership to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
Party's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">55 million</NUMEX>.

            The other unanimously fronted story is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s denial of funding for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-</ENAMEX>pricey <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>, already being prepped for production at
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX> warehouse. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX>
is reeling from the loss of the sale. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> attributes the decision to
cost worries, as well as tension between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> on
all matters military.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> inside piece report on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s first significant policy speech, which laid out a scheme to fund social
services through private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> proposed spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 billion</NUMEX>--or, as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WP</ENAMEX> reminds, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of the non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> budget surplus-on tax
incentives designed to stimulate contributions to nonprofits and religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s proposals the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> real glimpse of the face
of "compassionate conservatism" and an unmistakable rejection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
"free-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarian orthodoxy</ENAMEX>." His programs surely would work if other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> are as generous as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>: Despite his speaking in ground zero
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> territory, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> carted home a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">one-night</ENAMEX> haul of at least
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600,000</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s avid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technophilia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is outpacing him in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> a
close <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. High-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">titans</ENAMEX> admire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s nuanced grasp of financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">esoterica</ENAMEX> and support for free trade. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s stock suffers from his
tight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> with tort <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, who often bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholder</ENAMEX> suits against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">startups</ENAMEX> when their stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>.

            Need a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX>? A WSJ piece quotes friendly-sounding singles ads,
complete with descriptions like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Looking for a playmate?</ENAMEX>" "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of energy and
spunk," and "a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies man</ENAMEX>." But don't respond unless you're ready to get
down on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> legs; the ads feature <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> in need of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
