
   
   
      
         
            Another Bulletin From the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat Desk</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> just
received via <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snail</ENAMEX> mail an intriguing bundle of news clippings from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
Limpert, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washingtonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX>, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Mann</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX>--the
mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX> has never identified--was
probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Mark Felt</ENAMEX>, the No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Bureau of Investigation</ENAMEX>.
(See "
Deep <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Throat Revealed [Again</ENAMEX>]" and "
Deep <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Throat Revealed [One Last Time</ENAMEX>].") To recap: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>
celebrated the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">27th</NUMEX> anniversary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> break-in by reminding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
that much of the mystery appeared to have been solved by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Mann</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">little-noticed</ENAMEX> article published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years earlier</TIMEX>.
(The damn thing still can't be found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>'s Web archive.) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Mann</ENAMEX>
established, mainly by passing along private conversations he'd had with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> when the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> worked together at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> had
all but announced <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX> worked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incidentally</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> recently informed this column that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox's</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> Nexis search
should have turned up an item he, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX>, wrote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>
piece that questioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX>'s ethics in ratting out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>.)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX> was more sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-man than he was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-man
in question was Felt. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> last 
examined this question, he considered the theory put forth by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS News</ENAMEX>, in
its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">20th</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">-anniversary Watergate</ENAMEX> documentary, that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L. Patrick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX>, who briefly ran the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Edgar Hoover</ENAMEX> died. While Chatterbox
found the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS News</ENAMEX> theory provocative and intelligent, he didn't find it wholly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persuasive</ENAMEX>. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limpert</ENAMEX>'s care package has Chatterbox thinking about Felt
again.

            Limpert was a Felt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> long before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Mann</ENAMEX> wrote his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> (which, nonetheless, offered up a lot of hard evidence that Limpert
wouldn't have been privy to). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the clippings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limpert</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> sent
Chatterbox are "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Comment</ENAMEX>" columns he wrote for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June and August 1974</TIMEX>
issues of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washingtonian</ENAMEX> that finger Felt as the likely <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limpert</ENAMEX> doesn't say in the clippings how he arrived at his hypothesis, but in
his cover note to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Limpert</ENAMEX> explained, "the source for the pieces was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Waldrop</ENAMEX>, who was absolutely wired to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>." Waldrop, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> , which was folded into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX>, died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 92</TIMEX>. During <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waldrop</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last years</TIMEX>, he
remained a very knowledgeable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> scene; indeed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> himself used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Waldrop</ENAMEX> as a source from time to time, and always found
his memory and powers of analysis razor-sharp. As someone who was basically put
out of business by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waldrop</ENAMEX> would certainly have had
the motive to demystify its greatest journalistic coup. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waldrop</ENAMEX> thought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
Felt was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thinks that hypothesis is worth very serious
consideration.

            A difficulty with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felt Hypothesis</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> identified <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep</ENAMEX>
Throat as a heavy smoker. Felt gave up smoking in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX>. In an 
earlier dispatch, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> said it was "possible the heavy-smoker bit was
a phony novelistic detail that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> got wrong or invented." Apparently this
thought has also occurred to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .
Here's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limpert</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1974</TIMEX> Washingtonian :

            
               An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> told us: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Woodward disguised Deep Throat</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> tried not to lie, but he tried to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> as much as
possible. For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> made a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX> smoking cigarettes,
but I had the feeling that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX> doesn't smoke."
            

            Not knowing who the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in question was, it's hard to assess
whether that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s "feeling" that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX> didn't smoke was based on
inside knowledge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> reporting. Still, it's
interesting.

            An especially gripping part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limpert</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1974</TIMEX> Washingtonian
piece is a reprinted snippet from the transcripts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> tapes
dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 28, 1973</TIMEX>. It's an exchange between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dean</ENAMEX> focusing on
the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Felt</ENAMEX> is squealing:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>: Now, about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and the like, and, now,
the only, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that knows--is aware of it--is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Felt</ENAMEX>, and we've
talked about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Felt</ENAMEX>, and uh--I guess, uh--
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: What does it do to him, though? Let's face it. You know, suppose that
Felt comes out and unwraps the whole thing. What does it do to him?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>: He can't do it. It just--

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: But my point is: Who's going to hire him?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>: That's right.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: Let's face it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>: He can't. He's--

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: If he--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that does that can go out and, uh, you mean he's a--of
course, he couldn't do it unless he had a guarantee from somebody like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look</ENAMEX>, we'll give you a job for life." Then what
do they do? They put him in a job for life, and everybody would treat him like
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pariah</ENAMEX>. He's in a very dangerous situation. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> you know--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">informers</ENAMEX>, look what it did to [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whittaker</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>. ... They finished him.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh huh</ENAMEX>. Well, I think I, there's no--

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: Either way, either way, the<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, the</ENAMEX>, the informer is not wanted in our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>. Either way, that's the one thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do sort of line up against.
They--

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>: That's right.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: They say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>-of-a-bitch informed. I don't want him
around." We wouldn't want him around, would we?

            There's a lot going on in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>. As we now know, before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> was
out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX> would do precisely what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felt</ENAMEX> would never dare do--inform on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>--and so on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> level <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> was clearly trying to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX> to keep
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mum</ENAMEX>. (That "We wouldn't want him around, would we ?" is vintage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, and it must have chilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX>.) On a more elementary level,
though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> is trying to persuade both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX> and himself that Felt would never
commit career suicide by blowing the whistle. That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> himself isn't entirely
convinced is suggested by the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> makes the point over and over,
even dragging in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> and all but saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> to turn in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alger Hiss</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> never entertains the possibility that Felt would do precisely
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Limpert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX> (and, subsequently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> himself) believed Felt to have
done: be an informer, but a secret informer, exacting the promise not of
lifetime employment but of lifetime confidentiality that he was
indeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>.

            Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felt</ENAMEX> has always denied it.

            
               I can tell you that it was not I and it is not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX>
            

            Felt told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limpert</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>. Felt also said:

            
               I don't think it will ever be resolved whether it was an actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or
a composite ... Very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had access to all this information--some of it
was available only at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, some only at very high levels in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House.</ENAMEX> ... I don't see that even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> had all that information.
Though possibly an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX>, possibly [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kleindienst</ENAMEX> .

            It's very tempting to read this comment as deliberate misdirection on Felt's
part. Chatterbox wonders what Felt would say now.

            Do any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> happen to know where to find him?

            [ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Update</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8/4/99</NUMEX> : After much pestering online and by phone,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has finally gotten The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> to post on its Web site <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX>'s watershed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX> piece. Click here and wonder no more about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX>'s place of
employment.]

         
      
   
