
   
   
      
         
            Death and Taxes
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> and legacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX> Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is tax cuts.
Other issues: various <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign blunders and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> leadership
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convention</ENAMEX> (really just another excuse to interview <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">If JFK Jr.</ENAMEX>'s death was uncontroversial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, it's doubly so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>.
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol Gang</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> )--praise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s eulogy for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> and remark that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Ted</ENAMEX> has finally emerged as a worthy family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> says that
although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy</ENAMEX> is often considered the lesser of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, he is
actually a much better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX> than either <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sr.</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX> was. Mild
criticisms come from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Gang</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>, who says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> was
a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>, not a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>," and from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX>, who says media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">overkill</ENAMEX> has given the story a cynical edge. Most shows
run more pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> frolicking with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John-John</ENAMEX>. A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>,
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX>, make an issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s assertion (later proven false) that he was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invite JFK Jr.</ENAMEX> back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> passage of an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $700 billion</NUMEX> tax cut takes up most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>' time. Almost all agree that it was a crucial victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hastert</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , pronounces it the
"end" of "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> era"). Nobody gives the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> bill a chance of becoming
law, but many--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> --think it marks the emergence of tax cuts as a major campaign
issue. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX> agree that tax cuts are less popular in an age of
prosperity than they were in the early <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> era, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Gang</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> plan gives too many breaks to the very wealthy.

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol Gang</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Thomas</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cal.</ENAMEX>, calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> tax cut figure a negotiating position with which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
"will engage." Later, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Sperling</ENAMEX>, announces that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will veto not only the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> bill
but also a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 billion</NUMEX> compromise plan put forth by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>--suggesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will not engage with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>.
( Late Edition incorporates this news into its discussion of tax
cuts.)

            Discussion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> focuses less on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> itself than on
cult-of-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>. After professing he doesn't have access to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">federal</ENAMEX> budget figures, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> that he thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> should cut <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700 billion</NUMEX> over
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> he invites <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> to run
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits pick</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">canoeing</TIMEX> misadventure in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, in which
local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> dumped <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seven million gallons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dried-out-riverbed for a Gore</ENAMEX> photo-op (unbenownst to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign). His
campaign has become "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murphy's Law</ENAMEX> in motion" says <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casting Stones</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Thomas</ENAMEX> tells
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Gang</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apostate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Forbes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>,
switched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> just to get media attention, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> says, "Let's not
pretend that altruism is an operative principle in politics all of a sudden,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>. You're not a virgin."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanned</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rested, and Ready</ENAMEX>? When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Snow</ENAMEX> asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> whether he will run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>
replies that he might, "or I could be a beach bum ... throw away my watch, just
know that when the sun comes up you get up, when it's straight overhead you eat
lunch, and when it goes down you go to bed."

         
      
   
