
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRC</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Chris</ENAMEX>,

            To begin with the end of your last entry, I find I have to give you some
ground on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s reflexive leftism. It is wrong to equate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>communism
with opposition to "all public improvements," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> does tend to caricature
all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>communism under the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">rubric Red Scare</ENAMEX>. (I can't see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s putting
"freedom" in quotes as anything but a perfectly respectable rhetorical device,
though. Are you the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Caldwell</ENAMEX> whose excellent recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX>
report on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> campaign included the observation that "most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'neighbors</ENAMEX>' " rustled up for her initial appearance were in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>?)

            I'm asking myself why I so easily read past all such lefty rhetoric in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bio</ENAMEX>; I pretty much took it as a given--like the local weather, as you so nicely
put it--and at least felt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> took no pains to conceal her point of view.
I suspect myself of an end-of-history mellowness about it. Which I raise
because it seems to speak to the question of why I come down on the side of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">admiring Eleanor</ENAMEX> but really can't bring myself to like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            Your theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s do-goodism is distinguished from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s by its
"reactive" nature doesn't quite work for me. (Even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> had a
miserable childhood, I don't buy it as the complete explanation for her empathy
toward the downtrodden. I was as least equally interested in--and impressed
by--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s awareness of how much <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> came to savor power.) I think it's
more about circumstance: When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> talked about the excitement of forming a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> order, well, she had a point. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> was in the
midst of saving capitalism from itself. And <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> was talking about the redress of
some of the more shameful circumstances of pre-war life: lynching, child labor,
total segregation, pervasive poverty. What's not to reorder?

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> came along, and spoke at a similar rhetorical pitch, she was
talking to a generation of contented fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX>, in an era of prosperity,
at a time when social norms have shifted hugely--to the good--in a more
progressive direction. No, the heaven of racial harmony has not been achieved,
and yes, of course any number of social pathologies persist. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> has
always seemed to chide us, as if we were all mossback fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'30s</NUMEX> who
were getting ready to go down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Trans-Lux</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> (isn't that
how that other great cartoon of the times went?).

            That note in her voice, of the unreconstructed left, is the same one I
pretty much tuned out in reading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s bio. I suspect the world is divided
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who tune it out and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are driven crazy by it, with a
small remaining percentage who agree with it. (These are the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
held rallies to support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> during his impeachment and called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> "ayatollahs.") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s success in driving some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> crazy with it
is what's made her so darned successful at attracting the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, at
least. But it leaves me--and, polls suggest, the vast majority of my fellow
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>--wishing a pox on all their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>.

            Still, the parallels between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> are irresistibly striking:
A bright, intense young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> marries a profligately charming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who takes her
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to his disapproving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. She is dashed by his flirtations (and more?)
with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> when he runs for office and she discovers her own
skills as a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. The higher he rises, the more she uses the role of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spouse</ENAMEX> (and some apparent sense, within the marriage, that he owes her) to
bring her own agenda to the fore. He needs her to organize him (he's always
late and always talks too long to any gathering) and also to bring in money for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the few years</TIMEX> he spends out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, the practice of law bores
him silly). She gradually finds that her marriage to him allows her to exercise
power in his name that she was never able to claim in her own right.

            But of course the other circumstance that makes the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> different is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> really had no initial way of claiming power for herself, whereas
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> could have launched her own political career <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades ago</TIMEX>, instead of
offering us that unnerving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-for-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the</NUMEX>-price-of-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> arrangement. This is a big
reason why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> mistrust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, whereas it made a lot of sense to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s</TIMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> should be a kind of shape-shifting adjunct to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.
(Not, as indicated above, that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> was innocent of personal ambition. "How I
hate doing these things and then they say someday I'll run for an office," she
complained. "Well, I'd have to be chloroformed first!" Sure, sure ...)

            But I've saved the most important thing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last</TIMEX>: How could you say that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>
was not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> for good? Do you think she was the opposite, or not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of
any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kind</ENAMEX>?

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Marjorie</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
