
   
   
      
         
            You <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can Lead a Kid to Bacon ...</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Steve</ENAMEX>,

            You're right, we began somber and became silly, which is a fair
representation of my breakfast table--I'm thinking of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
trajectory from stumbling glumly downstairs to fighting over the comics, except
that around my table the only audible dialogue is generally, "You done with
those yet?" punctuated by the clank of spoon against cereal bowl. There was a
phase a while back when I filled with resolve, for reasons then unclear to
myself but transparent to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female</ENAMEX> who has ever cracked the pages of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCall's</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Circle</ENAMEX> , to cook hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> at breakfast. I had
in mind the sort that appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, with the little wisps of steam
visible as the plates were lowered to the table. I made muffins, or scrambled
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> with green chiles and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheddar cheese</ENAMEX>, or crepes rolled around blackberry
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jam</ENAMEX>, or whole-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat pancakes</ENAMEX> with peanut-butter chips (I know, this sort of
fits into the category of manteca en su bolsillo , but they're actually
pretty good). There was a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacon</ENAMEX>, too. Something elemental about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacon</ENAMEX>:
the smell, I think. Also good sound effects. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> looked startled at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>,
large plates of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steaming food</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 a.m.</TIMEX>--What is going on around here? Is Mom
OK? Maybe better not ask. Then there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cafe</ENAMEX> phase: "Oh, look, it's
breakfast at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cafe</ENAMEX>."

            Then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> got up the nerve to say: Um, this is nice but you know I
really like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crispix</ENAMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, who had rattled both of his deeply secular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years earlier</TIMEX> by requesting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> mitzvah (for which, to our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">astonishment</ENAMEX>, he studied intently for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, delivering himself of a
whomping cantor-led performance and bar mitzvah speech in which he discussed in
serious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> voice his intense feeling about carrying on a tradition his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> had let lapse), told me kindly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> that he had stopped
eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> so maybe I could cut back on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacon</ENAMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, in the
interests of middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> health, dropped <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> and muffins from his diet. So
that was that for the wisps of steam at our breakfast table. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crispix</ENAMEX> came
back in force; in fact, the last time I was at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket</ENAMEX>, the checker
gazed at my overflowing cart and said: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lot</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cereal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eaters</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, are
there?"

            I do have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more somber thought, though, because I really am troubled
about this, even though I can see no way to let off even a tiny rant without
personally contributing to the very problem of which I speak: I do believe the
press, and in particular the broadcast press, took leave of its collective
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">senses</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> when that little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> disappeared--surely not the first
time such a thing has happened, but I am afraid that the net result, following
day after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> of relentless, nonstop, overblown, breathless, self-referential,
nearly entirely content-free coverage, has been the transformation of a single
publicly shared tragedy into something venomous. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just
furious at the coverage. I think fury at the coverage has in some measure
replaced what might have been a brief period of honorable,
modestly-proportioned mourning for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous people</ENAMEX> who died. I think we'll
be hearing about this for quite a while, and that the demonstrably low public
regard for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> will dip still lower in the wake of this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past week</TIMEX>. I know, we do this all the time, we did it when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> died, and we
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">will</ENAMEX> surely do it again--but it seems mysterious to me that in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> year
post-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>, when so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> looked back in embarrassment and agreed
that events and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>-think had sucked us into dreadful vacuous coverage from
which we felt unable to extricate ourselves, the same blind terror of losing
audience share could have overtaken assignment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> again.

            So that is my closing rant. I'm afraid the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that
for interest factor can be rated anywhere near your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Inconspicuous</ENAMEX>
Consumption is our full-color glossy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowrider</ENAMEX> , which
was given to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>--no, not himself a lowrider, his only available <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> is
the denuded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX>--as a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas present last year</TIMEX>. I have actually
become quite fascinated by this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> and was going to dig out the latest
issue to report on exactly which babes in bikini tops and pachuco pants
were jutting their hips out beside which gleaming, curvaceous, cherried-out
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20-ton</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. But it seems I was overcome by feminist bile <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX>
and tossed it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pity</ENAMEX>. I bet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lowrider</ENAMEX> is a hit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>. And is now the
time to say I can hardly wait for your impending new novel about the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alamo</ENAMEX>?

            It's been swell, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>, but do something about that lard in your pocket,
OK?

            Yr <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful correspondent</ENAMEX>,
CG

         
      
   
