
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Much-Prompted Impromptu Memorial</ENAMEX>

            Exactly how spontaneous was the spontaneous shrine erected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX>'s doorstep? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> was walking
through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TriBeCa</ENAMEX> and decided to pass by the impromptu memorial that she had been
hearing so much about on television. There wasn't much to see: a gaggle of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">onlookers milled</ENAMEX> around the block and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few dozen</NUMEX> floral bouquets rested on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stoop</ENAMEX>. Above them, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> hand-lettered signs had been pasted to the side
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. What was most unusual about the scene was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phalanx</ENAMEX> of
reporters aiming microphones and cameras at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">onlookers</ENAMEX>.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> arrived home, the news shows were still broadcasting from
the scene. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> described the "outpouring" of emotion at the makeshift
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shrine</ENAMEX>, mentioning the address over and over again: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">N. Moore St.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Moore St.</ENAMEX> The accompanying videotape used close-up shots and slow pans of the
not-entirely cluttered stoop; the camera lingered over the flickering flames of
memorial candles and the droplets of water clinging to the flower petals. What
had appeared in person to be a loose gathering now looked like the altar of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All Saints' Day</TIMEX>. It also looked suspiciously like the
memorials that had sprung up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzhak Rabin</ENAMEX>'s death and in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death.

            By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late last week</TIMEX>, the scene at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">N. Moore St.</ENAMEX> matched its televised
accounts. Neighborhood delis ran out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> were telling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">onlookers</ENAMEX> to "say a prayer and move it along, please." The hill of bouquets had
become so mountainous that it had to be carted off to a local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital</ENAMEX> and the candles so many that they started a small fire.

         
      
   
