
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER's Sentimental Politics</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Marjorie</ENAMEX>,

            I must have overcompressed my last letter, because you've read as a single
argument what I meant as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) By "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrichian</ENAMEX>," I meant profiting off
governmental power that is not really your property. Maybe that's a problem,
maybe not. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s using the money she made to reward like-minded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">philanthropists</ENAMEX> (hence, buy political support) doesn't change the ethics of it.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) For someone intent on remaking the social order, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> was working with a
curiously narrow definition of privilege, a definition that left her lifestyle
largely untouched.

            Another thing: I didn't say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> was dictatorial, but anyone who sent a
friendly greeting to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Nazi</ENAMEX> rally in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Square Garden</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX> (a
discovery for which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> deserves great credit) was worth keeping an eye on.
The most high-handed moment of his presidency--the attempt to pack the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>--is made the worse by his almost insane assertion that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> was one of the "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> horses" pulling the New Deal "plow."
Without calling him undemocratic, one can wonder what his idea of democracy
was.

            The best point either of us made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all week</TIMEX> was your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX> about the
division of labor between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>. You asked,

            
               Did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bifurcated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> do a disservice in
providing a model for later <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX>, in which poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX> and the halt were insidiously sentimentalized as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s
work?
            

             My answer would be: Yes, we're still stuck with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>--although I
wouldn't blame <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eleanor</ENAMEX> for it. And I'm less bothered by the gender stereotyping
it entails than by the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>/bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> tactics through which it gets played
out.

            Because sentimental politics can be a way to fob off rhetorical
solutions on people demanding practical ones. Sometimes this is a good way to
defuse radicalism which would otherwise be hard to answer. When the Bonus
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marchers</ENAMEX> came back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> couldn't tell them to take a hike, but he
couldn't cave in to them, either, without unleashing similar protests across
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. So he gave them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hots</NUMEX>-and<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-a-cot</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Potomac</ENAMEX> and sent
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eleanor out to sing "It's a Long Way to Tipperary</ENAMEX>" with them.

            But sometimes sentimental politics is merely a way to salve one's conscience
when real action is possible and one would prefer to do nothing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> feels FDR
did much less than he could have to help <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1930s</TIMEX>.
She's right. But I would ask whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s public hand-wringing didn't
provide him with cover for his inaction. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> note: If I left the impression
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s pacifism extended to support for unilateral
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disarmament</ENAMEX> , I should be clear that--particularly as war approached--it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decidedly</ENAMEX> did not.)

            You're right that it's race where the interplay between rhetorical and
programmatic politics was most complex. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> snorts throughout at the demands
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jubal Early</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>, that "racial
etiquette" be respected. But at some level she understands that it was
a matter of etiquette. The guerrilla warfare of manners that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>
waged--showing up in public with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary McLeod Bethune</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter White</ENAMEX>, turning
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> into a place where black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were routinely seen coming in
and going out the front door--may have been the most effective way to strike
against racism at a time of severely limited options. (Of course, it alone
could never carry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull Connor</ENAMEX> advised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> matters until
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>'s death, ran <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost three decades</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s sit-down
protest, and was even the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committeeman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> during
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> administration.)

            You also noted early on that some of the "mixedness" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> was lost in Volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . I liked this book better
than the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, but I think you're right. I never quite figured out, for
example, what the particular crisis was that left <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hick</ENAMEX> worried that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>
would ditch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> on the eve of re-election--although it's another tidbit to add
to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton-Roosevelt Parallels</ENAMEX> file. Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hick</ENAMEX>, bereft of career, living in
a perpetual state of low-intensity jiltedness ("Miss you so much," runs the
typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> letter, "but you'd hate it here so don't come "),
traveling the barrooms of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s eyes and ears, remains for
me the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of the book.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marjorie</ENAMEX>, it's been a delight to correspond with you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. Best wishes
until we meet again--perhaps over Volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> of some future <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>-volume
biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosalynn Carter</ENAMEX>.

            Yours,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>

             

         
      
   
