
   
   
      
         
            Keeping Up With the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bushes</ENAMEX>

Times lead with the grisly massacre of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>,
reported by the latter paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
fronts the story as well. Each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> marks this as the worst attack yet
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holdouts</ENAMEX>, and predicts that it will spur even more
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> to flee. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> has denied the killings, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
LAT nod that no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> have emerged. But an anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> official
confides to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> that a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> is responsible.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story, headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Serbs Killed Within Earshot</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Troops</ENAMEX>,"
stresses the proximity of Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and their inability to suppress this
kind of outbreak of violence.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>, green with envy at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s well-stocked war chest, is on an all-out drive to soak up soft
money contributions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' Plan A is to raise as much soft money as
possible; if they come up short, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plan B</ENAMEX> is to adopt a folksy,
you-can't-buy-the-presidency spin. Not only is this approach disingenuous,
suggests the article, but it's also hypocritical: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> are all nominally committed to campaign finance reform. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> both report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has already slammed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> for
his unbridled pursuit of cash. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> camp, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ,
responded with the old necessity defense, accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> of wanting to leave
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> "to fend for themselves."

            The WP fronts a long account of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s midlife crisis,
circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, led to his acceptance of faith and embrace of politics. The story,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sourced</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and some of his closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consorts</ENAMEX>, describes his former drinking
habit in explicit terms ("if not clinically an alcoholic, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> sometimes came
close to the line," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ) and his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> use in implicit
ones (Says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, "I've told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I've learned from my mistakes-and I have.")
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" piece ticks off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> potential catastrophes that
could jeopardize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s coronation as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate-designate</ENAMEX>. The
scenarios: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> could lose his temper, be skewered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>-sponsored ads,
remain hopelessly fuzzy on the issues, be resented for his vast campaign (and
inherited) resources, get cocky, fall apart in an early primary, or be felled
by a scandalous skeleton rattling in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, a piece inside the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> puzzles over former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s newfound popularity in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> circles. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush Sr.</ENAMEX> was ostracized for running a lousy campaign
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> he is basking in newfound admiration. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> mentions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush Sr.</ENAMEX>'s glow of popularity has rubbed off on his son,
but never considers that it might be the other way around.

            Another WP front-pager reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has arrested <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 4,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> in its efforts to suppress the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX> sect, making this
the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> crackdown since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>
uprising. A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece posits that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> are flocking to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX> because they're worried about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s stalled economy. The article
does an excellent job of describing the potential burden of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s size: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">With</ENAMEX>
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.3 billion</NUMEX> that expands at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> must add at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5 million</NUMEX> jobs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> just to absorb the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> entering the labor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX>," it explains. Unemployment currently ranges from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> in more remote areas.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 
               Magazine cover story frets about a future when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> will select their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s gender. An experimental process dubbed
"Microsort" separates <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm</ENAMEX> carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> chromosomes (which create <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>) from
those carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> chromosomes, so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> can impregnate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with embryos
of the preferred gender. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ethicists</ENAMEX> fear that the technique will further
institutionalize sex discrimination.

            It seems that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> will have to revise their casualty numbers for
both the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> conflict and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> shootings. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pooh-bahs</ENAMEX> whine that their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> fund-raising drive was stymied by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkan</ENAMEX> war and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> massacre, each of which caused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s to cancel potentially lucrative events. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX> grouse that
these interruptions cost the party <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an estimated $6 million</NUMEX> in
contributions.

         
      
   
