
   
   
      
         
            High Life on the Potomac

            I am not
now--and never have been--a fan of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>'s economics or politics.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fourteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, I said in a review of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his books:

            This book has three
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX>: a description of the terrible present state and future prospects of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy, a theory of the causes of that dreadful condition, and a
prescription for rescuing us. The description of our condition is grossly
exaggerated. The theory of the causes of the alleged condition is inadequately
supported. The prescription is, with some exceptions, unpersuasive.

            Reading
his new book, Locked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alfred A. Knopf</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">338</NUMEX> pages; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>),
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about his four years</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of labor from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993 through 1996</TIMEX>, I find that
he has not changed his mind--or I mine--even though his new book gives us a
closer look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> than the earlier ones did. He does not come
through as particularly admirable. He is self-righteous and self-pitying. He is
unfair, often in a petty way, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with whom he disagrees--notably, for
some reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>. And his treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, his longtime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> a national figure by appointing him to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>, is,
if not exactly disloyal, surely unseemly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> comes through, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s
account, as an amiable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>, and a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX>, who is
nonetheless unprincipled, indecisive, and overwhelmed by the responsibilities
that come with the presidency. He is the kind of person least qualified to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and most likely to become one. There are plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> other than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> who could have told us all that. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> didn't have to do
it--or he could at least have waited until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was out of office. But, as
the saying goes, they all do it.

            Iput all these negatives up front so that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> won't
think that I have gone off my rocker when I say I enjoyed much of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Locked</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> and ended it feeling sorry for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>. The book has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
interwoven parts--a policy part and a life part. The policy part I find
inadequate and unconvincing. The life part I find fascinating. The story in the
policy part goes like this:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> with
a policy for relieving the suffering of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>. That policy
included stronger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, corporate responsibility, a higher minimum wage and,
most important, more federal spending on--or, as he would say, federal
investment in--job training and retraining. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year</TIMEX> effort to get
this policy adopted was largely defeated by the opposition of Wall Street, Big
Business, rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in general--and their hirelings or dupes in the
government. The main instrument they used for defeating him was a call for
obeisance to a false god, Balancing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX>. So our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> leaves the
battlefield with his head bloody but only slightly bowed.

            What value
you assign to this story depends on how valid you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s policy is. If
his policy would have been the salvation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>, the story of
its defeat is a tragic drama. If the policy was mistaken and would have been
ineffective anyway, there is no drama, no tragedy, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, and no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>. In
that case, his endless kvetching about training and the rest of it is a bore to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, as I suspect it sometimes was to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            
But aside from relating a few anecdotes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>
makes no effort to demonstrate the validity of his prescription. He could
hardly do so in a book like this one. The issues are complicated and difficult.
Job training is an example. That the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should support job
training is not a new idea. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> was taken by that idea
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years ago</TIMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$180 billion</NUMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>
dollars, on job training and employment programs. Probably <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $1 billion</NUMEX>
has been spent on research to evaluate these programs, trying to measure their
benefits and costs. My understanding of the conclusion of all this research is
that for male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, there was no net benefit and for female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, very
little. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> may have reason to dispute that conclusion. But to explain that
and convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> of it would require sophisticated analysis of a mass of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> and would be an entirely different book from the collection of personal
reminiscences he has produced.

            If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> bypass all that, however, and remind themselves not to enter into
policy debate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, they will find the other part of the book--the
life part--interesting, enjoyable, and valuable. This part is about what it is
like to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>. What does he do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>? What, if anything,
goes on at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> meeting? How can the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>,
all presumably on the same team, meet for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> to talk about the budget
without getting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step forward? How does one prepare for and behave at a
congressional hearing? What do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk about, and eat, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">receptions</ENAMEX> and dinners? How does it feel to address a meeting of hostile
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>, or to meet the press, or to appear on television with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Leno</ENAMEX>? And
so on.

            Idid not share all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s experiences when I was in the
government. But I observed such life enough to say that his picture is
realistic. (I was, however, shocked when he said that the cabins at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Camp David</ENAMEX>
were "mildewed." Things must have gone down a lot after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nixon</ENAMEX>
administration.) He tells this story with a vividness that I did not expect of
him, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX>, some irony, and touches of gallows humor. There are much
better books by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Shultz</ENAMEX>'s, for
example--but none that I know of that is so rich in personal detail.

            This book
is not a road map for improving the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy. It will probably have no
effect on future elections or public policy. But that is not the important test
of a book. This one can give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> pleasure and amusement, and also help them
understand a little better the world we live in. I have learned, mainly from
talking with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>, that everyone's life is interesting if you know
enough about it. That is true of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> as well as of taxi
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>.

            
So, why am I sorry for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>? It is
certainly not because he failed to get most of his policy proposals adopted. It
is because he did not enjoy his life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. His <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> here were
the most exciting part of his whole life and could have been the happiest part
of his professional <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. But he got no pleasure from it. He was so determined
to maintain his self-image of moral superiority that he could not relax to
enjoy his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> experience. I feel that after it was over, he realized he
may have missed something. In the epilogue, on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">334</NUMEX>, he says, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>]y job was
the most fascinating and rewarding I could ever hope for." But in the preceding
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">333</NUMEX> pages, derived from notes taken during his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> in office, we have
the picture of an angry and unhappy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. That is why I am sorry for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
