
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cult, the Comet</ENAMEX>, and the Web

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heaven's Gate</ENAMEX> mass
suicide promises to be the first great Internet mystery. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">UFO</ENAMEX>/computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> "shed their containers," they left behind a trove of
clues on the Internet about their work, their suicide, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale-Bopp</ENAMEX> comet.
Here's an introduction.

            Early news reports link the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rancho Santa Fe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to a loopy, apocalyptic Web site called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heaven's Gate</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warning</ENAMEX>: This
site and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> described below have been overwhelmed with traffic since
news of the suicide broke. Don't be surprised if you're denied access.)
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heaven's Gate</ENAMEX> introductory page, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale-Bopp</ENAMEX> comet heralds
the imminent arrival of an alien <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spacecraft</ENAMEX> "from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evolutionary Level Above</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom of Heaven</ENAMEX>)": The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">UFO</ENAMEX> may be traveling in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">comet</ENAMEX>'s wake.
(For more on the Internet controversy about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>-Bopp <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">UFO</ENAMEX>, click .)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spacecraft</ENAMEX> is coming to
transport "us" (whoever "us" might be) back to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom of Heaven</ENAMEX>." This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ascension</ENAMEX> will constitute " 'graduation' from the human evolutionary level. We
are happily prepared to leave 'this world' and go with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ti</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heaven's Gate</ENAMEX> Web site
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chronicles</ENAMEX>, if opaquely, the purported history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. A message from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>--the "Statement by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.T. Presently Incarnate</ENAMEX>"--relates that he
and his female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do" and "Ti"</ENAMEX>) are actually genderless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom of Heaven</ENAMEX>. They and their "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>" arrived on earth "in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">staged</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spacecraft</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">UFO</ENAMEX>) crashes." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1970s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> became human
by taking over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of a middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Before
becoming human, they presumably looked like this "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom of Heaven</ENAMEX>." He/She/It is a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ringer</ENAMEX> for the stereotypical
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unsolved Mysteries</ENAMEX> alien--big baby eyes, bulging alien forehead, tiny
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ears</ENAMEX>, silver skin.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heaven</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate</ENAMEX> warns
explicitly that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> are considering suicide.
"Our
Position <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Against Suicide</ENAMEX>," which ought to be titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Our Position in Favor</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suicide</ENAMEX>," hints darkly that "the powers that control the world" could
torture or imprison the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> "as occurred at both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby Ridge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX>." It
praises the legendary mass suicide of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masada</ENAMEX> as a "more dignified"
method of escape. "We have thoroughly discussed this topic (of the willful exit
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> under such conditions), and have mentally prepared ourselves for
this possibility." Not that suicide is anything to worry about: The spacecraft
would still transport them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom of Heaven</ENAMEX>. When they leave, the rest
of us are in big trouble: According to the transcript
of a video called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Chance to Evacuate Planet Earth Before It's</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recycled</ENAMEX> , "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he planet is about to be recycled, refurbished, started over.
That doesn't mean it's going to be destroyed. ... But it does mean that it is
going to be spaded under."

            The site makes a weak
attempt to enlist new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> for the voyage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom of Heaven</ENAMEX>. The
introductory page invites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to study the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heaven's Gate</ENAMEX> site and tells
them that "you may even find your 'boarding pass' to leave with us." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> and
other news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> have reported that Heaven's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> trolled Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chatrooms</ENAMEX> to find potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX>.

            But the suicides were more
than just <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">UFO cultists</ENAMEX>. They were also computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX>. They ran
Higher Source, a
Web-design <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rancho Santa Fe</ENAMEX>. In retrospect, it's easy to see something
sinister in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Source</ENAMEX> site. It is decorated with the same astral images
that appear on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heaven's Gate</ENAMEX> site, including several prominent pictures of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comets</ENAMEX>. The site brags about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Source</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>-minded effort," and mentions
that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> at the core of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> have worked closely together for
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>." (Heaven's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate</ENAMEX> hints that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> was founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>.)

            But the site makes clear
that what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Source</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> did is no different from what other Web
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> do. They programmed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Java</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C++</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Visual Basic</ENAMEX>, used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shockwave</ENAMEX>,
QuickTime, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AVI</ENAMEX>, and claimed familiarity with Unix and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novell Netware</ENAMEX>. Their
choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> was more ecumenical than cultish. They designed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
sites (Keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX>
sells <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> music) and low-culture sites (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pre-Madonna</ENAMEX> hypes an early
Madonna record). They did snooty culture--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Diego Polo Club</ENAMEX>, a topiary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and a firm
that specializes in fancy
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> parts. These <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> betray no trace of Heaven's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weirdness</ENAMEX>. They are, if anything, banal.

            The suicides will strand
Higher Source's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> has certainly delivered on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> promise it
made them: to promote "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strategies to Increase Web Traffic</ENAMEX>." As strategies for
increasing Web traffic go, a mass suicide can't be beat.

         
      
   
