
   
   
      
         
            Apology Not Accepted

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury Center</ENAMEX>, the interactive
online site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Jose Mercury News</ENAMEX> , is buzzing with anger at a new
target-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury News</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Ceppos</ENAMEX>. The subject was the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newspaper</ENAMEX>'s controversial series of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last August</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dark Alliance</ENAMEX>,"
which alleged that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> had promoted the sale of crack <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
as part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nicaraguan Contras</ENAMEX> in the
1980s.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ceppos</ENAMEX> wrote that the series had been irresponsibly written and
edited, and that it had failed to prove any wrongdoing on the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Online</ENAMEX> scandal-mongers immediately labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ceppos</ENAMEX> a turncoat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who
wrote the series, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Webb</ENAMEX>, called the column "nauseating," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, said that it shed "nothing new" on the debate over the
credibility of the allegations. Meanwhile, the mainstream media and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
heralded the end of an irresponsible story.

            The Internet is being blamed--and praised--for allowing
this story to gain so much stature. Despite being dissed and then shot down by
such standard-bearers as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury News</ENAMEX> allegations
spread like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> had in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, causing national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to scurry around
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two months</TIMEX> after "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dark Alliance</ENAMEX>" appeared, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Deutch</ENAMEX> made a rare public appearance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Central Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX> to answer the charges of an angry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>.

            The Web enabled "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alliance</ENAMEX>" to bypass the mainstream media and enter the forefront of national
debate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury News</ENAMEX> began touting its upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">series</ENAMEX> on Internet
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">newsgroups weeks</TIMEX> before it was completed. The electronic version was published
simultaneously with the print version, with the added features of hypertext
links to cited documents, audio tracks from wiretaps and hearings, and an image
(which was later removed) of the official stamp of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, superimposed on a
crack smoker. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of the story's appearance, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2,500</NUMEX> other Web
sites had linked directly to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury Center</ENAMEX>, causing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> additional hits a
day for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> afterward.

            For
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Final Call Online</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation of Islam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>, linked to the
piece with a short commentary titled "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA Drug Pipeline</ENAMEX>: How the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Government spread <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Black ghetto</ENAMEX>." ParaScope, one of
several online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> rich in conspiracy-theorizing, attached this headline:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contras Linked</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crack Trade</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Webzine Salon</ENAMEX> headlined its
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webb</ENAMEX> "Your worst fears are true--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> did help smuggle drugs
into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> ghettos, says an investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Parry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX>
of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> news story that first reported that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contras</ENAMEX> had
engaged in drug trafficking, is now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of an online news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consortium</ENAMEX>,
and has been promoting the story. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consortium</ENAMEX> charges for
access, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parry</ENAMEX>'s editorial in The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX>, endorsing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webb</ENAMEX>'s story, is available at no charge.

            
But it was the chat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that really whipped
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into a frenzy. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Usenet</ENAMEX> newsgroups--a hotbed of discussion on the
topic--may be accessed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> only, the topic spawned independent forums
with such titles as "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-Crack Connection</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black Experience</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Drug Connection</ENAMEX>." These <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> were
filled with stinging indictments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the mainstream media as
well as gleeful cheers for the Web. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader Forum</ENAMEX> (the original responses to the series are all still
available) wrote: "We have to raise hell! ... The power of the Web cannot be
underestimated." The overwhelming majority of chat-room <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> seem to
accept the premise of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dark Alliance</ENAMEX>," and to spend their time arguing over the
connections to other perceived conspiracies like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> assassination or that
more recent fave, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> land dealings. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> submitted this helpful
tip: "If you enjoy this conspiracy, you may want to visit the Squirrel
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Conspiracy Home Page</ENAMEX>."

            The
contagious hyperbole of the Internet clearly had an impact on the life of "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alliance</ENAMEX>." As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfer</ENAMEX> noted: "The outrage of the freshly exposed readers
is refreshing to see." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Webb</ENAMEX> himself joined the fray on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader Forum</ENAMEX>, and was clearly energized by his online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. His first
posting, dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 19</TIMEX>, reads thus: "Since I've been living with this story for
so long, it ceased to shock me long ago. I'm glad to see it still has some
punch." This was mild compared with his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1</TIMEX> attack on a lone Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfer</ENAMEX> who
raised questions about "proof" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> involvement: "That's like saying there's
no proof of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX>' involvement in making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webb</ENAMEX> raged. "I
also heard a great line while I was doing a radio show in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>:
Now we know what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> really stands for<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">--Crack In America</ENAMEX>."

            The feedback on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> and on radio talk shows fed each
other, creating an alternative media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> that shouted down the objections
of the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> and catapulted the series to national prominence. Anger
at the mainstream media overwhelms anger at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in many of these
forums. "How long will <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koppel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">co.</ENAMEX> dance away from this one?" asked one
Internet chatter. Black-oriented radio-show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> repeatedly plugged the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury News</ENAMEX> Web site in their broadcasts, and it became, in the words
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black America</ENAMEX>." From there, political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Boxer</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kweisi Mfume</ENAMEX> began calling for investigations, and the mainstream
press was forced to write metastories with headlines like this one, from the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 21</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Though Evidence is Thin, Tale</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drugs</ENAMEX>
Has <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life Of Its Own</ENAMEX>." Other news sites and respected political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> began to link to the series.

            The
widespread attention merely fueled the "us vs. them" sentiment of most Internet
discussions on the topic. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ceppos</ENAMEX> wrote his apologetic column, he was
merely saying what "they" had been saying all along. "Granted, there may be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inconsistencies</ENAMEX>, there may be fallacies, but why not take up the banner of
truth and march on?" argues <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webhead</ENAMEX>. The impact of the Internet has been
twofold: Not only has it allowed the series to leapfrog the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>,
but it has also made the mainstream press as much the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. The
fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ceppos</ENAMEX> has defected to the dark side merely <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX> the fire.

         
      
   
