
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica and Me</ENAMEX>

            I can imagine you saying,
"What's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> to him, or he to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica?</ENAMEX>" But, in fact, we are quite close.

            For <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
thing, I am her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>. I live in the East building of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>,
and she lives in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. It is said that she lives, with her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX>, next-door to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>. From the deck of my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> I can look
across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less than a hundred yards</NUMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> apartment. So, I
suppose I can look at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s presence is manifest. A picture of him getting a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">haircut</ENAMEX> is on the wall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">barbershop</ENAMEX>. Sometimes, when in the
swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pool</ENAMEX>, I have seen the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> on his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX> and exchanged a word with
him. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX>, before the presidential election campaign, I met him coming
out of the drugstore and used the occasion to advise him that cutting taxes was
not a winning issue. He did not take my advice, and now he is known chiefly as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>.

            I don't
think I have ever seen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>. There are always several young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, many of
them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington University</ENAMEX>, buying <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watergate Safeway</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, the overage <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lolita</ENAMEX>, may have been one of them--but
of course, I would not have singled her out for attention before the publicity.
In fact, I don't think I could pick her out in a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> even
now--unless she were embracing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Him I would recognize.

            
When I come out of my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> I usually see a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> waiting near the entrance to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watergate South</ENAMEX>, hoping to
get a glimpse of her. There used to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 or 20</TIMEX>. Now there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Some days</TIMEX> there are none. As I write this, on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, there are none.
Perhaps she has gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Passover</TIMEX>. Maybe, now that the Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case has been thrown out, the paparazzi will leave her alone and
she will feel free to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safeway</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> bring
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">folding chairs</ENAMEX>. They seem in no hurry. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">rainy days</TIMEX> they sit under umbrellas
and wrap their cameras in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX>. I saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> whom I knew slightly
and asked if he had sighted her. He had been there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> and had not.
In fact, I have never seen her on television coming out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>, but I
may just have missed it.

            I wonder
if the work of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> is in the GDP. Of course, it wouldn't be.
They are an input. The output will be a shot on television of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>, and the
value of that will be in the GDP. Someone evidently thinks this value
will exceed the cost of keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>. And who will pay
that cost? Why, you and I, TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX>, will pay, via the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soft drinks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX> we buy.

            But residential proximity is not my only connection to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>. I am a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cosmos Club</ENAMEX>, a rather conservative--some would say
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stuffy</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> in an old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massachusetts Avenue</ENAMEX>. The membership is also
pretty old, although not as old as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, stays there when he is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. He is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the Cosmos
but does belong to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> with which the Cosmos has reciprocal
arrangements. He has met with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> at the Cosmos and once had an interview
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX> there. Naturally this brought the press crowding around
the entrance. In fact, one pressed so close, his foot was run over by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limousine</ENAMEX>. There was no serious damage, however; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> are a hardy lot.
There's probably a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> in it for him. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> tried to get into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">club</ENAMEX> by tapping a connection with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, but he was refused
admission on the reasonable grounds that he wasn't wearing a necktie.

            There
hasn't been so much excitement around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> since a vote was taken, 10 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> who had voted no on that
occasion was heard to say, "See, you admit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and the next thing you know
you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX> hanging around." But
on the whole, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> took the excitement with good humor and were amused
by the irony of the difference in culture between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cosmos Club</ENAMEX> and the Oval
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>.

            
Igave a lecture on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aviv</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>. I did not mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> in my lecture, but the first
question I was asked was how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could do his job with all the
distractions caused by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair. I gave my stock answer: In
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, we don't know the truth; in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> place, the presidency
is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. Presumably some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, such as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of the treasury</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX>, were not that distracted.
I had my own experience, during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, of carrying on
despite swirling scandal.

            Later, I thought the subject
required more analysis. One had to separate the relationship, whatever it was,
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> before it hit the headlines from what
happened afterward. I remember that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> complained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX>
was distracted from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> because he was out playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>
so much. But we were told, and I think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> accepted the explanation,
that golf relaxed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ike</ENAMEX> from the stresses of his job and enabled him to perform
better. A similar explanation was offered, but privately, to some in the press
who were aware of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s sexual conduct. Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
relationships can be justified in the same way. That would assume, of course,
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> did not feel any psychological stress from realizing he was
behaving in what many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> regard as an immoral way. That apparently was no
problem for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>. About <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> we don't know.

            After the alleged
relationship became public property, the situation was different. Certainly
there was much distraction at that point. What we have to ask, however, is
whether that was a bad thing. Would it be better for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> too, for that matter, to be able to give their undivided attention
to getting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> across that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next millennium</TIMEX> than it is to
have them distracted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> affair? I'm not sure.

         
      
   
