
   
   
      
         
            Nothing but Net

            The Internet is a moving
target. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Every minute</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> pages are updated or abandoned. Messages
sent to newsgroups replace older postings. All but a fraction of the chat-room
conversations and digital images that streak across the Net vanish after
they're displayed.

            Seeking
to preserve the chaos of the Net for posterity is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brewster Kahle</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX>, a server, and a lot of magnetic tape. Kahle, who once designed
computers for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thinking Machines Corp.</ENAMEX>, founded the Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archive</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> to
collect and store all the disparate bits of the Internet. From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidio</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> base adjacent to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Gate Bridge</ENAMEX>,
the Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archive</ENAMEX>'s powerful computer the Internet at high speeds.
Consulting intelligent algorithms about what information to store and how
often, the archive's computer copies data to tape cassettes on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantum</ENAMEX>
DLT4500 recorder. When each cassette is full, a robotic arm removes it, stores
it in a carousel, and replaces it with a blank <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            The Internet may seem impossibly vast to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, but in fact
it's quite finite. The entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web</ENAMEX> is currently estimated to contain
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1.5</NUMEX> terabytes (or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.5 million megabytes</NUMEX>) of data. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newsgroups,</ENAMEX> , and other
Internet subsystems account for another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.5</NUMEX> or so terabytes. (Compare these
numbers with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> terabytes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASCII</ENAMEX> data contained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 million</NUMEX> books or the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> terabytes of data at the average video
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">store</ENAMEX>.) With tape-cassette storage costing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $20</NUMEX> per gigabyte (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 billion</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bytes</ENAMEX>), archiving the Internet is practically economical. Already, the
archivists have stockpiled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2</NUMEX> terabytes of the Net, and currently
they're storing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 100</NUMEX> gigabytes of data <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>. Faster connections to
the Net promise to speed things up, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kahle</ENAMEX> estimates that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> will be
done by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 1997</TIMEX>.

            Storing
the Internet once is only the beginning. As experienced Web surfers
know, things change rapidly on the Net. The archive doesn't have the computer
muscle to store the publicly available Internet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>, but even if it did,
a lot of stuff would still fall through the cracks. On sites like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, breaking news comes and goes
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every minute</TIMEX>, which means pages disappear faster than they can currently be
squirreled away. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is updated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>. Shifting faster still are Web sites
generated by databases, such as the online bookstore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Because the
information these sites produce is specific to a user's experience, they can
generate a literally infinite number of different pages. Finally, much of the
traffic on the Internet is dynamic--chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, instant messages, and now even
phone conversations. To archive the Internet with absolute fidelity would
require cloning not only every computer on the Internet, but also every person
using every computer.

            
Many responsible netizens already archive
themselves for selfish reasons. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archiving</ENAMEX> is a no-brainer for publication sites
like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">The Gate</ENAMEX>, which collects the contents of the daily
newspaper and connects them to a good search engine. And other sites like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deja News</ENAMEX> already
assemble postings from the Internet newsgroups.
            

            Where the
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archive</ENAMEX> trumps these archives, of course, is in its sheer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comprehensiveness</ENAMEX>. While it isn't a replica of the Internet, it's a start. And
it's not useful just to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>. Suppose your Web browser allowed you to
specify not only an address but also a date. Remember that headline you saw on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wired News</ENAMEX> , but
have been unable to find since? The headline was posted for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a day</TIMEX>, and you
haven't had much luck using the site's search tool to locate the piece. But
using the Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archive</ENAMEX> to turn back the hands of time will uncover it for
you. And what about your teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>'s Web page, with that cute picture of
her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mohawk</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cousin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> cancelled her ISP account, and now the site is
gone. But an intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">browser</ENAMEX> could catch the "no such site" error and look
it up on the archive instead, displaying the last-known version. Did your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite politician</ENAMEX> really just flip-flop on your hot-button issue? Compare
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s campaign Web site with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s. These are just a few of the many
valuable services that promise to keep the nonprofit Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archive</ENAMEX> richly
endowed.

            Useful though it might be, the idea of archiving the
Internet is assailed by all sides. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Berreby</ENAMEX> argued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> that exhaustive
documentation of our world threatens to box us into a corner. The recent
"Documenting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital</ENAMEX>
Age" conference gathered experts from the computing, telecommunication, and
archiving worlds to explore these issues. Corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> complained that
because their archives are routinely subpoenaed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, they
have every incentive to shred their data instead of preserving them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX>
worried aloud about privacy and copyright <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>. Should you have the right
to exclude your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> page from the archive? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consensus</ENAMEX> opinion: Yes.) Should
we be saving usage logs, which detail every page a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> sees? (Probably not.)
Doesn't this whole thing violate current copyright laws left and right? (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Almost</ENAMEX>
certainly.) Should those laws be amended to allow such an archive?
(Probably.)

            Professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archivists</ENAMEX> argue
that it's a waste of time to store the Internet without providing a proper
historical context. Others say that having too 
               much information
about the Web at our disposal will be as bad as not having enough. They add
that finding things promptly on the Web with a search engine is hard enough,
that using it as a historical research tool would be incredibly painful. They
advocate an orderly weeding, assembling, and categorizing of digital records.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s chief technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Myhrvold</ENAMEX>,
whose "Save the Web" memo <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> helped start the archive movement, counters
that we don't know now what will be important later. Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> might grow up
to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, at which point her teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mohawk</ENAMEX> Web site will become
substantially more important than it is now. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myhrvold</ENAMEX> adds that it's better to
start saving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s Internet now, even if it is badly collected and organized,
rather than lose it forever.

            And to
think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brewster Kahle</ENAMEX> thought he was just solving a problem by starting the
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archive</ENAMEX>, and not introducing lots of new ones.

         
      
   
