
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Permanent Bank Holiday</ENAMEX>

            Old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, long
gaseous with self-regard (self-esteem is for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>), suffered a grievous
deflating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 13</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of America</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">builder</ENAMEX> of new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX>; capitalizer of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Dream</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX>, indeed, gallant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Gate Bridge</ENAMEX>--announced its
merger with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NationsBank</ENAMEX> to form <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BankAmerica</ENAMEX> and its plans to move bank
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>

            There
is a loss of face in the move of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>'s home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, as well as a blow to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>'s economy. To many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Franciscans</ENAMEX>, the rejection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is
regarded as an insult to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BofA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.P. Giannini</ENAMEX>. Old-timers recall that
Giannini, who kept his desk on the banking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> itself, made loans to working
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> after inspecting their hands: If the loan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> had callused hands
that meant he was working, and he got the loan.

            
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 49 years</TIMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giannini</ENAMEX>'s death, the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BofA</ENAMEX> has discarded much of the old way, but even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the bank
supports urbanity high and low. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> it donated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $5 million</NUMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">greater San Francisco</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$178,000</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Opera</ENAMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> cash-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-par public benefits checks without requiring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> to have bank accounts there.

            While
there was no run on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> in the wake of the news, so great was the shock
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> made grief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> available to the stricken <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh</ENAMEX>
McColl, No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NationsBank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the combined operation, sought to
reassure the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, koaning at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> meeting, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> is
where we are. Now we're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This afternoon</TIMEX> we'll be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX> was bad enough, but by suggesting
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HQ</ENAMEX> is now also in much despised <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Franciscans</ENAMEX> say the
definition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Money</ENAMEX> is someone whose checks clear the bank the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time,
was a very bitter pill.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Mayor Willie Brown</ENAMEX> spoke for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> when he said, "They're stealing
our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>!" And while it may not be an actual defalcation, it certainly is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abscondment</ENAMEX>. The deal talks, worked out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only three weeks</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s
appropriately named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mandarin Hotel</ENAMEX>, were carried out in utter secrecy. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is an important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>--it has been so throughout the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s history," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> said. "It'll be a shock to our economy, an economic
crisis."

            
The most wired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a wired <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> learned of the merger at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 a.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 13</TIMEX>, when a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Examiner reporter</ENAMEX> called to tell him the deal was being announced then in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>.

            To old
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">San Franciscans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hands</ENAMEX> have shaken the hands of those who came in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gold Rush</ENAMEX>, the move is an act of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">l√®se-majest√</NUMEX>©, an impertinence rivaling
only that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Ralston</ENAMEX>, who chose to go for a refreshing swim in the harbor
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day in 1875</TIMEX> when his mighty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of California</ENAMEX> was crashing, rather than
stay at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralston</ENAMEX> drowned. Of course, in financial circles, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McColl</ENAMEX>,
who constructed the deal, is believed to be able to walk on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.

            The deal is colossal. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>, which might as
well have been named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TitanicBank</ENAMEX>, will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' largest, with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$570</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> in assets. It will:

            be the No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> in loans,
deposits, business lending (large and small), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATMs</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15,000</NUMEX>);

            be the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' first
coast-to-coast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, operating in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> contiguous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>,
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>;

            process
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> checks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            Currently the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> has
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> are largely
noncompeting, some will be closed, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 15,000</NUMEX> jobs are expected to be
eliminated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Staffers</ENAMEX> at the redundant former <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BofA</ENAMEX> are believed
to be the most vulnerable. Lifeboats have been constructed for the top dozen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BofA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. Eugene Lockhart</ENAMEX>, barely on the job for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>,
left his job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> after the merger with a severance package including <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> and stock grants cashable for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $17 million</NUMEX>.

            
Although layoffs violate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giannini</ENAMEX> ethos--in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80 years</TIMEX> there
were none--the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> were quick to invoke the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>'s blessing on the
deal. "This is a transaction I know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.P.</ENAMEX> would have done," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BofA</ENAMEX> head
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Coulter</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>.

            
Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giannini</ENAMEX> dreamed of creating the first
nationwide <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>. He started his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> in a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saloon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Beach</ENAMEX> under the name "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of Italy</ENAMEX>." It had no connection with
any official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, though a large part of its business, naturally
enough, involved transfers to and from that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>, he bought
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> to establish a beachhead, but he was beaten back, in a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-decade</TIMEX> struggle, by banking laws, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>, and in-house perfidy. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>, he bought a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> whose twin claims to fame were that it
had been founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1812</TIMEX> and was named "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of America</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giannini</ENAMEX> quickly
renamed his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McColl</ENAMEX>'s
insistence that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> are in perpetual motion, swirling
around him, didn't satisfy many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX>, who wondered why one of the deal's few
specific stipulations was moving <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">HQ</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>.

            
That no compelling or even cant-ridden
explanation for the move came forth made some wonder if it is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion-dollar</NUMEX>
slight, born of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Renne</ENAMEX>'s long-running feud with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renne</ENAMEX> had said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BofA</ENAMEX> should place warning labels on its advertising. "No
accurate records kept" was one she suggested. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last December</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> told
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that he looked forward to a newspaper article
headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Local Jurisdictions Prevail Over BofA</ENAMEX>."

            Behind
the tirades are a set of lawsuits on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> other
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> charging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BofA</ENAMEX> with mismanaging <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of
dollars from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,788</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> municipal bond issues. Actual and punitive
damages could top <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BofA</ENAMEX> says it has acted in good faith, having
already returned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$41 million</NUMEX> in unclaimed funds and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $5 million</NUMEX> in
accidental overcharges to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. It maintains it continues to
review its handling of the bond issues, many of which it inherited when it
merged with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Pacific Bank</ENAMEX>.

            City <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were stunned
to think a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion-dollar</NUMEX> bank might have been stung by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million-dollar</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">darts</ENAMEX>. But local investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Hellman</ENAMEX> thought otherwise.

            
"Corporations are run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have feelings," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hellman</ENAMEX> told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> . "I'm sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coulter</ENAMEX> doesn't appreciate public
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> delivering diatribes against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BofA</ENAMEX>."

            
How is it, asked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Franciscans</ENAMEX> on considering
the news, that it requires more public scrutiny to cut down a redwood than it
does to uproot a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>?

            It's a curiosity of our age
that just as the press, unable to find ideological or philosophical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> in
public life, is obsessed instead with the puny private lives of the powerful,
so also business, freed of the obligation to consider the public interest in
its deal-making, gives play to the purely personal.

            Of course, this works both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>. Shortly after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BofA</ENAMEX> left, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knight-Ridder Co.</ENAMEX>, long established in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>, announced it is relocating its home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> or, as we
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> like to say, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay Area</ENAMEX>."

            The news was greeted with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-hosannas, since it further establishes the fact that the real power in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern California</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
continues to attract <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, however, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">-million</ENAMEX> dollar Victorians sell in a day.

            The real story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX> may not be that it loses local <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>--almost every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is a branch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> now--but that it may be the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to be primarily a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> community. You can buy
sheets, linens, and furniture now in the great granite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grant Avenue</ENAMEX>
that was once the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Pacific National Bank</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
