
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hegemon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Proud of It</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> had
a tough <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, losing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and the
Yugoslavs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. The cheering around the world stopped short of classic
anti-Americanism, but it went beyond mere appreciation for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> games well
played. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many quarters</TIMEX> of the globe, there seemed to be a sense of relief:
Whew! At least here was one genuinely level playing field on which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> was just another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contender</ENAMEX>, not a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">superpower</ENAMEX>.

            
Complaining that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX> is too big for his britches is almost as popular an
international sport as soccer itself. Lately, an old word has resurfaced: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> stands accused of hegemonism . Didn't this musty term
figure in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thucydides</ENAMEX>' description of how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sparta</ENAMEX> feared the rising power of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>? And wasn't it a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maoist</ENAMEX> code word during the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sino</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> dispute (as in,
"dig <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnels</ENAMEX> deep, store grain everywhere, and never seek hegemony")?

            Yet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the H-word is commonly used to denounce, among
other things, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> practice of certifying other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>' cooperation in the
war on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> laws that punish foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> for doing business
with state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> of terrorism. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy of promoting democracy
and human rights is sometimes labeled hegemonist.

            There is
plenty of room for legitimate debate about where the line is between advancing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> values and imposing our own values on others; or when our country
should act alone, when in concert with others. But these days <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> power is
subject to a form of ambivalence verging on antagonism--even from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>--that
goes beyond the merits and motivations of this or that particular
criticism.

            
There is nothing new about other nations
resenting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> influence on their political, economic, and cultural lives. But
with the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>-bashing--or at least <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>-tweaking--is
enjoying a new boom. That's in part because of the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>.
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> tended to muffle or modulate their occasional annoyance with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that was their shield against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> threat. Now they feel less
constrained.

            It is
sometimes easier for other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to complain about what they depict as a
swaggering, cock-of-the-roost <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> attitude than it is to tackle us head-on
over substantive issues. Besides, taking potshots at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is often good
local politics: Blaming a faraway caricature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> can deflect
attention from shortcomings, or worse, closer to home.

            Much criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> has a damned if we
do/damned if we don't quality. Many of the same voices accuse us of arrogance
when we assert ourselves and of failure of nerve or vision when we encourage
them to take the lead in their own region. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> we are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rambo</ENAMEX>, while only
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> we were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forrest Gump</ENAMEX>.

            The former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> is an example. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> berated us for conditioning our
participation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> on transatlantic consensus. More recently, some of
those same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> have griped about our determination to apply
tough and, if necessary, military measures in response to the dangerous and
deteriorating situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.

            There is a similar schizoid aspect to the reaction of some
of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policies toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> financial crisis and the
nuclear rivalry between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. Both problems are too vast for us
to be able to address alone, yet both require us to play a central role in
orchestrating an effective international defense of common interests. That
means we must combine coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> with direct approaches to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>.
We have supported efforts by international financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> to stop the
plunge of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economies. We also have talked directly-- very
directly--to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> about the economic reforms it needs. Our attempt to defuse
the crisis between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> began with emergency meetings of the
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-5</ENAMEX> (the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-8</ENAMEX> (the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> major industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracies</ENAMEX>, plus <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>).
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has also conducted quiet diplomacy with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
involved.

            These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cases illustrate the need to pursue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
interests on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tracks--together as possible and alone as necessary (or, in
diplomatic jargon, multilaterally and unilaterally). In an increasingly
interdependent world, many pressing problems that affect <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> can be
addressed only through cooperation with other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. The spread of nuclear
and biological weapons, the growth of international organized crime, and global
environmental degradation are a few examples.

            An
important part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> diplomacy is getting sovereign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to work together
voluntarily. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coercion</ENAMEX> isn't appropriate and won't work. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has
got to be careful not to strut its stuff in ways that might disincline other
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> from cooperating with it. We should lead by example and suasion.

            
We have a solid basis for doing so. Uniquely in
the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Great Powers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> defines its greatness not as an
ability to dominate others but as an ability to work with others in the
interest of the international community. For <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, that phrase
"international community" is not abstract or cynical or euphemistic; and we try
to make good on its implications. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign policy strives for a consensus
among like-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> on behalf of common interests that we can and should
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">champion</ENAMEX> together.

            We do
this not out of philanthropy but out of enlightened self-interest. We believe
that when democracy and prosperity and security advance anywhere around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">globe</ENAMEX>, it enhances the freedom, prosperity, and security of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
as well. After <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> led the world in the design and
construction of a superstructure made up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> helped bring bitter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">adversaries</ENAMEX> into a
framework of mutual support and benefit. Now these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that served
what we used to think of as "the West" and "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX>" are opening up to the
developing and democratizing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> is also leading the creation of new international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Kyoto Protocol</ENAMEX> on Climate
Change, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chemical Weapons Convention</ENAMEX>.

            There is no need to apologize for our leadership role. But
there is room for improvement in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> style . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> has asked those of us who speak publicly for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> to make a conscious effort not to sound smug, patronizing, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hectoring</ENAMEX>. That includes talking about foreign policy here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. In the information age, what senior <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> is very likely to be heard or read around the world. What
plays well in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peoria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, might sound offensive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama City</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>--to
mention <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX> where there is special sensitivity to any hint of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hegemonism</ENAMEX>. (She isn't ordering us to pull our punches--just to be more
conscious of what punches we're landing where , and to what
intended effect.)

            While taking account of
foreign sensitivities to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assertiveness</ENAMEX>, we must also be on our guard
against a domestic temptation in the opposite direction. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> some
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>--including influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>--also worry about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
hegemonism, but from a different perspective. They warn that in the name of
exercising international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, we are foolishly risking our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and treasure in faraway lands of which we know little. This
concern--misguided and misguiding--loomed large <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> in congressional
opposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Fast Track</ENAMEX>, and it is present again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in opposition to paying
our share of support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> and our overdue bills to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX>.

            When all is said and done,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> can handle complaints about the style and even the substance
of our engagement with the world. Better that than disengagement or a return to
the isolationism of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century ago</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
