
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Invisible Ink</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last weekend</TIMEX>, the print
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> got cold feet and spiked the story. Television dipped its pinkie toe in,
yanked it out as if scalded, and then plunged back in. Meanwhile, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-told
tale unfolded in all its seamy glory on the Web, where everyone went to read
about it and post their comments in newsgroups. Not until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> did
the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> finally report what everyone was talking about: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
alleged affair with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> intern.

            It starts
late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>-newsie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> files this breathless report on his
site. "At the last
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> magazine killed a story
that was destined to shake official <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to its foundation: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
intern carried on a sexual affair with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>!"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> explains that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX> developed the story of his
career, only to have it spiked by top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> suits <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> before
publication."

            From here the story spreads with speed. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:23 a.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, someone posts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> item in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alt</ENAMEX>.current-events.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clinton</ENAMEX>.whitewater newsgroup. Other newsgroupers, though
they know only what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> tells them, repost the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alt</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impeach</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clinton</ENAMEX> is in on it. Following suit: alt.politics.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clinton</ENAMEX> and
talk.politics.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">misc</ENAMEX>. Many of them buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX>'s account ("I'd settle for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who doesn't f**k interns in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>"). Bickering ensues ("Do
right-wing morons really believe what they read in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> report?"). Some
don't trust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gosh</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX>, such a pillar of journalistic
integrity. Snicker!"). But the story's out there. Soon enough, talk turns to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">intern</ENAMEX>'s high-level security clearance and the chance that she might
blackmail the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

             

            The
scandal moves to television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Editor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kristol</ENAMEX> strategically inserts it in a discussion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>
case during the round-table section of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week With Sam and Cokie</ENAMEX>. It is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately 12:45 p.m. EST</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a half-day</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> eruption. Other "incidents" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
philandering may surface, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> says, and "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> is going to be an issue
here." He continues, "The story in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> this morning is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> was going to go with a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> based on
tape-recorded conversations, which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> intern at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, an intern of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Panetta</ENAMEX>'s--"

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> is cut off by fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
Stephanopoulos, who knows where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> is coming from and where he is going.
Before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> can explain why the intern is in the news or identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
Drudge as the source of his scoop, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">And Bill</ENAMEX>, where did it
come from? The Drudge 
               Report . You know, we've all seen how
discredited--"

            Now
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> is cut off as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> battles for control. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Co-host Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX>
comes up with the ball and concludes, "I'm not an apologist for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , but if their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> decided they didn't have it cold enough
to go with, I don't think that we can here ... how could we say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
was wrong to kill it?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Co-host Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> ends the discussion by changing
topics.

            By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> joins the fray. They agree that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX> is an extraordinarily
fine investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>," and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX> must have got
cold feet. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX>'s page is referred to as a "gossip report."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
brings more postings on various Web sites: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> updates the
story--and the story behind the story. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> names <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alleged paramour. 
                  Slate
                mentions the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol-Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson exchange</ENAMEX> in "Pundit
Central" and the alleged spiking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> story in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Other Magazines</ENAMEX>." The
Webzine the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Underground</ENAMEX> makes it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s feature story. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rivera</ENAMEX>
Live airs a few choice rumors about the scandal. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>
speaks his piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS Radio</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mary Matalin Show</ENAMEX> and keeps filing on the Web. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> writes that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> possess taped phone
conversations that substantiate the rumors of a presidential affair.

            
And from the print media? Not a peep until
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> withhold the story from their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> editions
but include it on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the home-delivery editions. (The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX>
don't trace the story back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> .) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> goes to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Defcon1</TIMEX>,
with constant updates, and so do the wire services. The other TV networks
follow, as do the big news Web sites--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN Interactive</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABCnews</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            Would the story have broken
if not for the Web? Probably. Did the Web give the story additional velocity?
Definitely. The ethics cops who patrol <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and magazine newsrooms can't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> the rumors and unsubstantiated stories that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> post to the Web. And
they can't undo whatever quick-tongued network-TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> say
in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 seconds</TIMEX>. If the Web prints it and television goes with it, print must
follow.

         
      
   
