
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Blue Book</ENAMEX>

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
budget for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1999</TIMEX> came out on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2</TIMEX>, we were all engrossed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">l'affaire Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and the spin the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> was putting on
it--right-wing conspiracy, executive privilege, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmudic</ENAMEX> definitions of
adultery, and so on. Perhaps interest in that subject has now abated
sufficiently to allow us to turn our attention to the budget. I propose here to
comment not on the policy it contains but on the rhetoric with which it is
presented--on the spin the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> puts on its policy.

            What is
most striking to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who has been reading budgets for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> is how
far the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> of presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> has progressed. In the past the budget
(I refer here to the main book titled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> and not the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
volumes that come with it) typically had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts. One was the budget message
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, written in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and signed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> knew there was going to be a fair measure of boasting and self-serving
in that section. But most of the book consisted of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> about the functions
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, with such prosaic titles as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Defense</ENAMEX>" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>."
These were written in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, had lots of probably boring facts, and
one could learn a lot from them. Of course, they reflected the point of view of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> didn't have the feeling that he was
constantly being urged to buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Brooklyn Bridge</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was scarcely
mentioned.

            The budget still has the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s message and a section
organized according to the functions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. But now, inserted between
these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts is a long section--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">132</NUMEX> pages--still pretending
to explain the whole thing but explaining it as having sprung full-blown from
the brow of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> has inspirational chapter heads such as
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Preparing the Nation for a New American Century" and "Creating a Bright</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Future</ENAMEX>."

            Each
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter</ENAMEX> and subchapter in this section starts with a quotation from previous
utterances of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, set in italics and enclosed in a box. These
quotations are of a banality that is hard to believe. For example, we have
this:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> want the best
for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. We want them to live out their dreams, empowered with the
tools they need to make the most of their lives and to build a future where
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> remains the world's beacon of hope and freedom and opportunity. To do
this, we must all make improving the quality of education in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> one of our
highest priorities.
            

            There is
an irresistible reminder here of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX>'s little red book, except <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX>'s
dicta were more pointed.

            
In these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">132</NUMEX> pages there are, by my count, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">113</NUMEX>
uses of the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." (I include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> cases of the word "his" used in
close proximity to and referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.) And what is the president
doing on these occasions? Of course, he is working and proposing and having
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">visions</ENAMEX> and making commitments. But he is not only working, he is, in some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instances</ENAMEX>, working "hard"--to expand health care coverage and improve the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s health, to improve education and the lives of working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, to
eliminate fraud in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, and to crack down on violent youth
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> also has "initiatives":

            The Brownfields
Initiative

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water Quality</ENAMEX>
Initiative

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential Initiative</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Increase Seat Belt Use</ENAMEX> Nation-wide

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s Initiative
on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Drugs, Driving and Youth</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>
Technology Initiative

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiterrorism/Counterterrorism/Security Initiative</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
Reads Initiative

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Initiative</ENAMEX> on Landmines

            This is
truly a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> whose eye is on the sparrow.

            Depending on your mood, this is either irritating or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">laughable</ENAMEX>. But I cannot believe that it is helpful to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The
incredibility infects and pollutes everything else in the budget.

            These
pages are filled to overflowing with the names of programs to be created or
increased. Each of these has to have a name with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Letters</ENAMEX>, and every
capital letter has to be part of an acronym. (My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEXTEA</ENAMEX>. Anyone who
knows what that is should win money on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Stein</ENAMEX>'s quiz show. Actually, it
stands for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Economic Crossroads Transportation Efficiency</ENAMEX> Act.) The
mind reels reading about all these good things that are being done for us.

            
What one would like to see is some listing of
programs that are being reduced or not being introduced. After all, to govern
is to choose, and to budget is especially to choose. We cannot appreciate the
reason for the things that are to be done unless we can compare them with
things that are not to be done. Why do we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Seat Belt Initiative</ENAMEX> and not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Smoke Detector Initiative</ENAMEX>? (Maybe there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Smoke Detector Initiative</ENAMEX>, and I
missed it.) True, there are some cuts in expenditures and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>. They are
all the result of what we used to call minimizing waste, fraud, and abuse and
what is now called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reinventing Government Program</ENAMEX>. There
are no identifiable places where anyone is asked to give up anything.

            Well,
there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> exceptions to that. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, especially young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
are asked to give up <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">smoking</ENAMEX>--but to go on paying hefty taxes on cigarettes. By
accounting maneuvers not worth describing here, this abstinence will enable the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to increase spending on a variety of programs, through an
instrument modestly called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fund for America</ENAMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> exception is that we are to forgo using the
prospective budget surplus for tax cuts or expenditure increases (other than
those proposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>) "until we have a solution to the long-term
financing challenge facing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>." It is here that we have the
greatest need for more explanation.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">formulation</ENAMEX> offered gives rise to the ridiculous table showing, for years
beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, an excess of receipts over outlays, exactly balanced by an
item called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Pending Social Security Reform</ENAMEX>, and a resulting
surplus/deficit that is exactly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>. By that logic we had a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> deficit every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 30 years</TIMEX>, except that the "reserve" was negative.

            
Moreover, the little word "until" contains a
number of ambiguities. Some have interpreted it as meaning that the surplus
would be used to solve the financial problems of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. That
has now been denied by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX>. Which leaves open
the question of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s intention for the use of the surplus after some
other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX>, such as cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> benefits or raising payroll
taxes, has been found. Would we then be free to spend whatever surplus there is
in the unified budget? Or would we still want to apply some of that surplus to
reducing the federal debt accumulated during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 30 years</TIMEX> of deficits? Could we
start spending it even if the discovered solution for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>'s
long-run problem didn't start to have a financial impact for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another 20 years</TIMEX>?
In other words, is the "reserved" surplus to be part of any long-term fiscal
program or only a carrot to be used to induce a solution to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>,
after which the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carrot</ENAMEX> can be eaten?

            I raise these questions not
to disagree with what may be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s program but to illustrate the
inadequacy of the budget as an explanation of it.

            When I told a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of my
problems with the budget as an explanatory document, he replied, "But you're
the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who reads it." That may be true. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> copies were
printed.

         
      
   
