
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubist Republican</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude Stein</ENAMEX> was not my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aunt</ENAMEX>, although I sometimes fantasize that she was. The notion that I am her
relative and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of her charmed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">circle</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> crazy, but it's not
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">200 percent</NUMEX> crazy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> and I share the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>, and we are both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>.
And I have recently discovered another affinity. We are both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.

            The idea
that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary</ENAMEX> in literary style, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX> of bohemians and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">radicals</ENAMEX>, this most famous lesbian since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sappho</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> is staggering
and delicious. Just imagine what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX>
would think if they knew! Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde writers</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> of a
type: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezra Pound</ENAMEX> was a fascist conservative; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.S. Eliot</ENAMEX> a high-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, elitist
conservative; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Faulkner</ENAMEX> an antique <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> gentleman conservative. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude Stein</ENAMEX>, whom I will call "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">GS</ENAMEX>" for brevity, was a mainstream,
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">middle-America</ENAMEX>, small-government <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. She was not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, even though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> endowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>,
celebrating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> she was among the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to recognize. She was more like
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Coolidge Republican</ENAMEX>, even sharing her literary style with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cal</ENAMEX>. He sounded
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX> when he said, "When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are out of work there is unemployment." The
superficial simple-mindedness of the statement makes one think there must be
some deeper meaning beneath it.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1934</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> "are the only
natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. What was special about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
was that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> were free and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was small, something
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX> did not understand. "When I say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX> are not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> I mean they do not feel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to be a
very large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> around which anybody can wander and so although a government
is there it is not always anywhere near but they feel it to be a little country
which they can govern, and so it is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> and not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> was, of course, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX> did not consider him an
authentic one. "It is not that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX> destroyed the republican
party that might have happened anyway." She saved her real dislike for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> were elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> only if they had a
"singular seductiveness." "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>] was honestly elected, but he is
not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as seductive as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>, so I don't think he will be elected
a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time."

            
Her dislike of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> was based partly on economic
policy. "Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX> trying to make money be so that it has no
existence that it ceases to be a thing that anybody could count, so that nobody
can any longer believe in it or is it all electioneering," she asked. If his
goal was ridding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the belief in money so that they would no longer
believe in it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX> thought it might be a good thing. But what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> really wanted,
she believed, was a lot of money at his disposal so that he could control
everything.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX> gave
the most extensive view of her thoughts on economics in a series of articles
published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday Evening Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> organ of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Main</ENAMEX>
Street Republicanism. Her basic theme was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> spend too much.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX>, the unemployed do not want to work, and if there were fewer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, there would be more poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> is not mentioned by
name in her pieces, it's evident that he is the main culprit.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> article, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>," starts with this simple
brass-tacks statement:

            
               Everybody just has to
make up their mind. Is money money or isn't money money. Everybody who earns it
and spends it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> in order to live knows that money is money, everybody
who votes it to be gathered in as taxes knows money is not money. That is what
makes everybody go crazy.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX>'s point is that the
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who tax and spend do not realize what money is to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who earn it. But because money really is money, those who tax and
spend should treat it the way that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earners</ENAMEX> treat it--but they don't. There
is trickery or confusion in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX>'s argument. Of course, money is money, but there
are different kinds of money, and the different kinds need to be regarded and
managed differently. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> is someone's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, but we
do not expect the commanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> to manage all of them the way their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> would.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Governments</ENAMEX> may be wasteful in managing money, but the only evidence GS
provides is in the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis XV</ENAMEX>, who, when accused of spending too much,
said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">After me</ENAMEX>, the deluge." The story was singularly inappropriate in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>--the deluge had come after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coolidge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoover</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s spending
was an effort to stem the deluge, or at least to keep some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from drowning
in it.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday Evening Post</ENAMEX> articles
eerily suggest words we were to hear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 or 60 years later</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis XV</ENAMEX> story
reminds me of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX>--about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> philosopher
who said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> came to the throne with high taxes and departed with low
revenue. "Is money money" similarly presages <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign
stump reminding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, "It's your money! It's your money! It's your money!"
And when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX> asks, "who is to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">congress</ENAMEX> from spending too much money. They
will not stop themselves, that is certain," I imagine her testifying before
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> about the balanced-budget amendment.

            How did this unconventional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> arrive at these conventional ideas? I never spoke to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>, and I am
not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> of the large literature by and about her. But if she could write
about fiscal policy, perhaps I can speculate a little about her.

            She was
either terribly ignorant about economic affairs or terribly foresighted. She
lived abroad continuously from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904 until 1934</TIMEX>, when she returned for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
lecture tour and then departed, never to return. She missed the worst part of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Depression</ENAMEX>. She did receive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> (which we
know because of the story of her giving the comic pages to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>), but we--or
at least I--don't know what news accounts she read. Had she been more aware of
the despair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX>, she might have been more understanding of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX>.

            One might say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX> had such great understanding of human
nature that she could see beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX>, beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, beyond
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, to the fiscal problems we would have in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. One could say that,
but I don't believe it. She was not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> of great foresight about public
events. Living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1939</TIMEX>, she rejected the opinion of
well-informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that war was imminent.

            However
ignorant of economics she may have been, there is one economic fact that all
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> living abroad know--the exchange rate. Before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> devalued the
dollar, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX> could get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25.6 francs</NUMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">each dollar</NUMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> income. After
the devaluation, the rate was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15.2 francs</NUMEX> to the dollar, a drop of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX>.
I can easily imagine her being greatly annoyed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> for that.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX> was not the stereotypical poor and alienated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> who was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> of capitalism. She always had a comfortable
income, derived from her inheritance and supplemented after she turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX> by
her publishing royalties. She also had great investments--in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picassos</ENAMEX>,
Matisses, and other paintings. Far from being alienated, she was the
internationally recognized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grande dame</ENAMEX> of a group of rising geniuses. And she
was not an intellectual, having little interest in general ideas about
economics or politics. "The real ideas," she said, "are not the relation of
human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beings</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> but a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> to himself inside him and that is an
idea that is more interesting than humanity in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>."

            It seems to me that her view
of society was "cubist," like the paintings she was early to appreciate and the
literature she wrote. A cubist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> tried to decompose an object into the
atoms that were its real essence. He could paint a violin as a number of
superimposed geometrical shapes of varying shades of brown. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX> tried to reveal
the essence of communication by stringing together heavy words without the
punctuation, connectives, adjectives, adverbs, and allusions we are accustomed
to. She understood society, or was interested in society, only as a collection
of individual human beings not bound together by any political or economic
system.

            This attitude has its
merits, but it also has its drawbacks. No one can play music with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cubist</ENAMEX>'s
idea of a violin. Very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could understand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX>'s writing. Her atomistic
view of society nourished her assignment of a high value to individual freedom,
but it limited her ability to understand much that was going on in the
world.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX> might ask, what is the
question to which this essay is the answer? Perhaps there is none. Every answer
doesn't have a question. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> lesson of this essay is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
like every other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, contains some surprises.

         
      
   
