
   
   
      
         
            The Second-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Best Sauce</ENAMEX>

            "There's no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> in the
world like hunger." You may think that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> made that up, but
actually it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Don Quixote</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 400 years ago</TIMEX>. Neither I
nor any of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are ever hungry except for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Yom Kippur</ENAMEX>, so
I am unable to test <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX>' proposition. I will concede it to him,
however.

            I want to
talk about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-best <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX>, which is "belonging." Food tastes enormously
better when it is eaten in a place where you are accepted as a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>,
special for something other than the color of your credit card.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iwas</ENAMEX> struck by this proposition <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month ago</TIMEX> when I
spent some time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. In the space of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX>, we ate
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> meals--lunch and dinner and then lunch and dinner again--in the same
restaurant. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> was great; I thought it was only pretty
good. He seemed disappointed that I did not share his appreciation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.
A little later I realized what the problem was. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> was a gathering
place for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in "the business," meaning the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> movie-and-TV
business. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was one of them. When he came into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, people
slapped him on the back and said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Great show</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>!" And he slapped someone else on the back
and said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Great show</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>!" (or whoever). This was his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, and that made the
food taste great. But it was not my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>.

            I can see
many other examples of this in my eating history. The most obvious is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Mess</ENAMEX>. To eat there one had to be either a fairly high-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> of such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. That is, eating there gave
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a strong sense of special privilege. (When I was there we hadn't yet
learned that access to the privileges of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> could be sold for
cash.) And this sense of belonging made the food taste great. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cooks</ENAMEX>
there were not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cordon Bleu</ENAMEX>. The pièces de résistance
were the cheeseburger, the hot fudge sundae, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tex-Mex</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursdays</TIMEX>.
Objectively speaking, one could get better food at any of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
within <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> blocks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. But the judgment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Mess</ENAMEX> was not an objective judgment.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> doesn't have to eat in "high-class"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">surroundings</ENAMEX> to get this delicious feeling of belonging. For some time after we
were married I used to tell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> about the great <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> prepared by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freddie</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cook</ENAMEX>. That referred to my college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. I had been the dishwasher at a
fraternity <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waiters</ENAMEX> were all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the fraternity and ate the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> in the same dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> as the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. But I was not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, so I ate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> with the other kitchen help who were not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and who were all "colored," as we used to say. We in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> felt
that we were getting the best of everything, better and fresher <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> than was
served to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> upstairs. What it all was, I no longer remember, with one
exception: For dessert I often had a quart brick of vanilla <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream bathed</ENAMEX> in
the wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">syrup</ENAMEX> extracted from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> maples around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Williamstown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>
But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freddie</ENAMEX> was really a mediocre <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX>.

            There was a time, probably
now past, when medium-price <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> would advertise themselves as serving
"home cooking." They were trying to play upon the memory of home cooking as
having been very good cooking. But the odds were against your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> having
been a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX>. It was mainly the feeling of having been part of the
family that made the food there seem so good in retrospect.

            Good
restaurants exploit this feeling. They know that you will enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> more
if the headwaiter greets you as "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>" without having to look in his book
when you come in. That is, if your name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>. Otherwise, to be called
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>" spoils the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX>.

            Ihave eaten in some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-star <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> in my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>--almost always on someone else's expense account. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only one</NUMEX> of those meals
was memorable. That was in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Champs Élysées</ENAMEX> where I ordered
in the belief that it was veal with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quelle</ENAMEX> horreur!
            

            Surely there are exceptions
to my general rule. There must be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with palates so fine that even
blindfolded they could tell the difference between food from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">La Tour d'Argent</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>. And there probably is some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> so good that even I,
eating it in a strange place, would recognize its merit. But, in general, my
rule holds. If you are not hungry, eat where you belong!

         
      
   
