
   
   
      
         
            Push <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me</ENAMEX>, Pull You

            
               (This
inaugurates a new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> column about developments on the Internet. The author
happens to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's chief computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, but the column is intended for
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> as innocent of technology as he is about a lot of the stuff they
write about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">in the Back of the Book</ENAMEX>.)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> recently announced
an alliance with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PointCast</ENAMEX>. The press heralded this deal as confirmation that
"push" is the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Thing</ENAMEX> for the Web. "Push" refers to the way that
information gets delivered. Do you have to go to it (pull)? Or does it come to
you (push)? The conventional way to read your favorite Internet content is to
dial up to the Internet, find your favorite site(s), wait for them to download,
navigate to items of interest, wait for them to download, and so forth. That's
"pull"--and the pull had better be pretty strong, or you'll give up. "Push"
technology, by contrast, is supposed to do all this for you. It dials up,
connects to selected sites, downloads certain information, and arranges it in
an easy-to-read format--all while you sleep (or are otherwise living your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">life</ENAMEX>). The advantage to you is that it's all there waiting to be read, at fast
hard-drive speed instead of slow modem speed. The advantage to the information
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">provider</ENAMEX> is that information "pushed" at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> is more likely to find them
than information they must go out and "pull."

            One
metaphor commonly applied here is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> being delivered to your door
instead of your having to pick it up at the newsstand. Given the Internet's
unreliability, a more appropriate metaphor might be sending a highly trained
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> to the newsstand to pick up the paper. Most of the time you'd get the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , but some of the time you'd get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire</ENAMEX> Hydrant
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> --and occasionally, your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> would just wander off looking for a
bone. Still, it's an improvement.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PointCast</ENAMEX> is the most successful "push" technology so far.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> provides a free piece of software (downloadable from its site) that
allows you to select from a handful of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>" (sports, business, arts and
entertainment, etc.). At set intervals, the software instructs your computer to
connect to the Internet, go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s site, and download the latest news
in those categories. It also downloads some ads. Then, whenever your computer
has been idle for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX>, this news and these ads pop up on the custom
screen saver the software has installed on your machine. Because the material
is presented after the download is complete, the display is fast. And because
the process uses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s own software and not a standard Web browser, the
display is customized to the task at hand, making it attractive and
eye-catching.

            In fact,
using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PointCast</ENAMEX>, you quickly realize that this is nothing like having a
newspaper delivered. This is a lot more like watching television. That helps to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">explain PointCast</ENAMEX>'s popularity: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> claims that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.7 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> have
downloaded its software to date, and that its site gets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40 million</NUMEX> hits a day.
(A "," though, is an elusive concept.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PointCast</ENAMEX>'s success at "push" is
drawing lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>, both small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">start-ups</ENAMEX> and the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PointCast</ENAMEX> essentially sells <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> automatically connects to the Internet and downloads things so
you can read them offline. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> finds and collects things that interest
you. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> presents them effectively. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> offer Web
offline-reading technologies. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> generation of these, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WebWhacker, Milktruck</ENAMEX> (now
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WebEx</ENAMEX>),
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">FreeLoader</ENAMEX>, all
work pretty much the same way: You tell the software which sites you want
downloaded, and the software tells your computer to do it at prearranged
times.

            But what
does it mean to "download a site"? A site is a collection of pages, linked
together as well as to other pages on other sites. How many pages should the
software download? Too few, and you're missing out on something. Too many, and
you might overflow your hard drive. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> solve this problem by
making relationships with specific sites that agree to tailor a version to that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s software. That's why some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> (like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>) sport FreeLoader logos,
while others (like the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX>) might recommend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WebEx</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acompany</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peak Media</ENAMEX> uses similar technology to take a different approach:
trying to make online browsing more satisfying. Peak
Net.Jet software uses idle modem time to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">download</NUMEX> pages it thinks--based on
pages you frequent--you probably want to read. For instance, every so often I
visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dilbert</ENAMEX> archive. To read <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> of cartoons, I would have to
click on each cartoon's date and wait for that image to download. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peak Net</ENAMEX>.Jet
promises to remember that I like that page, and to download it all for me ahead
of time while I surf elsewhere. When I go back, I find that it has already
downloaded the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two weeks</TIMEX>' cartoons, making my experience fast and
easy.

            
Unfortunately for these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, the technology to download sites ahead of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> is simple. In the past, small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have innovated with features like
disk compression and virus checking, only to find themselves squeezed out when
those features were incorporated into basic operating systems like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX> and
OS<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2</NUMEX>. So, if downloading <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> is simple, why shouldn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> build that
capability into Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape into Navigator</ENAMEX>? Well, they are.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4.0</ENAMEX> will provide an "Active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desktop</ENAMEX>," which shows
"pushed" content right there behind your Windows windows. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> has a
similar product in development called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constellation</ENAMEX>."

            
Smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, therefore, must distinguish
themselves by the content they gather and how they present it if they are to
compete. In the Internet world, where content--even good content--is
proliferating rapidly, a very good filter will be needed to sort out what
interests you from what doesn't. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PointCast</ENAMEX> has succeeded so far with a
mass-market approach--relatively few news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, sorted into relatively few
"buckets." Individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> (in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> owns a minority interest) provides
a high-tech clipping service called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NewsPage</ENAMEX>. You choose from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of distinct topics and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, and have relevant articles from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 630</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> delivered to you by
e-mail, or to a personalized Web page. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cognisoft</ENAMEX>, take this same
approach to corporate intranets (internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>), hoping that "push"
technology will be even more useful in distributing the right information to
the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.

            Another
"push" technology to watch is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marimba</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castanet</ENAMEX>, which attempts to generalize the technique.
Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PointCast</ENAMEX>, which downloads its own content, and the offline reader
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clones</ENAMEX>, which download only Web pages, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castanet</ENAMEX> can download Java applications
and applets in addition to Web pages.

            Although much of this software is
advertising-driven--hence, free--you will still pay a price. All these products
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">download</ENAMEX> content whether you actually read it or not. Since not everyone will
read everything they order up at no charge, an enormous amount of pointless net
traffic is being generated. As if the Web wasn't slow enough already. In fact,
some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> have banned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PointCast</ENAMEX> because it was causing huge increases
in their net traffic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PointCast</ENAMEX> responded with a piece of software for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' central computers designed to minimize its own impact. And this
one's not free. It's almost a protection racket. You give away your software
free to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks later</TIMEX>, you saunter over and say,
"Nice little corpnet you've got here--too bad it's getting all clogged up. Buy
our software and we'll keep it running smoothly." Once a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> buys that
software, it is less likely to switch content <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>. So maybe it's more
like dealing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. Either way, everybody wins: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> read their news,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has a clear net again, and it's a nice annuity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PointCast</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
