
   
   
      
         
            Surfing Through China 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Day One</ENAMEX>

            Day Two

            Day Three

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day Four</ENAMEX>

            Nobody
invited me to tag along on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX>-person <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entourage</ENAMEX>. I didn't spend my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
afternoon ogling ancient terra cotta <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">warriors</ENAMEX> or my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> gallivanting around
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forbidden City</ENAMEX>. But inspired by the grand tradition of foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent hackery</ENAMEX>, I won't be stopped from reporting on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s trip to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Here's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of a series of Internet dispatches--on Internet
coverage--of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> story.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Day One</ENAMEX>
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>'s attention was fixed on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s controversial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> welcome in
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>. While the Web address www.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tiananmensquare</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> has not yet
been claimed, other sites chronicle the massacre with bloody
photos and interactive tours. Coverage of the event by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Daily</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>'s voice, stresses
"bilateral" cooperation without delving into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen</ENAMEX>'s human rights issues:
"To accelerate their move toward the goal of establishing a constructive
decided that they would refrain from targeting their strategic nuclear weapons
against each other." Whew!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> roused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peking University</ENAMEX> with a speech advocating
human rights and did a Q
& A with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>'s Web
site is a bit of a disappointment, being more obsessed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998 centennial</TIMEX> than with the real world.

            Who's ever
heard of human rights? Well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Embassy</ENAMEX> has--there's a whole page of links to government
propaganda on the subject, including a diatribe titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"A Look at</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Human Rights Record</ENAMEX>."

            
Anumber of human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> paint the
real, less rosy picture. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Rights in China</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> started
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>, offers a comprehensive site with links to a site for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wang Dan</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> who was released from a long stint in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> only
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>. The site links to his speeches and the petition that helped set
him free, as well as to his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 4</TIMEX> statement on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> anniversary of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> massacre. For a daily critique of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s media coverage, turn
to the independent media
watchdog section of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Inside China Today</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
wins big with its comprehensive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trip Web links page. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, and other China
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> are just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> click away. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> also features a condensed history of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> (disguised as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> Tour"), links to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s music, and a reader
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forum</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> catalogs
its articles (and requires that you register) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> a discussion.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> posts top <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> stories, many of them from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated</ENAMEX>
Press.

            More as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> continues surfing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            
               Day Two
            

            As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> does
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second day</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Surfwatch</ENAMEX>, we plow into a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX>
paddy of local propaganda. An overview of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX> skims all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s tourist sites, including the classical
pavilions at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yuyuan Garden</ENAMEX>--a stop on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> itinerary. Another brief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">summary</ENAMEX> emphasizes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX> (a k a the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>) is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s biggest manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>, responsible for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-eighth</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s total <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> industrial output. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shanghai Daily</ENAMEX> gloats that "China is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> largest trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> is only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>."
            

            Excerpts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s entertaining radio talk show
include not only policy pronouncements but also the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> view of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
figure ("[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ou</ENAMEX> seem to have a very nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President"</ENAMEX>). And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
makes his unofficial call for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>. Another of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> mileposts was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shanghai Library</ENAMEX>, which he hopes will cooperate more
closely with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>. Progress won't be immediate. The digital branch is all
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Chinese</ENAMEX>. And though we can't hack our way into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX> stock market
(also the site of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> guest appearance), we can still get investing advice and
an overview.

            After all that surfing, it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX>, namely, some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX> specialties. Vegetarians take shelter, for the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">156</NUMEX> tantalizing possibilities include mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>, and seafood.
Randomly we settle on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jin Jiang Roast Duct</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ]. "Kill and depilate
[ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ] the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>," the instructions begin. No thanks, we'll order the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Pig</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stomachic</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ] <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pieces Soup</ENAMEX>, which, as you
will read, makes fewer demands on us.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tomorrow</TIMEX>
it's back to the serious stuff. We'll pay a call on the exiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> and
get the scoop on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>.

            
               Day Three
            

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> is treated to a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-anniversary-of-hand-over bash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, another independence issue still
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rankles</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>. (For a quick <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> refresher, check the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .)
Despite a conciliatory exchange between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Presidents</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, no easy resolutions are in the offing. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Daily</TIMEX> , revealingly titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Dalai</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama</ENAMEX>'s motives unmasked," takes the combative stance that has been wrapped
up in appeasement during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> tour.

            For the West, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> is
unquestionably a trendy cause. Several international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> lobby
through their extensive Web sites. Which one you choose to visit depends on
whether you want to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Save</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>. We recommend the latter, since its site has an up-to-date news
database on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s trip, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> itinerary, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> event schedule.
Most important, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>
sticks up for himself from his exile in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dharamsala</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North India</ENAMEX>. Good
surfing there--the well-organized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> site comprehensively explains the
government-in-exile's situation.

            What's so great about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>?
Well, take a spin through the spectacular photo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">courtesy Inside China Today</ENAMEX> ) of furry yaks, isolated desert
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tents</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> home ... too bad he isn't there to enjoy
it.

            Stay
tuned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s wrap-up whirl through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day Four</ENAMEX>
            

            We're back with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> tour's grand finale--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surfing</ENAMEX> through this glittering
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> is all about funky, colorful graphics, markedly different
from the mainland <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> Web experience. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> sports a
surprisingly fun Web site, which mingles facts and stats with blinking visuals.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> chunky pie graphs evaluate how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> officialdom is handling the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year 2000</TIMEX> problem. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is a</ENAMEX> "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37%</NUMEX> non-compliance rate" good news or bad?)

            High on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
agenda is a meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tung Chee-Hwa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX>. Here's his
pre-hand over prognosis, which includes a pledge to maintain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX>'s accustomed freedoms and to operate under a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-country, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-systems
scenario. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong Kong Journalists' Association</ENAMEX> disputes his success; its
"campaign for open <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>" notes that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69 percent</NUMEX> of surveyed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HKJA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> believe the pre-hand-over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was more open than the
current <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Corroborating evidence is offered by a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, which reports that an important documentary by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> about fighting in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has been kept off the
airwaves.
            

            OK, OK ... surf's up and
over. Craving some real fireworks--not to mention independence--we catch a cab
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">airport</ENAMEX> is just beginning service, expect delays in loading (the Web site). But
before you can say dim sum, we're back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> to celebrate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 4</TIMEX>--just
as if we'd never left.

         
      
   
