
   
   
      
         
            An <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Couch Potato's Lament</ENAMEX>

            I watch lots of television.
If you are as long in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and short in energy as I am, watching television is
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-best occupation. The best, of course, is sleeping, but you can't
sleep all the time.

            I watch many kinds of
television, but some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinds</ENAMEX> I don't watch. I don't watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> shows. If I wanted
all that violence, I would watch the local news at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 or 11 p.m.</TIMEX> I do not watch
sitcoms. They seem to me to consist entirely of juvenile <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leering</ENAMEX> about sex. I
am weaning myself from the talk shows about public policy that I used to think
it was my duty to watch. I have concluded that they are all games of Pin the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tail</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donkey</ENAMEX>--blindfolded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> trying to stick pins in evasive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>.

            I watch the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> news
because it comes on at dinner time and serves as background music to which
we--my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I--don't have to pay much attention. I think I could do with
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three minutes</TIMEX> of news a day. I watch some sports, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
afternoon professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>. I love seeing something done extremely well,
and I think that throwing a pass <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 yards</NUMEX> down the field to a precise point
where the receiver catches it amid a forest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> is doing something
extremely well. I like to watch with the sound off, because the sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>
are no better than the policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, and if I fall asleep during the game,
that's fine.

            I watch
the occasional symphony concert broadcast on television. I can hear better
sound on the radio or on a CD, but there is something special about the TV
performance that is connected with doing something extremely well. When I only
listen , I can hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haydn</ENAMEX> doing something extremely well. But
on television, I can see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> doing something extremely well. In the
course of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>, they play--I don't know how many--say, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> notes, and
all those notes come out right. I look at the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> clarinet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. He's no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>. He probably makes his living by giving lessons. But he always comes in
with his "duh" at the right time. As the former <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> clarinet in the
Schenectady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">High School orchestra</ENAMEX>, I appreciate that.

            The heart of our TV meal is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> story. Properly
done, with little violence and much detection, a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> story is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ideal</ENAMEX> nonirritating, guilt-free interactive program. I am not sitting passively
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> while gales of canned laughter blow over me or waves of fake blood
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">wash</ENAMEX> over me. I am doing something. I am helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> find or prove
who did it. If I don't find the answer--and I never do--I don't feel stupid
about it. And if I do find a little piece of the answer--noting a clue or
narrowing down the list of possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX>--I am pleased with myself.

            But, here
is my lament. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> story is disappearing from the TV screen.

            
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Britain</ENAMEX> has been the
source of TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> stories. I am grateful to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> for that, but
their stories have never been entirely satisfactory. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherlock Holmes</ENAMEX>, of
course, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives</ENAMEX>, and when he began to appear on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, we watched him regularly. But he does not inspire repeat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX>. As played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Brett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX> was so eccentric, so mannered, that
all attention was drawn to him, rather than to the story--and after you had
seen him several times, he elicited giggles rather than puzzlement.

            Hercule
Poirot was my favorite among the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>-detective-story <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives</ENAMEX> who made
their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> TV debut on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. Perhaps that reflects a connection formed 50 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> when I used to pass the time on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
reading his adventures. Anyway, in the TV incarnation, the stories were the
right length--<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poirot</ENAMEX> spoke clearly. The clues, moreover, were not
too obscure for the occasional <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to be recognized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX>. But there
have been no new Poirot stories for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>--and although we still watch
the reruns, I have the feeling that his shiny mustache is getting shinier and
his mincing steps even more mincing.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives</ENAMEX> now appearing in new series on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> are Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cmdr</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalgliesh</ENAMEX>. We appreciate and watch
them, but we are not entirely happy with them. Their stories run for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> installments separated by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>. That is too long for even
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">couch potato</ENAMEX> to sit still. Dalgliesh mumbles. Surprisingly, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>
speaking with what he thinks is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> accent speaks more clearly than an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> speaking in his own accent. The clues are too faint--too
understated. I don't feel that I am coming closer to the solution, even after
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX>. Maybe I am just not smart enough for a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> TV detective
story, as I am not smart enough for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> crossword puzzle. But I often
think that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dalgliesh</ENAMEX> don't have a clue until the whole thing is
revealed in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last 15 minutes</TIMEX>.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite detective</ENAMEX> stories
are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, and the most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> of all is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder, She Wrote</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">starring Angela Lansbury</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Fletcher</ENAMEX>. Murder episodes are almost
always <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> in length. Everyone--whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an Indian</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX>--speaks clear <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. The clues are not obvious,
but they are not too hard to get either, especially after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a second or third</TIMEX>
rerun. The "production values" are high. The setting--wherever it might
be--always seems authentic, not as if it were a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> back lot.

            The
stories are set in different walks of life--a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, a rodeo, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, an
advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, a toy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>--and each one seems to reflect the setting
accurately. (Having seen so many episodes and observed the formula, I have
thought it would be amusing to write an episode set in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tank</ENAMEX>. But I have
been unable to visualize <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">think-tank scholar</ENAMEX> killing another. For what--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">citation</ENAMEX> in a newspaper column?)

            
But best of all, there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela</ENAMEX>. She always
says the right thing, does the right thing, wears the right clothes. She is an
example of doing something extremely well. She does not rely on eccentricities
to create a recognizable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, and that is why you can watch her over and
over again. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> cannot wither, nor custom stale, her infinite normalcy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, no
new episodes of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder, She Wrote</ENAMEX> have been made for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>. We
are living on reruns. That is all right for now. True <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> can enjoy seeing the
same episode <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> times. They will discover something new each time.
But that cannot go on much longer. I fear that when we reach the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> or
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> repeat, it will have become boring. And what shall we do then?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> allegedly gave up programming new episodes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder, She Wrote</ENAMEX> because of the "demographics." We <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fletcher</ENAMEX> are too old to be a good market for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>. It is not because we
are old that we like the polite, civilized detective story. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> liked
that when we were young; we liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Charles</ENAMEX> in the movies and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellery Queen</ENAMEX> on the radio. In our middle age we liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry Mason</ENAMEX> on
television. We are of the generation that likes to have its intellect teased.
Later <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> like to have their emotions aroused. But it is true that we
are not a good market for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>. We have money, and spend it or invest
it. But we have been around too long, and have had too much experience, to buy
something or invest in something just because we see it advertised on
television.

            Perhaps in the era of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> TV
channels there will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> devoted to new episodes of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder, She Wrote</ENAMEX> ,
Columbo , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry Mason</ENAMEX> , and to other newly conceived, civilized
detective stories. But for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> of that genre, time is running out. For
the present, we have to try to learn to understand the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives</ENAMEX>. And
we have to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> the supply of old <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder, She Wrote s</ENAMEX>, rationing
ourselves to not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> viewing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>, hoping to preserve the
fascination until the need for such entertainment has passed.

         
      
   
