
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc</ENAMEX> in the Hat

            As preschoolers, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
briefly confused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spock</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seuss</ENAMEX>, whom they assumed to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> with a
stovepipe hat. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">household pediatrician</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cat in the Hat: The</ENAMEX>
image is unwittingly apt, linking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> upstart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> boomer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pantheon</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s helper with a bag of tricks that promised new fun for the
housebound, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Spock</ENAMEX> arrived on the postwar scene <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Child Care</ENAMEX> was published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>. It revealed his gift for juggling the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unbalanceable</ENAMEX> demands of life with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and for sounding serenely jaunty
as he did it. It goes without saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spock</ENAMEX>, like the acrobatic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat</ENAMEX>, proved
immensely popular and has remained so. What is perhaps less obvious is that,
much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat</ENAMEX> made sure his messes were temporary, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spock</ENAMEX> was not as
subversive as lore suggests.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spock</ENAMEX>'s
purported iconoclasm is twofold. First, he is typically hailed (or, rarely now,
condemned) as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary</ENAMEX> who emboldened postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX> against
the stern behaviorist style that had prevailed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s and 1930s</TIMEX>. The
truth is somewhat different. Like most wildly popular figures, he was riding a
wave, not bucking the tide. His genial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freudian</ENAMEX> approach fit right in with the
reigning sociological wisdom, which championed the democratic, "affectionate"
family as the welcome successor to the hierarchical home of the past. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reviewers</ENAMEX>
of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Child Care</ENAMEX> praised its don't rock the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boat</ENAMEX> (but do rock the cradle) tone. Spock, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Journal of Public</ENAMEX>
Health marveled, "has succeeded to an amazing degree in striking a middle
ground in his advice." That advice was seen to "typify the present-day
departure from rigidity in schedules and training."

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spock</ENAMEX> is renowned for an unprecedentedly
confidence-inspiring pitch. "Trust yourself. You know more than you think you
do," he told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. Instead of struggling to "do everything
letter-perfect out of a feeling of worry," he counseled, try to relax and be
flexible. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>, trust them, have "a deep desire to grow up to be like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> they admire and love." Yet the message of simple reassurance turned out
to be more complicated, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spock</ENAMEX> himself quickly discovered. The first expert
to say, "Don't be overawed by what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> say," became an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> of
awesome influence <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>. (His book sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> copies
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its first year</TIMEX>, without advertising.) Flattered, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spock</ENAMEX> was also flustered to
discover just how dependent on his advice his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> had become. Was parental
autonomy weakening on his own watch?

            Spock
frequently claimed that fears about "permissiveness" first surfaced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>,
voiced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of his antiwar activism. In fact, as early as in the second
edition of his classic, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>, he was worried that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> might be flailing.
They weren't friendly yet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, as he had recommended. They were confused and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hesitant</ENAMEX>, overawed by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of an imposing Victorian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">matriarch</ENAMEX> himself, he was surprised at how wobbly modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> seemed.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> stunned him by writing, "Don't you
realize that when you always emphasize that a child basically wants to behave
well, and will behave well if he is handled wisely, you make the parent
feel responsible for everything that goes wrong?"

            Spock
took the question personally. He also astutely recognized it as a midcentury
symptom of a "fascinating and somewhat mysterious phenomenon, this one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> being this nervous about doing right by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>." In
our anti-traditional culture, older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> had tended to be ambivalent
about their authority over younger ones. But now the swift pace of
technological change left <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> less equipped than ever to prepare their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for the future, even as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> needed the preparation more
desperately. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>--in particular, psychology, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spock</ENAMEX>'s own specialty--held
out a promise of newly fine-tuned control over their development.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX> understandably felt under pressure, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spock</ENAMEX> was
the rare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> who acknowledged their bewilderment. From then on, ministering
to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> parental uneasiness became his real <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">métier</ENAMEX>. Even in
its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> edition, his manual was more encyclopedic than others, packed with
up-to-date medical and practical advice delivered in down-to-earth prose. He
saw to it that, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, it remained so. Just as important, he became
even more solicitously therapeutic. In a field intent on claiming objective,
"scientific" status, he didn't hesitate to admit that doctrinaire ideas
shifted, conflicted, and could be disorienting.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spock</ENAMEX>'s
own simplistic Freudian perspective, with its emphasis on childhood Oedipal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dramas</ENAMEX> and the wonders of sublimation, sounds more quaint <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>. It's his
handling of the ambiguities of parenthood that is timeless. Called a
"confidence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>" by one impatient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spock</ENAMEX> indeed made a specialty of
delivering mixed messages to his insecure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.

            
He set out in his book to calm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, in the
process stirring up their anxiety. He urged them to rely on their instincts,
and went on to supply them with minute instructions. He emphasized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">resilience</ENAMEX>, and was quick to suggest that problems require a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX>'s
assistance. He started out psychologizing, and ended up moralizing. Through it
all, he prescribed spontaneity, an oxymoronic endeavor if ever there was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spock</ENAMEX>'s equivocations
were not evasions. On the contrary, they call attention to a truth less honest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> have preferred to obscure and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> want to hear: that
child rearing is a messy art of compromise and contradictions, full of
uncertainty. It is not a streamlined science. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spock</ENAMEX> did not cure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> of their impossible dream of being "professional" parents
equipped with the developmentally correct answers. But he played an important
part in bringing realism to child rearing by being an unapologetic improviser
himself.

            If he was sometimes a naive
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spock</ENAMEX> was always a resourceful pragmatist when it came to
child rearing wisdom. He let broad intuitions and motley experience guide him.
"I never looked at my records," he admitted about the writing of his classic.
"It really all came out of my head." All along, he treated his book as a
growing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX>, not as a fixed system. Spock relied on his own resilience,
not science, to update his expertise for an era of feminism and family
disarray. His classic has thickened gracelessly over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, but as the
forthcoming <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> edition once again shows, it has remained true to the
adaptable temperament it was born with. This one-of-a-kind creation has helped
spawn countless how-to manuals, but it's still easy to choose the indispensable
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seuss</ENAMEX>' words: Well, what would you say, if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> asked you?

         
      
   
