
   
   
      
         
            Bound in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chains</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1994</TIMEX>, an e-mail
letter began to circulate on the Internet detailing the dangers of a vicious,
hard-drive-eating computer virus called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Good Times</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Recipients</ENAMEX> were urged to
forward the e-mail to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> promptly debunked the
letter--the virus did not exist. Soon, a revamped "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Times</ENAMEX>" message appeared
on the Net, warning of an "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n th</ENAMEX> -complexity infinite binary loop"--a
device as fictional as it is impressive-sounding. Even though this note was
debunked, it continued to propagate as well-intentioned computer users
forwarded it to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>. Netizens translated it into other
languages and it appeared around the world. It was read over a radio broadcast
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malta</ENAMEX>. Eventually a parody arrived--it, too, was widely circulated.
According to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Times FAQ</ENAMEX>" Web page, "It's no longer accurate to speak
of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">'comebacks' and 'outbreaks' of Good Times</ENAMEX>. It's just there--part of the
landscape, like kudzu and dandelions."

            Of
course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> letters like the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Times</ENAMEX>" e-mail predate the Internet. In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX>, "prayer chains" encouraged the faithful to pray for
someone in need and extend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>. A well-known postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Jude</ENAMEX>
letter, claims a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903</TIMEX> inception date. It promises luck to those who forward it
and calamity to those who don't. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> estimates that the
chain has circled the globe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least nine</NUMEX> times. Prayer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> also thrive on
the telephone, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> dial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and acquaintances and ask them to pray
for someone in need--and then ask them to make the same request of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and acquaintances.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Jude</ENAMEX> letter is a "mind virus," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodenough of Vermont Law School</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodenough</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dawkins</ENAMEX>, the noted
Darwinist, have written about the survival techniques of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Jude</ENAMEX> letter
and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> mail for the scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> . In their view,
these information parasites seek to infect host brains. The most "fit" mind
virus is the one that is forwarded ("replicated") to prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infectees</ENAMEX>.
Less fit letters are not forwarded, and so die. Some potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> are
inoculated against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>-mail viruses by excessive exposure--they simply ignore
the letters.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX>, there were
measurable costs to extending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>--time-consuming hand-copying or
expensive photocopying or the price of postage. But thanks to virtually free
e-mail, the velocity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> mail has accelerated on the Net, and successful
chains now billow into huge, tumorous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> in a matter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>.

            The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Times</ENAMEX>" e-mail cribs
its evolutionary strategy from the old postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>: "A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> received this
letter and threw it away. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nine days later</TIMEX> he died." By invoking fear and
disaster, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Times</ENAMEX>" e-mail finds a soft spot to infect: <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Anxiety</ENAMEX> about a
hard-disk crash is never far from computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>' minds.

            Greed is
almost as good a parasitic strategy as fear. The ubiquitous "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Make Money Fast</ENAMEX>"
e-mail recasts the classic pyramid scheme as e-scam: Send <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> to the names on
the list, add your own name to the bottom, and reap your windfall later. The
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">MMF Hall of Humiliation</ENAMEX>" Web site traces the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Make Money Fast</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">origins</ENAMEX> and lists addresses and phones of the alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">originators</ENAMEX>, requesting
that you spam them.

            
Pitted against the evolutionary strategies of
fear and greed, we find a genre of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> e-mail that employs compassion. Surely
you've received the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Mydek</ENAMEX>" letter, birthed on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX>. It
reads:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LITTLE JESSICA MYDEK</ENAMEX> IS
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SEVEN YEARS OLD AND IS SUFFERING FROM AN ACUTE AND VERY</ENAMEX>

            RARE CASE OF CEREBRAL
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CARCINOMA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">THIS CONDITION CAUSES SEVERE MALIGNANT BRAIN</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TUMORS AND IS A TERMINAL</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ILLNESS</ENAMEX>. THE <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">DOCTORS HAVE GIVEN HER SIX MONTHS TO LIVE</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">AS PART OF HER DYING WISH</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SHE WANTED TO START A CHAIN LETTER TO INFORM PEOPLE</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">OF THIS CONDITION AND TO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SEND PEOPLE THE MESSAGE TO LIVE LIFE TO THE FULLEST AND</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ENJOY EVERY MOMENT</TIMEX>, A CHANCE

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMERICAN CANCER SOCIETY AND</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SEVERAL CORPORATE SPONSORS HAVE AGREED TO DONATE</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">THREE</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CENTS TOWARD</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONTINUING CANCER RESEARCH</ENAMEX> FOR <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EVERY</TIMEX> NEW PERSON THAT GETS

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">FORWARDED THIS MESSAGE</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">PLEASE GIVE JESSICA</ENAMEX> AND <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ALL CANCER VICTIMS A CHANCE</ENAMEX>.

            It is a
beautiful vision. A dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> spreads a noble message across the world. All
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> need to do to fill <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>-research coffers is click a button. The one
problem, of course, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Mydek</ENAMEX> is as fictitious as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n th</ENAMEX> -complexity infinite binary loop. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX>
disavows any involvement with the letter.

            The "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Mydek</ENAMEX>" e-mail succeeds because it promises the
replicator instant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">karma</ENAMEX>. So does the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Save NPR</ENAMEX>" letter, which claims that
public broadcasting is in peril. Its modest request is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> put
their names at the bottom of the list and forward it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Eventually,
the letter states, the e-mail petition will be collected and presented to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Never mind, of course, that public broadcasting
isn't under attack, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> receives little of its support directly from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokespeople</ENAMEX> say the letter is useless.

            Web sites
that campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> mail complain that junk e-mail wastes Internet
bandwidth, reduces productivity, and exploits human emotions. But let's not
forget the upside to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>. They make you feel as if the click of your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> has saved your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s hard drive, healed sickly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Mydek</ENAMEX>, and
rescued poor little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Mydek</ENAMEX> may not be real, but the emotion
showered on her is, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the millions</NUMEX> of e-mails containing her name suggest
that the impulse to do good on the Net could be harnessed.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Shergold</ENAMEX> was a genuine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Mydek</ENAMEX>, a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7-year-old</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> he began a conventional postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> letter
asking that greeting cards be mailed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Children's Wish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>--his goal was to break the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guinness World Record</ENAMEX>. He did it in two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, receiving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16 million</NUMEX> cards, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> went into permanent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">remission</ENAMEX>.

            Then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> moved to the
Internet, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> continued to send cards, even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX> asked them not
to. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> he was clearing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX> cards <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and stopped counting at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
million total cards. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> needed a donated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> full-time
staff to handle the mail, which it simply recycled.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX> I got a chain
e-mail requesting greeting cards for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Shergold</ENAMEX>. I forwarded it to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
