
   
   
      
         
            

             

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               To: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>
            

            Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> has been charged
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> with the grave responsibility of determining if there
has been any criminal wrongdoing by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> or those
acting at his direction.

            The most serious of the
issues we have examined is the alleged cover-up of the sexual affair between a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> intern, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> old enough to be her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>--in or near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> between
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1995 and December 1997</TIMEX>. This case is not about sex but about
possible criminal conduct by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> in violation of his oath of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and the laws of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, including perjury, subornation of perjury,
and obstruction of justice.

            A review
of the relevant criminal violations is in order for a proper judgment to be
rendered by your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PERJURY</ENAMEX>

            The details of the illicit
sexual contacts between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> contradict the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s sworn testimony in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and before the grand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>, despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s claims that his statements were "legally
accurate." Herein are highlights of our findings (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appendix XX</ENAMEX> for a
complete list and descriptions of sexual acts, including oral copulation,
mutual masturbation, and lewd and lascivious conduct with a cylindrical smoking
device in violation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> criminal code statute 531.6b).

            According to the testimony of
Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> sexual contacts between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and herself
began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 15, 1995</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> testimony, Part <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">I, Pages 12-18</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
testified that as an intern in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">West Wing</ENAMEX> she was summoned to deliver food
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and was so observed entering the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:59 p.m.</TIMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the uniformed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> detail (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Officer Lewis Fox</ENAMEX> testimony,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pages 5-12</ENAMEX>).

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>?"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> cooed, hoisting a large box of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domino</ENAMEX>'s above her stylish dark
tresses, according to the testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and Officer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>. The
raven-haired beauty, her voluptuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curves</ENAMEX> thrusting against the tight fabric
of a low-cut white dress, stood outside the door of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> near
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">midnight</ENAMEX>, a come-hither look in her flashing, dark eyes. "I'd love some," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> drawled, his eyes widening with desire, "but let me finish up here
talking about highway appropriations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>." He winked broadly, then
gave her a wide, rakish smile that lit her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> with excitement. She was alone
at last with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>! (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> I, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27-42</NUMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> has stated that ever
since arriving in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1995</TIMEX>, the brilliant young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intern</ENAMEX>, known both for her
shapely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and a powerful intelligence that would make her an asset in any
high-paying corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> job (contact: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plato Cacheris</ENAMEX>, [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">202</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">555-9432</ENAMEX>), looked
for ways to attract the attention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. He was tall, charismatic,
with piercing blue eyes that made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> weak inside--and, best of all, he was
the most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>! Now he put down the phone and looked at
her--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX>--with undisguised hunger. "You look as hot as that pie,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">darlin'</ENAMEX>," he said, glancing at the cleavage of her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, young breasts, while
her breath quickened with expectation. "I've seen you around before, haven't I?
What's your name again?"

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>," she said, her voice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">husky</ENAMEX> with longing. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exhibit A</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> diary," Page
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>).

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, I think
it's snack time," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> said with a sexy growl in his voice. [...] He
guided her into an adjoining study, holding a slice of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> in his free hand,
and said, in the warm, caring way she'd always admired, "I need someone like
you in times like these."

            With an unleashed passion
that took her breath away, he suddenly grabbed, through her sheer dress, the
firm yet pliant flesh of her buttocks, causing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> to shiver with
excitement, and then urgently kissed her, his tongue teasing hers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
stated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. "You really turn me on, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>," he said in a hoarse,
breathless whisper. "A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of state</ENAMEX> has needs, sweetie <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX>, just like any
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>," he added, putting his hand gently on the back of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s luxuriant
dark hair, guiding her down to his fiery loins. Her face beamed with adoration
as she explored his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, her tongue licking him slowly as she moved ever
closer to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> of love (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-24</NUMEX>; see also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>
tape transcripts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11-34</NUMEX>).

            She enveloped his throbbing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manhood</ENAMEX>, and the muscles in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thighs</ENAMEX> contracted while he moaned softly with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pleasure</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> testified. "You're fantastic, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>," he gasped. "I
wish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> knew how to treat me like you do." [...] Suddenly, the president
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> exploded in shuddering bursts of joy. After they hugged
each other, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> aglow in her newfound love, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> whispered to her,
"You're special to me, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>, but let's keep this our little secret" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diary</ENAMEX>, Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> tapes, Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>). He reached for the still-warm <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> with
a satisfied smirk. "Seems like I'm always hungry, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>," he said. She
understood exactly how he felt.

             

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> analysis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> found
on a cocktail dress owned by Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> corroborates another key sexual
encounter and thus contradicts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s sworn deposition on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 17</TIMEX> that
he could not recall meeting alone with Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cf</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> lab findings,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 10, 1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">re 'love juice</ENAMEX>' " <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5-9</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> deposition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52, 92</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>).

            Item: On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> returned from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> after services eulogizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Brown</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> phone logs for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that date</TIMEX> show that he placed a
phone call to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> residence at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:20 a.m.</TIMEX> He apparently felt the
familiar longing that only the beautiful and vivacious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> could
satisfy (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> testimony<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, Part II</ENAMEX>, Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">161</NUMEX>). He would do (or say) anything
to have her, even if it meant breaking the law--or a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s heart
(testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky II</ENAMEX>, Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">191</NUMEX>.) That <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>,
wondering if he really loved her, she was lounging in her black silk pajamas,
her ripe breasts exposed, waiting for his call. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, I want you with me all
the time," he told her, and that's all she needed to hear. [...] She was
wearing a sexy blue cocktail dress when she was ushered into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>
alone (testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Confidential Informant No. 12</ENAMEX>, code named <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Manolo</ENAMEX>"), and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> gazed at her with a wild, hungry passion (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> diary, Page
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">136</NUMEX>).

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>, I want to see all of
you ... naked," he begged. [...]

            Climbing on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secluded</ENAMEX> study, she wriggled her luscious hips, and slowly began peeling off
her dress, shaking her huge breasts free so he could see--and touch--them in
all their alabaster glory. She trembled as he caressed her, and she moved with
new, intense passion as she saw him arouse himself, his face distorted in a
mask of sheer lust. "Oh, my God, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>, you turn me on more than any woman
I've ever known," he exclaimed in between rapid pants of excitement. "I want to
marry you after I leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> far, far behind."
With that, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> exultantly threw the dress down at his feet as the president
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groaned</ENAMEX> in ecstasy and release, leaving traces of his love on her dress, a
memento of the passion they shared together (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> tapes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">124-192</ENAMEX>; Tripp
testimony, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36-43</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> I, Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> never imagined that
the dress she treasured would someday be used to help convince <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> that
her exclusive story of their steamy love affair, complete with shocking new
details, was well worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> or more, foreign rights included.

             

            In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 17, 1998</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deposition</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> said he couldn't recall the specifics of most gifts
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> gave him, and yet he strongly denied receiving a silver cigar box from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> deposition, Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX>). But a reported sexual encounter between
Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> challenges the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s veracity under oath on
this matter. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> has received compelling evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> not only
gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> the box, but Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> conspired with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to
use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) cigar from the box to perform a lewd and lascivious act in
violation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, criminal statute (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> testimony I, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">121-184; Exhibit C</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nieman-Marcus</ENAMEX> receipt, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1, 1996</TIMEX> ; The Drudge
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 22, 1998</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> statute 531.6b).

            Item: On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 16, 1996</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> logs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s sworn statements, where she asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> if
he would ever be willing to declare their romance to the world. In response,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> handed her a velvet box with a silver ring inside. "Our love is
important to me," he told her. Her heart filled with an overpowering love for
him, but she was puzzled when he leered, "It matches the silver of the cigar
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">box</ENAMEX>." He reached into the silver humidor and took out a clear-wrapped <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">El Tempo</ENAMEX>,
and gave her a big grin. "You can't commit adultery with a cigar, right?"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> I, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">155-170</ENAMEX>).

            She wondered again whether he
cared for her as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, or just as a sex object to service his sickest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">desires</ENAMEX>. She was shocked to realize that it didn't matter, really, as long as
she got to be with him now--and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">forever</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> diary, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92-93</NUMEX>). "Hand me
that cigar, big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>," she said, hoisting up her skirt, wallowing in all the
depravity he taught her, "and let's see if we can light your fire!" Soon she
was squirming on top of the blue carpet's presidential seal, moaning, "Oh, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>!" while his cauldron of lust came to a boil--and then overflowed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> stated (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> I, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">175-179</ENAMEX>). They were both plunged into a
crazed maelstrom of feverish ecstasy, and afterward he asked her a special
favor. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darlin'</ENAMEX>, if you're ever called to testify about our relationship, don't
ever lie."

            "I promise, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>."

            He added with a cackle, "But
just don't volunteer any extra information!" He was so brazen sometimes, she
couldn't help but love him (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> I, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">180-186</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> tapes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">211-212</ENAMEX>).

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> pattern of subornation of perjury and obstruction of justice (see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sections II</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>, below) was built on this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX> of lies and sexual
misconduct. We hope your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> will take appropriate action in response to
the enclosed material.
            

            More Flytrap
...

         
      
   
