
   
   
      
         
            Portraits of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Political Puzzle</ENAMEX>

            These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> images are halves
of a political puzzle. Fit them together, and you may solve the great mystery
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidency.

            That mystery, of course, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s continued high standing in the eye of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>. He's still
enjoying high enough poll figures to have refused to answer any scandal-related
questions at his recent press conference, even to have noted his comfort in
keeping silent. High approval ratings cushion even a stonewall.

            Yet polls also indicate that
the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> that "approves" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s presidency suspects that many
of the scandalous allegations against him are true. How can <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> such opinions
live peacefully together in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX> would probably
like to know the answer to that. That's him in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Image No. 1</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX> was running
snapshot of him with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Rice</ENAMEX> on his lap surfaced, promptly crushing his
candidacy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX> was already reeling from allegations of womanizing; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photo</ENAMEX>--which was exhibited often enough to be burned into our synapses--closed
the case against him. The consensus was that, as we could see with our own
eyes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hart</ENAMEX> lacked the discipline and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> for the presidency. He was
driven from public life.

            What,
then, does Image No. 2 show us? It shows us <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> on a
campaign flight in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. Seated next to him on a jump seat is flight attendant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debra Schiff</ENAMEX>; she's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s hand between her thighs. The image
is from a video clip shown in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> and since posted on the Internet.
This image has occasioned almost no comment. What does it reveal about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s discipline and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>? Apparently nothing. Or rather, nothing that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> cares to be bothered with. The apparent consensus is that,
whatever we can see with our own eyes, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schiff</ENAMEX>'s
business.

            If there's any visual difference between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> images,
it's that the one featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is more lurid. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX> are knowingly
posing for a camera; you could frame the shot and display it on the coffee
table (as long as you had the right sort of postmodern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> living in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schiff</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, have been caught off guard; the
result would have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peeping</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> quality if their encounter had any personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intimacy</ENAMEX>, which it does not. There's a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> present, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with whom
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is conversing even as he rubs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schiff</ENAMEX>'s thighs. The effect is
disturbing, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schiff</ENAMEX> is depersonalized.

            Why, then,
the disparity between the political effects of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> images? Because
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX>'s--was perceived to contain vital political information and the
other--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s--apparently isn't. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> between the public exhibition
of these images, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987 to 1998</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>" has been largely emptied of the
political significance it had throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the postwar era</TIMEX>, as least as far as
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are concerned. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> era, presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> has been
decoupled from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> character.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hart</ENAMEX>'s problem was actually that, as a symbol
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-ness, his "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>" mattered more then than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s does now.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> there was still a significant external threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> tradition of global competition over ideas and issues. Potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX>--like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronauts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> playing on
an international stage--still had to carry a lot of symbolic baggage: They had
to appear as forthright <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champions</ENAMEX> in a historic contest, disciplined leaders
who embodied national values. Look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>, an emotional stiff who
would have a tough time competing for national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Yet in his own era
he could parlay "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>" symbolism into a pair of landslide victories.
Leadership symbolism was pretty much what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> was about.

            What is
leadership minus strength of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX> failed that test. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
never even had to pass it. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, presidential role-playing was already
changing dramatically. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> were gone, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> had seemingly
solidified the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> global position. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> was able to shrug off the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX> scandal rather quickly; its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> were becoming domestic.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interestingly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is heard on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX> tapes telling her that, when
asked, she can characterize their relationship as she pleases precisely because
there are no known photographs of them together. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s concerns about
being another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX> turn out to have been anachronistic, as the limited impact
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> embrace imagery demonstrates.) Even as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was
running for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, a different presidential model was already asserting
itself.

            We've seen this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> before. Whenever the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> emerges
from a national trauma and focuses on its piggy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, presidential expectations
shrink. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> following the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War of 1812</ENAMEX> were, politically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Era</ENAMEX> of Good
Feelings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction</ENAMEX> were the political ciphers of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> ascendancy. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
was business.

            The idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
"approval" represents something new and immoral in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is historically
shortsighted. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1884</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> shrugged off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover Cleveland</ENAMEX>'s
confessed paternity of an out-of-wedlock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. Didn't matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland</ENAMEX>'s role,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rutherford Hayes</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Harding</ENAMEX>'s, was to take care of business.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is said to be concerned with shaping a historical legacy, but as may be
noted from his failed medical care program, his unpopular anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> saber
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rattling</ENAMEX>, and his largely ignored dialogue on race, the care of business is
pretty much all that's wanted of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, too.

         
      
   
