
   
   
      
         
            On Being a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>

            I venture to air these
musings about my life because so much is being written <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> about who is
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, or about who is a good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>. I don't know how typical my experience is,
but I am sure it is not unique.

            I
recently read a little book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Penguin Book of Jewish Short Stories</ENAMEX> ,
which my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> had given me. Reading these stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> life in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">eastern Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred or so years ago</TIMEX> was eye-opening. I had never before
felt so close to my roots. I could have been one of the pale, skinny young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>
who sat in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> studying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmud</ENAMEX>. I could have been the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warsaw</ENAMEX> fantasizing about his love affair with the beautiful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>. I felt that there was nothing in my own personality or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> that
would have prevented me from being just like them if I had been born in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> and place.

            The discontinuity between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shtetl</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1897</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate Apartments</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> must be the greatest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-century</TIMEX> gap in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> life since the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exodus</ENAMEX>.
If I could imagine myself back at the beginning of that discontinuity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1897</TIMEX>,
I could by easy stages imagine myself back <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> millennia.

            My family
and I made that leap in the direction from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1897 to 1997</TIMEX> with no intermediate
stops. We did not have resting places in prolonged settlement in a transplanted
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warsaw</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Side</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> or a transplanted shtetl in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brownsville</ENAMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> from the shtetl just about a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hundred years ago</TIMEX>, and almost immediately left the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> life behind. Having
no supportive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, at an early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> he joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States Cavalry</ENAMEX>,
using a borrowed birth certificate. That was about as un-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> an occupation
as you can imagine. He went with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troop</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> to chase the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> raj.

            
When I was born, he was living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, then
a quite un-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, working for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Motor Co.</ENAMEX>, a notoriously un-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">employer</ENAMEX>, as a blue-collar machinist, a very un-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX>. Until I was
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>, although I and everyone else knew I was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, I led a life with hardly
any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> content. After <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, I lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Schenectady</ENAMEX>, another gentile
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>. I never had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> mitzvah. Although I spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> studying
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>, I never spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> studying <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>. At the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 11</TIMEX>, I spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">semester</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX>. That was the extent of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> education. I spent much more time studying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> than studying the
Bible. I went to an isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Berkshire Mountains</ENAMEX> where <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> that entered with me was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jewish</TIMEX>. We had compulsory attendance at
Episcopal chapel services <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> times a week. Until I went to graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>,
I never had a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> except for my clarinet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>.

            The
raising of my consciousness as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> began at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>, when I married a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and community background were much more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> than mine, although
she was still not an observant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>. Other steps came with maturation. Being a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, then a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowner</ENAMEX>, gave me a more realistic sense of my own
identity and responsibilities than I had had when I lived in the fantasy world
of academia. As a result of the pattern of residential segregation that
remained in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> at least through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> houses
that we bought in succession was on a block with many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. I
became one of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a newly formed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX> in the suburban
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> where we lived. But I attended services rarely and felt
uncomfortable when I did, because I knew so little of what was going on.

            Learning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> was a powerful reminder that I
had an identity that, except for the accident of geography, would have brought
me to the same fate as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 million</NUMEX> others. The establishment, triumphs, and risks
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> were a source of pride and obligation to me.

            Oddly, two
of the most satisfying experiences of my life as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> came about on the
initiative of gentiles. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> sent me, with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>,
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> at the celebration of the anniversary of the
founding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. This was a great pleasure and honor for me personally,
but I also felt that I was doing something for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by serving as a token
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s support for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.

            
Having used the magic words "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>"
in the same paragraph, I want to answer a question often asked of me.
Apparently, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> said some things that I wish he had not said. But I know
of nothing in his behavior to me, to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, or to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in
general that entitles him to anything less than my total loyalty.

            The other
gentile who enters my story, and in a more important way, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Shultz</ENAMEX>. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, he named me to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> on the economic
problems of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. I worked with several other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>,
to develop a policy that would rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> from devastating inflation and set
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on a course of durable economic progress. The policy succeeded, and
I was fortunate to have had the opportunity to make that contribution to my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            So, what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> am I after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 years</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consciousness-raising</ENAMEX>? For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, I am proud to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>. I do not refer
only to the cliché of pride in belonging to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonas Salk</ENAMEX>; or to pride in the fact that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God Bless America</ENAMEX>" was
written by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irving Berlin</ENAMEX>. I refer also to pride in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> as a whole. I recently
saw statistics saying that there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 5 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the world, about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2 billion</NUMEX> of them <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 13 million</NUMEX> of them <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. And I thought,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wow</ENAMEX>, we precious few have achieved a lot and survived a lot! My Jewishness
certainly includes support for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, although not always support for the
policies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, and I have recommended a reduction in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government financial aid for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.

            I am puzzled about what to
say on the subject of my religion. I pray to God, but I do not feel that I am
praying to an exclusively <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> God. If, as we say, there is one God, surely
he is God of the whole universe, including the gentiles. I observe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 commandments</TIMEX>, excepting only the one about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabbath</ENAMEX>, but I don't think
the commandments are for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> alone. I recognize deficiencies in my <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Jewishness</ENAMEX>.
I wish I had studied <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>. I regret that I did not have
more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> education. I do not have the energy to remedy these deficiencies
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>. I am pleased that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have had more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> education than I did,
and that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> have even more.

            All in all, I believe that if
I ever meet one of my forebears, one of those pale, skinny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yeshiva students</ENAMEX>
from the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> shtetl of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1897</TIMEX>, I will be able to say to him,
"I, too, am a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>--not a saint, but a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> like you."

         
      
   
