
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirty Linen</ENAMEX>

            Fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Hilfiger</ENAMEX>
is in the news--make that "in the newsgroups." For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some months</TIMEX> now, the
Internet has been abuzz with rumors that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilfiger</ENAMEX> made racist remarks in two
separate television appearances.

            According
to various postings on the Net, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilfiger</ENAMEX> confessed on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> that if he
had been able to predict the success of his clothing among "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chinamen</ENAMEX> and
niggers," he would "never have made it so nice." A shocked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winfrey</ENAMEX> allegedly
cut to a commercial; when the show continued, she had changed out of her
now-tainted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Hilfiger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> was gone.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> story has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilfiger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Lauren</ENAMEX> appearing on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style With Elsa Klensch</ENAMEX> . Complimented on his success in selling
his goods in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren</ENAMEX> thanked his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. Enter <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hilfiger</ENAMEX>,
voicing his preference that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>--"these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>"--not wear his clothes. A
spotty paraphrase of the allegations appeared in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 13, 1996</TIMEX>, article in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Philippine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isyu</ENAMEX> . Titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Eat Your Clothes</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Racist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Designer</ENAMEX>," the piece has been excerpted on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Official</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Philippine Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Hilfiger</ENAMEX> site. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> tiptoes around the charges,
but is markedly less tentative when expressing her outrage. "I am shocked," she
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fulminates</ENAMEX>. "If [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hilfiger</ENAMEX>] really did insult my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, you can bet I will do
every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">single</NUMEX> thing I can in my power to make sure that his label never makes it
here."

            Forums
ranging from soc.culture.<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">african</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">american</ENAMEX> to talk.rumors and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Streetsound</ENAMEX> have been thick
with anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX> talk of late. When rumors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>'s alleged racist
outbursts filtered into the mainstream media, they were debunked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>. But that didn't stem for a boycott of his
products. Nor did the official response of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilfiger Corp.</ENAMEX> Claiming to have
become aware of the brouhaha only recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has posted a memo on
various anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX> sites detailing the "simple and incontrovertible facts":
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilfiger</ENAMEX> has never been on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilfiger</ENAMEX> has never been on
Style . Far from wanting to limit his appeal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilfiger</ENAMEX> is on record about
wanting to cross ethnic lines to appeal to everyone everywhere.

            
This isn't the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time a fashion designer
has been so vilified: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liz Claiborne</ENAMEX> was the subject of a virtually identical
story, promoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike Lee</ENAMEX> in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> interview. (An earlier myth had her
admitting publicly--again on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> --to connections with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX>.) Corporate collisions with racial <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> have become quite common. In
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1980s</TIMEX>, purported connections with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ku Klux Klan</ENAMEX> so damaged the
reputation of athletic-wear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Troop</ENAMEX> (whose name was rumored to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ku Klux Klan</ENAMEX> acronym for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Rule Over Oppressed People"</ENAMEX>) that it was forced
into bankruptcy. Talk of the inclusion of sterility-inducing ingredients
targeting black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> hobbled both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church's Fried Chicken</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>) and the soft
drink <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tropical Fantasy</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1990s</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Fried Chicken</ENAMEX> and a host of
tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown & Williamson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.J. Reynolds</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>, were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klan</ENAMEX>/sterility-related canards. Shoe
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturers Reebok</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Converse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puma</ENAMEX> were accused of supporting
apartheid in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>. The corporate-conspiracy paradigm was easily
extended to include <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> was purportedly a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-government-sponsored
tool for black genocide, as was crack. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury News</ENAMEX> recently published its findings linking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Contra</ENAMEX> drug-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runners</ENAMEX>, the rumors flared anew.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilfiger</ENAMEX> entered fashion circles in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lauren</ENAMEX> clone (read:
"khakis") at the outset, he identified an underserved fashion niche--urban
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black America</ENAMEX>, which was drawn to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WASPy</ENAMEX> abstractions but alienated by
their overstated inaccessibility. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilfiger</ENAMEX> saw potential for symbiosis between
hip-hop and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamptons</ENAMEX>. The result: He still does the khakis and the yacht
shots and the polo ponies (and the red-white-and-blue-stripe designs that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liken</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> flag), but he mixes them up with punch-bright colors
and exploded logos.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilfiger</ENAMEX> knew he had struck <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> when he noticed black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
mixing the preppy look with sports gear on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. As he told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, "I saw this and I said, 'Oh my God. What a great
opportunity.' " The fashion formula worked in both directions: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
craved the preppy look; white suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> wanted to be homeboys. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilfiger</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creations</ENAMEX> gained credibility when hip-hop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Puba</ENAMEX> (then of
Brand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nubian</ENAMEX>) started wearing them. Tapping his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Def Jam Music Group</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Simmons</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> pursued the rap crowd
aggressively. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snoop Doggy Dogg</ENAMEX> wore Hilfiger on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fugees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TLC</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doctor Dre</ENAMEX> have all donned the free threads <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tommy</ENAMEX>
has sent their way. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilfiger</ENAMEX> name was featured in the rap lyrics of Q-Tip
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Puba</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> has thrived. Its shares have risen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sevenfold</ENAMEX> since it went public in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>; its sales are expected to rise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
percent in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'97</ENAMEX> and a further <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> '98.

            Who, then,
is behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tommy tales</ENAMEX>? As with most contemporary conspiracy stories, the
source of this one remains elusive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX> folk legends are invariably ascribed
to a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" or, better still, a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" (a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOAF</ENAMEX>," to use
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">folklorist Jan Harold Brunvand</ENAMEX>'s acronym), who is close enough to stabilize the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> legend but distant enough to escape genuine scrutiny. Predictably,
therefore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Isyu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> takes no responsibility for her information;
some versions of the first inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>-related posting--by
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Geoff"</ENAMEX>--thank "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>" for the information; a newsgroup
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">respondent</ENAMEX> claims to have "heard ... from someone" that irate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Filipinos</ENAMEX> had
razed a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hilfiger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>. Less visible in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilfiger</ENAMEX> threads is the fact that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> textile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silas Chou</ENAMEX> owns <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilfiger Corp.</ENAMEX> Hilfiger himself owns <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22.5 percent</NUMEX>.

            
In theory, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> should be as good at
eradicating legends as it is at cultivating them, but in practice, denials are
quickly buried by new messages and updates. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilfiger</ENAMEX>'s official
response clogged newsgroup indexes. Today, it has been swamped by even newer
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX> postings and returning favorites.

            Why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX>? In her pathology of rumor in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> culture, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Heard It</ENAMEX>
Through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Grapevine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia A. Turner</ENAMEX> suggests that symbolically potent
products like athletic gear and flashy clothes--products that tote high price
tags but are of dubious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX>--invite hostile theorizing. Aware that they are
paying a premium for the label rather than the quality, minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> are
bound to feel exploited. Dissociation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of the offending
temptation--a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> jacket, say--becomes a coping mechanism, and rumor and
conspiracy theories are only a step away. "Yo I think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White America</ENAMEX> Is messing
up our mind whit all of this bullshit," claims one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protester</ENAMEX> in a newsgroup.
"They ... are laughing at us saying if we make it thsese [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ] stupid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ass Niggaz Will</ENAMEX> Buy it."

            As was the case with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilfiger</ENAMEX>'s pursuit of the
minority market has exposed him to a backlash (it's probably no accident that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren</ENAMEX>, whose turf he invaded, was cast as the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in the Klensch
Style story). And damage control will prove a challenge. Newsgroupies
were questioning the authenticity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilfiger's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> response soon after it
appeared on the Net. How many times can you kill the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">phoenix</ENAMEX>? It's a tough
job--any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">takers</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
