
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> I Knew

            Determined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> have fished through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> tapes and recovered enough material
to fill books and articles showing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> was obscene and unscrupulous. I
do not deny that there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> like that. But that was not the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nixon</ENAMEX>
or the most usual and important one. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> performed the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>,
difficult duties of being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> responsibly and respectably. I was not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confidant</ENAMEX> or crony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, but I saw him frequently during his
whole tenure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, when I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of</ENAMEX>
Economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advisers</ENAMEX>. On all these occasions he impressed me as a civil, serious,
dedicated, judicious, and highly intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. I believe that others who
worked with him in a professional way had the same impression.

            I first
met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 18, 1968</TIMEX>, after his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> election, when he was about to name
me a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEA</ENAMEX>. If I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> at all, I was not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nixon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. He was about to assume the most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in the world. I was
a little-known economics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">essayist</ENAMEX>. But I felt comfortable with him. He did not
try either to glad-hand me or to impress me with his importance. He showed
genuine interest in what I had to say about the matters on which I was assumed
to be well informed, and he was unreserved about expressing his own
opinion.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iwas</ENAMEX> also struck by my observation of him at the first
meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet Committee on Economic Policy</ENAMEX>, shortly after the
inauguration. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEA</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hendrik Houthakker</ENAMEX> and I were
the lowest-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> wanted to hear what we
had to say. He also made it clear that he did not expect his economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>
to engage in political activity, although we might make speeches on economic
policy to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> and others interested in a professional way. I
thought he showed courtesy, consideration, and a desire to learn. (Later, after
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> campaign, some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> thought that my speeches had
been too political. If so, it was because I enjoyed being in the political
game, not because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> urged me on.)

            In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next six years</TIMEX> I went through many meetings in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEA</ENAMEX>--would discuss economic policy
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. He usually listened to the interchange quietly. When the
discussion was over he would summarize it in a systematic way--distilling what
order could be extracted from it and indicating what he thought were the main
considerations and options. These scenes were light-years remote from the
locker-room conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haldeman, Erlichman</ENAMEX>, and others that have become
the subject of much recent interest.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> appreciated both the value and
the limitations of economics. He understood that it had something to contribute
and should be heard, but he also understood that economics is an uncertain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX>. There were no complaints or recriminations when the economic forecasts
turned out to be wrong. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of 1972</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEA</ENAMEX> had forecast that
unemployment would be down from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 6 percent to 4 percent</NUMEX> by the end of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, I had to report to him that unemployment was still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 5</NUMEX>
percent. I said that was "in the neighborhood" of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX>. All he replied was
that it was a streetcar ride across the neighborhood. That realistic attitude
was a great comfort to an economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>.

            I don't
recall him ever using an obscenity, unless you want to count the time he said
that he would rather have <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tent p...ing</ENAMEX> out than outside the tent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p...</ENAMEX>ing in. (I believe this was borrowed from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX>, and probably from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>.) I remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> once saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honesty</ENAMEX> may
not be the best policy, but it is worth trying once in a while." But that was
an occasion when he was arguing for honesty.

            In view of the grossness of some of the language
selectively extracted from the tapes, I think it important to note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>
showed an appreciation of, and capacity for, good writing and wit. He had
probably the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> of any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> since the time when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Hamilton</ENAMEX> wrote speeches for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> with him
that I best remember came in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1973</TIMEX>, when he was considering the
reimposition of a wage-and-price freeze that had been so popular when first
done in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1971</TIMEX>. In a smart-alecky kind of way, I said, quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heraclitus</ENAMEX>,
"You can't step in the same river twice." He immediately responded, "Yes, you
can, if it's frozen."

            In my
opinion the imposition of price-and-wage controls was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s one
serious economic-policy mistake. But that decision was within the range of
options urged upon him by respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>, mainly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. The control
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> extraordinary power over individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>.
I do not believe there was any case in which this power was improperly
used.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> recognized and utilized talent, whatever
its political connection. The leading example was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Shultz</ENAMEX>. He saw in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>, whom he had never met before he invited him to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">labor</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of extraordinary intelligence, management ability, and integrity.
He quickly elevated him to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> and
then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>. There must have been few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> that
had as much talent in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> positions--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>--as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s had in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shultz</ENAMEX>.

            I do not put down these few
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recollections</ENAMEX> in order to excuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>. I knew him and liked and
respected him. I am not inclined to judge him. I do not feel I have the wisdom
and moral elevation to do that. Anyway, what would be the point? He is now
beyond our--or, at least, my--power to add or detract. I only want to suggest
that those who feel the need and ability to judge him should try to look beyond
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revelation of the Day</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
