
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice</ENAMEX> Is Nice

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> and Frank
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX> hail from opposite ends of the political spectrum, but on the subject of
gambling, you could barely squeeze a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> chip between them. Safire preaches
his immovable conviction "that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predators</ENAMEX>; that
state-sponsored lotteries make a mockery of public policy; that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who
are on the take from gambling interests are wallowing in the occasion of sin."
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Counterpoint, Frank?</ENAMEX> "Already, such gambling-saturated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biloxi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>,
are looking like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Stewart</ENAMEX>'s nightmare vision of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bedford Falls</ENAMEX> in It's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wonderful Life</ENAMEX> . The stench of influence-peddling suffuses some state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> where gambling rules. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>, riverboat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> can be an
economic boon but sometimes suck local retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> dry. Statistics
suggest that crime, domestic abuse and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> rise in gambling's
wake--while the poor most conspicuously get poorer."

            Legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gambling</ENAMEX> brings out the latent puritan in many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. The right detests
gambling because it promises something for nothing. The left hates it because
it enriches <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> by emptying the pockets of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gullible</ENAMEX> lower classes.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX>-liberal-than-thou <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Sandel</ENAMEX> condemn it, as do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>.

            Everyone seems to detest legal gambling--everyone, that is,
except the public. Once regarded as a low habit, gambling is now generally
treated as wholesome entertainment in all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> spend
nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$51 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> on various games of chance--twice as much as they
spend on movies, plays, operas, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectator</ENAMEX> sports combined.

            But
gambling's place at the table is threatened by the puritans, who've used their
political muscle to help establish a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gambling Impact Study Commission</ENAMEX>.
They hope its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1999</TIMEX> report will prove their claims that gambling wrecks
lives, stimulates crime, saps local economies, mercilessly exploits human
weakness, and sustains itself through bribery and corruption. A review, then,
and a brief refutation of their best arguments.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> Become <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Addicted to Gambling: The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> warn of an exploding epidemic of addicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX>, but a recent study
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Medical School</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Addictions</ENAMEX> argues
against this notion. An estimated <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.6 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> will become
pathological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX>, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.2 percent</NUMEX> who will succumb to drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">addiction</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13.8 percent</NUMEX> who will become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alcoholics</ENAMEX>. A study published last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> claimed that the legalization of casinos causes an increase in suicide
rates. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>'s suicide rate is the highest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, double the
national average. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, home of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic City</ENAMEX>, enjoys the lowest
rate. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>'s gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mecca</ENAMEX>, falls slightly below the
national average.

            
               Legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gambling Fosters Crime: Exhibit A</ENAMEX> for the prosecution is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic City</ENAMEX>,
which went from being No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in crimes per capita to
being No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> after the arrival of casinos. This increase fails to account for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s huge influx of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, who on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any given day</TIMEX> outnumber <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2-to</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. As noted in a study by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reuter</ENAMEX>, homicides barely increased at all, despite the influx of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assaults</ENAMEX> rose only about as fast as the average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. The real
increases have come in robbery and aggravated assaults. Elsewhere, though, it's
impossible to detect any consistent relationship between the existence of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> and the prevalence of lawlessness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Margolis</ENAMEX>, who headed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">State Police</ENAMEX> when the state introduced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> riverboat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>, has
testified that "crime has not been a problem." Looking at rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A&M</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Stokowski</ENAMEX> found that with the arrival of casinos, "the
likelihood of becoming a crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gilpin County</ENAMEX> has decreased."

            

               Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gambling Depletes the Local</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economy: Economists</ENAMEX> normally extol anything that allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> to
satisfy their preferences, but several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the profession depict casinos
as the enemy of prosperity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Grinols</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Illinois</ENAMEX>
excoriates them as "a shell game, attracting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s pocket
to another and from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> to another." Another view holds that life for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> means death for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>, hardware <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, and
other wholesome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> unless legal gambling attracts massive numbers of
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>.

            But these
are the wrong measures of the economic value of gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX>.
Existing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are threatened when a new business comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, whether
it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nordstrom</ENAMEX> or a shoe repair <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>. No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> with ambitions for tenure
would dream of dismissing a business as a "shell game" merely because its
revenue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">diverts</TIMEX> revenue from other businesses.

            

               Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gambling Causes Corruption: Casino</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> are portrayed as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Typhoid Marys</ENAMEX> of political corruption, the usual
evidence being their lavish bankrolling of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. But of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
industries that gave "soft money" to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>,
the gambling industry ranked <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16 th</NUMEX> , according to the ultrafastidious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Responsive Politics</ENAMEX>.

            Casino <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> are right to
take a greater-than-average interest in the workings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Until
recently, their industry was illegal almost everywhere. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) They cannot operate
without hard-to-get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> licenses. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Their many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> want to
legislate them out of existence.

            As long
as we're talking about corruption and exploitation, we should not forget that
the wickedest gambling sharpies don't live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> but in the state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">capitals</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX> are headquartered. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX>' pitiful
payout--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> of all money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wagered</ENAMEX>, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">92 percent</NUMEX> or so at your
average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX>--rightly draws cries of outrage. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> were interested
in remedying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX>, they'd have the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> repeal their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX> on
these games and let the market compete away the excess profits.

            

               Whose <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life Is It, Anyway</ENAMEX>? Gambling's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> never tire of reciting statistics and anecdotes to suggest that the
costs of legalized gambling dwarf any possible benefits. But they fail to count
the central benefit--the diversion and pleasure it provides to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> were accessible only to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with the means to
travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>. The relaxation of prohibitionist laws has brought them
within easy reach of most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, and the public has voted for
them with its feet. The overwhelming majority of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX> gamble
responsibly and impose no burden on their fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. They treat games of
chance as exactly that--games.

            Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> insist on
portraying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX> as a pitiable class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX>, enslaved by fantasies of
unearned wealth. It's hard to see why. No one accuses movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> or
gardening-supply <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ruthlessly</ENAMEX> exploiting the weaknesses of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> who
turn over their money only because they lack the self-control to refuse. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who patronize the lottery, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX>, or the slot machines end up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poorer</ENAMEX>, with nothing to show for the transaction--which is also true of people
who eat in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and attend concerts. To incurable bluenoses, gambling is
an infuriating scam. But why assume <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX> are being fooled? It's more
reasonable to assume that they know they will probably lose but are happy to
take that chance for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the pleasure of playing and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the chance of coming out
ahead.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, that's a decision
they ought to be free to make, unimpeded by moralists and social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> who
think ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> cannot be trusted to look after their own interests. If
gambling were the grim scourge portrayed by its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>, it would not have
gone from a contemptible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX> to an innocent diversion in a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who have visited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> and played the lottery have seen that misery
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">damnation</ENAMEX> don't necessarily follow, either for themselves or for
surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. Gambling has become a widespread pastime for the
simple and unassailable reason that it adds to the sum of human happiness.
That's reason enough to leave it alone.

         
      
   
