
   
   
      
         
            Text

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artists</ENAMEX> have been playing
with the Web for as long as there's been one to play with. (For the record,
that's slightly less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>.) The whole idea behind the Web-browsing
revolution, after all, was that eye-catching colors, friendly graphics, and a
certain amount of motion would bring a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> online. They have.
watching live feeds from cameras positioned in all sorts of strange
places, including a satellite in outer space, a microscope, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>'s
own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            But the ideas behind
computer art are not new. The work of art has been dissolving into reproducible
signals for more than a quarter-century now. Video art had its heyday in the
1970s. CD-ROM art, which is basically computer art on a disc, is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a decade</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old</ENAMEX>. There are a few things Web art can do that other kinds of art can't,
however. It can enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who might otherwise never have sought
it out (or bought the CD-ROM that contained it). It can host any number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> logging on from any number of places at exactly the same time. It can
change--you can change it--and it can stay changed, a lasting if not indelible
record that you were there.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE Gallery</ENAMEX> is meant to
be a place where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> try things out and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> respond to them. Jenny
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holzer</ENAMEX> is our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the world's better-known conceptual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>,
she's been testing out different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> ever since she put her oddball "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Truisms</ENAMEX>"
into bus stops in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE Gallery</ENAMEX> will host a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> more or less
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every two weeks</TIMEX>. At first, we won't be able to show you every unusual feature
Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> have at their disposal. But we'll be getting better at this as we
go along, and whatever we can't do ourselves, we can link you to. (For example,
you can jump from this page to a piece <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holzer</ENAMEX> did
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>,in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got to create and post their very own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny Holzer</ENAMEX> truisms.) Along with the artwork, we'll be posting articles or
essays about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> or about the ideas behind the art. We hope you find it
interesting, or better yet, fun.

         
      
   
