
   
   
      
         
            Nuttiness

            
               [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s note: The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> articles listed here are factual and correctly quoted. The others are
not.]
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 3</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
               
            

            

               Headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Airlines May Have to Bag the Peanuts</ENAMEX>"
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation Department</ENAMEX> has informed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> that under new disability
rules, it must provide "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX>-free buffer zones"--defined as at least three
rows--for any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> who declares in advance a medically documented severe
allergy to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanuts</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 23</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX>
               
            

            
               Headline:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Growing Number of Schools Ban Peanut Butter as Allergy Threat</ENAMEX>"
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Prodded</ENAMEX>
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> warning of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lethal allergies</ENAMEX>, by the contentions of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>
that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">peanut allergies</ENAMEX> are on the rise and, not least, by a fear of litigation,
growing numbers of public and private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, including
many of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s most selective independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, have banned <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> from their cafeterias. Others have declared <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX>-free zones or set up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committees</ENAMEX> to figure out what to do.
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 10</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
               
            

            

               Headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Congress Declares Capitol Peanut-Free Zone</ENAMEX>"
            

            
               Citing
complaints by allergy-prone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> banned
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanuts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut products</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol</ENAMEX> and adjacent federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. The bipartisan resolution passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> on a vote of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">429-3</ENAMEX> and
was approved by voice vote in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Capitol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> distributed
epinephrine syringes throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX> allergy symptoms such as throat constriction and
rapid loss of blood pressure.
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 15</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
               
            

            
               Headline:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chinese Restaurants Declare Peanut Sauce 'Peanut-Free'</ENAMEX> "
            

            

               Prompted by widespread concern over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX>-related health risks, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restaurant Association of America</ENAMEX> banned <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanuts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut oil</ENAMEX> from all
"<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut sauce</ENAMEX>" served in accredited <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restaurants</ENAMEX> may
continue to serve "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut sauce</ENAMEX>" in dishes such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kung Pao</ENAMEX> Chicken, but that
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> may no longer contain actual <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanuts</ENAMEX>. Restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> who had opposed
the ban agreed to support it and to accept random enforcement inspections in
exchange for the right to retain the phrase "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut sauce</ENAMEX>" in carryout
menus.
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 18</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX>
               
            

            

               Headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts Killed Our Children</ENAMEX>"
            

            

               Support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> have sprouted up across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> for those whose lives have
been shattered by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanuts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX>. "This is a place for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
to come together and share their grief," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas French</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of PNUTTS
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People Newly United</ENAMEX> Through Their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Peanut</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Related Stress</ENAMEX>). "Peanuts stole away
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> never had a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX>. ... Now they can tell their stories without shame or ridicule."
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 20</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe Editorial</ENAMEX> Page

            
               Headline:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Peanut Menace</ENAMEX>"
            

            
               Gone
are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of innocently cracking salted shells at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballpark</ENAMEX> or spreading
a thick "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p.b.&j</ENAMEX>." at a family picnic. Civic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have at last confronted
the truth: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX> are a menace to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> way of life. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should
move immediately to prohibit the cultivation, sale, and use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanuts</ENAMEX> and
their byproducts.
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 23</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
               
            

            

               Headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">GOP Declares 'War on Peanuts'</ENAMEX> "
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> outlined a plan to eradicate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX> abuse by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the century</TIMEX>. Responding to a proposal backed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, under which government-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> would distribute cashews
to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut abusers</ENAMEX> on a transitional basis, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in both houses
demanded an aggressive interdiction program to "fight <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanuts</ENAMEX> at their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>."
Preliminary plans drafted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> involve napalm strikes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. "These <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut-</ENAMEX>growing bandits are
going to face the hellfire of their darkest, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX>-fueled nightmares,"
declared <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 24</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX>
               
            

            
               Headline:
"In Shift, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vests Powers</ENAMEX> in 'Czar' "
            

            
               Senior
administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> will appoint a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanut Czar</ENAMEX>" to oversee the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX> production and
consumption. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Aides</ENAMEX> commended the decision and cited progress on several fronts.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX>, the long-running syndicated comic strip <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX> has been
pulled from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, famed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX> advocate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX> has been demoted from "historic figure" to "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hatemonger</ENAMEX>,"
and the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> has been stripped of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>. Said a stoic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>, "It was only a matter of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>."
            

         
      
   
