
   
   
      
         
            Stop <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me Before I Link Again</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TicketMaster</ENAMEX> is suing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sidewalk</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s online city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX>--for linking to its Web site. A
half-dozen big media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have targeted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TotalNEWS</ENAMEX> with a lawsuit because,
they say, the site is using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> technology to steal their content. Suddenly,
the ease of linking from Web site to Web site, which makes the World Wide Web
so useful, is generating lawsuits that cloud the right to link.

            A world
of interconnected information, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> jump from one document to another,
was <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> envisioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vannevar Bush</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>. His whirling system of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motors</ENAMEX>, levers, and microfilm is to the Web what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo da Vinci</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">helicopters</ENAMEX> are to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinook</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CH-47</ENAMEX>. But you get the idea. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> disciple <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX> took the idea to the world of digital computers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>, calling his
creation "hypermedia" and dubbing these jumping points "hyperlinks." One early
commercial hypermedia product was <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HyperCard</ENAMEX>, released with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX>
computer in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>. HyperCard allows users to link "stacks" of information
they've written or assembled on computer "notecards." But the true promise of
hypermedia was linking information across a global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, and that had to
wait until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Berners-Lee</ENAMEX>'s invention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>'s rapid acceptance owes much to the ease with which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web pages</ENAMEX> can be created. And the proliferation of the lawsuits owes much to
the ease with which Web pages can be linked to one another. Creating links is
easy because each Web page, and each image on the page, has a unique address on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> called a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Resource Locator</ENAMEX>). For instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX> for
this page is <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slate</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com/webhead/97-06-06/webhead.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">asp</ENAMEX>.

            To see how this all works,
follow me as I build a Web site containing home page A and image B.

             

            A browser loading home page A
sees that it refers to image B and loads that too, then displays the whole
thing.

             

            
The great thing about this scheme is that if
you are on a slow connection to the Internet, you can tell your browser to
ignore the images. This speeds things up quite a bit (click to find out
how).

            The bad thing about this
scheme is that since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every</TIMEX> image has a public URL, anyone can use it. In the
example below, some villain has co-opted image B for his nefarious (and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">libelous</ENAMEX>) ends.

             

            The offending page doesn't technically copy or distribute
the image in question. It just points the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>'s browser to address B. Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> think that this may constitute a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> display," similar to illegally
publishing a copyrighted photograph in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, but this argument remains
untested.

            
Interestingly, if the page simply provides a hyperlink to the image in
question, the law becomes even murkier. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Entertain</ENAMEX>, for a moment, this scenario:
If we at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> captured your voicemail recording and played it on our site
without your permission, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> would say that we had violated your
copyright. But if we cited your telephone number instead, we wouldn't be
violating copyright laws--even though Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX> could hear the same recording
by dialing the number. Hyperlinks are like telephone numbers--but instead of
dialing them, you click on them.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">TicketMaster</ENAMEX> dispute muddles this point
further. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is upset not because <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX> provided a hyperlink to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TicketMaster's</ENAMEX> site, but because <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX> provided a hyperlink "deep" into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TicketMaster's</ENAMEX> site. What is "deep"? Well, the page you're looking at is
relatively deep in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. To find your way here, you probably typed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
home page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slate</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. We showed you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s cover, then our table
of contents, and you eventually clicked on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Webhead</ENAMEX>" link. But if a friend
gave you the precise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX> for this column, you could go directly to it. So, in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, the link to this story is a "deep" hyperlink, because it avoids our home
page.

            This is
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidewalk</ENAMEX> did: It recorded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URLs of TicketMaster's</ENAMEX> transaction pages,
where you buy tickets for specific shows. It then placed hotlinks to these URLs
on its own pages that hype various concerts and theatrical productions. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">angered TicketMaster</ENAMEX> because it allowed potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purchasers</ENAMEX> of tickets to
avoid ads and promotions on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TicketMaster</ENAMEX>'s home page and all the intermediate
pages you must visit before you can buy a ticket. Returning to my voicemail
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">analogy</ENAMEX>, it's as if I cited not only your telephone number, but also the code
to skip your clever message (hint: on most voicemail systems, press "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">#"</ENAMEX>). While
this may not be friendly, it doesn't seem like a violation of
intellectual-property law.

            While the lawsuit proceeds, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TicketMaster</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX> have
exchanged some entertaining technological volleys. Click for a brief account of
these.

            Just as a Web page can
include an image by citing that image's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX>, so also can it include another Web
page by citing that page's address. This technique is called "framing." I
framed pages in my last Webhead to compare search results from various search services.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> tells me this sort of framing doesn't violate anyone's copyright
(<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phew</ENAMEX>!). It's called "fair use," and is comparable to the quotation of a short
passage of a book in a review.

            So why did the news sites sue
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TotalNEWS</ENAMEX>? See for yourself. When you click to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TotalNEWS</ENAMEX>, a column of icons for
several news sites appears down the left side of the page. If you click, say,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , up pops the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> Web site, but inside a frame.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TotalNEWS</ENAMEX>' advertisement remains visible. This definitely isn't "fair use." If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> decide that such framing constitutes a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> display," or even that it
causes confusion in the market ("unfair competition"), then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TotalNEWS</ENAMEX> is

            As we go to press, TotalNEWS
has settled out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. For details, see this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 6</TIMEX> Wired
News story.

         
      
   
