
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX>

            When the weather is good, I
often take the bus to my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. I suppose that is partly because the bus trip
costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> less than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> trip and I am of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> generation that
still thinks that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> is a lot of money. I tell myself that it is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only 60 cents</NUMEX>
in real <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX> dollars, but that doesn't stick in my mind. Also, I really like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>. I like to observe the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>. And I get a better view of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> from my seat on the bus than I do from the
back seat of a taxi, especially during one of those wild rides where I am
closing my eyes to blot out the dangers.

            The bus
stop is across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> in which I live. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, possibly even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years ago</TIMEX>, when I came out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> there
would be knots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, often <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>, standing around, looking to take
pictures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> where it happened. They are all gone now. "Watergate"
has become an abstraction, a symbol for something bad a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> did. But
there are fewer and fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who remember just what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> did.
Hardly anyone now remembers why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Hamilton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Burr</ENAMEX> fought a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">duel</ENAMEX>, or why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Johnson</ENAMEX> was almost voted out of office. So it is becoming
with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>.

            How accommodating it is of history to have located the
break-in of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> with a distinctive
architectural style and name! Suppose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">break-in</ENAMEX> had been at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those
identical cubical office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, with names like <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1150 17 th St.,</ENAMEX>
that fill downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. Would <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> have come to take its picture?
And what would we have instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Contragate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewatergate</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Filegate</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> would have been clichéless.

            But back
to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> is always an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> and often a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. I can't
get used to saying "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>." Her ancestors probably came here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long</TIMEX>
before <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>--perhaps well over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> before mine. If she is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">African-American</ENAMEX>, what am I--a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>? But whatever we call her, I am
glad to see her. She has overcome centuries of race and gender prejudice to get
where she is. I am pleased to see the competence with which she wrestles that
big bus around corners, hands out transfers, and answers <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>' questions
about stops and connections. Not long ago, such competence would not have been
expected of her.

            
After snaking around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> blocks, we arrive at
a corner on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Avenue</ENAMEX> where one can see, separated by a narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>. What a
concentration of worldwide power! But more impressive than the power is the
concentration of homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> lounging on the grates and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX>.

            Two
blocks down on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Avenue</ENAMEX>, we come to the site of my epiphany. Looking out
of the bus window <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, I saw a tall, graceful fountain in the garden behind
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that fronted on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution Avenue</ENAMEX>. I had passed it dozens of times
without noticing it, perhaps because the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> had not been playing before. I
suddenly had the thought that if I had been on a tour <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> would have called our attention to that fountain and explained its
history, and we would all have marveled at it. From that moment, at least for a
while, I looked at my surroundings with fresh eyes--the eyes of a tourist.

            We turn up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Street</ENAMEX> and pass the rear
entrance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution Hall</ENAMEX>, the property of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Daughters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Revolution. I wondered how many other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are famous for something that
didn't happen in them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marian Anderson</ENAMEX> didn't sing here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>.
I have recently seen assertions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DAR</ENAMEX> excluded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marian Anderson</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution Hall</ENAMEX> because she wanted to sing on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter Sunday</ENAMEX>, and not because
she was "colored," as we used to say. I don't know the truth of that, but it
really doesn't matter. The truth is that conditions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX> were
such that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marian Anderson</ENAMEX> could be excluded because of her race, and
that conditions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are such that she could not.

            A little
farther up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> th Street we see the huge <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, among other things, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Indian Affairs</ENAMEX>.
That is the locus of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s favorite stories, about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrat</ENAMEX> who was found with his head down on his desk, sobbing because his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> had died. That is a funny story, but it should not have been told by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, who should have realized that the historic
relation between the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Indians</ENAMEX> is no laughing
matter.

            
As we proceed up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Street</ENAMEX>, we
take on more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>, almost all of them "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>" or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>.
Often I am the only "white" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>. In my new stance as a tourist, I
think to myself: "How exotic. I could be on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, and all the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> could be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>. I know so little about them, about their lives
and thoughts and feelings."

            But then
I realize how superficial that attitude is. Fundamentally the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> and I are pretty much alike, riding on the same bus to the same
destination over the same potholes. (And we have reached a degree of liberation
that permits me to think of these potholes as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>'s potholes without
feeling guilty of racism.)

            The word "fundamentally" in the previous paragraph carries
a lot of weight, but it is important to think of what is fundamental. I mean
having the experience of love and loneliness, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> and health, the joy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, the satisfaction of work, and the inevitability of death. Those are
the respects in which we are all alike. That is the sense in which we are all
on the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>. Perhaps it is being <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80 years of age</TIMEX> that makes me think that
these are the overwhelmingly important and overwhelmingly common aspects of
life. But many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> much wiser than I am have thought that at a much earlier
age than mine.

            Nearing the end of my trip, I
realize that my observations have been largely about race. That is not
surprising. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Race</ENAMEX> is the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> problem. From the standpoint of human
history, race is not the distinctive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> condition--freedom and prosperity
are. But even this pretend-tourist takes that for granted. It is the race
problem--that tangled web of history, hostility, demands, frustrations,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">injustice</ENAMEX>, and lawlessness--that gets, and deserves, attention. And yet, as I
think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marian Anderson</ENAMEX> and about my fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and about the female
bus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>, I feel hopeful.

            At my destination she pulls
the handle to open the door for me. I say, "Thank you." She says, "Have a nice
day."

         
      
   
