
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>

            When I walk in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX>
with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, pretty young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> nudge each other and whisper, "It's him! It's
him!" They don't mean me. My function in this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> scene is to hold the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>' camera and take their picture with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>.

            I am
surely not the most objective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Stein</ENAMEX> phenomenon, but I am
probably the best informed. So let me explore the question: How did my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>, become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Star</ENAMEX>? It wasn't by being the world's most devoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, making the
long trip from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> about once a month to give me <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>,
which he does. It wasn't by being the world's most devoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, spending
many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX> with his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>; or by writing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> books. I have a
devoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who is a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX>, and pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>--but that doesn't make her a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>.

            You become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> by being seen repeatedly in a
recognizable way by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. That means being in the movies or,
especially, on TV. What you have done in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> doesn't matter terribly
much; what matters is having been seen. Even after my occasional appearances on
TV-talk shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come up to me and say, "I saw you on TV." They don't say
whether they liked my performance or agreed with what I had to say. The
important thing is that they recognize a face they have seen on TV.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s
approach toward stardom began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 12 years ago</TIMEX> with a movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bueller</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Day Off</ENAMEX> , and continued through various other films, sitcoms, and
TV commercials. But he was not then a full-fledged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>. (I guess we don't use
the word "starlet" for such cases; it is reserved for something else.) What
made him a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> was his new TV show, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Win Ben Stein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money</ENAMEX> . As its name
suggests, the show would not be the same without him.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WBSM</ENAMEX> is a unique quiz show. It is more playful
than, for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jeopardy</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> first plays the role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>,
explaining the game and asking the questions. But he then becomes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contestant</ENAMEX>,
competing with the more successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>. There is a witty, sometimes rude,
interchange among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Kimmel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-host</ENAMEX>; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>. The closest
parallel I can think of is the old <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Groucho Marx show You Bet Your</ENAMEX>
Life .

            The fact
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> are competing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>'s money gives it an unusual thrill. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> in other quiz shows are not taking the money away from any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">identifiable</ENAMEX>, live <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Trebek</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jeopardy</ENAMEX> , for example. They
are taking the money from some faceless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merv Griffin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprises</ENAMEX>. But trying to get the money from this well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>, who is right there and expressing his torment at losing the money,
creates an unusual tension. (Of course, the money is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>'s only in what an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> might call the "opportunity cost" sense. That is, he did not put it
up originally, but the more the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> win the less he has to keep.)

            Even after I have seen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 20</NUMEX> episodes of the show, I am
still amazed that my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> is up there on the screen. There has been very
little theater in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-aunt</ENAMEX> had the candy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concession</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> theater on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower East Side</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> was in the
chorus of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those doughboy musicals after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I. The Steins</ENAMEX> are not
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barrymores</ENAMEX>, but there is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> on the screen. I'm also amazed at the things
he knows, like of what river the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zambezi</ENAMEX> is a tributary.

            He plays
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> on the show. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> he is what I think of as
himself. He is witty, well-informed, and good-natured. In the other character
he shouts; becomes excited; and goes through various gestures, like bowing,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">saluting</ENAMEX>, and rapping himself on the chest. I much prefer the former, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> seems to like it all, and that's show business.

            
"How does it feel to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star?</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> often ask me. It would be hypocritical of me to deny that there is a
certain amount of envy. Like almost everyone else, I like attention. He may be
diverting attention from me, although those pretty, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> on the street
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> would not have been giving me attention anyway. And there is some
gain in attention, probably a net gain for me. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who never paid any
attention to me as economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, or even as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>
for 
                  Slate
               , do give me some attention because I am the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of a
Star. And I get satisfaction from thinking that part of his theatrical success
derives from the dull voice he inherited from me.

            But the
envy is a small thing, and I confess it only in a rather transparent effort to
gain credibility. Mainly I am happy and proud--not just because he is a TV Star
but because he is a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Star</ENAMEX> in addition to being a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, a
good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, and an energetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> for many good public causes. I am happy to
think that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and I, if we did not make him what he is, did not prevent
him from becoming what he is.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ido</ENAMEX> feel, however, some anxiety in this situation. In one
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Bellow</ENAMEX>'s books there is a sentence, which I have never been able to
find since I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> read it, about grasping "the hot wire of publicity"--and not
being able to let go. Stardom can be addictive. It can be so exhilarating that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> needs ever greater amounts of it and can be induced to do silly or reckless
things to get more of it. Stardom can also be very transitory, and losing it,
after once having had it, can be terribly depressing. I don't think any of that
will happen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>. He is too many other solid things, in addition to being a
Star. But that is something the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> worries about, when he isn't
just enjoying the fun of it all.

         
      
   
