
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Songs We Feel With</ENAMEX>

            Once upon a time, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was
in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> waiting to go out on a date to which he was looking forward
with pleasure. Unexpectedly it began to rain. For a moment this depressed him.
But soon these words came tripping through his brain: "Isn't it a lovely day to
be caught in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>?" He could see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Astaire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginger Rogers</ENAMEX> in a gazebo
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX> with the rain pitter-pattering around them. He was happy
again.

            Once upon
another time, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, perhaps not the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, was expecting someone for whom
he cared to return from a brief trip. When he saw her he spontaneously began to
sing softly: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, hello, Dolly! <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX>, Dolly! It's so nice to have you back
where you belong." He felt warmth and joy. He experienced the joy that shone
out of the face of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis Armstrong</ENAMEX> when he sang that in the movie.

            At an earlier time, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who was lonely used to find
running through his head a song that went: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sometimes</ENAMEX> I wonder why I spend each
lonely <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, dreaming of a song." Those words consoled him. As the song said,
he found his consolation in the stardust of a song. The song reminded him that
he was not alone in his loneliness, and that made it seem not so bad.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> more
example, of a different type. There was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who had frequent occasion to
drive north and south along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Route 29</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>. At some point he would see
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Ridge Mountains</ENAMEX> to the west and he would begin to sing to himself,
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX>, the mountains, we greet them with a song," his college anthem.
Recalling that song gave him a sweet, sad nostalgic feeling of youth gone
by.

            
These little stories are all about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> of certain songs with certain emotions. They raise the same
question. What was causing what? To concentrate on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> story, did the man
in question think of "Isn't it a lovely day" because he was happy, or was he
happy because he thought of that song? He didn't have to think of that song
when the rain began. He could have thought of: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stormy</ENAMEX> weather, can't go on,
everything I had is gone." He didn't have to think of any song at all.

            I don't know which caused
which. I am not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX>. But I think the answer is some of each. (That seems to
be my answer to most questions.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> recalled the song because he was happy
and he was happy because he recalled the song. Many factors led to his being
happy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of them was the song. He might have been happy without
it. But retrieving that song from his memory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> helped to articulate his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">happiness</ENAMEX>, intensify it and prolong it.

            Of
course, there was something about this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that led him to store that song in
his memory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> so it could be recalled when appropriate, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after he first
encountered it. It was something about how this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was in his late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> and
his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">20s</NUMEX>, before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life crowded out room for taking in new
impressions from songs. But, still, if that song had not been written or if he
had not heard it at an impressionable age, his reaction would have been
different when the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> fell.

            For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> the key <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s</TIMEX> and
'40s--the era of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bing Crosby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethel Merman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred and Ginger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irving Berlin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole Porter</ENAMEX>. Ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wilderness</ENAMEX>! I do not share the songs that are in the memory
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>--although I understand them a
little. I do not understand the songs of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> at all.

            How people
will react to particular circumstances is not ordained at birth. It is learned
in part by experience, and the songs that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> absorb are part of the
experience that guides their reactions. Not only songs have that effect. Among
other things, snatches of poetry do too. Sometimes when it is very cold I find
myself saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St. Agnes Eve</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ah</ENAMEX>, bitter chill it was!" and I am back in my
sophomore year at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romantic Poetry of the Early 19 th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX> , in a very cold college <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.

            
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> insist they don't know what they
think until they hear what they say. So there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't know what
they feel until they listen to the songs or poetry that are in their heart. I
don't suppose that everyone is like that. I suppose that there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
feel happiness or sorrow or jealousy or triumph directly, without any
combination of words, either remembered or made up for the purpose.

            Knowing your emotions are
shaped by songs you heard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years ago</TIMEX> is a little troubling. It makes you
wonder whether your emotions are really yours or whether they are really <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irving</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>'s set down with music to make a buck. It makes you wonder who is the
real you. As my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Aunt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX> used to say about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>, there's no there
there; and maybe there's no real you in your emotions either.

            But I don't believe that.
When I say, "I've got the sun in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and the moon at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>," there's a
big dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethel Merman</ENAMEX> but also some of me.

         
      
   
