
   
   
      
         
            Onward, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Clothiers</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> are at it
again. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Baptists</ENAMEX> explain how marriage ought to work and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cardinal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Connor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, never shy about his inside line on which political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> will be going to hell, wants no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major League Baseball</ENAMEX> games on Good
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> (or at least not <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between noon and 3 p.m.</TIMEX>) and no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Leaguers</ENAMEX> missing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> for ball. Led by the likes of hymn-singing, tip-leaking truth-seeker
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Amendment</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is in
the midst of a renaissance of rectitude. This time, though, faith is not enough
for the really, really faithful. They wear their devotion on their shirts now,
also on their baseball caps and their lapels. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piety</ENAMEX> is a commodity for these
truest of true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX>, touted with a zeal that would make the most
aggressive huckster blush.

            You've
probably seen the initials "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WWJD?</ENAMEX>" around. I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> encountered them while
browsing with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Okefenokee Swamp</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>. I was unpleasantly surprised to find little woven bracelets
bearing the letters, which stand for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Would Jesus Do?</ENAMEX>, for sale along with
the gator mugs and kudzu T-shirts. When we got home, I sent off a snappy e-mail
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> about the separation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week</TIMEX> or so
later, I got an inconclusive reply, which addressed me as Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ringold</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suspiciously Wagnerian</ENAMEX> misspelling of my <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> name. By then, I realized that
this stuff really gave me the willies.

            Sales of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>-honoring product," as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Booksellers Association</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Anderson</ENAMEX> calls the bumper stickers, key
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rings</ENAMEX>, coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mugs</ENAMEX>, and clothing now linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, have grown from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. The big winner is anything with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWJD</ENAMEX>? on
it. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 million</NUMEX> of those logoed bracelets were
sold in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. But there's lots more than just bracelets: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeColores Designs</ENAMEX>
offers "fine apparel for witnessing," while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX> Wear
"rages with an attitude." (I'm not sure what it means, but it doesn't have the
same ring as "love thy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>.") The grimmer, punkier side of the phenomenon
features death's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX>, stigmata, and creepy apocalyptic texts. A T-shirt with
a silk-screened design of skulls, surrounded by the words "Eat my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flesh</ENAMEX>, drink my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cannibals for Christ</ENAMEX>" would look right at home in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> shop, glowing beneath the black light. And for that devout <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> thug
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your Christmas</TIMEX> list, there's a black
T-shirt with a skull and crossbones captioned "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> nd death" on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front</ENAMEX> and, on the back, a spiky, harsh drawing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crucifixion</ENAMEX>, captioned
"It's hell without <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>."

            Now, I'm a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dyed-in-the-wool</ENAMEX>, freedom o'speech kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, and it takes more than visceral
disagreement to make me want a particular point of view erased from the face of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>, or at least legally required to keep away from me. So why does a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fishers of Men</ENAMEX>" baseball hat make me want to spit bile? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> reasons:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Aesthetics</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> sportswear bears the same
relation to piety that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Hilfiger</ENAMEX> clothing does to good taste: It's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cheesy</ENAMEX>, commercialized imitation of the real thing. For a bracing look at
hypocrisy in cyberspace, take a look at the claims these schmatte
peddlers make on their Web sites:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XP Apparel</ENAMEX>
"helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of all ages meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>'s challenge by providing clothing that
helps them share their faith."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiritual Wear</ENAMEX> hopes "to
provide a means for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> to express their
religious convictions." Actually, they go beyond mere self-expression. "With
our products we strive to provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> with wearable
messages that motivate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> [to] consider their own religious
convictions."

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Would Jesus Do?</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that moves "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WWJD?</ENAMEX>" coffee cups, sweatshirts, and watches, offers this
warranty: "Rest assured that when you purchase our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WWJD</ENAMEX>? products you are
supporting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Ministry</ENAMEX> led by the hand of God."

            Excuse
me, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWJD</ENAMEX>? is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX>, it's a business, selling its
products by claiming God is on its side. You don't have to be religious to be
nauseated by entrepreneurs professing sanctity for their products.
Incidentally, while all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>-honoring retailing sites I examined claimed
to donate a portion of profits to charity, none are charitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
Haven't these jokers heard about not taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX>'s name in vain? This is
advertising presented as evangelism, and that brings me to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> reason
why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> sportswear is bad for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Spiritual Thing</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kennedy</ENAMEX>
reassured the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, skittish about a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, when he
stated, "I believe in an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> where the separation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and state is
absolute."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flies</ENAMEX>. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of both realms mix, mingle, and meddle in each
other's business at will. While we are used to secular types such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>
weighing in with their views on sin, it's harder to swallow when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWJD</ENAMEX>? tell us that wearing their duds is a virtue. When spirituality becomes a
selling point, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>-of-pearl buttons, then religion has entered the
realm to which it's supposed to provide a detached alternative. It's not
religion anymore, it's commerce.

            
Blurring the line between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and state
isn't always a business strategy; it serves other forms of self-interest too.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s comments on homosexuality surely have more to do with how they play in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> than with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innermost</ENAMEX> convictions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Connor</ENAMEX>'s desire for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>-free <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Friday</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, is surely heartfelt. But his
opinion is not God's law, as a great many angry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little League</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were
quick to remind him. Why doesn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Connor</ENAMEX> address his pronouncements to his
flock instead of the world at large and suggest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ballplayers</ENAMEX> sit out
Good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>? There have been observant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> even in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>, most notably
the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Koufax</ENAMEX>, who declined to play on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Yom Kippur</ENAMEX>. He did not,
however, suggest that everybody follow his example. He knew where to draw the
line.

            It's a line the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
sportswear industry does its best to fudge, boasting that its wares are
expressions of faith, when they are in fact crass, occasionally intimidating
assertions of spiritual superiority. What would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> do if he encountered the
schlock that is marketed in his name? He chased the money-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lenders</ENAMEX> out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX>, didn't he?

         
      
   
