
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braver New World</ENAMEX>

            Are we in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aldous Huxley</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave New World</ENAMEX> already?

            I suppose that many people
who watched the TV version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huxley</ENAMEX>'s novel (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 19, 1998</TIMEX>) must have
asked themselves this question. Huxley visualized a society in which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>--except for the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX>--is kept under control, not by fear of
punishment but through the "reinforcement of desirable behavior by rewards" and
the "non-violent manipulation of the environment and of the thoughts and
feelings of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>." In the novel everyone has free
access to an unlimited supply of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>--soma--that induces a feeling of
happiness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are constantly brainwashed with the thought that they deserve
to be happy. Sex is readily available without complications. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Babies</ENAMEX> are
produced in vats. There is no love between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, no
devotion to anyone or anything to compete with devotion to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>.

            All this
brings up thoughts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>, the "sexual revolution," the constant
bombardment of product advertising, and the political imposition of "spin" on
every issue. Hence the question "Are we there already?"

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huxley</ENAMEX> wrote his book, published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX>, he placed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave New World</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 25 th century</TIMEX>. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX> he wrote a
little book called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brave New World Revisited</ENAMEX> , in which he expressed the
thought that we were getting there much sooner than he had earlier imagined,
and that, indeed, we would be far into it by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 20</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>. He advised his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to read that book "against a background of
thoughts about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarian</ENAMEX> uprising [of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>] and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">repression</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> forces
led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huxley</ENAMEX> to advance the date at which his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> would arrive. They were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and technology. He foresaw that the world's population would
increase enormously by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of this century</TIMEX>. He thought that the great
increase in population would cause economic misery around the world, creating
the need for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX> to maintain order and control future population
growth. Technological change would require the concentration of production in
the hands of huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, controlled either by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Business</ENAMEX> or by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big</ENAMEX>
Government. Within these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, the technology would require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to
perform more and more as robots. But the main contribution of "advancing"
technology to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huxley</ENAMEX>'s world was the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> it provided for manipulating the
minds of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. Television would greatly enhance the ability of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> to bring their message constantly into every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. Little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> with dissenting opinions could not survive
economically. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> would be constantly immersed in soap operas and
sports on television, effectively diverted from any thinking about society.
Mind-altering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> would be increasingly available, cheap, and without
dangerous side effects.

            
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Huxley</ENAMEX> saw all this already happening
or just around the corner. What he would say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> we cannot know. He died in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>. But it seems to me that the main lesson, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of the main
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lessons</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huxley</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX> essay is how wrong a brilliant mind can be.

            He was
right about the growth of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. But that growth did not produce an
economic crisis, with incomes declining and government control needed to
maintain order. World per capita income is higher than ever and still rising.
In what were the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most populous poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, the
improvement in the economic conditions of life has been especially noticeable.
This improvement of economic conditions was not brought about by an increase of
centralized control. Government control of economies is diminishing everywhere.
The greatest economic crisis since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huxley</ENAMEX> wrote occurred in the most controlled
state, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, and led to the dismantling of controls.

            Moreover, technological change did not lead to a
centralization of production in a few giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. The trend has been
the reverse. Improved information technology has facilitated the efficient
interaction of independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> through the market without central control.
And technology has not changed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> into robots. On the contrary, technology
has created mechanical robots and calls upon human beings to do what robots
cannot do.

            The
centralized manipulation of human minds through modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> that Huxley
predicted and feared is not happening either. He did not foresee cable
television, let alone the Internet. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> have access to more varied sources
of information than ever before. Moreover, television is turning out to be an
ineffective medium for influencing human emotions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huxley</ENAMEX> describes the rousing
effect that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> could have on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> listening to him in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in moonlight in an amphitheater. If he had delivered the same speeches
on television to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sitting at home in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>--eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">popcorn</ENAMEX>, getting up to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>, and channel-surfing
with their remote control--the effect would have been very small. Certainly TV
exposure of our great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> has not increased respect for them or our
willingness to follow their lead. And the effect of advertising, which
concerned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huxley</ENAMEX> greatly as an instrument that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> might use, has turned
out to be trivial. We may buy red or black <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> rather than green or brown ones
because of television, but we don't buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> because of television.

            
The use of mind-altering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> has probably
increased as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huxley</ENAMEX> foresaw, although probably not to the extent that he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">foresaw</ENAMEX>. He thought that the use of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> would make the population
indifferent and willing to accept control by political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. But first there
would have to be seizure of control by some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that was not indifferent.
Today, we neither have such a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> nor the atmosphere for its emergence. Of
course, we do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who want to be in office, but once in office they
don't want to be in control. Anyway, what causes indifference to politics today
is not <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> but politics, which seems less and less relevant to our lives.

            There is
a trick in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huxley</ENAMEX>'s argument that makes it difficult to refute. Unlike the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gulag Archipelago</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huxley</ENAMEX>'s world do not
know they are not free. They have been drugged and brainwashed into thinking
that they are doing exactly what they want, not what some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> wants them
to do. So, if we say that we are free, how can we prove that we have not been
programmed to say that by a Master who is manipulating us into thinking that?
Perhaps he put soma into our drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.

            There is, however, an answer to that. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave New World</ENAMEX> would not allow a movie version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave New World</ENAMEX> to be
shown on television. The movie reveals what such a society could be like and
what a horror it would be. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> of the movie are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who
escape the system with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> and are going to live like a traditional
family. As long as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave New World</ENAMEX> is shown on television we will know
we are not in it.

            I describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave New</ENAMEX>
World as a horror, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huxley</ENAMEX> thought of it as that also. He was writing a
warning, not a prescription. There may be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do not look upon it as
horrible. It is a society in which every want is fulfilled. But, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank H. Knight</ENAMEX> used to say, what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want is not only to have their wants
fulfilled but also to have better wants. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave New World</ENAMEX>
satisfy the wants they have but are prevented from having some good wants, like
want for love and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and deprived of the opportunity to reach for new and
better wants.

         
      
   
