
   
   
      
         
            Pointillism

            Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s obstruction of justice case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is likely to turn
on his identification of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the so-called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talking Points</ENAMEX>." Like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s works and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-page document, has inspired
numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of thought that disagree on the meaning of seemingly banal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phrases</ENAMEX> and discern the handiwork of different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>. As a service to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> in the burgeoning field of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP Studies</ENAMEX>--as well as to the general
public--here is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmudic</ENAMEX> exegesis, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Guide</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> .

            
               Background: Only one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> claims to have firsthand knowledge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>'s origins: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> had
given her the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 14, 1998</TIMEX>, while driving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> home from work. That
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> handed the document over to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The following day</TIMEX>,
wearing an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>-supplied wire, she met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritz-Carlton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> interrupted their conversation and took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to a
room in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> for questioning.

            The TP
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">advises Tripp</ENAMEX> on crafting an affidavit that would recant statements she had
made to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> that she had
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bumped into Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> after she left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 29, 1993</TIMEX>, and
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> had looked flushed, lipstickless, and happy. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three days</TIMEX> before
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> received the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> gave sworn testimony in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had fondled her breasts and placed her hand on his crotch. Tripp
had been scheduled to be deposed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, but the
deposition was postponed.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whodunit</ENAMEX>? There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> theories about the authorship of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>. The
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tripp</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirby Behre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Right-Wing Conspiracy</ENAMEX>, and a
collaboration among several of the above. Click here for a summary
of the major theories.

            The TP
appears to have been composed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> parts, each in a different voice. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> section, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> receives legal-sounding advice, is smoothly and
efficiently written. The document then shifts from the substance of the
affidavit to the strategy behind it, with special reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s
relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bennett</ENAMEX>. The final portion
recasts the original section in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. It also includes a chatty
paragraph discrediting allegations about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s alleged affair with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            
               Exegesis: This is
the widely circulated version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>. For annotations, click on the
hot-linked phrases.

            
               Points
to Make in an Affidavit
            

            Your first few paragraphs
should be about yourself--what you do now, what you did at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, and
for how many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> you were there as a career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and as a political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX>.

            You and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. At around the time of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s death (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> has claimed
it was after her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> died. Do you really
want to contradict him?), she came
to you after she allegedly came out of
the oval and looked (however she
looked), you don't recall her exact words, but she claimed at the time
(whatever she claimed) and was very happy.

            You did not see her go in or
see her come out.

            Talk about when you became
out of touch with her and maybe why.

            The next you heard of her
was when a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> (I wouldn't name him specifically) showed up in
your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> saying she was naming you as someone who would corroborate that she
was sexually harassed. You spoke with her <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that evening</TIMEX>, etc., and she relayed
to you a sequence of events that was very dissimilar from what you remembered
happening. As a result of your conversation with her and subsequent reports
that showed that she had tried to enlist the help of someone else in her lie
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> sexually harassed her, you now do not believe that what she
claimed happened really happened. You now find it completely plausible
that she herself smeared her lipstick, untucked her blouse, etc.

            You never saw her go into
the oval
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, or come out of the oval <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            You are not sure you've been
clear about whose side you're on. (Kirby
has been saying you should look neutral;
better for credibility but you aren't neutral. Neutral makes you look like
you're on the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> since you are a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX>)

            It's important to you
that they think you're a team <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, after all, you are a political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX>. You believe that they think you're on the other side because you
wouldn't meet with them.

            You want to meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>. You are upset about the comment he made, but
you'll take the high <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> and do what's in your best interest.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 18th</TIMEX>, you were in
a better position to attend an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day or half-day</TIMEX> deposition, but now you are
into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JCOC</ENAMEX> mode. Your livelihood is dependent on the success of this program.
Therefore, you want to provide an affidavit laying out all
of the facts in lieu of a deposition.

            You want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
see your affidavit before it's signed.

            Your deposition should include enough information to satisfy their questioning.

            By the way, remember how I
said there was someone else that I knew
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>. Well, she turned out to be
a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>. I found out she left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WH</ENAMEX> because she was stalking the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> or something like that. Well, at least that gets me out of another
scandal I know about.

            The first few paragraphs
should be about me--what I do now, what I did at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and for how
many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> I was there as a career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and as a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX> and I were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
At around the time of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s death, she came to me after she allegedly
came out of the oval <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and looked
_____, I don't recall her exact words, but
she claimed at the time ______ and was very happy.

            I did not see her go in or
see her come out.

            Talk about when I became out
of touch with her and maybe why.

            The next time I heard of her
was when a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> showed up in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> saying she was naming me as
a someone who would corroborate that she was sexually harassed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. I spoke with her <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that evening</TIMEX>, etc., and she relayed to me a
sequence of events that was very dissimilar from what I remembered happening.
As a result of my conversation with her and subsequent reports that showed she
had tried to enlist the help of someone else in her lie that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
sexually harassed her, I now do not believe that what she claimed happened
really happened. I now find it completely plausible that she herself smeared
her lipstick, untucked her blouse, etc.

            I never saw her go into the
oval <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, or come out of the oval <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            I have never observed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> behave inappropriately with anybody.

             

             

            
               Note 1
            

            Here are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> good guesses about the authorship of the TP:

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lone Gunman</ENAMEX>. Panic-stricken by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s threat that she would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">expose Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> if asked about it in a deposition,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> mustered all her intellectual resources to cobble together the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, never denied his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s
involvement in the document's preparation. Strikes against this theory: a)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> doesn't have enough knowledge of the law. b) Apparently, she is not
the sharpest tool in the shed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> has said she immediately suspected the TP
was too deftly crafted to have originated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. c) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was too
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">panic-stricken</ENAMEX> to have acted this rationally. Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, for example,
the tapes record her suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> have a "foot accident" and be
hospitalized during the time her deposition was scheduled to take place.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
Tripp, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Manipulative Bitch</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gunning</ENAMEX> to bring down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> denounced her, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> entrapped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. One scenario has her prodding
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gullible</ENAMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to write the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> so she, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tripp</ENAMEX>, could get physical
evidence of obstruction of justice. Another has her drafting a chunk of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>--or even the entire thing--herself. A senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> has even
suggested a draft of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> lives on the hard drive of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s computer. The
theory's defects: a) Why would Tripp risk getting caught fabricating evidence
when she has mountains of damning tapes and e-mail? b) While the tapes expose
Tripp as a horrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and a vicious schemer, we have no evidence that she
is capable of conceiving of such a complicated machination.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The
Right-Wing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Conspiracy</ENAMEX>. An elaboration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> theory. Without any
specific evidence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> of this theory posit that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> drafted the TP
with the assistance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case or otherwise
committed to conservative causes.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
Behre, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Mole</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> testified before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelgate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s death, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> helped her retain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Behre</ENAMEX>. She
fired him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> before the TP surfaced, when he asked her to hand the
tapes over to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Behre</ENAMEX> has the knowledge and the motive (he's loyal to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>) to write the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>. (Some implicate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Behre</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moody</ENAMEX>. It seems unlikely, however, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moody</ENAMEX>, a conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stalwart</ENAMEX>, would
have helped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> prepare talking points apparently so favorable to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.) And while the document presents legal-sounding advice, it's too
rambling, repetitive, and error-ridden to have been written out by a lawyer
worth his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> (though it might be notes based on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s advice). In
addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> know better than to give a witness written instructions about
the preparation of false testimony. Note, however, that, as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX>
argues, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> is entirely true (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> did muss her own clothes, etc.),
assisting in its preparation would not be unethical or tantamount to
subornation of perjury--though it would then be most unlikely that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> was
prepared by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moody</ENAMEX> or a right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cabal</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dictator</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> by training, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spent much time on the
phone with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. He could have dictated points during his calls, and he has
a clear interest in changing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s testimony. But in crises such as this one,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has historically turned to proxies for his dirty work. Moreover the TP
is wrong about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said in his Jones deposition about when his meeting
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> took place.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fixer</ENAMEX>. Immediately following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>'s release, reporters
fingered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confidant</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>. He was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
point <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case and has been known to wipe up after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s bimbo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eruptions</ENAMEX>. And he had reason to believe he could change or blunt the impact of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s testimony. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> she doubted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
advances to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> constituted sexual harassment, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>--despite her later
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protestations</ENAMEX>--had not seemed upset at the time. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> also contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> to discuss the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> affair. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> spoke on at least
two more occasions, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . However, there is
no evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> knew each other or ever communicated.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) A
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Combo of the Above</ENAMEX>. While there is no credible scenario in which the people
mentioned above could have concocted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> on their own, several of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> could have worked in concert. For instance, it is plausible <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> collaborated on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> with insight from a trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Behre</ENAMEX>). As our annotation of the text shows, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> appears to be the
handiwork of multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note 2
            

            One
scenario has the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> dictating points over the phone to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, with
whom he spent much time talking. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> by training, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has a clear
interest in changing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s testimony. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> seems
unfamiliar with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s actual testimony in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case, in which he
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX>'s visit occurred before her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s suicide. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contradiction</ENAMEX> might exculpate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            But it does
not necessarily clear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> or others close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. After all,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s sealed, private testimony contradicts his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s
public pronouncements that the encounter with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> took place after
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s suicide.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note 3
            

            According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX>'s book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin Cycle</ENAMEX> , this characterization of the Oval
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> is common only among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>.

            And it
seems possible that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> wrote a chunk of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>. Immediately
following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>'s release, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> fingered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> as the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>.
Many speculate that he wipes up after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s bimbo eruptions; he was
also the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s point <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> also had reason
to believe he could change <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s testimony. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last summer</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> contacted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> to discuss the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> affair (she told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> that because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> didn't seem upset at the time, she didn't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> had been sexually
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">harassed</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> spoke at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more times, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . However, there is no evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX>
knew each other or ever communicated.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note 4
            

            The
parenthetical phrasing is emblematic of the tight construction of the first
half of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> have pointed to it as evidence that a lawyer
drafted--or at least advised on the drafting of--the document. Fabricating
evidence would, of course, be a highly unethical activity for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, but if,
as some administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> maintain, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> is all true, assistance in
its drafting would not be unethical. However, as noted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> makes
legal errors, and the smooth phrasing could as easily be that of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, or nonpracticing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. Nonetheless, it casts doubt on the theory
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was the lone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> she suspected
immediately that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> was too deftly crafted to have originated with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> never denied his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s
involvement in the document's preparation (his theory is that it was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collaborative</ENAMEX> effort).

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note 5
            

            Why doesn't
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> want to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> in question? Only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> had a
clear interest in not seeming unduly familiar with him. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, she had
been meeting clandestinely with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>, discussing her conversations with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> had hoped to remain anonymous in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s story. There's no
good reason why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> should have inserted this detail.

            Aside from
this sentence, there is no specific hint that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> penned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> to entrap
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> had a motive: She wanted to take down the president
after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, denounced her. One scenario has <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tripp</ENAMEX>--with the
assistance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case or otherwise committed to
conservative causes--prodding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gullible</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to write the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> so she,
Tripp, would have clear evidence of attempted obstruction of justice. Another
has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> drafting a chunk of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>--or even the whole thing--herself. A
senior administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> has suggested that a draft of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> lives on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s hard drive. The defect with these theories: Why would Tripp risk
getting caught fabricating evidence when she has mountains of damning tapes and
e-mail?

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note 7
            

            "Someone
else" apparently refers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Steele</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey's</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> initially
told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> had confided the details of the incident with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to her shortly after it happened. Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> changed her story,
saying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> had told her that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had "made a pass" at her only
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> after the alleged incident and that she had lied at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s behest.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note 8
            

            On its
face, the suggestion seems highly unlikely: that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX>, who had gone in
seeking a job from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, would leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> and stop to muss
herself, hoping to run into someone who could later confirm a false allegation
of sexual advances by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. However, by this time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> had changed her
story, saying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> had asked her to lie about exactly when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> had
confided in her and also about the details of the alleged sexual encounter. The
suggestion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> would be consistent with the amended Steele statements.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> also says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX>'s blouse was untucked--a point that has been cited as
evidence <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> was lying, since an untucked blouse would probably have been
noticed by the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> waiting in the reception area outside the Oval
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> is quoted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> as observing only that
Willey was "disheveled. Her face was red and her lipstick was off." So the
added detail in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> may have been intended to further discredit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note 9
            

            At this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">juncture</ENAMEX>, it seems another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> takes over. Note the "the oval" is now
referred to as the "oval <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>." Also, this sentence essentially repeats the
advice already given: "You did not see her go in or see her come out." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tenor</ENAMEX> and tone shift from legalistic to colloquial.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
            

            The author
is obviously on the side he or she thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> would do well to be on. As
subsequent sentences make clear, that side is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s--as distinct
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
            

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX>
testified before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelgate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster</ENAMEX>'s death, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> helped her retain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirby Behre</ENAMEX>. She fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Behre</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> before
she gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, when, she says, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Behre</ENAMEX> asked her to hand the tapes
over to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Behre</ENAMEX> has the knowledge and the motive (he's loyal to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>) to have written the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>.

            The writer
is familiar with what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Behre</ENAMEX> has been telling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> and calls him by his first
name, which might suggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> (or perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, who has been discussing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s legal strategy with her) is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Observer columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Weiss</ENAMEX> says presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">troubleshooter Lindsey</ENAMEX> also commonly refers to everyone but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> by a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Behre</ENAMEX> denies having talked with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX>.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
            

            This is
clumsily phrased: The identity of the "other side" is ambiguous. It sounds more
like loose drafting by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> than it does the work of a practicing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
            

            The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> and others, quoting "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> connected to the case," report
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> had earlier advised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> to seek <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s help, advice Tripp
eschewed.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> was
quoted as saying that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> is not to be believed" in the Willey
controversy.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
            

            The date
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> was originally scheduled to be deposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
            

            This is the
acronym for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Joint Civilian Orientation Course</ENAMEX>, a program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tripp</ENAMEX> ran at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX>, would be familiar with the acronym, as
would <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> who knew where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> had been placed following
her transfer.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>
            

            Presumably,
only someone with legal training--though not necessarily a practicing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>--would know that an affidavit could substitute for a deposition.
However, this is not good lawyerly advice. It is unlikely that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' lawyers
would have accepted an affidavit in lieu of a deposition from someone who had
changed her story.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>
            

            The writer
means "affidavit," since the stated point of this exercise is to enable Tripp
to avoid being deposed in person. This is not a mistake that a practicing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> would make, though it could be a mistake made in dictation.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
            

            The
remainder of the document is cast in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> rather than the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
And, in this paragraph--though not in the following ones--the tone becomes more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chatty</ENAMEX>. This might suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> herself is writing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> in her own
words. However, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> were creating a bogus document for purposes of
entrapment, it would not seem in her interest to recast <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-person
paragraphs from earlier in the document in such a way that they are potentially
confusing.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
            

            This
apparent reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is the only substantive addition to the second
part of the document. It seems unlikely that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> would refer to herself as
a "big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>" who was "stalking" the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> had recently
given sworn testimony in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case that flatly contradicted her lengthy
taped conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>, in which she had talked about her affair with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. So it is possible that she decided it was better to label herself a
liar in this context than to face perjury charges. The word "huge," which
appears here, is used by Tripp <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times in the transcript of her taped
conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . This point is made by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skip Fox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Gillis</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Southwestern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX> whose analysis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> may be found here.

            
               Back to story.

            Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>

            
Narcissistic phrasing that allegedly sounds very much like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>
            

            No effort
is made to fill in the blanks. This suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> is not attempting to
construct a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> draft in her own words following the earlier
instructions.

            
               Back to story.

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>
            

            In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>--given here--a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-person version
of this sentence does not appear in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> section of the document. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s
version of the document, it appears in both places. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> claim to have copies of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>. In itself, the discrepancy has no
apparent significance, although it has been pointed to by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> who contend
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> was leaked through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>.

            
               Back to story.

         
      
   
