
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Communion</ENAMEX>

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 29</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohlomi Makobane</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soweto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy</ENAMEX>
Communion to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jesuit</ENAMEX>-educated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> who worships at his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methodist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>

            The
policy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic Church</ENAMEX> is that except in extreme circumstances,
only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> (and sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eastern Orthodox Christians</ENAMEX>) are invited to
consume the consecrated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> Mass. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Makobane</ENAMEX> was
criticized for his action, as was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, who was judged to have
characteristically grabbed something to which he was not entitled. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardinal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John O'Connor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> used his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> sermon to declare the episode
"legally and doctrinally wrong" and added this grace note: "Some undoubtedly
believe that if one has enough prestige or money, anything goes."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> isn't the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>
to have been warned he would never eat <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Communion</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> again. Several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> rival <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kerrey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Neb.</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congregationalist</ENAMEX>,
stopped taking <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Communion</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>-only policy
was called to his attention. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul mate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican</ENAMEX>, was reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers to have
complied with a request that he no longer receive <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Communion</ENAMEX> at his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parish</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX>'s scruples about intercommunion cut both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic of Ireland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary McAleese</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>, was
lectured by the hierarchy after she took <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Communion</ENAMEX> at an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican cathedral</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>.

            A
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">generation ago</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> who took <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Communion</ENAMEX>
at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> ceremony would have had to worry about censure not from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>
but from co-religionists appalled at the spectacle of a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>-believing
Protestant participating in the "popish superstition" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX> It's a
measure of the self-confidence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Catholic</ENAMEX> hierarchy that the flak
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> flap came from the other direction.

            
Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Makobane</ENAMEX> pull a fast one? Not
really. Their supposed transgression is a common occurrence at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> and the logical outcome of the ecumenical movement energized
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic Church</ENAMEX> itself.

            
Returning to my childhood <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> parish for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Easter Mass</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, I was struck by the thought that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> (a term never applied to
Catholic worship in my altar boy days in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1960s</TIMEX>) would have
scandalized past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pastors</ENAMEX>. Not only was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, celebrated by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congregation</ENAMEX>, but at <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Communion</ENAMEX> time, the sacrament was
distributed in both "species" (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>) by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> of both
sexes--though some older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parishioners</ENAMEX>, after receiving the consecrated wafer
from priestly hands, avoided the female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eucharistic minister</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a laywoman</NUMEX>)
offering the chalice.

            
Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> call this
"Protestantizing" the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX> But ecumenical cross-pollination has led to at
least as significant a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Catholicization</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> worship. Once
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">infrequently</ENAMEX> celebrated in many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Episcopal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Communion</ENAMEX>
is increasingly the principal act of worship on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Episcopalians,</ENAMEX>
Lutherans, and some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Methodists</ENAMEX> have rediscovered rituals, ornaments, and
clerical vestments (the "rags of popery" of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">polemic</ENAMEX>) discarded
during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reformation</ENAMEX>. The result is a consensus <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Communion</ENAMEX> ceremony that might
be called "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> lite."

            Yes,
differences in interpretation remain and, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Communion</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> ritualistically recited the theological boilerplate I learned in
parochial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> regard the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eucharist</ENAMEX> as a sacrifice, while for
Protestants it is a mere memorial. Writing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Alt</ENAMEX> contrasted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX> belief in transubstantiation, "whereby
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, while maintaining their ordinary physical qualities, are
substantively transformed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eucharist</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> and
divinity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX>," with consubstantiation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methodist</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran</ENAMEX>)
teaching that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>'s presence exist
simultaneously."

            
The nature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eucharist</ENAMEX> was a defining
issue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reformation</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> issues loomed large: the nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>'s
presence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Communion</ENAMEX> and whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eucharist</ENAMEX> was a
sacrifice offered for the forgiveness of sins. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reformers</ENAMEX> objected to the latter
as a derogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX>'s redemptive death on the cross and a
theological close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> to the selling of indulgences. But these once-bright
lines have become blurred.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries later</TIMEX>, partly due to new scholarship about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> roots of the
sacrament, a panel of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologians</ENAMEX> released an "Agreed
Statement on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eucharistic</ENAMEX> Doctrine." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This 1971</TIMEX> document affirmed the "true
presence" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">of Christ in the Eucharist</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">effectually</ENAMEX> signified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and
wine, which, in this mystery, become his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>." As for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>-word:
"The word transubstantiation is commonly used in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic Church</ENAMEX> to
indicate that God acting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eucharist</ENAMEX> effects a change in the inner reality
of the elements." It "should be seen as affirming the fact" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">of Christ</ENAMEX>'s
presence, but not as explaining "how the change takes place." (Despite this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fudge</ENAMEX>, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catechism</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> retains the term.)

            
As for the divisive issue of whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX>
is a sacrifice for the remission of sins, the statement affirms that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>'s
death upon the cross ... was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, perfect and sufficient sacrifice for the
sins of the world." However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eucharist</ENAMEX> is a memorial (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> anamnesis) in
which "the atoning work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> on the cross is proclaimed and made effective
in the life of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>."

            This and
a similar ecumenical agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutherans</ENAMEX> have not been embraced as
authoritative by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vatican</ENAMEX>. Nevertheless, they have affected not only
Catholic academic theology but also popular teaching and practice. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eucharist</ENAMEX> is likelier to be described as a meal, albeit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> graced by the
saving presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>, than as a propitiatory sacrifice.

            
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX> have no doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is
really present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Communion</ENAMEX> distributed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Masses</ENAMEX>. And they reject
the notion that they are ineligible to partake of a gift that ultimately comes
from God, not from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Connor</ENAMEX>. Anglicans are particularly aggrieved
by the no-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX> policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preaching</ENAMEX> recently in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luxembourg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cathedral</ENAMEX>, the Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Carey</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archbishop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canterbury</ENAMEX>, noted that
"it hurts to be denied the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Supper</ENAMEX> by a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic Church</ENAMEX> to adopt the open-rail policy followed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>.

            Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican II</ENAMEX> (and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of its little-noted consequences, an ebbing of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American anti-Catholicism</ENAMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> unself-consciously socialize with other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> and attend their
christenings, weddings, and funerals. On the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Connor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chastising Makobane</ENAMEX> for sharing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Communion</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, I wandered into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Episcopal Church</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lafayette Square</ENAMEX>, opposite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. This is
the historic "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of the Presidents</ENAMEX>," though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> was not in
attendance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>. I was edified by the hospitality extended to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> at
Communion time. Inviting non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Episcopalian Christians</ENAMEX> to partake, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>
explained, "This is God's altar; this isn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Episcopal Church</ENAMEX>'s altar." If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Communion</ENAMEX> is a meal, it is rude not to reciprocate.

         
      
   
