
   
   
      
         
            PC = TV = <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mixmaster</ENAMEX>?

            Does your television want to
be a computer? Does your computer want to be a VCR? Does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mixmaster</ENAMEX> want to
be a telephone? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moguls</ENAMEX> who control the computer, television, and telephone
businesses think so, and they are populating your future with Internet
appliances . Already on sale are such I-appliance devices as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>-aware
televisions and e-mail telephones, which offer quick and easy Internet access
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> who fear personal computers. These appliances are as simple to
run as a microwave or a toaster oven. Just plug them in, and before you know
it, you're reading your favorite online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, ordering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puff Daddy &</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Family</ENAMEX> concert tickets, and composing e-mail from the comfort of your
Naugahyde <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX>.

            TV and
telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> are nuts about I-appliances because they view them as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to sell new boxes to a world supersaturated with phones and televisions:
More <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> have a television (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">96 percent</NUMEX>) than have phone service. The
computer industry sees I-appliances as a way to sell chip and software packages
to what they consider an under-PCed world. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 40 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> households
own a PC, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of all new PC purchases are made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who already
own one.

            The vision of a computer/television/telephone thingamajig
dates back to early episodes of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Jetsons</ENAMEX> , if not before.
Techno-utopian <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Gilder</ENAMEX> foresaw the convergence of all these
electronic boxes into one back in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Television</ENAMEX> ,
proposing a simple yet powerful "teleputer" device. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilder</ENAMEX> was right about
convergence, but as we'll see, he was also wrong.

            Among the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> entries in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-</ENAMEX>appliance market is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WebTV</ENAMEX> , a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">box-</ENAMEX>and-keyboard combination built by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>. WebTV hooks your
television into your telephone line to provide access to the Web. (Full
disclosure: I work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Satan</ENAMEX> that is behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WebTV</ENAMEX>.) Think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WebTV</ENAMEX> as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX>-smart version of the set-top box you rent from your cable-TV
provider. What's smart about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WebTV</ENAMEX> compared with a set-top box? WebTVs are
essentially tiny, simple computers. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> boasts a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.1-gigabyte</NUMEX> hard
drive and a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">56,600 bits</NUMEX>-per<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-second</TIMEX> modem, comparable to what you'd find in a
low-end laptop. The cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s set-top boxes, which couldn't calculate the
cube root of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> if you gave them a hint, merely decode TV signals from the cable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oracle Corp.</ENAMEX> has developed a similar Web-aware product called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enhanced TV</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Microsystems</ENAMEX>, which recently bought I-appliance
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">designer Diba Inc.</ENAMEX>, is also developing a competing set-top standard of its own,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OpenTV</ENAMEX> .

            
Web-aware televisions are fantastic because
they're cheap and they work. But they also suck because they're slow and their
graphics are worse than what you find on a PC monitor. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only 100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">WebTVs</ENAMEX> have
been sold so far, but that number is sure to rise: WebTV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> is
peddling the machine door-to-door, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fuller Brush</ENAMEX>-style. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Salesmen</ENAMEX> will visit your
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, plug you in, and explain all the machine's wonders to you.

            Another
even simpler I-appliance is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EP-200</ENAMEX> e-mail telephone by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uniden</ENAMEX>. This
device merges a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Caller ID-</ENAMEX>ready, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHz</ENAMEX> cordless phone with e-mail and
calendar systems. A tad pricier at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$399</NUMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WebTV</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EP-200</ENAMEX> is fun for the
whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, allowing multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to receive and send e-mail (the Internet
connection costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.95</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uniden</ENAMEX> and others promise Web browsing on
future e-mail telephones. Also flooding the market are cellular phones that
send and receive e-mail.

            Not content with being your spreadsheet program, word
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">processor</ENAMEX>, Web device, game machine, and recipe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">keeper</ENAMEX>, PCs want to be your
home entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> , too. A variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> build PCs
that connect you to the Web, display TV broadcasts, play music CDs, and screen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DVD</ENAMEX> movies. PC <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> Gateway <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> bills the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Destination Digital Media Computer</ENAMEX>
as an audio/video monster that engulfs you in a "wall of sound" as you play
Doom on a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">31-inch</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitor</ENAMEX> with a "screaming <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHz Intel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pentium II</ENAMEX>
processor." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gateway</ENAMEX> hasn't attached a phone to it. Yet.)

            The PC
industry may believe in convergence, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> don't. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Broadcasters</ENAMEX>
like their televisions dumb, mostly because they're afraid that the PC industry
will steal their business if computers and televisions merge. (They're probably
right.) So, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> groups have gone to war over the technical standards for
the next TV technology, digital TV . All you need to know about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digital TV</ENAMEX> standard proposed by the computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is that it's more flexible
and powerful and offers better resolution (and is much more computer-friendly)
than the current standard of analog TV or the digital standard pitched by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company spinoff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WorldGate</ENAMEX> also
wants your television to stay as dumb as an eggbeater, because it's found a way
to offer cheap Internet access through existing cable boxes. The cost is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.95</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> (keyboard rental will set you back <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $1.95</NUMEX>). Question: How
can something as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid</ENAMEX> as a set-top <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> connect to the Internet? Answer:
WorldGate keeps all the brains back at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Its computers recognize
Web-page requests from set-top boxes and then ship the pages back to the
requesting televisions in a compact, single image (a "bitmap"). (The WorldGate
system depends on the vertical blanking interval, an unused part of each TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX>, to send the bitmap. Click for a tidy explanation of the vertical
blanking interval.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WorldGate</ENAMEX>'s computers will choke when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX> start demanding Web pages. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webhead</ENAMEX> says don't underestimate the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, who have such enormous bandwidth at their disposal that they
can do anything (see my piece on bandwidth).

            Will your
Mixmaster ever fulfill its career ambition to become an I-appliance?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuman</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> Law of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computational Dynamics</ENAMEX> suggests so. This law
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that wherever computer chips go, the Internet will follow: Everything
that's powered by electricity will eventually become studded with computer
chips. And as these dumb devices become smarter, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> will explore
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> to make them more useful--that is, smarter still, which means connecting
them to the Internet so they can share their wisdom with other devices. Take
the example of the Internet-enabled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, currently a pipe dream. The modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">automobile</ENAMEX> is laden with microchips, which control fuel intake, cruise control,
anti-lock brakes, and more. It's only a short step from where we are now to the
Network <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vehicle</ENAMEX> , being developed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delco</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>. It
will be "outfitted with voice recognition, transparent displays, global
positioning systems, and Internet access." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Network Vehicle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> left
car phones off the list, I guess, because they assume that car phones are
practically standard equipment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            The take-home lesson of this edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webhead</ENAMEX> is that all
electronic devices are converging at a wicked rate. But they're also diverging.
Our powerful, multipurpose computers will continue to become even more
powerful, but as they acquire new skills--like voice recognition--their appeal
will be limited by their price. Meanwhile their simpler <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brethren</ENAMEX>, assigned
specific and narrow tasks (look for Internet-aware watches, biomedical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monitors</ENAMEX>, and security devices), will occupy the price niche of clock radios
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>. In the future, the way to tell a real computer from an
I-appliance will be that you tell a real computer what to do and when to
do it whereas an I-appliance will tell you what to do and when to do
it.

         
      
   
