
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millennium Verboten</ENAMEX>

            "The
language of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium</ENAMEX>, and the logo (until we hear otherwise), is for
millennium use only. ... It is very important to the overall strength and
infrastructure of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> project [for it to remain distinct] from our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">day-to-day</ENAMEX> messages and words that we use."

            
               --Memo from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> communications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to speechwriters and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, banning the
use of certain words reserved for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>-led effort to welcome the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next century</TIMEX>. Quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 30</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
            

            

               From: rodney@dot.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>

            
               To:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX>@<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium Project Directive</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> of
Transportation speechwriters implored me to write in protest of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
directive. We're putting together congressional testimony on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s budget
and having a devil of a time finding substitutes for the prohibited words.
Specifically, we had trouble dancing around the ban of the words "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>,"
"road," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>." We appreciate their metaphorical importance for
welcoming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>, but could you suggest alternatives?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rodney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Slater</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX>

            ******

            
               From:
clintonspeak@whitehouse.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>

            
               To:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX>@<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium Project Directive</ENAMEX>

            Anyone
have a synonym for "future"? It seems this word has been banned, along with all
references to specific dates (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>) beyond <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> hence. The
standard phraseology I am leaning toward for discussing future events is "an
event to occur on a day subsequent to the several other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> that shall proceed
duly in the natural course of time forward from the present moment, eventually
accruing into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> characterized as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> and, much later, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>." Too
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wordy</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L. Herbert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith III</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
speechwriter

            ******

            

               From: lexi@<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>

            
               To:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX>@<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium Project Directive</ENAMEX>

            And what,
may I ask, shall I say we are training <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> for? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial Revolution</ENAMEX>? How about 1999?

            Alexis
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Herman</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>

            ******

            
               From:
trustbuster@doj.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>

            
               To:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX>@<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>; lexi@<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium Project Directive</ENAMEX>

            Alexis,
lay off the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'99</NUMEX> for the moment. We hear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is trying to trademark it for
their next Windows release (though we're working on that).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klein</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asst</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> for
antitrust

            ******

            

               From: stonewall@whitehouse.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>

            
               To:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX>@<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium Project Directive</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Counsel's Office</ENAMEX> endorses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX>' effort to control rhetoric.
Let's use this occasion to remind ourselves of other verboten words. In
speeches and official communications, please refrain from using the
following:

            "trip"

            "harmonica"

            "knees"

            "kneepads"

            "blows"

            "lipstick"

            "dress"

            
"stain"

            Use good
judgment. Avoid potentially evocative terms. For an example of careful word
choice, take note of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Public Affairs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>'s suggestion that all
references to "seamen" be changed to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>." As always, we appreciate your
help.

            FC
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Charles</ENAMEX>" Ruff

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
counsel

         
      
   
