
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Long Run of Living Dangerously</ENAMEX>

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two weeks</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, culminating in the resignation of its longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autocrat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
Suharto, have been exhilarating, especially for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> who
succeeded in pushing him out. Unfortunately, it is not yet time to celebrate a
triumph for democracy. The "smart money" in the international community is
betting on another round of military-dominated rule, even though the popular
opposition wants a much more representative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, partly to protect
itself against the international <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s neoliberal economic agenda. The
resulting conflict between economic liberalization and political
liberalization is likely to be a prolonged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            To
understand this next phase of the struggle, start with the positions taken by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s most influential trading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> during the crisis. From <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, when that crisis first broke, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this May</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX> finally
implemented the sharp price increases and subsidy cuts demanded by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> were primarily concerned with
economic reform--budget cuts, currency boards, bank regulation, and other
technical policy questions. Only at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s base eroded
and the mass movement threatened to seize power, did they rediscover the need
for political reform. It was not until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX> resigned that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> advised him to "enter a dialogue with the rest of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>."

            This focus on economic performance has been consistent. One
recalls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, dressed in his bright new batik <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX>, greeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Suharto</ENAMEX> warmly
praising him for economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> also helped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX> to
seize power back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965-66</TIMEX>, sanctioned his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>,
and basically looked the other way at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-man rule and serious
human rights violations. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> tried to hedge its bets,
money to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> nongovernmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> involved in grass-roots
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizing</ENAMEX>. But until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this March</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> spent more than that each
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> on training for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>.

            All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s other key First World trading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, Great
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>--did much the same. They had few complaints about his anti-democratic
methods as long as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s growth rates remained high; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> got access
to its ample minerals, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>, cheap labor, and market for foreign capital; and
foreign debts were serviced. No one in official circles questioned the way the
fruits of growth were distributed or the extreme corruption and environmental
devastation that it generated. No one criticized the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX> had
somehow made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> list of billionaires, with a personal net worth
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14 billion</NUMEX>, or that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> always seemed to be selected as
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> by such leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill Lynch</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeport McMoRan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyatt</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marubeni</ENAMEX>. Everyone ignored the deep-seated ethnic
resentments sowed by this system--ultimately grounded in the fact that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> , a majority of whom happen to be ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>--control <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 60 percent</NUMEX> of the wealth. (The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99.99</NUMEX>
percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>.)

            
In short, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX> the international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> never bothered to question whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s system was capable of
sustaining social and political development in the long run. His global
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> turned against him only when his unpopular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> had become
a threat to the region's stability and just plain bad for business.

            So now
comes the long run. With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX> off the stage, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> are eager to turn <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s focus back to economic policy,
especially the matter of rescheduling its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$137 billion</NUMEX> foreign debt and
restarting its stalled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> program. This agenda's main political imperative is
a strong government that can implement the program quickly. A genuine national
election that gave the opposition time to organize and prepare an alternative
agenda might mean yet another change of government and costly delays,
especially if an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> program actually had to be debated by a popular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>.
Far better to have it implemented unilaterally. The basic creditor country
preference is for a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> solution, a secular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> with a civilian
face, support for free-market policies, and a pro-Western, if unaccountable,
military.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> basic requirement of this agenda is an alliance with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s military. This will be essential to implement the tough medicine
likely to be included in a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> program--higher interest rates, more
spending cuts, increased prices, more unemployment, and renewed debt service,
all at once. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> took great pains
to cultivate closer relationships with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>, notably Lt.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prabowo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the feared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kopassus</ENAMEX> special
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forces</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiranto</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX>; as well as many younger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. On his visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last January</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> spent half a day with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prabowo</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kopassus</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> has been a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> training, when it is
not busy repressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>
believe that this "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> face/military fist" strategy can succeed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> so long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> remains united. Similar efforts have worked
before in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964-69</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973-1985</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991-now</TIMEX>). Of course,
there have also been some remarkable failures--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, for example.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s situation is rather different from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s entire economy is
now on life support, and the West controls the breathing apparatus. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>'s riots destroyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> distribution system--there are acute
shortages of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and raw materials. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Ninety percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are technically bankrupt, and most of the money they owe is to
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has been very dependent for management skills on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX>, most of whom have now fled. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade and</ENAMEX>
investment have shrunk to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>, capital flight reached <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $20 billion</NUMEX> in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last three months</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s foreign reserves could be completely
exhausted by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of June</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s military appears
to be united, in charge, and armed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bear</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just this week</TIMEX> it succeeded in
intimidating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> with a massive show of force in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>. No
"left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonels</ENAMEX>" have yet appeared to help the opposition, at least not in
public.

            Most
important, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s popular movement is not nearly as well-organized and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">united</ENAMEX> as the opposition movements of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> or even the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>. In general,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX> did a supremely effective job of dividing, co-opting, and simply
eliminating his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> movement was a rather spontaneous
resistance led by ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, the unemployed, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lower-middle</ENAMEX> classes. Its only <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> was its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> demonstrated capacity to
mobilize mass protests and shock the world with violence. Many had hoped that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sukarno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megawati Sukarnoputri</ENAMEX>, would play the
central role that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corazón Aquino</ENAMEX> did, but that has not happened. Fortunately,
perhaps, for those who favor tolerance and democracy, there is also no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khomeini</ENAMEX>--the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> are deeply divided.

            
To the extent that the popular movement has an
agenda, it is precisely the inverse of the international <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s. It seeks
genuine direct elections after a period that is sufficient to organize
alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and prepare a campaign based on freedom of speech and other
civil rights, the right to have free trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, the release of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX>
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>, debt relief, stronger penalties for corruption and
pollution, no amnesty for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX> and his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX>, and a respite for the
poor from the hardest edges of "economic reform." But aside from primitive
prescriptions such as "cut prices" and "nationalize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>," the opposition
has no coherent economic program.

            This is not to minimize last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s extraordinary accomplishment. But even though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX> has been defeated,
the real battle lines between economic and political liberalization are just
now being drawn. As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> right after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcos</ENAMEX> fell,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Baba</ENAMEX> is gone, but the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> still remain." At the very least it is by
no means clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> will soon be able to rid itself of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">unaccountable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX>, rapacious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, massive foreign debts, or the
political impoverishment that could well be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s most lasting legacy.

         
      
   
