
   
   
      
         
            The Sex God

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Olympus</ENAMEX> they must
be laughing at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s pleas for privacy, and at our attempts to explain
his impulses. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 3,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> gods <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> appeared in
mythology, they've been dropping their tunics, because that's what gods
do . In fact, the parallels among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympus</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in the drama playing out at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> are striking.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeus</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">gods</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeus</ENAMEX> is the most powerful in the pantheon. He
wields the thunderbolt, which is useful both as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> and as a way of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extracting</ENAMEX> himself from the sticky situations he often finds himself in. For
all his power and brilliance, he has a few overwhelming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> flaws. At
times his "pride and petulance" became intolerable, writes classicist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Greek Myths</ENAMEX> . In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mythology</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Hamilton</ENAMEX> writes,
"He is represented as falling in love with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> after another and
descending to all manner of tricks to hide his infidelity from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX> even reports that the god's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, "foreseeing what trouble his lust
would cause, forbade him to marry." But what young god ever listens to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>?

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hera</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hera</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> appeared
in mythology as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeus</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, she was also his co-sovereign, writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX>, but
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millenniums</ENAMEX> marched on, she became subservient to him. Think of starting
out heading health care reform and ending up supervising the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium</ENAMEX>
Project. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ovid</ENAMEX> wrote in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Metamorphoses</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hera</ENAMEX> says
of herself, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> indeed are my achievements, and mighty my strength." So she
was incensed at finding herself humiliated repeatedly by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeus</ENAMEX>' philandering and
reduced to being his sexual parole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hera</ENAMEX> is--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> have mercy--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> of marriage. As for her own, writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX>, she and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeus</ENAMEX> "bickered
constantly," mostly over his infidelities. "Though he would confide his secrets
to her, and sometimes accept her advice, he never fully trusted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hera</ENAMEX>." The
feeling was mutual.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Io</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ovid</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zeus</ENAMEX> first saw this nymph, he said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maiden</ENAMEX>,
you are fit for [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Zeus</ENAMEX>] himself to love, and will make someone divinely happy
when you share his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovid</ENAMEX> does not say if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeus</ENAMEX>' private
study.) Zeus spread a cloud over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> to conceal the dalliance, which had
the unintended consequence of alerting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hera</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ovid</ENAMEX>, "When she could
not find him in the sky, 'Unless I am mistaken,' she said, 'he is doing me some
wrong.' " She was right. When she confronts him, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX>' telling, he simply
lies: "I have never touched <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Io</ENAMEX>." It's clear now that a better translation from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> would have read, "I have never touched that nymph , Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Io</ENAMEX>."
Never <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to confess voluntarily, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zeus</ENAMEX> then silences <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Io</ENAMEX> by turning her into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Semele</ENAMEX>. One clear
lesson from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> is that mortals pay a heavy price for being desired by a
god. After the mortal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Semele</ENAMEX> had an affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeus, Hera</ENAMEX>, consumed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jealousy</ENAMEX>, encouraged her to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zeus</ENAMEX> to display to her all the power he
possessed. He did--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Semele</ENAMEX> was burned to ashes by the flame from his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thunderbolt</ENAMEX>.

            
               Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nemesis</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX>'s name means, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Righteous Anger</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX> writes that she became the embodiment of "divine
vengeance on proud <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX>." In his telling, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeus</ENAMEX> pursued the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX>, who fled
from him. To keep him at bay, she "constantly changed her shape," apparently
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hellenic</ENAMEX> equivalent of a makeover and nose job.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eris</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> is not just
like you, but she is just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eris</ENAMEX>, a minor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> who helped spark a huge
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conflagration</ENAMEX>. Eris, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX> writes, "is always stirring up occasions for war
by the spread of rumour and the inculcation of jealousy." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamilton</ENAMEX> describes
her as the "evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discord</ENAMEX>." She was hugely unpopular and always being
left out of things. "Resenting this deeply, she determined to make trouble--and
she succeeded very well indeed," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX>. When she was not included at
an important wedding banquet, she threw into the hall a golden <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apple</ENAMEX> marked
"For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fairest</ENAMEX>." The scramble for possession of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apple</ENAMEX> was the event that
ignited the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Trojan War</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hermes</ENAMEX>. This god got the job of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeus</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messenger</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeus</ENAMEX> heard
of his clever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escapades</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX> writes of the job interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zeus</ENAMEX> said, "You
seem to be a very ingenious, eloquent, and persuasive godling." "Then make me
your herald, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>," the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hermes</ENAMEX> answered, adding that he would "never
tell lies, though I cannot promise always to tell the whole truth." "That would
not be expected of you," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zeus</ENAMEX>, with a smile.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Typhon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Typhon</ENAMEX> is, according
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX>, "the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> ever born. ... His brutish ass-head touched the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stars</ENAMEX>, his vast wings darkened the sun, fire flashed from his eyes, and flaming
rocks hurtled from his mouth." When he appeared, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gods</ENAMEX> fled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Olympus</ENAMEX> to
hide. Finally, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeus</ENAMEX> overcame his cowardice and grappled with the
monster. It did not go well. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Typhon</ENAMEX> cut the sinews in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeus</ENAMEX>' hands and feet. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX> writes, "Now he could not move a finger." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zeus</ENAMEX>, like the presidency,
if not individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>, has immortality. Eventually his power was
restored, and he threw <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Aetna</ENAMEX> on top of the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, ah,
monster.

            Finally, the only deities
possibly more powerful than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympians</ENAMEX>--the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddesses</ENAMEX> who literally
measure out the course and length of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s life--are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fates</ENAMEX>. Zeus, not
surprisingly, fancies himself their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. That's always a dangerous fancy. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aeschylus</ENAMEX> wrote of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Zeus in Prometheus Bound</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">He</ENAMEX> cannot fly from
Fate."

         
      
   
