
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Citizen Bandwidth</ENAMEX>

            How fast can you read this?
How fast will your computer keyboard accept the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> you type? How fast
does water flow out of your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> faucet? The answers depend on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bandwidth</ENAMEX> . Simply put, bandwidth is a measurement of how much, how
quickly. The speed at which your brain absorbs words (words per minute), your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">computer</ENAMEX> accepts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">keystrokes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> per second), or your faucet squirts
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gallons</NUMEX> per minute) can be described in terms of bandwidth.

            The rate
at which computers can send and receive information is expressed in bandwidth,
too, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as bits</NUMEX> per second . Surveys tell us that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> connect to

                  Slate
                with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28.8</NUMEX> modems, which, under optimal conditions, deliver
a bandwidth of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">28,800 bits</NUMEX> of data per second. What's a bit? A bit is
the smallest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of data, either a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> or a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. For example, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eight bits</NUMEX>
represent a single letter in the alphabet: The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-letter word "alphabet"
contains <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">64 bits</NUMEX>.

            The average 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>--and I just happen
to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right here, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Booker Snooker"</ENAMEX>--contains <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 800,000 bits</NUMEX> of text,
images, and formatting information. It takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 30 seconds</TIMEX> to download via a
28.8 modem. (Let's do the math: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight hundred thousand</NUMEX> bits divided by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28,800</NUMEX>
bits per second equals <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">27.8 seconds</TIMEX>.)

            Software
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> like me lust for more bandwidth, and so do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> like you who
only use computers. We all want 
                  Slate
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN Sportszone</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> to download faster to our computers. Bandwidth! Bandwidth!
Bandwidth! the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> cry. But ever since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX> first took serious notice
of bandwidth--ever since the invention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morse</ENAMEX> code , that is--there
hasn't been enough of it. An average telegrapher can communicate at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 to 40</NUMEX>
words per minute. That's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 16 to 32 bits</NUMEX> per second. If your computer
operated at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morse</ENAMEX> code's bandwidth, it would take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between a half-day</TIMEX> and a full
day to download a page from 
                  Slate
               .

            
The bandwidth bottleneck bugs me because we've
seen dramatic increases in performance on almost every other computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front</ENAMEX>. A
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> processor (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">386</ENAMEX>) ran at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 MHz</TIMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pentium II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">processor</ENAMEX> runs at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHz</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 20</NUMEX> times faster. Over that same time, the storage capacity of the
average computer has grown by a factor of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX>. But usable bandwidth for the
home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> has increased only about threefold.

            Have the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bandwidth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> been taking long lunches, or what? Actually, they've been doing
a great job--it's the rotten telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that have been lollygagging.
Everybody has heard about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>'s Law , named after an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>,
which holds that the power of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPUs</ENAMEX> doubles every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months</TIMEX>. There's a
corresponding bandwidth law, named after its discoverer, right-wing
techno-utopian <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Gilder</ENAMEX> , which states that bandwidth triples every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX>. And it has been tripling every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX>
or so.

            The phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> haven't piped this wonderful bandwidth
into most <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> yet because they're fairly happy with the quaint technology of
copper wire they've installed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last century</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Copper</ENAMEX>-wire telephone
connections have enough bandwidth to transmit voices, but not enough for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gluttons</ENAMEX> like me. Click for an explanation of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shannon</ENAMEX>'s Limit ," which
tells you why the bandwidth of conventional telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX> will never
exceed <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">56,000 bits</NUMEX> per second.

            If you're
lucky, your friendly neighborhood telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> provides ISDN
service in your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISDN</ENAMEX> stands for "integrated services digital <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>,"
and the technology moves data to computers at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">128,000 bits</NUMEX> per second. That's
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times faster than a regular modem, which means you can download the
average 
                  Slate
                page in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about six seconds</TIMEX>. The service isn't cheap.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, the phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> charges <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $100</NUMEX> for ISDN installation and
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $65</NUMEX> a month for flat-rate access. The ISDN modem itself will set you back
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $200</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISDN</ENAMEX> is the most popular alternative to conventional modems:

                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> connect to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redmond</ENAMEX> mothership through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISDN</ENAMEX>.

            
The best bandwidth is free bandwidth. For most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, that means a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">T1</NUMEX> connection at work or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. (In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>,
some Net-savvy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX> are outfitting apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">T1</NUMEX> service. I
wish those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX> would buy my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>.) Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISDN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T1</ENAMEX> breaks
the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">56,000-bits</NUMEX>-per<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-second</TIMEX> barrier by going <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-percent digital , that
is, by transmitting ones and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zeros</NUMEX> instead of the up-and-down waves of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analog</ENAMEX> signal. For a more detailed explanation of how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISDN</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">T1</TIMEX>, and
other ultrafast technologies work, click .

            T1
transmits data at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.5 million bits</NUMEX> per second, delivering 
                  Slate
               
articles in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. Of course, your mileage may vary depending on
how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are connected to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T1</ENAMEX> line, how busy the Internet or

                  Slate
               's Web site might be at the moment, and how clogged your
local-area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> might be. You can only move so much data through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pipe</ENAMEX> at a time.

            But you want faster. Some phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are offering test
trials of a new technology, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSL</ENAMEX> , or "asymmetric digital subscription
line." Right now, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSL</ENAMEX> is ridiculously expensive--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1,000</NUMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modem</ENAMEX> alone. But it's also ridiculously fast. Connection speeds are around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">million bits per second</NUMEX> from the Internet to you and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 800,000 bits</NUMEX> per
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> from you to the Internet. It would take only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-tenth</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one second</TIMEX> to
download a 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSL</ENAMEX>.

            If ISDN or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSL</ENAMEX> haven't come to your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> and you want to punish the phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> for
their intransigence, try the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DirecPC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> service from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electronics</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question you should ask yourself is, "Are you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> enough
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DirecPC</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">400,000-bits</NUMEX>-per<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-second</TIMEX> bandwidth?" The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s Web site sets
down these specific restrictions, among others: You must have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) an
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">u</ENAMEX>]nobstructed line of site to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> from your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> [or] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>" and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
"[n]o tolerance for waiting." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DirecPC</ENAMEX> beams the Internet from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>'
satellites to personal dishes and then into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>' computers. Please allow two
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> for 
                  Slate
                pages to download. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DirecPC</ENAMEX> is a bad choice for
those who want to transmit data, because it uplinks on conventional phone lines
at a paltry <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">28,800 bits</NUMEX> per second. Another bandwidth initiative, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadcast</ENAMEX>
PC , will exploit the unused <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bandwidth</ENAMEX> in broadcast television signals to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beam</ENAMEX> content. This one-way connection will offer speeds up to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">150,000 bits</NUMEX> per
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>.

            
The bandwidth to end all bandwidth comes to you
from another despicable monopoly , your local cable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. The cleverly
named <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> start up @<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> promises <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 million bits per second</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bandwidth</ENAMEX> through cable-TV lines . Theoretically, @<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> can deliver a

                  Slate
                page in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">0.0266 seconds</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has forged alliances
with several cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comcast</ENAMEX> (full disclosure: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
recently invested <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comcast</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cox</ENAMEX> to provide service. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX>
say cable-modem service will be ubiquitous by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX>.

            Sounds
like nirvana, right? The big gotcha is that <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 million bits</NUMEX> per second is
faster than the Internet connects to itself. Many Web sites connect to the
Internet through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">T1</NUMEX> lines, which, you recall, have a bandwidth of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5 million</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits per second</NUMEX>. Because your Internet connection is no faster than your
slowest link, you won't see a Web page in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">0.0266 seconds</TIMEX> unless it is stored on
the @Home computer. 
                  Slate
                throws a fire hose at this problem and
connects to the Internet through a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DS3</ENAMEX> line, which has a bandwidth of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">million bits</NUMEX> per second.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gilder's Law</ENAMEX> is correct, bandwidth will soon be cheaper
than air. But will the bandwidth explosion be undermined by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuman</ENAMEX>'s
Law ? <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Shuman's Law</ENAMEX> holds that you can count on talented twentysomething
software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> (like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuman</ENAMEX>) to write big, stinking pieces of software
that will swallow all your expanding computer resources--your processor, your
hard disk, your memory, and your bandwidth --resulting in no net
performance gains. Already, talented twentysomething software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> are
laying plans to choke the cable-enhanced Internet with full-motion video
( one feature-length movie contains <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">almost 17 gigabytes</NUMEX> of data, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">136</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">billion bits</NUMEX> ), virtual-reality games, assorted business applications, XXX
live smut, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webzines</ENAMEX> about politics and culture.

            Actually, I think that the
young software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> will be swamped by a bandwidth tsunami and that we're
entering the "age of experience " on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> predicted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Cochrane</ENAMEX>,
top research geek at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BT Networks and Systems</ENAMEX>. Soon, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> will transmit what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cochrane</ENAMEX> calls "full expertise." If a picture is worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> words, he writes,
and a moving picture is worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000,000</NUMEX> words, then an "interactive
pictographic world" of a supercharged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000,000,000</NUMEX> words.
Bandwidth permitting, anything that can be done in meatspace will be doable in
virtual space. I just hope that by the time I'm scheduled for remote
double-bypass surgery, the Web no longer transmits "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">404 Site Not Found</ENAMEX>"
errors.

         
      
   
