
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Stein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unfamiliar Quotations</ENAMEX>

             

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stein</ENAMEX>

            
               (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,184</NUMEX> words; posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15</TIMEX>; to be composted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22</TIMEX>)
            

            I love to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">browse</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bartlett</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Familiar Quotations</ENAMEX> . It may be lazy of me, but
I like to taste the plums of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> whose full puddings I cannot digest.
For example, I cannot make anything of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T.S. Eliot</ENAMEX> in his entirety. But I know
that I am in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> when I read the following lines from The
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wasteland :</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> the moon shone bright on
Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porter</ENAMEX>
            

            
               And on her
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">daughter</ENAMEX>
            

            
               They
wash their feet in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda water</ENAMEX>.
            

            Of course, some of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nuggets</ENAMEX> are ambiguous. Thus, we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swedish Count Axel Oxenstierna</ENAMEX> writing in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 th century</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Behold</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, with how little wisdom the world
is governed." For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> I thought that this was a complaint that the
world is not governed with more wisdom. Recently I have come to think it means
that not much wisdom is required to govern the world.

            As
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recompense</ENAMEX>--small though it be--for the pleasure I have got from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bartlett</ENAMEX>, I am
setting down a few quotations (with explanations where necessary) that have
resonated with me and are not included in that book.

             

            
               If you
meet a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">madman</ENAMEX> who says that he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and that we are all fishes, do you
take off your clothes to show him that you do not have fins?
            

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan Kundera</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Risibles Amours</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>

            I love this in part because I
am proud that I translated it from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, which, in turn, was translated
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX>. But I love it even more because it has saved me so much
trouble. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> when I encountered some outlandish inanity--often about
taxes--I would sit down at my keyboard and write an answer. I am still tempted
to do that, but since I encountered that quotation, I have resisted.

            You may
ask: How will I know if he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">madman</ENAMEX>? The answer is: Don't worry, you'll
know. And if you are in doubt, assume he is mad and leave the refutation to
others. You have plenty to do in the world without having to worry about
debating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who may be mad.

             

            
               Never
waste any time you can spend sleeping .

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank H.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>

            Clear
enough, aside from these questions: What qualifies as wasting time, and what
should you do if you can't sleep? I recently encountered a somewhat different
quotation from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baudelaire</ENAMEX>:

            
               To kill that particular
monster [time] is the most ordinary and legitimate occupation of each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
            

            It is
interesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX> should have used the word "waste," which is the
gangland term for "kill." Perhaps the reconciliation here is that sleep is the
best way of killing time.

             

            
               Honesty
may not be the best policy, but it is worth trying once in a while .

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>, in a
meeting, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>

            This may seem the ultimate
in cynicism, but the second half of the quotation (about trying honesty once in
a while) seems foreign to many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, among others.

             

            
               Surely
there is something unlovely, to modern as against medieval minds, about marked
inequality of either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kind</ENAMEX> [income or power].

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry C. Simons</ENAMEX>,
Economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Society</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>

            What
fascinates me about this sentence is the word "unlovely." It is a candid
declaration that feelings on this subject are "feelings," not matters of
efficiency or justice but matters of taste, of aesthetics, of emotions.

             

            
               There is
a great deal of ruin in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
            

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Smith</ENAMEX>, in a letter
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who, after the battle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saratoga</ENAMEX>, was lamenting that the revolt of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> was going to ruin <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 18 th century</TIMEX>

            This is a
comfort when one is listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> or editorialists describing the
ruin that will follow if their pet policies are not adopted.

             

            
               If
something cannot go on forever, it will stop .

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s Law, first
pronounced in the 1980s

            This proposition, arising
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in a discussion of the balance-of-payments deficit, is a response to
those who think that if something cannot go on forever, steps must be taken to
stop it--even to stop it at once.

             

            
               If a
plank creaks in the floor, he [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernesto IV</ENAMEX>] snatches up his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistols</ENAMEX> and
imagines that there is a liberal hiding under his bed.
            

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stendhal</ENAMEX>, The
Charterhouse of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parma</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1839</TIMEX>

            A comment
on many of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>.

             

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three</TIMEX>
percent exceeds <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>, not by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> .

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Denison</ENAMEX>, in
conversation, about 1960

            An obvious point, but one
that is important--and commonly overlooked--in discussions of economic
growth.

             

            
               Observe
how he has made a breast of his back.
            

            
               In life
he wished to see too far before him,
            

            
               And now
he must crab backwards round this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> .

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dante Alighieri</ENAMEX>,
The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inferno</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canto XX</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle Eight</ENAMEX>--The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune Tellers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diviners</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 14 th century</TIMEX>

            This is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dante</ENAMEX>'s vision of the fate of economic and political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forecasters</ENAMEX>.

             

            
               Where is the wisdom we
have lost in knowledge?
            

            
               Where is the knowledge we
have lost in information?
            

            --T.S.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">The Rock</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>

            These
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliot</ENAMEX> lines, not in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bartlett</ENAMEX>'s, are an advance comment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Age</ENAMEX>
of which we are now so proud.

             

            
               Don't
worry, you'll do it again!
            

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mother-in-law</ENAMEX>, in
conversation many times

            In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> tradition, this sardonic remark is intended to comfort a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who is
grieving over having made a serious mistake.

             

            
               Thus,
prediction of whether or not the capitalist order will survive is, in part, a
matter of terminology.
            

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Shumpeter</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Encyclopedia Britannica</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>

            

               Capitalism survived its crisis and went on to great successes. But the
capitalism that survived and succeeded was not the capitalism of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>.
            

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX>, The
Triumph of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adaptive Society</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>

            This joint
entry is a reminder that terms like "capitalism," "socialism," "liberalism,"
"conservatism," "welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>," and "free market" have to be defined if they
are to be used in intelligent discussion. The required definitions are missing
most of the time.

             

            
               We
[the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">colonists</ENAMEX> fighting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Independence</ENAMEX>] have shed our
blood in the glorious cause in which we are engaged; we are ready to shed the
last drop in its defense. Nothing is above our courage, except only (with shame
I speak it) the courage to TAX ourselves .

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Madison</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1782</TIMEX>

            I was not
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to observe this fact.

             

            
               Anyone
can do any amount of work, provided it isn't the work he is supposed to be
doing.
            

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humorist Robert</ENAMEX>
Benchley, quoted in The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algonquin Wits</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>

            This comes to mind frequently
when I am emptying the dishwasher or engaging in a similar activity.

         
      
   
