
   
   
      
         
            Follow the Semen

            Coverage of the Flytrap
story has focused almost entirely on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> question: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Did Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> have sex
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>? Yet very few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, and almost none of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> beat, have any doubts about the answer. So why has
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> journalism concentrated on the least mysterious aspect of this
story?

            One
explanation is that "did they have sex" is a question of fact, whereas other
Flytrap questions are matters of judgment or policy or values. The social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">critic Dwight Macdonald</ENAMEX> wrote in his great <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX> essay, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Triumph of the</ENAMEX>
Fact" (later reprinted in his book Against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Grain</ENAMEX> ) that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are in love with facts, "valuing Facts in themselves, collecting them
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> collect postage stamps, treating them, in short, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> of
consumption rather than as productive tools."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macdonald</ENAMEX>'s point was that the obsessive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> of data had become an unsatisfactory substitute for formulating
notions about what anything meant--an argument that seems even more compelling
since the advent of the Internet and all-news cable TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>. His best
example of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">empiricism</ENAMEX>'s limits was the (apocryphal) story of how, at the dawn
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enlightenment</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> tried to establish the existence of the human
soul "not by speculating on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vital Principle and the Intrinsic Substance of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soul</ENAMEX>, as described in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aristotle</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fathers</ENAMEX>, but by weighing a
condemned criminal before and after execution."

            
Similarly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> press corps has spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last half-year</TIMEX> examining whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adultery</ENAMEX> and perjury disqualify a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> by chasing a cocktail
dress allegedly stained with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX>'s semen. This fact hunt,
while somewhat insane, is also perfectly understandable--and even laudable--in
the context of what's broadly understood to be the press's mandate to gather
information with rigorous impartiality. As press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> never tire of saying,
the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>'s job isn't, or shouldn't be, to jump to conclusions--even
in instances such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hypothesis</ENAMEX> and Conclusion seem separated by
a very short evidentiary hop.

            
It's true that some Flytrap allegations were
poorly sourced and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> respected news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> , had to retract a couple of
particularly lurid stories. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Hamill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Brill</ENAMEX>
have lacerated the press for getting the facts wrong. But now that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> is
entering what looks like its penultimate stage, all this high-minded outrage is
starting to look a bit quaint. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is expected to tell a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> that
she did indeed have sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> encouraged her to lie
about the relationship in an affidavit submitted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has agreed to answer grand jury questions via closed-circuit TV.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, of course, is one of those few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who still claim there is a
factual issue at stake. Before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>, he may admit to having had sex
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, thereby admitting to having committed perjury in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> suit.
(The general view is that perjury in civil suits isn't easy to prosecute,
especially if the suit has been dismissed, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' was.) Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could
stick to his story and perjure himself before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> (a much more
serious crime). Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might stick to his story because it's true. But this
scenario--never plausible--is even more unlikely now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> have what
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> dubbed the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Dress</ENAMEX>.

            
This dress is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Hitchcock</ENAMEX> used to
call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGuffin</ENAMEX>--the all-important object whose pursuit frames a narrative
(examples: the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Maltese falcon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Foster Kane</ENAMEX>'s sled, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium-packed wine</ENAMEX> bottles in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hitchcock</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notorious</ENAMEX> ). The Love
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dress</ENAMEX>'s existence was first speculated upon in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> (where
it was black) and then on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> (where it was navy blue). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> Press
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>, passing along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> report, asserted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> had saved a
semen-stained dress; in fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Judd</ENAMEX> had reported only that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
said she'd saved such a dress. Then a few news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> got the
stained dress confused with another dress that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> allegedly had
received from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. This other dress was a "multicolored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasant</ENAMEX> dress"
(according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> ), purchased for not much money on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ), that might not exist at all (according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek Washington</ENAMEX> bureau <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann McDaniel</ENAMEX>) or really be a long
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T-shirt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> ).

            
Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> reportedly was going through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s closets at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watergate</ENAMEX>, testing every dress in sight and finding no stains. It turns out (if
the latest reports are accurate) the dress had been in hiding with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s
Manhattanite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia</ENAMEX>, who turned it over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> in
exchange for immunity. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> will first establish whether there is any semen on the dress
(easy to do) and then spend "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks</TIMEX>" finding out whose semen it is
(somewhat more difficult but, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1990s</TIMEX>, not all that hard, according
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). Assuming the genetic markers point to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
(and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> doesn't resort to claiming a heretofore undisclosed identical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twin</ENAMEX>), scientific empiricism, in collaboration with the more untidy empiricism
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> journalism, will have triumphed.

            
But please permit an unscientific
generalization: There is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> who seriously doubts,
amid this furious DNA hunt, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had a sexual encounter with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. Indeed, it would likely be hard to find even a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> who,
in the privacy of his/her home, would tell a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> that he/she buys <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
story. Whenever a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Begala</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX> asserts in public that he truly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">believes Clinton</ENAMEX>, it's treated by the press as news, because the common
assumption is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> believe their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> is lying. And when they
say they believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is telling the truth, every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> quoting them
assumes they're lying, too.

            The
only new fact in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flytrap</ENAMEX> that would qualify as genuine news would be one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">proving Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> didn't have sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The important
question is not whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had sex with her and lied about it but what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> should do about this.

            
In dealing with the real issue, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
press is hobbled by its strengths as well as its weaknesses. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macdonald</ENAMEX>'s
fictitious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>, it is uncomfortable with abstractions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> is a case
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> doing precisely what press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are always hectoring them to
do--just supply the facts, don't indulge in opinion or conclusion--and shows
the inadequacy of that journalistic ideal. Some might say the inadequacies of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> coverage are a point in favor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> system, in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> are freer to reveal their opinions. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> convention is not
quite what it seems: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> are permitted to act on their
prejudices--the news columns and air time devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> wouldn't make
sense unless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> believed the accusations. They're just not
permitted to express this belief.) At the very least, Flytrap
illustrates the need for less fact chasing and more analysis and illumination
of the "what should we do about it" question.

            Or maybe the moral is simply
the need for more humility about how useful journalism is in addressing matters
of public importance. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fifteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, now a top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, wrote an incisive piece for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX>
examining why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">then-President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s frequent factual misstatements
hadn't made him as unpopular as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>. The answer was
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who assailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s howlers were empiricists, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>
himself was not. He was animated not by Fact but by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Belief</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX>
unconsciously seconded this judgment at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican convention</ENAMEX> when,
botching a quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX>, he declared, "Facts are stupid things.")
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> has very little in common with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and, if anything, wears
his beliefs too lightly. But somewhere along the way, he may have absorbed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s lesson that while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> like to gather Facts, the power Facts have
to settle important questions is vastly overrated.

            More Flytrap
...

         
      
   
