
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conspiracy Commerce Department</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Plotz

            When it comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
scandals, it's usually the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX> who spout conspiracy theories. But now
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is engaging in a little conspiracy-mongering of its own with
its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">331</NUMEX>-page report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Communication Stream of Conspiracy Commerce</ENAMEX>."
Publicized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, the report posits a right-wing media
conspiracy to spread, well, conspiracy theories.

            According
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, this is how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stream</ENAMEX> of Conspiracy courses its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>-funded right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tanks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>"
subsidize fringe media such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pittsburgh Tribune-Review</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Journalism Center</ENAMEX>, which publish outlandish charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
(These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfits</ENAMEX> are especially intrigued by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counsel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Foster</ENAMEX>'s suicide--or rather, "suicide"--hinting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> was
murdered; that his suicide note was forged; and that he died in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX>.) These stories are "bounced all over the world" on the Internet
and reprinted in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> before they filter up to conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> , the New York
by their appearance prompts congressional investigations; congressional
investigations lead to articles in mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>; and voilà , we
have a manufactured scandal!

            Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> have joyfully ridiculed
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Conspiracy Commerce</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> compared the report to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> lists. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> alleged a
counterconspiracy: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is trying to suppress reporting about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandals. (These conspiracies are stacking up like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> nesting
dolls: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Right-wingers</ENAMEX> advance conspiracy theories about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whitewater</ENAMEX>; the
administration shoots back with a conspiracy theory about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX>'
conspiracy theories; now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counters</ENAMEX> with a conspiracy theory
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s conspiracy theory about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX>' conspiracy
theories. Whew!)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s charge
that the Internet has become a conduit and multiplier of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tall tales
poses a tricky question about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>: Is the free flow of information always a
good thing? The Internet is a marvelous instrument for educating large numbers
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> very quickly, but it is also a marvelous instrument for deceiving
large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> very quickly. Remember the Flight 800 "friendly-fire"
theory? That particular unsubstantiated rumor is still circulating on the
Internet, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> after it was shot down.

            So what to
make of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Conspiracy Commerce"</ENAMEX>? Is it another friendly-fire theory? Is the
Internet nourishing and promoting anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> conspiracies? Is there a
right-wing plot to spread baseless rumor and innuendo around the online
world?

            
Consider this example, cited in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Conspiracy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>" report: the right-wing charge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster</ENAMEX>'s "suicide note" was
forged. This little drama began on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 25, 1995</TIMEX>, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> handwriting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> held a news conference to announce that the note was a forgery. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> were paid by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dale Davidson</ENAMEX>, a full-time investment-newsletter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> and part-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-hater.

            Even
before the news conference started, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Usenet</ENAMEX> discussion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> devoted to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> (alt.current-events.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clinton</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">whitewater</ENAMEX>) was buzzing about it. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Usenet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> examines every rumor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal--both the possible and the
absurd. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 100,000</NUMEX> messages have been posted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> during the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two years</TIMEX>, all of which can be viewed at this archive, maintained by some diligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dartmouth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX>.

            The news conference made great copy for the right-fringe
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>. On the afternoon of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 25</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Ruddy</ENAMEX> filed a story about it,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Experts: Foster Note Fake</ENAMEX>," in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune-Review</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Mellon Scaife</ENAMEX>, who owns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune-Review</ENAMEX>
and a fortune of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800 million</NUMEX>, is dubbed the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wizard of Oz</ENAMEX> behind the Foster
conspiracy industry" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> report. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scaife</ENAMEX> certainly does seem
obsessed. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune-Review</ENAMEX> is a small suburban <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> (lots of
zoning and high-school sports), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scaife</ENAMEX> employs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruddy</ENAMEX> as a full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foster reporter</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune-Review</ENAMEX> posted the forgery story in its
online archive of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX>'s work.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> also promoted the forgery theory, with a story headlined,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster Suicide Note Forged</ENAMEX>, Say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> is the
only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> that matches <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>-mania. Its principal scandal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambrose Evans-Pritchard</ENAMEX>, has published lots of stories on the
suicide. All of them are stored on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> 's snazzy Web site.

            
The forgery story churned its way into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 26</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few days later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> printed
an op-ed criticizing the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> for ignoring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davidson</ENAMEX> news
conference. (Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> filed small stories about the news
conference, only a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>--none of them big, mainstream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dailies</ENAMEX>--carried the dispatches.) The online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> offers a daily
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitewater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Etc.</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">update</ENAMEX>, as well as flashbacks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> coverage from a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>. It also maintains a link to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> in its
"media links" section.

            The
forgery story spread from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune-Review</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> to the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater Web</ENAMEX>. Soon, the Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journalism Center</ENAMEX> republished <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX>'s story in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsletter</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dispatches</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foster 'suicide</ENAMEX>' note forged"). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WJC</ENAMEX>, which
is also funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scaife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> investigative reporting for right-wing
causes. (You may recognize the name from the full-page ads the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WJC</ENAMEX> buys in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> to reprint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX>'s articles.)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WJC</ENAMEX> placed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX> story on its "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster Scoops</ENAMEX>" page.
The "scoops" are mostly recycled articles by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans-Pritchard</ENAMEX>. The WJC
site also sells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX>'s book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Foster Investigation</ENAMEX> , and a video,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of Vince Foster: What Really Happened</ENAMEX>? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incidentally</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WJC</ENAMEX> page, which
links to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> site, boasts some of the most intrusive
music of any site on the Web.)

            The right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press critics</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Accuracy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> hyped the
forgery theory as well, wondering why big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> skipped the story (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Experts Say</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Suicide Note Was a Forgery"</ENAMEX>). The site also maintains an online
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archive</ENAMEX> packed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> columns. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Weekly</ENAMEX> , a Web
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX> devoted to right-wing politics, also promoted the forgery claim. The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> had first suggested that the note was a fabrication in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> before the press conference. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> 's articles are now
stored in its "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitewater Scandal Page</ENAMEX>," but you must subscribe to view
them.

            The
forgery controversy eventually reached the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>'s noncommercial fringes. Almost
every story about the forgery resides on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater Archives</ENAMEX>, an encyclopedic compendium of
Whitewater <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>-murder intrigue, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelgate</ENAMEX> accusations, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mena</ENAMEX> airstrip
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">revelations</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INSLAW</ENAMEX> case. The site republishes articles from the
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accuracy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune-Review</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> , and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>. Another Web site
alleges that the Foster suicide note was forged, and includes a picture of the note plus links to the full
text of the handwriting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>' study. Yet another offers a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> index of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> links.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Orlin Grabbe</ENAMEX>, the most prolific conspiracist
on the Web, has written a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX>-part (and counting) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foster exposé</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grabbe</ENAMEX>'s
conspiracy-theory net is so wide that it encompasses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alleged cocaine
habit, the "bombing" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s espionage history, the
machinations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bert Lance</ENAMEX>, and the bribery of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Wallace</ENAMEX>.) Another site presents a
massive compilation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandals--from Flight 800 to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Whitewater Body</ENAMEX>
Count." An even
stranger page explores the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Unified Mena</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">airport/drug-dealing/arms-dealing/Clinton/</ENAMEX>murder theory.

            There may be a Web
conspiracy against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, but it isn't very organized or very efficient. In
the case of the forged-note story, the allegation originated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scaife</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune-Review</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> . From there, it progressed to
the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> and the editorial page of the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> . Only then did it find a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> on the Internet, where it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">festers</ENAMEX> to this day. But this <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rivulet of Conspiracy</ENAMEX> has never merged into the
mainstream of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> . All of which proves that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">adminstration</ENAMEX> is almost as
paranoid as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater Webheads</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
