
   
   
      
         
            Special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sauce</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Evening</TIMEX>. The Oval
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> works on papers at his desk. A door opens , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> enters, carrying a large bag. She is wearing a blue cocktail
dress. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> doesn't look up. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> waits a moment, then
speaks.
            

            
               ML: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hi</ENAMEX>, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>.

            
               BC: Oh, hi, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>.
Don't you look nice! Why don't we go in here? [He motions to adjacent
study.] It's more private. [He smiles.]
            

            
               ML: Sure.

            
               [They walk into the
study.]
            

            
               BC: Did anyone see
you come in?

            
               ML: No.

            
               BC: Do you think
anyone knows what we're up to?

            
               ML: No. To be
honest, I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> think we're having an affair. [She
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giggles</ENAMEX>.]
            

            
               BC: That's OK.
That's better than if they suspected the truth.

            
               ML: Don't you think
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to wonder why I'm here so much?

            
               BC: If I thought my
science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> would take me seriously, I'd go to them directly with this.
But I need some kind of proof--or, I'm telling you, they'll laugh their heads
off.

            
               ML: 
               [Indicating
bag] I brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hamburgers</ENAMEX> and the golf balls.

            
               BC: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good</ENAMEX>. Did you
remember to make them ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ML: ... Big Macs</ENAMEX>.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titleists</ENAMEX>.

            
               BC: That's my
intern! [He starts to line the balls up on the floor.]
            

            
               ML: How'd you get
the idea again? I want to get it right for our records. [Pulls out notebook
and pen.] This could be historical someday!

            
               BC: It's like I
said. I was golfing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon</ENAMEX>, and when I was teed up on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
I was finishing this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Mac</ENAMEX> and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> fell off and went plop right
on my <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Titleist</ENAMEX>. I thought, "What the hell," and just hit it, and I swear to God
it went <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 yards</NUMEX> farther than any drive I'd ever hit. So I thought, "Maybe
there's something to this."

            
               ML: Like
Flubber , when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX> invented that stuff.

            
               BC: You can't
imagine the applications this kind of thing could have. That's why we've got to
be able to replicate it.

            
               ML: What does Mrs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> think?

            
               BC: I told her we
can make some money on this after I leave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, but she thinks I'm useless in
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. It's better to work on this when she's out of town. She can
always smell a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Mac</ENAMEX> on me.

            
               [He finishes lining up
the balls.]
            

            
               BC: There!
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> reaches for a putter leaning against the wall and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> above the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ball.] OK. Hand me a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Mac</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ML: Here</ENAMEX>, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>.

            
               [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> takes stock of
himself, with putter in one hand and hamburger in the other.]
            

            
               BC: Quite a sight,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eh</ENAMEX>? [He's suddenly self-conscious.] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>--promise me you won't
tell anyone about this.

            
               ML: 
               [She puts
her pen down.] If it's important to you, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>, sure.

            
               BC: It's too
embarrassing. Let's keep it just between us. If anyone ever presses you about
all these visits, just tell them we were having sex. [He laughs.] No one
would care--they all think I'm fooling around anyway. This they'd run me out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> for!

            
               [A red phone rings.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, both hands full, turns abruptly to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>.]
            

            
               BC: Can you hold
this?

            
               [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> nods. He hands
her the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Mac</ENAMEX>, grabs the phone.]
            

            
               BC: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hi</ENAMEX> ...
Yeah, I'm working on it now ... I'll let you know ... Yeah ... I promise.

            
               [He hangs up. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> is
fussing with her dress.]
            

            
               BC: What
happened?

            
               ML: It's nothing.
[She reaches for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kleenex</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> on the end table.]
            

            
               BC: 
               [Sees the
stain.] I feel terrible. It's my fault. Let me get it cleaned for you.

            
               ML: That's OK, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. I'm sure it'll come out. [She brightens.] Or maybe I'll just
save it. As a souvenir of our little experiment.

            
               BC: Sure, why not?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Edison</ENAMEX>'s intern probably had a few popped <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bulbs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> herself!
Although ...

            
               ML: What, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>?

            
               BC: No, forget it.
For a second I thought some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> might get the wrong idea. The longer I'm in
this job, the more paranoid I get. All right, Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, back to work!

            
               [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> holds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Mac</ENAMEX>
over ball and swings putter back.]
            

            
               [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> stands poised
with pen to record results.]
            

            
               [Curtain.]
            

            More Flytrap
...

         
      
   
