
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dear Family, Friends, and Other Invited Guests</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caitlin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macy</ENAMEX>

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dear Family, Friends</ENAMEX>, and
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Invited Guests</ENAMEX>,

            We are so happy you are going
to join us on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Day</ENAMEX>!

            You all have such a special
place in our hearts, and we are delighted that you are planning to spend this
weekend with us as we celebrate our love for you and one another.

            We want to make your stay as
comfortable as possible, so there are a few things you should know about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ponkawog</ENAMEX>. (The most important being that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> proposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX> on the eastern
shore <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year ago</TIMEX>!) It's hard to believe that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX> have flown by so
fast. There were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many days</TIMEX> when we thought we wouldn't make it, either
psychologically or financially, so the fact that we are getting married after
all makes it even more special to us.

            (Whoops!
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> is pulling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX>'s hair and telling her to get to the point, so here
goes.)

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACCOMMODATIONS</ENAMEX>:

            Located on scenic <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake</ENAMEX>
Ponkawog, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inn</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Ponkawog</ENAMEX>" has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> rustic cabins that sleep <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> to
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 each</TIMEX> (depending on how you feel about sharing floor space). These will be
assigned on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> come, first served basis. Everyone else will be
assigned to one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tent sites</ENAMEX>--unless of course you'd like to join <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX> and sleep out under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>!

            If you
don't own your own tent, you will be able to lease <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inn</ENAMEX>, but in
that case, please bring your own mosquito netting, as many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inn</ENAMEX>'s tents
are old and ripped, and the lake is famous for its <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">KILLER</ENAMEX> Squites!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CHILDREN</ENAMEX> AND
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">PETS</ENAMEX>:

            Love is not about keeping
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out, it's about inviting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in. In other words, we want to invite
all those who would normally be excluded. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX> is inviting her entire nursery
school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> so, please, hug <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 4-year-old</TIMEX>!

            Meanwhile,
if you believe in the domestication of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>," that's a personal
choice.

            THE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FESTIVITIES</ENAMEX>:

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> there will be a
nondenominational sunset ceremony (optional, but we hope you'll come!) in front
of the inn followed by a vegan cookout. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYO</ENAMEX> soy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX>.)

            Note: As you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sobriety</ENAMEX> is something that is really important to us as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>, so please
respect our wishes and keep this entire event <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ALCOHOL</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FREE</ENAMEX>.

            You'll probably want to hit
the sack early, b/c the nuptials themselves will take place at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dawn</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:21 a.m.</TIMEX>)
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> on top of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Big Mountain</ENAMEX>. Please allow yourselves plenty
of time to reach the summit.

            (If you're not in shape <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>,
you may want to consider embarking on a moderate program of weight training,
alternating with aerobic exercise--call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX> at work if you need some tips on
getting started.)

            For those who would prefer a
guided ascent to the top, trail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> will leave <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base camp</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:30 and 5 a.m.</TIMEX>
The earlier departure time is for anyone desiring to scale the north face
rather than taking the gentler trail option (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.2 mi</NUMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">/elev.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4,000 feet</NUMEX>).

            
               Do not pick the
wildflowers , which grow in abundance (but not so abundantly as they did
before the hand of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX> came to destroy) on the side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX>. RESPECT
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WILDLIFE</ENAMEX> and EACH OTHER.

            For the group
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recitation</ENAMEX> in the oral response part of the ceremony we ask that you have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX>'s poem "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Womb</ENAMEX>" memorized. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Packet</ENAMEX> enclosed.)

            In lieu of a reception, Dr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdiswami</ENAMEX> will lead us in a silent meditation before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> descent and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">song</ENAMEX>-fest. Remember:

            
               Don't be shy--
            

            
               Raise
your voice to the sky!
            

            FINALLY:

            
               A word
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Ned</ENAMEX>
               . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>'s birth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> has an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund</ENAMEX>, who
is known in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Ned</ENAMEX>." In the past, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Ned</ENAMEX> has been known to
make rude and/or offensive statements about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of color, overweight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
those struggling with addictions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5'4</NUMEX>", <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">virgins</ENAMEX>, teetotalers, and registered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. Please do not take any of his
remarks personally, should you overhear them or (worst-case scenario) find them
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> at you. Don't let him get to you! If you find yourself trapped in a
conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Ned</ENAMEX>, assume either the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Down Dog</ENAMEX>" or the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warrior One</ENAMEX>"
position and someone will come to your assistance as quickly as possible.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIRECTIONS</ENAMEX>
TO <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LAKE</ENAMEX> PONKAWOG:

            Take <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Interstate 40</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Exit</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>. Make immediate left after toll onto unnamed/unmarked dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. Follow till
road ends (approx. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">23 miles</NUMEX>).

            Abandon <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> at trailhead and
hike in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four miles</NUMEX>. When you come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarry</ENAMEX>, ford it. On a clear day, inn
and lake should be visible from far side; otherwise, follow compass heading
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">172</NUMEX>. Stay east of the swamp ... and listen for the sounds of happy folks
in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">joyous communion</ENAMEX> .

            Good luck, no gifts
... and see you on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> !!!

         
      
   
