
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Searching for Roots We Never Had</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come
to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape Cod</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>--for the natural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">amenities</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, the mountains, the clear, fresh, cool air, the blue
skies. But they also come, I think, in search of their roots. They want not
only to find but also to identify with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">200 years ago</TIMEX>. They want
to sit on the porch of the local country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink coffee</ENAMEX> and eat
blueberry muffins. They want to browse through the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">flea</ENAMEX> market searching for
some memento that connects with, let us say, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1830</TIMEX>. If they are near the sea
they want to eat lobsters by the peck. Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> will grow little beards,
to be shaved off after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX>.

            Some of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been coming to the same small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX>,
even for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>, that they are part of the local scene and do
have roots there. I am thinking of the more occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. Very few have
roots in small-town <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>. Some may have <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> roots. More have New York
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> roots. And most have roots <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> back in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lithuania</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sicily</ENAMEX>. But they like to think of themselves as having
a family connection with early <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.

            These small <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> are part of the origins of
the political, economic, and social world we all live in. But so are
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlottesville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX> The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming to these small
towns are not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> looking for a civics lesson. They are, it seems to me,
seeking and imagining a more personal, familial connection. That is what I mean
by "roots."

            I don't
deride this at all. On the contrary, I think it is wonderful that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here
should become so Americanized, so naturalized, that they come to admire and
seek to identify with a history in which their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> had no part. It is a
testament to openness and democracy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> that so many of us want this
connection and succeed in achieving it. I don't know this, but I doubt that
this absorption occurs elsewhere in the world. Would a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> whose family had
lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> come to identify himself with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> culture of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">200 years ago</TIMEX> as if his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> had been a
part of it? I don't think so, unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was exceptionally rich or
distinguished and so transcended national boundaries.

            
The search for roots is a common phenomenon.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> want to see where they came from in order to understand and appreciate
themselves better. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> like to go back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old Sod</ENAMEX> and see the
conditions in which their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> lived and perhaps meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> they
had not known before. The same seems to be true of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> and probably
others. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> phenomenon is the adoption of roots that are not
really there.

            Why do
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seek ersatz roots to identify with? Perhaps because the world changes so
rapidly that for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the real roots no longer exist. Once on a trip to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, where I was born, I tried to visit the scenes of my boyhood. Nothing
remained that had any possible connection with me. The scene of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">childhood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brownsville</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, is now light-years distant from the
culture in which she grew up.

            Finding real roots is especially difficult for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">eastern European</ENAMEX> origin. The shtetl in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belarus</ENAMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> left to
come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> as a boy, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 100 years ago</TIMEX>, certainly bears no traces of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">origins</ENAMEX>--if it still exists. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> was quite thorough in cutting us off at the
roots. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jews</ENAMEX> do go back to visit the larger eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> once lived. But the occasion is one for mourning a
separation, not for celebrating a connection. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> find a trace of their
roots in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. They can look at those stony fields and think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> lived and worked there. But that was a long, long time ago, and
the connection grows faint.

            So we--and now I do not speak
only of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>--come to small <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> to find our roots and imagine an
old family connection. I understand that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX>," the year-round
residents, do not want to adopt the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> into their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>--and may even
resent them. But they are courteous. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, they are all in the
business of selling roots. And maybe in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the long winter</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX>"
may realize that they are not really <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX> either, that there were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> here before them who have now been cut off from their roots.

         
      
   
