
   
   
      
         
            Reading the Inaugurals

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
Inaugural Address <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">53 rd</NUMEX> in the series that began in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1789</TIMEX>. All are worth a read--not just the highlights, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>. They will give you a feeling of being there, not as
an omniscient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> looking back at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1837 or 1897</TIMEX> but as an ordinary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> who shares--and is limited by--the information, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, and the
values of those times. (Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University</ENAMEX>, all the addresses can be
found on the Web.)

            Among all
the past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> and their speech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> there was only one literary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genius</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">132 years</TIMEX>, his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> inaugural still brings tears to
your eyes and chills your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. None of the other inaugural addresses are in
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>. But by and large they are dignified and intelligent speeches given
by articulate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, each in touch with his times and aware that his inauguration
was the most solemn occasion of his life.

            The stance and style of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inaugurals</ENAMEX> seem to have gone
through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> phases. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, lasting until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, was that of the modest,
classic public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, lasting through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Howard Taft</ENAMEX>, was of
the prosaic government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, in which we are still, is the
phase of the assertive, theatrical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX>. This classification is not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">waterproof</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX> may belong in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> phase and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren G.</ENAMEX>
clear.

            On picking up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> inaugural, one is immediately struck by the modesty. He had just been
elected unanimously by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electoral College</ENAMEX>. He was more respected than any
subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has been at the time of his inauguration. And what does he
say?

            
               [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he magnitude and
difficulty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> to which the voice of my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> called me, being
sufficient to awaken in the wisest and most experienced of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> a
distrustful scrutiny into his qualifications, could not but overwhelm with
despondence one who (inheriting inferior endowments from nature and unpracticed
in the duties of civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>) ought to be peculiarly conscious of his
own deficiencies.
            

            
None of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX> has made the point as
forcefully as that. But echoes are to be found in almost every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 68 years</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX> was an exception. He was apparently so envious
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> that he spent a large part of his address spelling out his own
excellent qualifications for the job.) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">That era</TIMEX> ended with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>. Subsequent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inaugurals</ENAMEX> routinely contain protestations of humility, but they are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perfunctory</ENAMEX> and do not sound sincere.

            The
antebellum modesty, while in part a reflection of the conventional etiquette of
the time, may also have served a political objective: to alleviate the concerns
of those who--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>--feared it might be transformed
into a monarchy, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>. A little later, perhaps after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1820</TIMEX>, a new worry arose. Would the power of the federal government be used to
interfere with the "peculiar domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX>' assurance of the limitation of their powers may have been intended
to give comfort to those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> faced a different situation. With the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> already
seceding, he could only "preserve, protect and defend the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>" by
asserting the power of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and his own power as chief
executive. It was no time for modesty. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX> inherited a federal
government with much more authority--and more need to use it--than before the
war, and they had less motivation to belittle themselves and their powers.

            In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> phase, the
Inaugural Address metamorphosed from describing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s policy to
inspiring the public's behavior. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presidents</ENAMEX> recognized--or, at least,
believed--that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> had problems they ought to deal with but could not
manage by using the instruments of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> alone. Thus, in his first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inaugural</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodrow Wilson</ENAMEX> said: "At last a vision has been vouchsafed us of our
life as a whole. We see the bad with the good, the debased and decadent with
the sound and the vital. With this vision we approach new affairs."

            If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is debased and decadent, the cure has to come from uplifting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, not from acts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Similar diagnoses and prescriptions appear
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> inaugurals.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presidents</ENAMEX> derived their license to serve as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader-preacher</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s remark that the presidency was "a
bully pulpit," a remark that did not appear in his <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inaugural Address</ENAMEX>. The
metaphor of the pulpit suggests not reading but oral and visual contact between
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> and his flock. Radio and--even more--television made this possible
on a national scale. A telltale sign of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> inaugural is the
use of the phrase, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Let us ...</ENAMEX> "--meaning, "You do as I say." This expression
appears occasionally throughout the history of inaugurals, but it has hit its
stride in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX> repeated it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> times in his <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inaugural</ENAMEX>
Address, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> has it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> times in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one.

            The
change in literary style from classical to colloquial can be demonstrated by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> statistic. In all the inaugurals from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Buchanan</ENAMEX>,
the average number of words per sentence was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX>. From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilson</ENAMEX> it was
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>, and since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilson</ENAMEX> it has been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>. I do not consider this a deterioration
(this article has an average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> words per sentence), but it does reflect the
change in the size and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> and in the means of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Henry Harrison</ENAMEX> could talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helvetic Confederacy</ENAMEX> and expect his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> to know what
he was talking about. That wouldn't be true <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX>'s audience
would not have known what the Internet was.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presidents</ENAMEX> and their speech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> have mined their
predecessors for memorable words and repeated them without attribution.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s trumpet call, "Ask not what your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> can do for you: Ask what you
can do for your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," has an ironic history. In his inaugural, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harding</ENAMEX>,
surely no model for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, had said, "Our most dangerous tendency is to
expect too little of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and at the same time do for it too little."
And even before he became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, in a speech in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1916</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harding</ENAMEX> had said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In</ENAMEX>
the great fulfillment we must have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> less concerned about what the
government can do for it and more anxious about what it can do for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>."

            Many an
issue frets its hour on the inaugural stage and then is heard no more. That
includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>, the coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fortifications</ENAMEX>, territorial expansion, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Isthmus Canal</ENAMEX>, civil-service reform, polygamy, and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition</ENAMEX>. Some subjects
that you expect to appear, don't. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoover</ENAMEX>'s inaugural, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 4, 1929</TIMEX>, gives no
hint of economic vulnerability. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> inaugural, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 20, 1937</TIMEX>,
contains no reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> or to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. But what is most amazing, at
least to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, is the silence of the inaugurals on the subject of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. The word "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>" does not appear at all until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilson</ENAMEX>'s first inaugural,
and it always appears as part of the phrase "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>," never as referring
to any special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harding</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to be
chosen in an election in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> voted nationally, does not remark on the
uniqueness of the fact in his inaugural.

            
One subject that does get ample treatment is
taxes. "Taxes," or some equivalent word, appears in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX> inaugural
addresses to date. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coolidge</ENAMEX> said in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX>: "The time is arriving when we can
have further tax reduction. ... I am opposed to extremely high rates, because
they produce little or no revenue, because they are bad for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and,
finally, because they are wrong." Federal taxes were then <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 3 percent</NUMEX> of
the gross domestic product. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> said essentially the same thing in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, when they were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>.

            The most
disturbing aspect of the whole series of inaugurals is what is said and unsaid
on the subject of race relations, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger Jr.</ENAMEX> calls "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supreme American</ENAMEX> problem." The words "black," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Negro</ENAMEX>," or "race" (as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>) do not appear at all until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rutherford Hayes</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1877</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monroe</ENAMEX> asked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1817</TIMEX>, "On whom has oppression fallen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any quarter</TIMEX> of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>? Who has been deprived of any right of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or property?" These were
rhetorical questions, intended to get the answer "No one!"--as if there were
not <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of slaves</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.

            Before the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> the word "slavery" appears only in the
Inaugural Address of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Van Buren</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1837</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1857</TIMEX>, and then only
as something that, pursuant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> and in order to preserve the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>, should not be interfered with. But although generally unmentionable, the
subject was boiling, and would boil over in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1861</TIMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>, it is in
the inaugurals of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hayes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Garfield</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1881</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Harrison</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1889</TIMEX>)
that we find the most explicit and positive discussion of the need to convert
into reality the rights and freedom granted to the "freedmen" on paper by the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13 th</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14 th</NUMEX> , and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> amendments. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garfield</ENAMEX>'s
was the strongest among these. (He had been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams College</ENAMEX> in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1850s</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80 years</TIMEX> before me, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> had been a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> on the
underground railway.) But the subject then began to fade. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William McKinley</ENAMEX> said
in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inaugural Address</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 4, 1897</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynchings</ENAMEX> must not be tolerated
in a great and civilized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>," but he said it
without horror. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taft</ENAMEX> raised the subject of race relations in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1909</TIMEX> only to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express</ENAMEX> satisfaction at the progress that had been made. And then the subject
disappeared. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> never mentioned it in any of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> inaugurals.

            After <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II the</ENAMEX>
subject came back to inaugural addresses, but in a weak and abstract form. That
is true even of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> we think of as being most concerned with race
relations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>.
Perhaps each thought he had made a sufficient statement by having a black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marian Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leontyne Price</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maya Angelou</ENAMEX>--perform at his
ceremony. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s first inaugural, the only allusion to the race problem
is in this sentence: "From our revolution, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
Depression to the civil rights movement, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have always mustered the
determination to construct from these crises the pillars of our history." I
recall this not to suggest that their concern was not deep and sincere, but
only to indicate what is acceptable to say in a speech intended to appeal to
the values shared by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.

            There is
much more to ponder in these speeches than I have suggested here. There is much
to be proud of, in what we have endured and achieved, in the peaceful
transference of power, and in the reasonableness and moderation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX> we have elected. But there is also much humility to be learned. We
look back with amazement at the ignorance and moral obtuseness revealed by what
our past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have said and our past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> believed. We should recognize
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that 50 or 100 years from now</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will shake their heads at what we are
saying and believing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            

               POSTSCRIPT: To read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX>'s analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s second
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Inaugural Address,</ENAMEX> click .
            

         
      
   
