
   
   
      
         
            Pay for Say

            In journalism, few things
are considered worse than paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> that pay for
information--the paper and TV tabloids--are branded sleazy and unprofessional.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> and their information are regarded as being highly unreliable. In
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> scandal, those who have sold their stories or tried to include
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> state troopers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cristy Zercher</ENAMEX>
(a flight attendant on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McGrath</ENAMEX> (a
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> steward). All have been denigrated--and their credibility
challenged--as a result.

            But that
is not the whole list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've cashed in on private knowledge of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his doings. There's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>, who has been paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.8</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little, Brown and Co.</ENAMEX> for his forthcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> memoir.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> advised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> to hold a "come-clean"
press conference and "tell us everything about [his] relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>." But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> can't come clean himself on everything he knows
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. As he's explained to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, he's under a gag order from
Little, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, which wants to protect its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.8 million</NUMEX> investment in anything
juicy he may have to reveal.

            That's different, of course. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>' book
comes out, nobody will impugn his motives or question his reliability simply
because he sold his story to the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX>. Nobody will call him a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>--at least, not just because of the money. And the difference is ... what,
exactly? Well, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> difference is a matter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>--a journalistic attitude
toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> that parallels the "trailer trash"
dismissal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>.

            This is
not to suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> shouldn't be trusted. It is meant to suggest
that the respectable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> covering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX> have not been serving their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
or the truth by dismissing paid-for information out of hand.

            
The current spate of say and pay began back in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX> made a big splash with her account of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 year</TIMEX> affair with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The story was too big to ignore but was easy to dismiss as fiction,
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> had paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">her $150,000</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> denied the affair, and
it wasn't until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> that we learned his denial was a lie: During <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">his</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> deposition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> acknowledged that he had had sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX>--though
he says it happened only once.

            More
recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zercher</ENAMEX> earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> for her story about how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> talked dirty and squeezed her breast during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '92</TIMEX> campaign.
(
                  Slate
               's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid roundup</ENAMEX> gives you the
skinny on that story.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zercher</ENAMEX>'s story supports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s
accounts of unwanted touching by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, yet the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have largely
snubbed it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> knocked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zercher</ENAMEX>'s credibility in a short piece,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Still More Tawdry Tales</ENAMEX>," because she didn't tell this version of the story to
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> after she was counseled to say "all positive things" by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s lip-quivering confession on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> was
unpaid, but the press raised doubts about her by reporting that she had
approached a book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> in the hope of turning the breast grab into a money
grab. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> reported this and
other damaging information provided by her former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Steele</ENAMEX>. (Steele
has changed her story of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> told her more times than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> has
changed her hairstyle.) Oddly, neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
identified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> as the recipient of tabloid cash, even though the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">her $7,000</NUMEX> for a photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Was this an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oversight</ENAMEX>, or was it a recognition that applying the say and pay standards
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uniformly</ENAMEX> would render Steele useless as a source to discredit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX>?

            You've
probably never heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McGrath</ENAMEX>. He's the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">steward</ENAMEX> who told his
stories to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> (for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> again)--and to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s grand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>--of what he had seen and heard about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> and others at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.
More tainted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>, disdained by the respectable media.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> broke
a money story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troopers</ENAMEX>. Having served as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bodyguards</ENAMEX> when he was governor, the troopers later told the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Spectator</ENAMEX> about his sexual exploits.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> , conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Smith</ENAMEX>
helped bring the troopers to the attention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> also gave the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> troopers money when they lost their part-time
jobs after their story appeared in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> . (The troopers split <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21,000</NUMEX>, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> he'd paid them <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,700</NUMEX>
each.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> also paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Brock $5,000</NUMEX> for an abandoned book project.

            These revelations were
"embarrassing" to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>, wrote the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times</ENAMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahm Emanuel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, on the
revelation: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Day One</ENAMEX> I always thought this was politically motivated and
had politics written all over it; after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, it is nice to have the
truth catch up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>." The "truth"? What on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">earth is Emanuel</ENAMEX> talking about? The troopers have yet to recant their charges
that they had arranged and concealed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sexual adventures on public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>.

            Now don't get me wrong. I
don't endorse the practice of paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. And I certainly don't endorse the
practice of giving money to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> in a criminal investigation (rich
right-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">winger Richard Mellon Scaife</ENAMEX> is accused of having provided the money that
allegedly went to former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hale</ENAMEX>). Above all, I don't
condemn the practice of paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> to tell their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>'
stories. In fact, as long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> can be persuaded to supply the information
for free, there's more money for those of us who repackage it for public
consumption.

         
      
   
