
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Search Me</ENAMEX>

            Imagine walking into your
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> to look for a book. Hoping for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarian</ENAMEX> to guide you, you are
confronted instead by a bewildering array of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX>, each offering to
find what you're looking for. But none has cataloged the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>, each
has cataloged a different part of it, each uses a different system, and none is
terribly satisfactory. That is the situation on the Internet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            The
old-fashioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarian</ENAMEX> still has an edge over the vast resources and computing
power of the Internet in several ways. First, a library offers more valuable
stuff . Certainly there is more raw information on the Web than in any
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">library</ENAMEX>. But the kind of stuff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are actually willing to pay for is sadly
lacking. So long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> fear cannibalizing their sales--or aren't able
to make money maintaining Web sites--there will be books and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals</ENAMEX> that
are only available offline, or online for a fee. You can read the Wall
Street Journal free at your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>, but you have to pay to read it
on the Web. And of course
there are for-a-fee search <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEXIS-NEXIS</ENAMEX> that allow you to read documents online, but
for the time being, serious research--especially for the budgetarily
challenged--still usually leads to paper.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libraries</ENAMEX> also have a distributed cataloging
infrastructure . This means that everyone shares a common cataloging system.
When a new book gets published, a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> will do the work to abstract
and catalog it, then share that work with all the others. This effort
(coordinated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Online</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer Library Center</ENAMEX>) is assisted by standards for cataloging
information . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dewey Decimal System</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> are both
schemes that help guarantee that a book can be found the same way in different
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">libraries</ENAMEX>.

            Most
important, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> invite reduced expectations . No one expects
to walk into a library and get a list of every book that contains the word
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>" organized by subject, title, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. We're just happy to look up
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>" in the (online?) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> catalog and find the books that are actually
about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>. And typically we'd be just as happy not to find the references to
"red-hot poker" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> faced."

            
Of the many Internet search services, Yahoo! comes the closest to this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX>-catalog approach. It does it the old-fashioned way, hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to look
at each site and assign it an abstract and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or more</NUMEX> categories. This is easy
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to understand, but it's not comprehensive. Even very diverse sites
seldom appear in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a few</NUMEX> categories. For instance, a search for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
(click here) shows it somewhere under the Politics
category, but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Movie Reviews</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics</ENAMEX>
categories. Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> runs a movie review <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> and has published many
articles on economics.

            Even if Yahoo! wanted to be
this comprehensive, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> cataloging the materials cannot possibly keep up
with the ever changing nature of the Web. To stay current, they would have to
read every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> of every site <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. To solve this problem, most other
search services use computers instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> to do their cataloging. Their
machines scan every Web page they can find by a process known as crawling (see
my discussion of crawling in a previous "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Webhead"</ENAMEX> column) and put every word on every page
into a giant index.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> to
take that approach was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Infoseek</ENAMEX>. Click here to search for "slate." The naive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> might expect to
see a link to our home page. But the problem is that our home page includes few
instances of the word "slate"--many fewer than, say, the home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> of a dealer
of roofing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> or pool tables is likely to. That's the limitation of a
system based on text indexing. It doesn't really know what a page is about,
just what words appear on it. Using a little artificial intelligence, the
computer tries to decide which pages are more "about" a given word than others,
but it's not always successful.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HotBot</ENAMEX> is another search
site. Try the "slate" search by clicking here. By the way, as you try out these searches, you may
see an advertisement for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. That means we bought the rights to the word
"slate." Whenever someone searches for it, our ad shows up. On the Web you can
buy words--isn't that great?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excite</ENAMEX>'s site uses some of that
artificial intelligence to help you refine your searches. Try searching for
"slate" by clicking here. If you find a page that you like you can click on "more like
this." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excite</ENAMEX> will return a list of pages which "look like" the page you
clicked on. That means that similar words appear on the pages with similar
frequency. Sometimes this works, more often it returns pages that seem
impressively unrelated. For instance, this search for pages like the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Slate parody Stale</ENAMEX> yields not only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> (a good
guess) but also the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steel Lunch Boxes Web</ENAMEX> page (not a good guess, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entertaining</ENAMEX> nonetheless).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AltaVista's</ENAMEX> site takes a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weirder</ENAMEX> approach to this idea of refining searches. Search for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clicking</ENAMEX> here. Adding or subtracting words from your search criteria
can help find what you're looking for. For instance adding "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kinsley</ENAMEX>" and
subtracting "roofing" would probably increase your chances of finding our home
page. Their "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LiveTopics</ENAMEX>" technology attempts to help you do this. They look up
"slate" in their index and see that it often occurs on the same page as "roof,"
so they suggest this as a possible refinement of the search. But since these
suggestions are generated by computer, they can be very weird. (To see this in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">action,</ENAMEX> click on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LiveTopics</ENAMEX>" links on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AltaVista</ENAMEX> search-results
page.) How did "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Adaptec</ENAMEX>" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skadden</ENAMEX>" get on the list? Your guess is as good as
mine. (Well, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skadden</ENAMEX> it's not such a mystery, considering that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slate</ENAMEX>" is
part of the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> law firm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skadden, Arps, Slate, Meagher</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flom</ENAMEX>.)

            The best <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solutions</ENAMEX> for searching will probably result from
a combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> and computers. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AltaVista</ENAMEX>'s list of search
refinements was generated by a human, for instance, it might be more helpful.
If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> of every site cataloged it themselves, then Yahoo! wouldn't
have a hard time keeping up with them. Of course, everyone would have to agree
on standard ways to do this, and if everyone agreed, for-profit search sites
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yahoo</ENAMEX>! probably wouldn't be necessary. So don't be surprised if the status
quo lasts just a little while longer.

         
      
   
