
   
   
      
         
            Signed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sealed</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dismembe</ENAMEX> red

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> , produced by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shea & Associates</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Fund for Animal Welfare</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> seal hunt is
back, and so are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> , produced by political ad maker
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Shea</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Fund for Animal Welfare</ENAMEX>, is part of an
unprecedented effort to increase public awareness before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> and the next
hunting season. Polls show that once informed of the facts, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 80 percent</NUMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> oppose the killing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> ,
hopes its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>, will give its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> those facts and rouse them to
action.

            The spot opens with a
moist-eyed white seal pup on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. "Think this little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> is safe?" asks
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>, the camera zooming to a close-up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>'s eye, in which a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">club</ENAMEX>-brandishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> is now silhouetted. As the pup attempts futilely to
escape, we are given the numbers. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Up to half a million</NUMEX> seals, most of them pups
under <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year old</TIMEX>, were killed by commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> (a key
study by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clive Southey</ENAMEX> offered a lower figure--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">269,000</NUMEX>--that has been
contested).

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> flag dissolves on
a bloody ice field as the sealer drags the pup away. The image of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">government's</ENAMEX> complicity is a powerful one: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southey's</ENAMEX> study claims that the hunt
adds little value, especially once government subsidies (on which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.4 million</NUMEX> just in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>) are subtracted. The end does not
justify the means, says the spot, cutting <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto Globe</ENAMEX> and
Mail headline--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sealers</ENAMEX> convicted for cruel slaughter"--and then to a shot
of an abandoned carcass. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFAW</ENAMEX> has videotaped atrocities, and while we are
not made to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> a skinning or an impaling, we hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pup</ENAMEX> crying and see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hooks</ENAMEX> waving. (And though the spot never really tells us that these crimes are
ignored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, there have been reports to that effect.)

            The seals are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> not of
research or of subsistence hunting, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> , but of an unsubstantiated
claim that their penises increase human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potency</ENAMEX> ("totally inexcusable" in "what
is supposed to be an enlightened age," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shatner</ENAMEX>, one of a growing
cast of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">luminaries</ENAMEX> who have signed on to the IFAW cause, has been quoted as
saying). We see a shot of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a bustling</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> market, followed by one of a seal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. (The juxtaposition is familiar enough, and reaches for the
emotional energy of other battles between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> and apparently
impervious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. But the portrayal of the transaction in question is
interesting: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> is white.)

            The spot ends with the image
of a white-coat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pup</ENAMEX>, a phone number, and an explicit exhortation. The animal
can't stop this, but you can. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> numbers represent a fivefold increase
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">previous annual</TIMEX> takes, which had plateaued at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55,000</NUMEX> after mass
international protest drove them down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1970s</TIMEX>. Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, that is.
Dwindling cod <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> in the waters off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newfoundland</ENAMEX> inspired the federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fisheries and Oceans</ENAMEX> to raise annual hunt quotas on harp and
hooded seals to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">275,000</NUMEX>. Echoing the classical political appeal to "speak for
those who have no voice," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> hopes your conscience will win the
day.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
