
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> Pattern

             

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUNDIT CENTRAL</ENAMEX>" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: Allegations that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and corporate campaign donations to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> compromised <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> security. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s
rejection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s executive privilege claim for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>. The
crumbling tobacco deal places a distant <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>.

            "It's
serious," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) of the
prima facie evidence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>- and corporate-<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">quid</NUMEX> for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satellite</ENAMEX>-technology transfer quo. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentariat</ENAMEX> agrees. "What was the
national security damage?" asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> chew
on the question, but nobody can connect the dots of satellite waivers, know-how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">leaks</ENAMEX>, and campaign donations, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gang</ENAMEX> ).

            Only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ) discern a distinct pattern of
play-for-pay. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> expresses "no doubt" that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> influenced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
policy with their money. ("Am I glad we're off the sex topic," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> adds.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) finds watershed significance in the fact
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> deserted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the vote on future satellite waivers.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> connection is "driving a wedge" between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> says, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> vote foreshadows future defections from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            Tempering
the hard line are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ), who
say corporate soft money--not foreign money--is the real problem. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Kearns</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodwin</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ) further puddles the issue, insisting the "whole
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> has become corrupted." Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> downplay the accusations of treason
and malfeasance, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> were the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to enlist
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> assistance in launching <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> satellites (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doyle McManus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review ; Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> ).

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and scheduled visit to
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> draws fire from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ), who calls it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill's</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bitburg</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> finds the symbolism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen</ENAMEX> visit "shameful." But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> speculates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could turn the visit into a big moment if
he uses the occasion to denounce the massacre.

            Liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) frames <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>'s dull <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, imploring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> to get to the bottom of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinagate</ENAMEX> by appointing an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to
investigate campaign-finance violations.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s rejection of the executive privilege claim for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>--Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>--is interpreted as a huge victory for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bruised Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is batting "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>" against
presidential legal challenges, note <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ), proving that he's "not a rogue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prosecutor"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ). "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> was downright
scornful of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>," adds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>.

            The executive privilege
ruling is a big so-what for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> doesn't really mind losing individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> cases as long as losing
buys him time. His "delaying" strategy is to run the clock down until the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> elections, then win <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> back with just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> new seats and shut down
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> investigations with his new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>.

            The
tobacco settlement--Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>--is dead for now, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwen Ifill</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ). "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> just isn't in a barter mood, which is what
[legislation] requires," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ifill</ENAMEX> says.

            
               Sorry, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It Was Never in My Mouth:</ENAMEX> "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
case, per se, has left a bad taste in a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s mouths," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundit</ENAMEX>-in-training <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Conniff</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ).

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Loves Late Edition :</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punditry</ENAMEX>'s leading exponent of redundancy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>, plows new ground on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NewsHour</ENAMEX> . Ordinarily, he recycles sound bites from his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
NewsHour gig on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>
expresses amazement at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> spin machine's "cautious, almost slow"
response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinagate</ENAMEX> accusations. This precise sentiment was voiced last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> .

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
