
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greener Than Thou</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shore Revised</ENAMEX> ,
produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Axelrod</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associates</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Andrews</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Jersey Democratic</ENAMEX>
gubernatorial primary sent a trickle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to the polls <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This off-year</TIMEX> contest--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between four</NUMEX>-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Andrews</ENAMEX> and two-term state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim McGreevey</ENAMEX>--generated little attention: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> Gov.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Todd Whitman</ENAMEX>, is likely to trounce her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> competition in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 350,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> turned out at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s poll.

            Despite the low levels of
interest, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> took to the airwaves in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few weeks</TIMEX> of
campaigning, blitzing the costly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> media markets with
negative ads. The cost of the air war: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an estimated $4 million</NUMEX>.

            McGreevey, who came from
behind to win the primary by a slim <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX>, painted his opponent as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gingrich Democrat</ENAMEX> who had voted to cut <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and the school-lunch program
and deprive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX>. And if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews</ENAMEX> spots were to be believed,
McGreevey was an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalist</ENAMEX> who had delayed closing a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipeline</ENAMEX> that
pumped treated chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waste</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>. "For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ciba-Geigy</ENAMEX>
pipeline dumped cancer-causing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxins</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX> shore," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shore</ENAMEX>
Revised , produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Axelrod</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associates</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrews</ENAMEX> campaign.
"As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trenton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim McGreevey</ENAMEX> ... sided with the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">polluters</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">visuals</ENAMEX>--a sleepy coastline that, gradually leached of color, tightens into a
jaundiced, roiling froth--offer third-party verification via superimposed
newspaper clips. But it is worth noting that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the clips take on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ciba</ENAMEX>, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGreevey</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) they are more tentative than the context would suggest. One
headline merely places <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ciba</ENAMEX> at the storm's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>; another notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>
blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases in the area.

            The hope, of course, is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> will skim the ad and buy its message. And to this end, the spot proffers
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX>-disclosure form, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGreevey</ENAMEX>'s signature in ominous close-up. The
form, which is largely indecipherable, is from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>. It documents <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGreevey</ENAMEX>'s
efforts to amend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ciba-Geigy</ENAMEX> bill, efforts that have been spun differently
by each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> primary debate, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrews</ENAMEX> had raised
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ciba-McGreevey</ENAMEX> issue, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGreevey</ENAMEX> issued a statement saying that he had in
fact "drafted compromise amendments that broke the logjam and allowed the ban
on ocean discharges to be written into law." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Detractors</ENAMEX> have pointed out that
the only significant amendment to the bill ended up delaying the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipeline</ENAMEX>'s
closure by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. Determined to establish his distance from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ciba</ENAMEX> issue,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGreevey</ENAMEX> has cited newspaper reports in which major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> on the bill say
they have no memory of his involvement. But his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protests</ENAMEX> seem to have had
little effect on area <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Jersey Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation</ENAMEX> has endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrews</ENAMEX>, a fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shore</ENAMEX> Revised trumpets. And
a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX> who had supported the closure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipeline</ENAMEX> recently held a
press conference disputing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGreevey</ENAMEX>'s claims, saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s big
business and industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX>, with which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGreevey</ENAMEX> was affiliated at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, had opposed the bill.

            Going from negative to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comparative</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shore</ENAMEX> 
               Revised touts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrews</ENAMEX>' dedication to the
environment. He's taken on the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">polluters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, we're told, the spot
cutting to what looks like footage of a congressional hearing but which is, in
fact, staged. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> ethics rules prohibit the use of official
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> for campaign purposes, which means that any "hearing" in a political
ad must be contrived, and made to look as authentic as possible.)

            The unnoted ironies pile up:
Their fulminations notwithstanding, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGreevey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrews</ENAMEX> have received
better-than-average ratings from green <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Environmental score cards
produced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Jersey Public Interest Group</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGreevey</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX>
rating in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> did better. A different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League of Conservation Voters</ENAMEX>, gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. His soaring score notwithstanding, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrews</ENAMEX> came under fire in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> for
supporting a measure that would have diverted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 billion</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superfund</ENAMEX>
program (a fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGreevey</ENAMEX> has made much of in radio ads). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGreevey</ENAMEX>'s
involvement in the pipeline issue notwithstanding, he gets credit for
sponsoring the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Pollution Prevention Act</ENAMEX>, which reduced the toxins released by
the chemical industry. His initiative notwithstanding, he has come under fire
for letting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> administration undermine what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollution Prevention</ENAMEX>
Act sought to achieve. Clearly, there was time yet for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> indecisions,
and for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> visions and revisions--and alas, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">it isn't Andrews</ENAMEX> who gets to
take the toast and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>. Shore Revised ends with the ubiquitous shot of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and the ubiquitous spiel about him fighting for
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and yours. The fight was in vain, as it turned out. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews</ENAMEX> lost.
Does that mean the spot failed? It was a classic play on a hot-button issue,
and it fell <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just</NUMEX> short. Making the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGreevey</ENAMEX> in the broadest and
barest terms, its message never quite landed.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
