
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> or Bust

             

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUNDIT CENTRAL</ENAMEX>" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            The death of the tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s upcoming visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> vie for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Issue 1</ENAMEX> berth. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> is Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. A raft of unfocused speculation about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s next
move is Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> save <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) agree <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should use his China
tour to publicly spank the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> for human rights abuses. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> thinks
"Asiatic" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> ought to be chided behind closed doors.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX>
( The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) believes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> needs to flatter his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> as
well as confront them--she terms it "a delicate dance."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) worries <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will "wimp out." Clift
points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made critical comments during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>'s recent
visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and predicts he will toe the same line in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. All
the hot air expended on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> disproves the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> don't care
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> foreign policy, notes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grinning</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Harris</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>tobacco bill is dead because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX> bought
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, charges <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ).
True enough, agrees <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX>, but let's not forget that the trial lawyers bought
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) disagrees,
citing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ/NBC</ENAMEX> poll taken before the industry's ad campaign that indicates
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> viewed the bill primarily as a revenue-raising instrument. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX>
didn't kill the bill, argues <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX>, the bill killed itself.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ) agree that the big loser in the tobacco bill's
death is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. It was his chance to put something in the history books,
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>. It proves that he is feckless, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX>.

            
Will the vote affect midterm elections? It will
hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, predict <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ). It will be "a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wash</ENAMEX>," predicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX>, because anti-smoking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
will be balanced by anti-tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> suggest the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
may backtrack by passing a slimmed-down bill to cover up their assassination of
this one. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Birnbaum</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> terms this a
"tobacco leaf" bill.)

            In his
second week as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press scourge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Brill</ENAMEX> remains a hot topic. (He appears on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> .) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> describe his article as "not
an honest piece of work" and "more than sloppiness" and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> himself as a
"slime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>," who "on fire ... will never be doused" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brit Hume</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gang</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ). The middle way is best
expressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> )--he scolds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> for
undisclosed campaign contributions and for overstretching his legal case
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> but applauds him for casting light on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lars-Erik Nelson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ) pronounces <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s article "a great
public service for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."

            

               What on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Earth Are These Two Talking</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About</TIMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> dedicates <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the final minutes</TIMEX> of his show to the
proposition that contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture sneers at fatherhood: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> are
regarded as "inseminating instruments, superfluous after that." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>'s
take is accurate in "a general, nonspecific way," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Carlson</ENAMEX>
presumably means that anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> thinking is a widespread belief of which
there are no instances.

            
               Would
You Say That if He Knocked <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">on Your Door</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX>'s advice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>: Whenever
you have the impulse to give an on-the-record interview, you ought to "just sit
down, take a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Valium</ENAMEX>, and get over it."

            

               Well Said: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Brill</ENAMEX> flap:
"It's an interesting story, rather than an important story."

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Message for Kids Who</ENAMEX>
Want To Be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Judges Someday</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> showing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> had all the usual suspects as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> (grain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX>,
telecommunications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, luxury car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>) as well as one unexpected spot
apparently meant to keep <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4- to 6</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-year-olds</TIMEX> off <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. The ad features a purple
cockroach being spread on toast, all the while singing, "I'd rather eat a big
old bug, than ever take a stupid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>!"

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
