
   
   
      
         
            Bring Me the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> was Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> as the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> pundits readied the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for war against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>. As they did,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX> on both the right (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) and the left
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) asked why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX>
wasn't mobilizing public opinion for the coming clash. No problem, said all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>, who swarmed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> shows, conducting well-scripted
teach-ins about the dangers posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> and his biological weapons. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s line was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s quarrel was with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> the emphasis shifted slightly to leave no doubt
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will settle the dispute, unilaterally if need be.

            The talking heads were
a-babble with bellicosity. "Form as big a posse as we can," urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mort</ENAMEX>
Kondracke on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> predicted a cruise-missile attack followed by "hand-to-hand combat."
"Clearly, we've got to strike the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> on This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> . "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>] must go," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gang</ENAMEX> . "Extend the no-fly zone," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gergen</ENAMEX>. "Tighten the noose."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Contemplating Saddam</ENAMEX>'s anthrax-tipped warheads on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Limbaugh</ENAMEX> answered his own question when he asked, should we "wait until he
does it, or pre-empt it?"

            Having cast their vote for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assassinating Saddam</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> had no room to escalate. So they offered sober military
strategies. "If you go in, it has to be a sustained bombing campaign and that
has to be followed up by the threat of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>. The silver
lining of the coming war, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> smiled, was that it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> would make <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> a "foreign-policy year."

            Having
declared war, the pundit posse immediately expressed doubt that it could be
won. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> absorbed <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">88,000 tons</NUMEX> of bombs during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 43 days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>
without folding or replacing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>, noted several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Russert on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s bio-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chem arsenal</ENAMEX> was surely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bunkered</ENAMEX> beyond the reach of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> bombs, they concluded. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> pointed out that "it took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manuel Noriega</ENAMEX>" in tiny
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> after the invasion.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Schwarzkopf</ENAMEX> agreed on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX>
that invaders would never apprehend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>, but he still insisted that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> "bomb him into submission." The "end game" of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>'s
schemes is undermining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> authority and "getting the sanctions lifted,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzkopf</ENAMEX> said. Only by pulverizing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> could the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> deny <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
these diplomatic victories and preserve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>' power to police
rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> in the future.

            The only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AWOLs</ENAMEX> in the pundit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">battalion</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX>, who
suggested that we talk the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> into compliance. (They were shouted down.)
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Accept Saddam</ENAMEX> as he is," ventured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX>, and make a deal. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reintegrate Iraq</ENAMEX>
into the world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>," offered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>, who added that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> wasn't the
only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider nation</ENAMEX> with chemical and biological weapons.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Berger</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction repeat-offender."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Extending Berger</ENAMEX>'s criminal-justice metaphor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s demand that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> be excluded from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inspection</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>], being a parolee, is not in a position to determine
who his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parole officer</ENAMEX> will be." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> also played show-and-tell on This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> , holding up a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5-pound</NUMEX> bag of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domino</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>. The same-sized package
containing anthrax could kill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, he
warned.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> tipped their hand
on where the debate will go <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> when they tried--without much success--to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">inject Israel</ENAMEX> into the debate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab League</ENAMEX> had aligned with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>, said
Gergen on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> and others, because it was angry with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> for the stalled peace process.

            "All
politics is personal" was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commentariat</ENAMEX>'s reading of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
failure to muster <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> support for fast-track trade legislation. The
defeat was "payback" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liasson, Limbaugh</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gang</ENAMEX> ) by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sins of triangulation
(the balanced budget, welfare reform, the tax cuts). "They're not scared of
him," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>. "It's beyond not being scared of him," shot back This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX>. "They're mad at him!" Reprising an earlier
theme about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX> criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> for not organizing a
"campaign far enough in advance" to pass fast track.

            

               Innuendos <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">97</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX>
claimed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> that the "word around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>" has it that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>--which has failed to nail even one of the million
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> guilty of campaign-finance violations--is aggressively pursuing its
investigation of former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Barbour</ENAMEX>. "It
looks terrible," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox Washington</ENAMEX> bureau <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> observed, more in anger than
in sorrow.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pundit Bites: Last</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> claimed on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> that he hasn't eaten
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> since becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Limbaugh</ENAMEX> countered that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had, in
fact, snarfed at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey D</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>. "If he'll [lie] about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>, he'll
do it about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Limbaugh</ENAMEX> charged. ... Can you bomb a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> into
compliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> resolutions? Yes, said former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagleburger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Maj. Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry Smith</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ret.</ENAMEX>) on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ,
citing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> surrender to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Dayton</ENAMEX> peace conference as an example.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
