
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bucks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butts</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Books</ENAMEX>

             

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUNDIT CENTRAL</ENAMEX>" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            Politicking on campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX>, tobacco, and education are Issues <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The sex scandal plays
as background music, coming in as Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' appearance at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Correspondents' Dinner</ENAMEX>--where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>--is
Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' bumbling on campaign finance reform shows they're a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that
"could screw up a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ).
First, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> squashed the bill in the most underhanded way possible, and
now they're trying to take credit for reviving it. Cynical in the extreme, says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) senses growing pressure to
change campaign finance rules; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer )</ENAMEX> thinks this issue can decide elections, maybe winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
a congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ) worries that eliminating
soft money will induce self-interested money-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to fund their own commercials,
thereby permitting private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> to set the agendas in congressional
races.

            Is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> tobacco bill a tax on the middle class or protection for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commentariat</ENAMEX> agrees the public's eventual answer to this question will
determine the bill's fate. The early line on what that answer will be:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two-thirds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> deal as a tax, according to a Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal /NBC</ENAMEX> poll cited by many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARepublican</ENAMEX> proposal allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to spend
tax-free dollars on private elementary and secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> is important
because education is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Issue No. 1</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> and Cokie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> may erase its historical weakness on
education with this issue, suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX>. But this particular proposal is a
stinker, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ), because it offers parents
a mere token of tax relief (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37</NUMEX> per year).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s decision to
demand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> testimony from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> draws fire from some in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commentariat</ENAMEX>. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s side (against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service testimony) convinces a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s stance is no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> stonewall. How about letting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> decide the question case by
case, suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Thomas</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ). Do we really want the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to have a publicly funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Praetorian Guard</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wonders Krauthammer</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDougal</ENAMEX>'s defiant appearance in leg irons moves some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> to sympathy. It
moves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krauthammer</ENAMEX> to wonder, "Who the hell does she think she is [not to
testify because] she doesn't like her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' decision to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insight</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s
invitation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s speech at the swanky <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Correspondents</ENAMEX>' Dinner makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> )
scratch his head. Given her claim that she cannot stand to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on
television--a fortiori in the flesh--does she really want to give the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> "a stick to beat her with<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> asks. Her appearance is
a needless affront to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and the presidency, say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germond</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> )
sat next to her at dinner and reports she "carried herself like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>," in
contrast to certain vulgar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX> who booed her and made classist snipes
about her appearance.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>'s
on-the-record contention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a "scumbag"--helpfully defined as a
slang term for a soiled rubber by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX>--is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">universally</ENAMEX> derided as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>. He should have had the sense to call the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> names in private, says the smart set. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is lucky to have
such dumb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, opine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krauthammer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ).

            It is
never wise practice to call the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> names in public, even if you're not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, continues <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krauthammer</ENAMEX>. He once called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> a
louse, and the phone didn't stop ringing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Related</ENAMEX> story: Pundit
Central once called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Schmucko</ENAMEX>" and got <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bushels</NUMEX> of harsh mail,
some from his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>. The fact that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Schmucko</ENAMEX>" was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s phrase placated no one.)

            

               Product <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Placement</ENAMEX>: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Group panelists</ENAMEX> appeared discomforted by the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, timbre of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>'s opening segment on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>, the newly released sexual wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>.
The discussion began bawdily enough, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes characterizing the $10</ENAMEX>
pill as "the greatest thing for trophy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> since joint banking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">accounts</ENAMEX> ...
[but] bad for gigolos." Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX> agreed that mo' better coitus can only
be a good thing. All were amused by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>'s suggestion that refurbished
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">libidos</ENAMEX> and the promise of better sex will drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to get toned and fit.
Faces froze into uncomfortable smiles, however, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> went on to cite
studies that claim frequent ejaculation leads to healthy prostates. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
totally lost the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> with his argument that dispensing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> will encourage
more sexual exertion, ergo better health. No one but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> seemed
convinced that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will subsidize <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX>, either.

            
               Whoops! I'm Not Saying
She's Guilty, Though: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, appearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ,
predicted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> will not be indicted. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week concur</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> does, however, let slip his belief
that "her fingerprints are on almost everything from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to now</TIMEX>."

            
               Wasn't That in
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Federalist" No. 10</ENAMEX>? 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Drew</ENAMEX> said she has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">talked to Gingrich</ENAMEX> confidants who claim the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> is seriously interested in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impeaching</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, then nailing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> for pardoning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Who, asks clever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX>, is next in line for the Oval
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>? Why, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, of course!

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
