
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>

             

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUNDIT CENTRAL</ENAMEX>" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
telecast of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sharp comments to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>. Sometimes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gleefully</ENAMEX>, sometimes grudgingly, the commentariat pronounces <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s
telecast an important victory for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s
obligatory opining on Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-- l'affaire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> --centers on the
upcoming grand jury testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>.

            Just in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> criticized the crackdown in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s general approach to human rights. The televised criticism will have a
long-lasting effect, believes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ): "You let
a little freedom get started, you can't stop it." "Great stuff," agrees <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hume</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) is
"very proud of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>," though he believes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s evolution into a free
state will not be sped by lectures.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> note that at the outset the trip smelled like
a public relations disaster (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> refused visas to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio Free Asia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> and arrested several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
Late <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edition</ENAMEX> ) called it "sticking a finger in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s eye."
Nevertheless, the televised debate "redeemed" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the eyes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liasson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ). But a few critical voices point out that the
decision to broadcast the debate was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s--further evidence
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s stooge (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulus</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hume</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX>).

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> role reversal on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">amazes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
talks about human rights while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dems</ENAMEX> defend business interests. "It's actually
enough to make your head spin," agrees <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) charges that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> profess
support for human rights over commerce just to court votes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> know
that they won't alienate their true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX>--big business--because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> don't control the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and therefore have no foreign
policy teeth. "The farther you are away from power, the more likely you are to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">bash China</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX>.

            
The commentariat doesn't have much that is new
to say about Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-- l'affaire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> . Everyone thinks that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s long awaited testimony is just around the corner. Everyone seems
tired of waiting. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) complains that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> gets to take a vacation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> while the opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> must hang
around swampy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> just because a new wrinkle might break.

            The only new development is
the revelation that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> will testify <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX> ( The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) thinks the timing is suspect--it may be an attempt to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">steal Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> thunder. Let's not forget that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> rescheduled the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trip to coincide with the expected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> trial date, points out
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hume</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s testimony will be a "bombshell," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanopoulus</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s
testimony is proof that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s inquiry is coming to a close, say others.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caveat</ENAMEX> emptor: the same voices that have been predicting a close for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Hunt</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) alleges that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is an out of control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. Novak
attacks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for his tactics of delay. This is an argument that Novak
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> have been having since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 1</TIMEX> of the scandal.

            

               Won't This Hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Feelings</ENAMEX>?
Most of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> shows begin with a brief news report on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trip
delivered by a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>. Generally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> strike an air
of stern impartiality, just as on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> news. But not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Angle</ENAMEX>, who reports, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> went toe-to-toe with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>,
the smoothest talker in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> world."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pundits Get It Right:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, responding to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> mail, has decided to keep stats on the
opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX> predicted that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> would detarget its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Barone</ENAMEX> predicted the outcome of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>'s election. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> guessed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s scandal would not be resolved during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> are correct and earn a point each, though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX> loses <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a
point for scoring on a bunt.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
