
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Invade</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bomb</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stall</ENAMEX>?

             

            The commentariat abandon
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past weeks</TIMEX>' hawkish bluster to ask hard questions about Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. Their
conclusion? None of the alternatives look too thumping. While few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>
endorse specific proposals, that doesn't stop them from criticizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> in search of a rationale," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cokie</ENAMEX> ) calls them. "I'm not sure they know what comes after,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laments Martha Raddatz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
where "the idea of bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has really fallen into trouble," is equally
confused, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> explains the
appeal of bombing: It provides "gratification without commitment." Yet air
attacks will not remove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> agree, and greasing the
maximum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> with smart bombs is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">poppyhead</ENAMEX>'s dangerous "pipe dream" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ). Many follow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX>'s ( This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ) lead in worrying about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> after, when an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unruffled</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
emerges to mug for the cameras.

            Leading the war caucus are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Crier</ENAMEX>
(both on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ), who predict that when push comes to shove
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will support the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> )
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ), who sense public support for a drawn-out
ground war.

            But many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> believe that renewed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> inspections will be enough to satisfy
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>. The "make love, not war" sentiment is strong on The

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> , as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Page</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
forecast a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60-percent</NUMEX> chance that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will stand down from armed
conflict. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) forecasts a "better than
even" chance that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will give peace a chance. (Fifty-fifty
predictions are popular with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> because they provide the necessary
wiggle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in both directions.)

            
In the absence of any new revelations on the
presidential sexcapade, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> demote it to Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and place it on
automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>. They're looking forward to the next step in the process, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> delivers to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. "Judgment day is getting closer and closer,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> warns ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> identify
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s political victory in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> looked like a partisan bully)
and his legal defeat (what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> pulled from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> is another nail in
the coffin).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Duffy</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) dispute the
distinction between the political and the legal. By making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> look like an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obsessed Ahab</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Spear Carrier</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX>) hope to
taint the investigation and deter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> from impeaching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> with
the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s wiggy evidence. According to this logic, a series of
small anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> political victories will add up to a whopper of a legal
triumph.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX> reminds all that supposed ideologue <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> was once
"every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>'s favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>," and that when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dems</ENAMEX> wanted a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX>-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> to deal with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Packwood</ENAMEX> sex scandal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> was their
first choice. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NewsHour</ENAMEX> co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Oliphant</ENAMEX> both agree
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "smash-mouth politics" have hardened <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, and made him a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rougher</ENAMEX>, hungrier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ) suggests the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will counter the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> tactics with "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> water torture,"
weakening <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> bit by bit while keeping him alive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> won't be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impeached</ENAMEX>, predicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX>, but he will be substantially weakened.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision to appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to investigate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Babbitt</ENAMEX> is Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Amazing, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>: Babbitt
has "the finest reputation [for ethical conduct] of anyone in public life"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oliphant</ENAMEX>); is "the last [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>] one would imagine getting in trouble"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doyle McManus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ); and is "the most honest man
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>" (an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adoring</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ). The
oft-ironic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> do not note that being the most honest man in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is
like being the best-complexioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dermatologist</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Novak
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) is not so sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babbitt</ENAMEX> is really <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mr. Clean</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) quips that if exonerated, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babbitt</ENAMEX> will be the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> who doesn't end up in the stir. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>
wonder aloud: Will the new independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> follow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s instructions and
keep his nose out of larger campaign-finance issues?

            

               What's in a Name? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Producers</ENAMEX> at This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> catch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> mispronouncing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Surgeon General Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satcher</ENAMEX>'s name at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satcher</ENAMEX>'s swearing-in ceremony. In introductory speeches <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
called him "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatcher</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> called him "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX>." The segment notes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was known to misidentify his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and also the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> in official settings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> purposely mispronounced "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>" to annoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> newsreaders retaliated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mispronouncing Bush</ENAMEX> so that, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>, it meant "nothing."

            Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
stares directly at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred "Beetle" Barnes</ENAMEX>, pauses, and calls him "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>."
Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> refers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guard</ENAMEX> as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Guard</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> looks directly at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> and calls him "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>," much to the amusement of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX>.

            
               Legal Math: Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> shouted down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> for alleging
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> was composed of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> reveals his research to announce that of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> deputy and
associate counsels, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> are on loan from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> are
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> have no DOJ affiliation. "You can line up to
apologize to me after the show," booms an effulgent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nemesis Hunt</ENAMEX> refutes
the slack-jawed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX>, with the computation that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> and therefore half
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX> are not current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
