
   
   
      
         
            Drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rehabilitation</ENAMEX>

            
               Daifotis , produced
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter Eskew</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bozell-Eskew for the Pharmaceutical</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manufacturers Assn</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daifotis</ENAMEX> faced a Herculean task: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Survey</ENAMEX> data showed that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>,
the pharmaceutical industry, had an image problem. Like your friendly
neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>, your friendly neighborhood drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was considered
anything but. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Au</ENAMEX> contraire , the unhappy consensus was that it was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">avaricious</ENAMEX>, monopolistic, loyal only to the bottom line.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appropriately</ENAMEX>, the man
charged with the task is a past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> at peddling image as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> of
the ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> '92, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter Eskew</ENAMEX> has since migrated to the
commercial side of the business. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daifotis</ENAMEX> , like the other spots in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bozell-Eskew</ENAMEX> campaign for the pharmaceutical industry, marks the
convergence of political and commercial advertising. Using one of the former's
most powerful ploys, it chooses to come at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> obliquely via a human
face, a human tragedy, that carefully fronts the industry behind.

            The issue here is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteoporosis</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> whose life it touched. "My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandmother</ENAMEX> had osteoporosis," she says, briefly humanizing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> who might have otherwise been collapsed into a single statistic by the
opening chyron. Here and through the spot, she speaks directly to the camera,
her earnest face and voice limning with hope the shots of an ailing elder and
of single, bleak lines of text that bring the disease to life and the living
room. Her speech seems spontaneous, not scripted: The desired effect, of
course, is that she personalize the industry she is promoting, edging it into
our consciousness as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> of solutions--nay, as a caring provider
of solutions.

            A black-and-white photograph
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">briefly</ENAMEX> recalls happier times, then makes way for this young professional
(she's wearing the mandatory blue suit) describing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s
degeneration, her increasing frailty and the consequent reversal of roles: "I
had to carry her and hold her as I remember her always carrying me." As we read
the astounding numbers--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62,000</NUMEX> osteoporosis <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> will enter nursing homes
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, few to return <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX>--she tells us how the disease operates, of soft
bones that yield to the gentlest touch. There is a solution in sight, however,
and she tells us that she is a part of it. The stage set, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> primed,
the spot can reveal that she is a pharmaceutical-company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> who "really
feels" she is making a difference, that she is a proud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that
has found a way to "increase the bone mass in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." And "her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>"--this
is the clincher, which, fusing human face and industry, testifies to a mission
accomplished--has developed one of these rehabilitative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> makes only a
brief appearance, and the spot seesaws right back to the human issue. A
close-up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s hands reinforces the fact that osteoporosis could
become anyone's reality. Going behind the figures and images, she talks of the
psychological impact of the disease, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s discovery that she is
"that frail old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> she never wanted to become." Then the counterpoint, the
explicit projection of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> as the harbinger of hope: It
is helping over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and she, its human face, is tireless in her
effort to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> that will enable a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to "climb stairs without fear,
stand a little taller."

            Reinforcing the commitment
and humanity that energize this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">behemoth</ENAMEX> behind her, the
final chyrons stress that this is no pat pitch: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Ã</NUMEX>  la political spots that seek
to convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> that she is on the threshold of a wider truth,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daifotis</ENAMEX> serves up a toll-free number. This isn't just a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60-second</TIMEX> spot,
we are supposed to decide; more information is a mere phone call away. And this
isn't the same old drug industry either; "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmaceutical Companies</ENAMEX>"
are in your corner, pulling for you. They're new and improved, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'97</NUMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'92</TIMEX>. And before you carp about old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and new
bottles, old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and new tricks, take a look at those election returns.
Something sure worked.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
