
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governor</ENAMEX>

            
               Cool <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> , produced
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pintak, Gautier, Hudome Agency Inc.</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>.

            
               Cool 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mom</ENAMEX> gives
us the softer side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christie Whitman</ENAMEX>, drawing viewer
attention away from polls (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just the last week</TIMEX>) that show her in a dead
heat with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> challenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim McGreevey</ENAMEX>. Besides giving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
a much-needed break from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX>'s attacks on her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> and his "high-tax
philosophy," it is also a well-calculated response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGreevey</ENAMEX>'s
attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> as clueless snob and insensitive patrician. Produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Murphy</ENAMEX>, this spot disdains contentious facts and boring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stats</ENAMEX> in favor of fuzz. It focuses on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>--a cool one, if her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>, are to be believed--and in so doing recalls a radio ad
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> used to good effect when trying to revive a sagging campaign in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>.

            That ad had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX> talking of
her mother as a role model. This one has both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> going the same route. Not
only does <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> get the credit for instilling in him basic values--integrity and
responsibility and honesty; the importance of keeping one's promises--but she
also gets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">extra</NUMEX> points for having taught by example. As important, perhaps, is
that she has been a caring, fun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX>, the glue that keeps the family
"tight-knit."

            The opening frames show the
Whitmans on a lush, picket-fenced green, making no apologies for what is
obviously a life of privilege. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> is tossed--and almost missed--amid
much laughter and camaraderie, reprising what is arguably one of the most
memorable images of modern politics, that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> playing touch
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyannisport</ENAMEX>. No matter that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> have a bigger lawn, these
images are meant to say: What matters is heart, the desire to do good. The idea
that wealth is venial if pressed into public service is a harder sell for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> than it is for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> (even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> was lambasted as being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitor</ENAMEX>
to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, remember?). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX>'s intentions, insists <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cool Mom</ENAMEX> ,
are unimpeachable and always have been, her commitment to her various roles
absolute ("she has that ability to go home and forget about all the political
stuff and be a ... mom").

            The testimonials from these
clean-cut, well-adjusted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> (to say nothing of the family resemblance) make a
clear play for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> vote--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> that attack ads have been known
to alienate. That aside, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> have sought, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX>, to
undermine her popularity among female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> by attacking her handling of
sexual-harassment allegations against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cool Mom</ENAMEX>
would regain that ground--and wreak its own subtle havoc (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGreevey</ENAMEX> is going
through a divorce, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morag</ENAMEX>, lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> with her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX>'s allegedly
successful separation of personal from political does not, however, extend to
this ad. Images of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> at work--signing bills, making speeches--splice
a story that is told by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>, speaking to camera, lauds "what
she's done for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>," as a shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> amid cheering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> (one
prominently uniformed) reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that it is she who deserves credit for
the decrease in crime. And she has "stuck with what she said she was going to
do" (there's no denying that she cut income taxes--so what if property taxes
then went up?).

            The images flow thick:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX>, baseball cap and all, mingling easily at what looks like a
transportation event ("what she does, she does to help <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>"); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitman</ENAMEX>
behind a sign that trumpets her "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work First</ENAMEX>" program, then a shot of her
hugging a politically correct mix of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> ("she loves this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>"). As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>
points out, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> "wants to do the best that she can" for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>.
Cool <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> invites its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> to look beyond an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shortfalls</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--or, at least, the intentions--of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> at its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">helm</ENAMEX>. Less obviously clever than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGreevey</ENAMEX>'s caricature of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX>, the spot
makes artful use of the personal to validate the political. Whether it can
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trump</ENAMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>'s attacks and ease an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>'s frustrations remains, of
course, to be seen.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
