
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forrest Gump</ENAMEX>

            
               Growth & <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> ,
produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Media Inc.</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Association of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Manufacturers</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Manufacturers</ENAMEX> during the now-resolved debate over cutting
federal taxes, this timely, pointed spot extends history's reach in an effort
to push for the tax breaks favored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAM</ENAMEX>.

            The opening shot of
Growth & <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> takes us back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>.
Black-and-white footage invokes a past that, thanks to the image of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
remains a compelling symbol of hope, is not passé. Targeting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and the
middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> who were, at the time, being told by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> version of the tax cut was unfair, the spot challenges their
confidence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Whom do you believe, it seems to ask, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>? (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> later compromised with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, and the final bill included
many of the latter's proposals.)

            "This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> needs a tax
cut," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> says--nothing new here, given the climate: This "need" for a tax cut
seems to have asserted itself in every post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>. In the very
different context of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to call for
a tax cut with the explicitly Keynesian purpose of creating a deficit to
stimulate the economy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> was concerned about an economy in crisis; current
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> don't have to be. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s tax cut was designed to result in a deficit;
the current cut, in keeping with the supply-side doctrine of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>,
was part of a deficit-ending package.

            Moving to a full-screen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chyron</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s words (etched in an appropriately antique font), the spot
transitions seamlessly to another section of the speech. Back then to a shot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>, who now links a tax cut to "buying power." It's true that buying power
isn't exactly a problem in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s economy--credit-card debt is at an all-time
high--but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> won't stumble over the words, which are quickly absorbed
by a visual transition to "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>" and what appears to be a scene in a
contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s voice continues to extol the tax cut, predicting
that it will bring "more production and the jobs the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>"--and the workers
we see--need.

            At this point, the spot
'fesses up via a crush of chyrons that it's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Republican Tax Cut Plan</ENAMEX>"
that's at issue here. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s words imply that he's for the plan, or at least for
something very like it (in fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">the three Kennedys</ENAMEX> currently in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
opposed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> version and were split on the final compromise). Details
of the plan are listed in order of polling appeal--starting with the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX>-per-child tax credit, a proposal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaigned on in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>; and
spiraling to the far less popular capital-gains tax cut, that Holy Grail of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> revolution. The ad's euphemism for capital gains--"tax cuts for
economic growth and jobs"--testifies to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>: They don't
want to talk it up, and probably assume that it will be lost in the crowded
screen.

            Against the background of
validating words and what seem to be specific details, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Growth & Jobs</ENAMEX>
responds explicitly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s accusation that the plan served the wealthy:
"<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">76%</NUMEX> of the tax relief is aimed at middle income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>." "Aimed" lets the
spot skirt the charge; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of the plan argued that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> would get little or nothing.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> urges that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
accept the tax cut "we're talking about." History is the more persuasive when
the facts are blurred: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost</ENAMEX> is the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> proposed to cut the top rate
from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent to 60 percent</NUMEX>, whereas the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'97</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> bill reduced the
capital-gains tax from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28 percent to 20 percent</NUMEX> and even lower.

            Legally required to carry a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disclaimer</ENAMEX>, the spot eventually identifies its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX>: the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Manufacturers</ENAMEX>, which believes that "[t]<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ax</ENAMEX> relief ... [is] a good
idea then ... a good idea now." Ironies abound. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAM</ENAMEX> didn't think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> was "a
good idea then." His address to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAM</ENAMEX> convention included this dig: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It</ENAMEX>
would be premature to ask for your support in the next election--and untrue to
thank you for it in the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>." And it is also true that most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX>'s corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> opposed the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'63</NUMEX> tax cut.

            But for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">varnish</ENAMEX> remains. Growth & <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> follows the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganesque</ENAMEX> strategy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invoking Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s words on behalf of a very different kind of tax cut.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> revel in quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, and especially to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX>
now in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>.) It also follows an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> tradition: In the
Lincoln-Douglas debates, both sides quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX>. Anyone can cite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> for his own purpose--and will.
It's not clear what, if any, effect this spot had on the outcome. Growth
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Jobs</ENAMEX> seems to make a good job of it--the devil is in the details.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
