
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s refusal to appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>,
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel O'Leary</ENAMEX>--over the objections of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Freeh</ENAMEX>--was Topic 1
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> shows. Having unanimously predicted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> wouldn't
appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, the commentarians briefly reiterated their
positions. On the attack, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> presides over a
"politicized" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> that had "changed" her mind on appointing a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counsel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ). Defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ), who said independent counsels are
"not independent" because they're appointed by a partisan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX> then moved on to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s fresh meat: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX>. Videotapes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX>'s icy comments about the rebellious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Freeh</ENAMEX> were
repeatedly unspooled. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s unveiled message to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX>: "Don't let the
door hit you on the way out" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwen Ifill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ).
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louie Freeh</ENAMEX> all of a sudden became free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louie</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shribman</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ), who predicted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> would leave
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX>. So outrageous was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeh</ENAMEX>'s "dis" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "ought to fire him," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Germond</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX> ).

            While the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> simultaneously applauded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX>'s
integrity as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, and now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, they insinuated that he
had tilted against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> to shore up his reputation with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>, who still resent him for his handling of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Filegate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby Ridge</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> crime-lab snafu (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shribman</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara</ENAMEX>
Liasson, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Mayer</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ) exonerated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX> from the charges of gross
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">politicking</ENAMEX>, saying that his real campaign is to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> from
criticism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) posited a wily <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Freeh</ENAMEX> who had
deliberately written his memo in support of an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, knowing
that it would be leaked and/or subpoenaed.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> repeatedly denigrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>.
Evidence of their low regard for her: Nobody hissed when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hume</ENAMEX> said she is not
"the sharpest knife in the drawer" or "the brightest bulb on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circuit</ENAMEX>."
Damning her with faint praise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>
the "least political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> )
compared her to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queeg</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Caine Mutiny</ENAMEX> , obsessed with micro
legal matters while neglecting macro legal matters. Riffing off a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> article, which reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> refer
to her as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martian</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shribman</ENAMEX> said now she's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s "favorite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martian</ENAMEX>."

            Gigot,
top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheerleader</ENAMEX> for an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, confessed that he couldn't explain
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' mellow response to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision. His befuddlement was
enough to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) make you think you had finally met an honest pundit or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) make you
reach for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> changer. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX>'s final consensus was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> would all clash again, but that an independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> would be appointed to investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior Bruce</ENAMEX>
Babbitt, and the investigation would come back to haunt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>,
because independent-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> investigations "spread like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hume</ENAMEX>). Also,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> will survive. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayer</ENAMEX> quoted a source as saying: "She's the perfect
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">firewall</ENAMEX> ... because nobody can say that she's in the tank for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>."

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latrell Sprewell</ENAMEX>'s assault on and death threat
against his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, moved across the shows like a fast break. But because
everybody was playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>--all condemned the assault--nobody scored.
Inexplicably, none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> proposed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomonic</ENAMEX> principle of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prosecuting Sprewell</ENAMEX> on criminal assault charges instead of suspending him for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> sends him to jail, consider that his long-term suspension. If
they find him innocent, let him play again--if any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> will have him.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>'s future-of-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> speech at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> was Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> sparred over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>'s intention: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gang</ENAMEX> ) said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> was energizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> contests.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> called the speech a "letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late</ENAMEX>
Edition ) backed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX>, calling it a "broadside" against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The
speech was "bad politics," ruled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ), who
has worked for both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>, because it didn't give the president
any credit.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">low marks</NUMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> round
table in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Akron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> (Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>), especially for abruptly switching talk-show
styles from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) in order
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abigail Thernstrom</ENAMEX>. "If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> wants a debate about
affirmative action, he can't just throw in a question at the end of the
session. He's got to structure it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liasson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX> noted that real dialogue
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about</NUMEX> race in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is precipitated by presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX> framed the race debate by integrating the armed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> and
passing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Civil Rights Act</ENAMEX>, not by asking questions.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pissy Fit</ENAMEX> at This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> contributed not one word to the
independent-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> decision, the only show to hold its fire on the issue. Were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cokie</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> demonstrating their superior news judgment or staging a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pissy</ENAMEX> fit? Halfway through the program--and apropos of nothing--host <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX>
explained that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> had been invited to appear on the show but had "set
conditions" that the show was "not able to meet." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> didn't seem to receive
any special treatment on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> , where she appeared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> didn't even rate a mention in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> 's closing round table.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" demands an independent-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> investigation of this pundit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">malfeasance</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
