
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Movietone Miller</ENAMEX>

            
               Bottles , produced
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wieden & Kennedy</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller Brewing Co.</ENAMEX>

            The blur of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> bottles,
the boom of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>. Strains of music, the words foreign yet familiar.
"C'est si bon ," croons the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chanteuse</ENAMEX> as the black-and-white images tap
barely there memories of a better time: "It's so good."

            
               Bottles , produced by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wieden & Kennedy</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller Brewing Co.</ENAMEX>, is "about real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in real
situations," according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Rooney</ENAMEX>. And there's little
doubt that it aims to re-create a smaller, more intimate world. If the marriage
of that world and this mass-produced manna strains credulity somewhat, that's
OK: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nostalgia</ENAMEX> yields to laughter at the resolution, but it is used to good
effect along the way. Explicitly abandoning the brittle brightness of standard
beer commercials, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bottles</ENAMEX> starts by drawing on a vastly different set of
themes: simplicity, pride, diligence.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harking</ENAMEX> back to a time when
there was a human element in the production process, the spot consists largely
of industrial-film-style footage of a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> monitoring bottles of beer
as they go by on the belt. Eyes narrowed, concentration absolute, this Hattie
McDaniel of the hops watches the line with an unwavering eye. The visuals
suggest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX>--a draft that sent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> into the armed forces and
created unprecedented employment opportunities for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and women
(opportunities that were lost when peace returned and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX> came marching
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">home</ENAMEX>); mass migration from the rural <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> to the industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX> that made
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riveter</ENAMEX> a household name and exemplar. And the lyrics suggest
optimism, romance. No gloomy prognostications of doom and bloodshed here;
rather, the voice of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eartha Kitt</ENAMEX>, recalling the languor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX>, the
sinuous energy of the cabaret and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catwoman</ENAMEX>. (No matter that the base note here,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kitt</ENAMEX>'s notorious opposition to another war, complicates the harmony
somewhat.)

            The long line of bottles
rolls on, the equipment right out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Chaplin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Times</ENAMEX> and
the name on the labels almost discernible. A clunky chyron, recalling Flash
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> serials and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Movietone</ENAMEX> news, dims, then sharpens, replicating the
technical difficulties of early live television as it presents the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> words:
"It's time for a good old," followed by an unexpected "macro-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">brew</ENAMEX>." Unprepared
for this jab at the rising popularity of microbrews, you realize that this is
what the spot was setting up all along. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retro</ENAMEX> feel, the sense of intimacy
and personal attention, were gimmicks--but effective ones. Reversing roles and
recasting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">behemoth</ENAMEX>, the spot transfers the old-world authenticity popularly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with microbrews to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>. The next chyron cements the transposition
by drawing attention to the words "genuine" and "time" while linking them with
the brand name. The message, of course, is that this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">brew</ENAMEX> is the real thing;
and the humor, of course, makes the message more palatable.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rooney</ENAMEX> says that the ads in this series showcase the "brand's unpretentious
personality." Part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s move to generate fresh ideas for the
faltering brand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottles</ENAMEX> is clearly not as straightforward as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rooney</ENAMEX>'s
words would suggest. Like the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wieden & Kennedy</ENAMEX> spots featured in this
column (for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>), Bottles
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mines</ENAMEX> a largely imagined cultural memory, using fuzzy images of the past to
peddle a distinctly contemporary product. Like the other spots, this one works:
C'est si bon .

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
