
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Suing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX>
            

            The latest trend in
malpractice law is educational lawsuits. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are suing their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>
for "breach of contract, fraud, misrepresentation, or negligence." Most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">claimants</ENAMEX> are angry at the poor quality or low value of the degrees they
received. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James M. Houston</ENAMEX>, who earned a Ph.D. in educational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Arizona University</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, is seeking <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> in punitive damages for an education he says
makes him a "fraud."

            Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> are suing over degrees that were never awarded. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> who had
enrolled at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lorain County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> but never graduated
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s nursing program is suing for breach of contract and violation
of consumer protection laws, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community College</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> reports. According to that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> contended that
"the catalogue of course offerings and academic policies created a contract
that obligated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> to provide him with a nursing degree." He complained
that courses required for his degree hadn't been offered during the time of his
matriculation, forcing him to leave before earning the degree. But an appeals
court threw out the suit, stating, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> does not recognize educational
malpractice claims for public policy reasons."

            
               Cutting
Off the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Nose</ENAMEX> ...
            

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois University Daily Egyptian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIU</ENAMEX>'s medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> has "changed its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">long-standing</ENAMEX> policy of cutting the limbs off of cadavers to fit them into
wardrobe boxes" before shipping them off to be cremated. An e-mail message sent
to local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois Board of Higher Education</ENAMEX> had claimed that
student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> were employed to remove the limbs and that the policy was
designed to save money. Both charges turned out to be false. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of
medicine has stated that "in the future no student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> will work with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cadavers</ENAMEX> or disintegrated anatomical remains. Further, we will no longer
physically alter anatomical remains." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIU</ENAMEX> says the new policy is more
respectful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have donated their remains to the cause of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX>.

            In other
cadaver news, a technique developed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> anatomy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gunther</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">von Hagens</ENAMEX>, which allows him to preserve and study the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> in detail, has
occasioned protest. Plastination, as the preservation method is called, involves the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> by a colored polymer, which maintains its shape as the
flesh is gradually removed. The entire circulatory system, down to the tiniest
capillaries, can be examined at full scale. An exhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">von Hagens</ENAMEX>' work
has toured <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> have called it an affront to human
dignity--which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to preserve.

            
               Go
Fish
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Fish</ENAMEX>, the flamboyant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>, legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX>, and academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lodge</ENAMEX> based his
jet-setting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris Zapp</ENAMEX> on him), has left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> to which he attracted a parade of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and controversies.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Education</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX> will become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of
liberal arts and sciences at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Illinois</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, a respected
commuter campus making a bid for greater prestige and attention. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Tompkins</ENAMEX>, who has made her disenchantment with conventional teaching and
scholarship the subject of both her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> and her writing, will teach one
course <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of education.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX> is
not the only academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> making a somewhat mysterious job switch.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philosopher Richard Rorty</ENAMEX> (whose work was the topic of "Out of
Left <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> ) has given up his chair at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Virginia</ENAMEX> (and a
salary that made him the highest-paid public employee in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>) in favor of
a nontenured post at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>, where he'll teach until he retires--or until a
better offer comes along. His reason: He wants to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearer</NUMEX> to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.

            
               Face
It
            

of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mainz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, believes she has figured out what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shakespeare</ENAMEX>
really looked like. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hildegard Hammerschmidt-Hummel</ENAMEX> believes the closest
likeness may be a death mask most other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> think is a fake.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerschmidt-Hummel</ENAMEX>, working with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> using advanced
photographic techniques, found close similarities between the mask and a famous
bust of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>, which she believes was copied from it. In particular, the
bust bears traces of "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> small swellings on the nasal corner of the left
eye"--swellings that are evident on the death mask as well. The mask also shows
a swelling in the upper left eyelid, which, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX>
Lerche, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horst-Schmidt</ENAMEX> eye <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wiesbaden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, could be
evidence of a rare form of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> that may have killed the bard. British
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> remain skeptical, both of the death mask's authenticity
and of the possibility of discovering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s true face.

            
               All
Politics Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Local</ENAMEX>
            

            Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX> video
controversy: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project on Media Ownership</ENAMEX>, under the direction of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">journalism</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Crispin Miller</ENAMEX>, recently completed a study of the
effects of local television news on the civic life of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PROMO</ENAMEX>'s report
claimed that local TV news foments fear and hostility among city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suburbanites</ENAMEX> alike by devoting a disproportionate share of its broadcast time
to crime. Such "inadvertent anti-urban propaganda" also hurts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>'s
reputation and economy.

            But the
nonprofit research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
Agenda, whose polls <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PROMO</ENAMEX> used for the report, has publicly disavowed it.
In its own press release, given to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Sun</ENAMEX> and posted on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s Web site,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Agenda</ENAMEX> charged that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PROMO</ENAMEX>'s report "while using data that are
technically correct, distorts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Agenda</ENAMEX>'s findings by presenting them in a
biased context and tone." In particular, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> charge that PROMO
downplayed the extent to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>' fear of crime was based on the
experience of crime--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53 percent</NUMEX> of those polled had said that they or someone
they loved had been the victim of a crime. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> stands by his conclusions and
insists that "anyone who reads my overview and their report will see that there
is absolutely no disagreement."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Girls</ENAMEX>!
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Girls</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Girls</ENAMEX>!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> has filed a lawsuit against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> of a soft porn Web site.
The site purported to display footage, picked up from an "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY University</ENAMEX> Dorm
Cam," of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> dressed in skimpy clothing bearing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX> insignia
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cavorting</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> decorated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX> paraphernalia. The site promises that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> will "romp for your enjoyment in their own dorm <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> to
the site have included journalistic bon vivant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Haden-Guest</ENAMEX>, who noted
in a recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk of the Town</ENAMEX>" piece for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> that among the
"humdrum vulgarities that have become the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> of the Internet,"
one can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> "a peek at some female <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who have wired up their dorm
room." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>'s suit refers to the rompers as "alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX> co-eds"
and assures all concerned that "there is no 'NYU <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dorm Cam</ENAMEX>' installed in any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX>
dorm <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>."

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Class System</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX>
at less prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> will soon be able to take <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> with
such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">luminaries</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Hawking</ENAMEX>, literary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">critic Terry Eagleton</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paleontologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dawkins</ENAMEX>, through a national
system of video linkups. The plan has drawn criticism on a number of fronts.
Some say it slights the teaching abilities and intellectual talents of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> who don't happen to be world famous but who do a perfectly good job
instructing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pupils</ENAMEX> at places such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bristol</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newcastle</ENAMEX>. Others point
out that world-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> don't always make the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and worry
that the videos will pacify the minds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> rather than stimulate them.
"It would be like watching television," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brunel University</ENAMEX> told
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times of London</ENAMEX>, which published a story about the proposal.
"You would lose that excitement of a live performance on a stage."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctor</ENAMEX>'s
Fees
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New Orleans</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> and best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Ambrose</ENAMEX> is credited as a consultant
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> epic <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saving Private Ryan</ENAMEX> . But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambrose</ENAMEX> did his consulting after the film was completed. According to a story
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> approached <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ambrose</ENAMEX> this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past spring</TIMEX> and arranged a screening for him. Once he'd seen the film--which he
loved--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambrose</ENAMEX> signed on for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $100,000</NUMEX>, a pittance by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
standards. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> speculates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>, who seems to have
borrowed heavily from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambrose</ENAMEX>'s books in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryan</ENAMEX> , was anxious to avoid
another lawsuit like the one that plagued his last movie, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> trade epic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amistad</ENAMEX> . (For more on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amistad</ENAMEX> flap, see this

                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheat Sheet</ENAMEX>" on plagiarism.)

         
      
   
