
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sweet Problem</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Success</ENAMEX>

             

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> made the budget
surplus Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> should spend it and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX>
said it should be given back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.J. Dionne</ENAMEX>'s proposal on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> that the surplus could engender a "substantive" political
debate about "what we want <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to do" was truncheoned by fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>. Surpluses always lead to talk of "tax cuts or higher spending,"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX>, with spending inevitably winning. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Broder</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press ) criticized the "element of fantasy" in the spend-it-or-give-it-back
discussion given the unfunded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> liabilities looming
early in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Biden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Del.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">seconded Broder</ENAMEX>: The surplus allows us to "set the system straight 30 years
out" with "no political costs" to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who resist the calls
for increased spending and tax cuts.

            "Isn't it
nice," said a radiant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Schieffer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> ), that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>'s biggest problem was how to handle the extraordinary good news of a
budget surplus? Not nice at all, said the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Thinkers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Beschloss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Kearns Goodwin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haynes Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Rosenblatt</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rodriguez</ENAMEX>). The Big Thinkers
found only the dark lining in our silver cloud. Future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> will judge
us, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beschloss</ENAMEX>, on how we used "this tranquil moment" to address our
problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodwin</ENAMEX> said that as long as the public's hunger for a national
purpose and community goes unfed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, they will turn to tabloid
tales--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death, the nanny case, the murder of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gianni Versace</ENAMEX>--for meaning
and civic involvement.

            Embracing this theme, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionne</ENAMEX> instructed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
to "stop all this public pondering" over his "legacy" and actually harness our
current good fortune to some glowing idea. But the liberal commentarians
themselves had little to offer in the way of imaginative suggestions, falling
back on the usual ideas about expanding the federal role in education,
rebuilding the infrastructure, and providing health care to the uninsured.
Meanwhile, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>--with an
eye on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> elections--are already celebrating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Golden Age</ENAMEX> with
tax cuts.

            A snarl of
other news issues vied for the No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> slot, but all failed to reach critical
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mass</ENAMEX> because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> failed to advance the debate (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> bailout of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> had nothing weighty to
say (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s rebuke of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> for failing to fill
federal judgeships; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan to extend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62-year-olds</TIMEX>), or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3</NUMEX>)
because a political talk show is an awkward venue for the discussion (the
"Unabomber" prosecution of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kaczynski</ENAMEX>; the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kennedy</ENAMEX>). With
the issue-generating machine of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> out of session, the commentariat
proved that it's as bad at the vision thing as it accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of being.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Punditus Interruptus</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week 3</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
Novak was a gentleman <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> , letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> finish
all his sentences without interruption. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> cut <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> off once, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> the
running score at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-2</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brinkley Returns</ENAMEX> to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> : As pitchman for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer Daniels</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Midland</ENAMEX>, the
government-subsidy swilling, political-talk-show sponsoring agribiz <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" is
sufficiently cynical about TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> that the transformation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them
into a corporate shill should set off no alarms. But it does, perhaps because
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four decades</TIMEX> of sanctimonious droning by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brinkley</ENAMEX> as a network news anchor and
then as the founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundit</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> created the illusion that he
was a principled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who couldn't be bought by a price-fixing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ADM commercial unspooled on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> , he spoke obliquely about having accepted a new position, deliberately
fostering the notion that he was returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> as some sort of superpundit.
Then he explained that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming weeks</TIMEX> he'd be talking about nutrition and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agriculture</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADM. Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s appearance as a pitchman in the
middle of his old program was so disconcerting that when <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX>
resumed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> attempted to salvage the show's good name by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reiterating Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s disclaimer. The move backfired, unintentionally
reminding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> that the big difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADM</ENAMEX> is
just a couple of letters farther down the alphabet.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
