
   
   
      
         
            Just Say Yes

            
               Hair Dryer/Never
Easy , produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merkley Newman Harty</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC TV</ENAMEX>'s public-service
announcements.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC Television</ENAMEX>'s anti-drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">crusade--March Against Drugs</ENAMEX>--has already been attacked in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> as bogus propagandizing. Whatever the merits of the
campaign, which includes public-service announcements and "drug-education"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plugs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>'s dramas and sitcoms, this piece of advertising works.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hair Dryer</ENAMEX> , the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of this spot, uses a combination of laconism
and high production values to appeal to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Never
Easy , the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, reverses field and feel with a talking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> who, while
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost didactic</TIMEX> in her delivery of a simple message and a not-so-subtle push
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> itself, is young enough, earnest enough, to strike a chord across her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.

            Cobbling multiple cuts of
film into a snappy collage, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first 13 seconds</TIMEX> seem to prepare you for a
hair-care pitch, not a drug advisory. But pace and contrast set up a complex
visual message before the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> words are ever spoken. First the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair dryer</ENAMEX>,
then the clutter of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">dryer</TIMEX> blasting at a flipped
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of hair, then a mirrored glimpse of a soulful pout. A full-length view of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, shot from behind in sharply faded color, then a less clearly
articulated close-up of her face. And then the eyes, lidded, strangely knowing,
lingering in the mirror.

            There is a disquieting
dialogue at work here, the play of color capturing the tensions of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chrysalis</ENAMEX>. Vibrant hues for prelapsarian innocence; bleached tones for the
budding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>. A switch to full color accompanies the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> words, spoken in a
childlike voice-over: "It might not be easy to talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> today ...
especially about marijuana." As the words begin, the colors fade, drawing you
toward the obvious "it's hard to talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> today because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are no longer
just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>" theme. But a fillip of clichés--the braces under the smile, the
self-conscious glance downward--brings the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> back for the moment. The spot
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quickens</ENAMEX>--she's almost done with the dryer ... she's almost outta here.

            The spot briefly reprises
the faded hues--the blond hair flashing gray, the lighting evoking a street
corner for a moment--before focusing on ringed fingers and thumb turning the
dryer off. The thumb ring, even more than the earrings that have been there all
along, taps fertile ground, its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> with rebellion and the
unwillingness to conform inevitable. From thumb rings to smoke rings wouldn't
be a long step, some would say--and the statistics show that for an increasing
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>, the smoke is coming from marijuana. But this one hasn't taken
that step--yet. She's standing stock-still for now, the voice that acknowledged
how difficult it was for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to talk marijuana with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> now asking,
Camus-like: "But if you don't do it, who will?"

            This is the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> and
the most persuasive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX>: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> want and
need to hear from them. As the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the spot ends, we notice the
disclaimer crediting it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnership</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug-Free America</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>--actually the last <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven seconds</TIMEX>--takes a radically different, entirely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">linear</ENAMEX> approach, using a talking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Hospital</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amber Tamblyn</ENAMEX>,
who plays the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost</NUMEX>-but-not-quite-redoubtable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Bowen</ENAMEX> (whose drug
abuse--yes, indeed--"sparked shocking and tragic consequences" on GH
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>). Tamblyn reiterates that marijuana is a sticky wicket, then suggests
a way out--almost as a matter of course: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tune</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 30</TIMEX>, and "we'll
help." Research shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> today want that help, that they lack the
language to bridge the generation gap and persuade their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> not to do as
they did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s and '70s</TIMEX>. That's why this spot will probably succeed in
its effort to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> tune in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 30</TIMEX>.

            The other message, of
course, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> is au courant with the role of family values in
politics <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, and that it cares enough to turn over prime time to the
anti-drug campaign. It has been estimated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> could lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $1.7</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> revenue just by running <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-second</TIMEX> public-service spot in
lieu of its paid commercial equivalent during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>'s highest-priced hour
of time (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX>). The ratings-pandering and
suspension-of-skepticism charges notwithstanding, the public is likely to give
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> some credit.

            The
contrast between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts of the ad shows why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are paid so much to
be creative--the talking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> wouldn't have done quite as well opening the act.
The spot closes with a chyron urging parental action: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silence</ENAMEX> is acceptance."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ennui</ENAMEX> is exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> complain about: They say the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'90s</NUMEX> have seen a
steep drop in the time and space donated to anti-drug messages, from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$365</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$260 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX>'s much derided "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Say No</ENAMEX>"
seems to have had an effect on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> it targeted--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use actually went
down. This time, it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who are being told they can make a
difference. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gauntlet</ENAMEX>'s down, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>: Just Say Yes.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
