
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> Crosscurrents

             

            The victory of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> presidential election suggests the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
revolutionary zeal has been tempered. While little change is likely to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s
political structure or foreign policy, a more moderate line in social policy
may emerge. In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunni Muslim Taliban</ENAMEX> is still in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revolutionary</ENAMEX> phase of development. Currently, its advance is generating the
greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> in the ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Asia</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> may
yet resonate more strongly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>. The net effect of
these contrasting trends on the attainment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> objectives across the region
is not likely to be positive. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> may come to regret its reported
support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>. And while a more moderate social policy may
emerge in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s resistance to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military presence in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> is unlikely to soften.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s
May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> election, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 70 percent</NUMEX> of votes cast, putting him
far ahead of his main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Akbar Nategh-Nuri</ENAMEX>. The result was a surprise, since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nategh</ENAMEX>-Nuri
enjoys the tacit support of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayatollah Sayyed Ali</ENAMEX>
Khamenei, and was viewed as the clerical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX>'s huge mandate is a clear sign of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">electorate</ENAMEX>'s desire for change and may become a significant landmark in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s history. Offered a clear choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> and policies for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1979 revolution</ENAMEX>, an overwhelming majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX>
voted to overturn the social and cultural restrictions that have become
synonymous with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>'s revolutionary zeal.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX>'s
reputation for supporting liberal policies during his tenure as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> for
culture and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> guidance was combined with a populist campaign message
stressing the importance of civil society, individual rights, a wider role for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and greater freedom of expression. This allowed him to appeal to a broad
range of constituencies that have eschewed electoral participation since the
revolution. In addition to the support of left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX>
received the overwhelming backing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intelligentsia</ENAMEX>, the urban middle
class, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female</ENAMEX> and younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>.

            
Nevertheless, and despite his reputation as a
moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ayatollah</ENAMEX>, remains a product of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shiite Muslim</ENAMEX> clerical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>. He has emphasized his commitment to the
principles of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>, and will do nothing to fundamentally alter
the existing political system. Moreover, moves to introduce radical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX>-reform legislation may <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>, where there is a
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>.

            
Ultimately, the extent of any shift in domestic policy will depend on the
position adopted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khamenei</ENAMEX>. If the spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> views the election result
as a threat to his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>, he could side with hard-line <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamists</ENAMEX> to
thwart reform initiatives. However, given the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX>'s mandate,
Khamenei may conclude that the desire for easing social and cultural
restrictions is compelling enough, and opt to assist the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in
overcoming conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>.

            Similar transformations in foreign policy, particularly
toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, are far less likely. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX>'s statements reflect a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> that foreign policy remains the domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khamenei</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ayatollah</ENAMEX>
has been dogmatic in opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s policies in the region, particularly
"dual containment," which he views as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victimization</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> is particularly unlikely to moderate its opposition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
military presence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>, which it perceives as detrimental to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX>.

            Both sides
believe that the other must make the first conciliatory move. There is debate
within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign-policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> regarding the efficacy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s approach, which is based on the perception of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> as a rogue
state and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> of international terror. However, social reform in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>
will not by itself be enough to facilitate a dramatic shift in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy.

            
Set against the evidence of moderation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>'s advance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> has generated alarm, particularly among
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Central Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, who fear the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
fundamentalism northward. Since most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Central Asians</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sunni</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, the
Taliban potentially may be a more inspiring model for local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
revolutionaries than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shiah Iran</ENAMEX>. However, while there is a real danger that the
fighting could destabilize <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Asia</ENAMEX>'s southern flank, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>'s
restricted ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">base</ENAMEX> may limit its attractiveness. In contrast, this may not
be the case in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunni</ENAMEX>-dominated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamabad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Riyadh</ENAMEX>
and, by extension, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> may yet come to regret their reported support for
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunni</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> that apparently now exceeds <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shiah Iran</ENAMEX> in its fundamentalist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">zeal</ENAMEX> and potential appeal to discontented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunni</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>.

            Although
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> operates autonomously, its advance would not have been possible
without foreign backing. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> has been the key <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>--both keen to stem <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> influence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX>--also
are believed to have supplied finance. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have an interest in
stabilizing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> sufficiently to construct oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pipelines</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, as an alternative route to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> is both a product of and a reaction to the
civil war that has gripped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> since the demise of the Soviet-backed
regime in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> developed out of refugee <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Koranic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> declared a holy war against the various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warlords</ENAMEX> who
carved up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, and preached the role of strict <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> rules as a
unifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. This simple message found a ready <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> among the largely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taliban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">southerners</ENAMEX> are ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pashtun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sunni</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> who, though accounting for the
majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, had not fared well in the civil war.

            The
Taliban captured the southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kandahar</ENAMEX>--where its reclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mullah Mohammed Omar</ENAMEX>, resides--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1994</TIMEX> and the capital, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kabul</ENAMEX>, last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>. In all conquered regions, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> has immediately implemented
its own interpretation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> law. Among other things, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are barred
from work and most education, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> may not trim their compulsory beards. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern</ENAMEX> rural areas, such strictures have been accepted, especially as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> has provided a stable environment for the cultivation of poppies.
Domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use is severely punished, but <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> production for export is
permitted.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> rule has not been popular with
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pashtun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> or the more sophisticated, liberal-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of
the major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kabul</ENAMEX>. This is unlikely to change. The recent
heavy defeat of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> in the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mazar-e-Sharif</ENAMEX> highlights
both its failure to incorporate ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tajiks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uzbeks</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shiah Hazaras</ENAMEX> into
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, and its refusal to moderate its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> zeal. Even if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taliban</ENAMEX> succeeds in conquering the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, many areas will remain
subject to guerrilla warfare.

         
      
   
