
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>'s

             

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUNDIT CENTRAL</ENAMEX>" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits inflate Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Clintonism</ENAMEX> to Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Previously, protestations that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was
getting a bum rap were aimed at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>, right-wing money, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>. But the friction between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> and, well, just about everybody is
now discussed as a Very <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serious Issue</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s continued offensive against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.

            Everyone
agrees that further revelations about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> tapes, coupled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s
admission that he's out to get the "scumbag" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, have tainted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s
investigation. "This is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX> imploded," announces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ). What's more, absent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s
stupidity, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> tapes would have been a slam-dunk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> victory, leading
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX> to charge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> with "political malpractice."

            The commentariat enjoys swapping stories about the extent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burton</ENAMEX>'s lunacy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) hears that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> wear latex gloves while opening mail, for prophylaxis against
left-wingers sending condoms to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have always known <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> is a genuine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nutter</ENAMEX>--remember that stunt with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> and the watermelon?--and therefore
the blame must rest on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s shoulders. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> needs to shut <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burton</ENAMEX> up
and make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magisterial</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, the face of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> investigation,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">advises David Gergen</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gang</ENAMEX> ) reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> was nearly sent packing by a panicked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>,
who was placated when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bossie</ENAMEX>, a top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>.

            The
conventional explanation for the newly aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>--he has publicly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supported Burton</ENAMEX> and advises <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> to speak of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "crimes"
rather than of charges--is that he is shoring up support in his political base,
the extreme right wing. This may be sound politics, argues <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> ), because midterm elections are often decided by political
bases. So are presidential primaries, notes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ). On the other hand, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ), "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> is the best fund-raiser the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have ever
had."

            
Has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> tainted himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">à la Burton</ENAMEX>? Almost
certainly, answers <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>. He undoubtedly treads on "delicate
political <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>," euphemizes the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gigot</ENAMEX>.

            Bibi
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s unwillingness to attend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, negotiations
leads some to blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX> and others to blame <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stubbornness</ENAMEX>. However, most discussion of the issue <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s publicly revealed support for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX> accuses her
of "practicing foreign policy without a license." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> ( This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ) spins the most elaborate explanation: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has lost
support in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> after the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> standoff, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>'s
intentional gaffe is an unofficial way of placating <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> at the expense
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.

            

               P.S.--<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Won't Be Attending Your Funeral</ENAMEX>,
Either: During a rambling discussion of oncology and longevity on This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> shares the happy fact that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has a centenarian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandmother</ENAMEX> who lived past <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> too. "Having [good]
genes is still the way to go!" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grins Kristol</ENAMEX>. "We'll enjoy meeting her second
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>," mutters <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX>.

            
               Spin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heal Thyself: On Meet the Press</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>
jeers that "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is] trying to do a job in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>--too bad his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> doesn't
agree with him." An unremarkable snipe coming from a noted anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clintonite</ENAMEX>,
except that this particular snipe comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Matalin</ENAMEX>, who spent a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter-hour this Sunday</TIMEX> sneering at every point offered by her fellow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">panelist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX>. Sample sneer: After admitting that her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hubby</ENAMEX>'s strategizing may have kept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from being ridden out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> on a
rail, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matalin</ENAMEX> predicts that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Someday</ENAMEX>, in the history book, you [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Carville</ENAMEX>] will
look back and rue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> that you helped wage this war the way you have."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Speak Into the Ear Horn, Boy</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>, on
the ropes after a particularly tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Snow</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> )
question, retreats with the most transparent wiggle of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>. "Beg your
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">pardon?</ENAMEX>" asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>, cupping his ear. Again the question is asked, again
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> feigns deafness: "I ... I ... I'm sorry. I can't hear you." An amused
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow lobs Burton</ENAMEX> a few softballs--What do you think about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>? Who does your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcribing</ENAMEX>?--which cures <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s temporary deafness.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiggle No. 2</ENAMEX>: The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> most transparent wiggle of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Conyers Jr.</ENAMEX>,
D-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>, who appears to defend his request that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>
investigate collusion between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> favorite bogeymen: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conyers</ENAMEX> have any evidence that could provide
cause for investigation, wonders <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ). Well, no,
that's actually what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> is supposed to investigate.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
