
   
   
      
         
            It's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr Time</ENAMEX>

             

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUNDIT CENTRAL</ENAMEX>" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>--the unexpected
dismissal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' lawsuit--cleaves the commentariat along ideological
lines. Left-leaning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> join the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in breaking out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohibas</ENAMEX> and
bongos, while right-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaners</ENAMEX> maintain that "it ain't over till <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> sings"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ). Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' work on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s business, which receives relatively little attention.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'
fall has damaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, maintain most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and centrists. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-Paula</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
will find the political world a harsher place, predict <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Germond</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ),
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gergen</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> must deliver a
"blockbuster" wad of evidence to make a splash, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ). With the Jones matter resolved, the public and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX>
will lean on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to finish his work pdq, say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX>
( The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ).

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> operates in a legal world, maintain the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, where facts are facts and polls matter little, if at all--the
federal case will stand or fall based upon the evidence <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> uncovers. In a
legal sense, the Jones proceeding is an apple to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s orange, claims <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krauthammer</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> point out--sometimes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ominously</ENAMEX>, sometimes dismissively--that no one has seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s cards: They may
show "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lizzie Borden</ENAMEX> in drag" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> proclaim their confidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> holds enough to undo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s presidency (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor</ENAMEX> wrote as much this week
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Journal</ENAMEX> and appears on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> to reprise the
point. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>'s article is referred to in reverential tones <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all weekend</TIMEX>.

            The Jones
dismissal directs the scandal's focus away from sex and toward allegations of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cover-up</ENAMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> note. That is bad news for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krauthammer</ENAMEX>. No, it isn't, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clift</ENAMEX>, who doesn't think <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are overly
upset by sex-related cover-ups.

            
The suggestion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> may indict <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> an unindicted co-conspirator is a sure public
relations disaster (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clift</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) calls such a
trial an excellent chance to play the heretofore-sealed tapes in public.

            How
should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> play his hand? Hold a press conference to answer all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
questions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, thereby ending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circus</ENAMEX> immediately, advises
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>. He also admits a "zero <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> chance" of this happening. The
public isn't calling for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> explanation, reports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX>, and therefore
won't get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Don't rock the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>, agrees <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>--Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>--draw fire from all
sides. The transportation bill is porky, the squashing of the campaign finance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> was a dastardly use of procedural rules, the tobacco settlement may go
through, but only because everyone wants to get their paws on the proceeds. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> wish the impeachment hearings would just go away,
particularly because the lunatic fringe of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is howling for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, which will play poorly for the cameras.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Mom,</ENAMEX>
Can <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Grandpa Say That on TV</ENAMEX>? Presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Ambrose</ENAMEX> begins
his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> appearance by inveighing against evening newscasts too
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">smutty</ENAMEX> to watch with his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">granddaughter</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambrose</ENAMEX>--in the very next
sentence!--goes on to discuss his theory that "God created <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a penis and
a brain and gave them only enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> to run one at a time. And that's why we
used to have dormitories that separated the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, and we had
chaperones at the dances."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blaxsploitation</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gang ster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> contended that black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' post-bellum
achievements represent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> trade's oft-overlooked silver lining. This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, he apologizes for offending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, pronounces slavery an "unmitigated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evil</ENAMEX>," and claims to have meant only that "our society was enriched by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">African-Americans</ENAMEX>." Here is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX>'s original quotation from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gang</ENAMEX> :

            He brought along this
whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> full of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>, and some of our really fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, in business, in athletics, in show business.
You know how they got here? They were all slaves, weren't they? So it's kind of
a problem. We wouldn't have this enrichment of our society if it wasn't for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slavery</ENAMEX>.

            And
here's an almost identical Novak comment on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 27</TIMEX> edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Crossfire :</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> makes these
amends for slavery and then he says how wonderful the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> who
accompanied him are. If it hadn't been for slavery, they wouldn't even be in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, would they? That's kind of a problem, isn't it?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX>'s own apology is, no
doubt, unrelated to a letter-writing campaign to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times</ENAMEX> --mounted by the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
