
   
   
      
         
            

            Compiled by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of Lingua 
               Franca
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>)
            

            
               Holy
War
            

            A group of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> known as "biblical minimalists" is claiming that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Book</ENAMEX> is
thoroughly worthless as a historical document, and that all future efforts to
reconstruct the early history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> must rely strictly on archaeology. In a
recent discussion of the subject in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible Review</ENAMEX> , leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scholar Philip Davies</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying that "the figure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> as real as [that of] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>," and minimalists point out that the
archaeological evidence for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>'s existence amounts to a solitary reference
to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">House of David</ENAMEX>" on a victory monument at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tel Dan</ENAMEX>. Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Merling</ENAMEX> says that "only those who are friendly to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biblical</ENAMEX> story would actually believe in an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exodus event</ENAMEX>." Discarding the
biblical narrative, minimalists reinterpret the flight from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
as a variety of indigenous peasant revolt in which fed-up Canaanite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>
wrested their land from feudal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lords</ENAMEX>. Traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> respond that, while
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> may have a shaky sense of chronology, to dismiss the text entirely is
irresponsible.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deconstructing Martha</ENAMEX>
            

            Cultural
studies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> are assembling an anthology tentatively titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Martha</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart Collection</ENAMEX> that will analyze the "image and rhetoric" of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homemaker</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobart</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Smith Colleges Professors</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Robertson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi Dean</ENAMEX> have circulated a prospectus for the project on
the Internet. Hoping to inspire submissions, they note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> "offers a
simulacrum of warmth in a house devoid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>; she represents the instinct
of workmanship to a population long divorced from it." With a nod to another
leading icon of cultural studies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX> suggest that "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> refers
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Child</ENAMEX>'s cooking, naming her expertise, but to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>--as with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>--image is the product."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kiss</ENAMEX> and
Make Up
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Kiss</ENAMEX>, a memoir of her incestuous relationship with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>,
has been given a glowing review in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of the American Medical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> . The review, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hodo</ENAMEX>, praises the book as
"exquisite" and "highly recommended to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>." Discussing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">harrowing</ENAMEX> encounters with uncomprehending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>--such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">broke Harrison</ENAMEX>'s hymen in front of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hodo</ENAMEX> concludes that "there is
not much help for a troubled young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> with a fearful secret if a medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> fails to be personal, complex, creative, [and] sophisticated." In a
somewhat mysterious allusion, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hodo</ENAMEX> also compares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX>'s "pilgrimage" to
that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dilsey</ENAMEX>, the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sound and the Fury</ENAMEX> ; perhaps he
meant to refer to incest-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caddy</ENAMEX>.

            
               How the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Snake Lost Its Legs</ENAMEX>
            

            A
hitherto unnoticed fossil in an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> is being heralded as the answer
to this evolutionary mystery. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lee</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Caldwell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Field Museum</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100-million</NUMEX>-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fossil</ENAMEX>, christened <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pachyrachis</ENAMEX> problematicus ("problematic thick-ribbed
animal") in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX>, is a proto-snake with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> legs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long</ENAMEX> ignored by
snake <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, the skeleton shares many physical characteristics with that of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX>, including its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">140</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vertebrae</ENAMEX> and its extraordinarily flexible jaws.
Noting the fossil's eel-like tail and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">aquatic</ENAMEX> attributes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caldwell</ENAMEX> suggest that these proto-snakes retreated into the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, shed their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">legs</ENAMEX>, then slithered back out.

            
               Mostly
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Mozart</ENAMEX>
            

have created a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> nd <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX> symphony. Cope broke down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">41 symphonies</TIMEX> into reusable parts, then blended them together in his computer
into a convincing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pastiche</ENAMEX>. "There's no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in the world who could, without
knowing its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, say for certain that [the piece] is not [by] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX>," Cope
boasted to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Scientist</ENAMEX> . Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cope</ENAMEX> grants that his
artificial intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">algorithms</ENAMEX> may not produce masterpieces, he promises
the result is at least "better than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salieri</ENAMEX>." (The computer is currently
composing a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahler</ENAMEX> symphony: "I'm so tired of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> symphonies," Cope
said. "God, it would be great to hear a new one.") Music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> complain about
the computer's tin ear, but artificial intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> are impressed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Hofstadter</ENAMEX>, an amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist</ENAMEX>, recently played
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cope</ENAMEX>'s fake <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chopin</ENAMEX> mazurkas, and told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientist</ENAMEX> he was
"stunned" by its seeming authenticity. Click here to listen to one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cope</ENAMEX>'s imitation Chopin
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mazurkas</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economics 2001</ENAMEX>
            

            After
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 50 years</TIMEX>, a new economics textbook is challenging the supremacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samuelson's Economics</ENAMEX> . Written by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">N. Gregory Mankiw</ENAMEX>, the book,
Principles of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics</ENAMEX>, received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 million</NUMEX> advance from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harcourt Brace</ENAMEX> imprint
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dryden Press</ENAMEX>. Whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samuelson</ENAMEX>'s text, now in its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 th</NUMEX> edition,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">staunchly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> Keynesian prescriptions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mankiw's</ENAMEX> is touted as
post-ideological, pitting rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of thought against each other. Mankiw
also updates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samuelson</ENAMEX>'s chatty tone--the putative source of his longstanding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>--with such pop references as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX>'s seemingly
excessive compensation and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mia Farrow</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,900</NUMEX> rent-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
apartment. In a typical example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mankiw</ENAMEX> illustrates the law of comparative
advantage by way of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawn mowing</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> can probably mow
his lawn faster than anyone else," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mankiw</ENAMEX> writes. "But just because he can mow
his lawn fast, does this mean he should?"

         
      
   
