
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil</ENAMEX> and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>

             

            Questions about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s sex life won Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> nods on all the shows. If not for the return
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> to the news, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spacefaring</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Glenn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newsmaking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX>
would have given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> the feel of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> administration
retrospective.

            Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> swarmed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, struggling in vain to make their case
despite a judicial gag order. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX> is "upbeat" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX>
With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cokie</ENAMEX> ) and "the rule of law is alive and well" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> ). With the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> falling silent (a deliberate
strategy, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ), the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>
made the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>: She has become a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">pitiful pawn"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) of the wacko right, who are "making <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) and "diminishing the presidency" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) by dredging up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s dirty laundry.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> predicted that this episode, too, would
roll off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s back (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ), as the president
is now "beyond humiliation" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX>, Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ).
The smart money insisted that the case would end with a trial and not in a
settlement. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) referred to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>'s
unsubstantiated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> spiked a story about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> having an affair with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> intern, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX>
barked at him. Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> killed the story because they didn't have
the goods, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX> bellowed.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commentariat</ENAMEX> returned once more to Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> crisis, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> ), comparing the situation to "the movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groundhog Day</ENAMEX> : We wake up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every morning</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> is sticking his thumb
in our eye." After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of playing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">devil</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) finally threw in completely with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>, endorsing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Ritter</ENAMEX>, the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX>,
is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> "spy" whose placement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> was a "calculated and deliberate
Press ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Richardson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> ) promised to answer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s intransigence with more
international peacemaking attempts, a policy condemned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krauthammer</ENAMEX> as "the
wages of appeasement." Also working the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neville Chamberlain</ENAMEX> angle was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>, who
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> had "the scruples of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>."

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> was a tie: the soon-to-orbit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Glenn</ENAMEX> or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">papal</ENAMEX> visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> were generally enthusiastic about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX>'s
rocket ride--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> gushed that it would "change the outlook on who is
old"--although the cynics deemed the trip an "interplanetary perk for a favored
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">politician"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ) worked the issue for the gag: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Send Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX> instead, to
determine "the effect of weightlessness on orange <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On This Week</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX> uncorked an old joke of his own: "How would you feel if you were sitting
on top of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 million</NUMEX> parts built by the lowest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX> on a government
contract?") The commentariat was divided as to whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s visit
presaged the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX> or of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' "inane embargo"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ). Most agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s courting
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> vote would prohibit any change in our current policy.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost in the Shuffle: Thanks to the</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s busy news cycle, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> gave the new developments in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
financial crises a wide berth--not much of a loss, seeing as most of them are
completely at sea about it anyway.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Punditus Interruptus</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week 5</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Has Robert Novak</ENAMEX> lost his nerve? He didn't
even bluff interruption in all his bantering with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>'s edition
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> . (Maybe he was calmed by the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX>.) After repeated viewings of the tape, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" referees
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">charged Hunt</ENAMEX> with one verbal offside, bringing the running interruption total
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunt</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> 2.

            

               Goodnight, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>: After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two weeks</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s controversial <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer Daniels Midland</ENAMEX> ads have been pulled from
the broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> will continue to show them). An outraged Brinkley
told The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> that everyone's acting "like I robbed a bank
or something." A relieved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie</ENAMEX> made no mention of his
disappearance.

            
               How <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About Condoms as</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pledge-Week Premiums</ENAMEX>? Treading delicately around the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case, the
commentariat giggled like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX> over a recent poll proclaiming that
public television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> have more sex than most. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX> blamed
it on "all those nature shows."

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murphy</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
