
   
   
      
         
            

            
               White Is
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Color Too</ENAMEX>
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">front-page</ENAMEX> article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> certified that
"whiteness studies" has arrived. The burgeoning academic field--informed by
both thoughtful race theory and liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Caucasian</ENAMEX> guilt--has already spawned
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of acolytes; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 70</NUMEX> books (according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for the Study</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White American Culture Inc.</ENAMEX>'s Web site); subspecialties such as white trash, suburban
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">resentment</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall ethnography</ENAMEX>; and a national conference, held at the
objectives is exposing the privileges that come with being white in order to
make them go away. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">minnesota review</ENAMEX> 's current issue is titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
Issue." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This fall</TIMEX>, Transition , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> of global
culture, will publish its own white issue, in which nonwhite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> will
weigh in on whiteness.

            
               Science
Wars, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sequel</ENAMEX>
            

            For the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>, the prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute for Advanced Study</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX> has vetoed the appointment of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of science studies with,
apparently, impeccable credentials. Despite the unanimous support of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institute</ENAMEX>'s tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Social Science</ENAMEX> and a search <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s favorable
vote, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> ruled against the appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX>
University <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Norton Wise</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX> of a prize-winning book on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX> thermodynamics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> Lord <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelvin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute defenders</ENAMEX>
say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wise</ENAMEX>'s scholarship was not up to snuff. Others (including
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anthropologist Clifford Geertz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Scott</ENAMEX>) accuse their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in chemistry and physics of harboring a bias against anyone who
questions science's claims to truth. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX> closed its doors to
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruno Latour</ENAMEX>, who made declarations such as the
following: "To call a claim 'absurd' or knowledge 'accurate' has no more
meaning than to call a smuggler trail 'illogical' and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeway 'logical</ENAMEX>.' "
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wise</ENAMEX>, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latour</ENAMEX>, has a Ph.D. in physics, and was perceived as a moderate in
the bitter debates that ensued after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Sokal</ENAMEX> affair <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>.
However, he may have damaged his cause when he criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sokal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinberg</ENAMEX> in a letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> .

            
               This
Side Up
            

            
Astronomers have long assumed that the universe is directionally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indiscriminate</ENAMEX>--that is, that it has no top, bottom, up, or down. But in a
paper published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physical Review Letters</ENAMEX> (click here for an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abstract</ENAMEX>) and immediately picked up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">physicists</ENAMEX> reported that polarized light moves through <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> according to a
predictable but previously undetected corkscrew pattern. This means, they
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inferred</ENAMEX>, that light flows through the universe in one direction, along an
identifiable axis of orientation. (Which end we want to call "up" is up to us.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ralston</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Kansas</ENAMEX> and Dr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borge Nodland</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Rochester</ENAMEX> made this discovery by
analyzing radio waves from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">160</NUMEX> faraway galaxies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are combing through
the data for errors. The findings could have more than just topographical
implications. Questions they raise include: Was the Big Bang not a uniform
explosion after all? Is the speed of light not always constant?

            
               Still
Empty
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
remains unable to choose a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> to fill a new chair in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>
studies, and has deferred a decision until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 1998</TIMEX>. The chair was
foisted on reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> eager to please wealthy donor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Lipper</ENAMEX> (a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and, more recently, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> of the screenplay of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Hall</ENAMEX> ). It took the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>-studies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> on the search <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> a year and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> to come up
with a job description. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> proposed a temporary
solution--hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Friedlander</ENAMEX>, a distinguished elder statesman in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lipper</ENAMEX> said no. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are publicly
feuding: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Browning</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Jonah Goldhagen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> whose work
has focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> and not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> is a junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> and, reportedly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lipper</ENAMEX>'s choice for the chair. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s
book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willing Executioners</ENAMEX>, which imputes homicidal
anti-Semitic impulses to most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, has earned
him notoriety and worldwide speaking engagements but not, as yet, tenure.

            
               Penrose
Pattern
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematician</ENAMEX> Sir
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Penrose</ENAMEX>, best known for his contributions to the theory of consciousness,
has turned his attention to toilet paper. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">don</ENAMEX> noticed that the pattern on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kleenex</ENAMEX> quilted tissue uncannily resembled the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penrose Arrowed Rhombi</ENAMEX> tilings pattern, which Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX> had invented--and
copyrighted--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penrose</ENAMEX> licensed the pattern to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentaplex Ltd.</ENAMEX>, which
manufactures puzzles and games, and now both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are suing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kimberly-Clark</ENAMEX>,
the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kleenex</ENAMEX>, for copyright infringement. The plaintiffs
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">claim Penrose</ENAMEX>'s design is distinguished by its aperiodicity (the pattern almost
but never quite repeats itself) and its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-fold symmetry (a trait that at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> was thought not to exist in nature but has since been identified in
certain crystal formations). As the London 
               Independent put it,
"This non-repeating aperiodic pattern was no trivial solution to relieving the
boredom of tiling the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom floor</ENAMEX>, nor some mathematical doodle. It was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mind-boggling</ENAMEX>, preconception-shattering illustration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-fold symmetry,
'non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">computability</ENAMEX>' and, quite possibly, the meaning of life."

            

               --Compiled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lingua Franca</ENAMEX> , the review of academic
life. Click here to
visit their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> or to subscribe.
            

             

         
      
   
