
   
   
      
         
            We <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love a Man in Uniform</ENAMEX>

            
               Bio , produced by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Laguens and Hamburger for Harmon</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX>.

            Just when you thought it was
safe to turn on your television, the political spots are back. No matter that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s
chair--odd-numbered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> like this one bring what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campaigners</ENAMEX> call "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">off-year</TIMEX>
elections," the gubernatorial campaigns in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and mayoral
races in big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.

            
               Bio , produced for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX> mayoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Harmon</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn Laguens</ENAMEX>, presents something of an
anomaly: an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American Democrat</ENAMEX> running to the right. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Harmon</ENAMEX>, faces another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American Democrat</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> is forbidden ground for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harmon</ENAMEX>-Bosley
rivalry is not new: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harmon</ENAMEX> was the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosley</ENAMEX> until he quit in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, claiming political interference from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            The spot is crafted to reach
more conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> by building on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harmon</ENAMEX>'s image as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who's tough on
crime. Both image and issue also resonate in the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, whose
neighborhoods have been hit the hardest by crime. The ad opens like a
traditional biography. "As a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>," the narrator reassures us, "he worked
to help support his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>." The language is precisely calibrated, giving no
details about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s labors. The accompanying photograph reinforces the
squeaky-clean image--the picture might have been the only one available, or one
of a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handful</ENAMEX>, but it strikes a note that will carry through the spot:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harmon</ENAMEX> is always well-dressed, and he is always smiling.

            The next scene is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photograph of Harmon</ENAMEX> as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>, conveying both the passage of years
and steadiness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. The hard-working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> has become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who does the
tough jobs, but the smile endures. Again, the language is careful, precise;
again, it says little: "When duty called, he stepped forward." The words echo
that famous line from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inaugural Address</ENAMEX> and evoke an image of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stalwart soldier</ENAMEX> answering the clarion call to battle. Did Harmon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">volunteer</ENAMEX>, or was he drafted?

            The spot then puts <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Harmon</ENAMEX> in
a new uniform, this time the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>'s. Unfolding headlines reiterate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harmon</ENAMEX>'s public service. "A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chief Who Welcomes Change"</ENAMEX>--you can bet that
polling results show the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want change, as usual. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Black</ENAMEX> to Lead
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX>," the only racial reference, attempts to touch black pride while still
appealing across racial lines. And finally, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Super-Chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Harmon</ENAMEX>," a
much stronger fillip than a conventional bio spot's recitation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s achievements.

            The spot then moves to the
present--and the problem: a shot of an abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Louis Arch</ENAMEX> in
the background and a chyron proclaiming, "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> cries out for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>."
Overworked language, no doubt, but effective shorthand that communicates how
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> has been stripped of its vitality as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> have moved
to the suburbs. Continuous narration ("once again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Harmon</ENAMEX> answers the
call") implies that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harmon</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> needs, as the camera captures
him shaking hands with a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harmon</ENAMEX> is in a coat and tie here,
we keep seeing him as he was and as he's really running--as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in uniform
who was ousted by the system and has now stepped up to the plate, yet again.
Whether or not he can "solve problems" as the chyron suggests he will, and
despite the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio</ENAMEX> is mute on his plans, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and cops who
surround him in these scenes provide visual endorsements, suggesting that he
stands for progress.

            The chyron announcing that
he will "stop corruption" appears over a scene apparently set in a district
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. This may be fertile ground, and taps a background of
accusations (against the incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, against the circuit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX>)
and intrigue (about a mysterious murder, and about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> himself being
barred for life from federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> after allegedly defaulting on an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> loan). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harmon</ENAMEX> is running by default as the anti-corruption
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>.

            The last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> scenes carry
the same message: "Help our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to be great again." What does "great" imply
here? The spot hopes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> will fill in the blanks with "old-fashioned
values," "law and order," "economic growth," and "cleaning up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>," all
of which the spot has claimed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harmon</ENAMEX> stands for. And who constitutes the "our"
in "our city"? The visuals first focus on elderly white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and then cut
across racial lines to a mixed group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, an appeal for change, a break
from the past.

            The pileup of clichés ends
with a safe "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Harmon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX>." Nothing strident, nothing to disapprove
of.

            Nothing
to pop the corks over, either.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
