
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Yoknapatawpha TV
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centennial</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Faulkner</ENAMEX>'s birth and the Web release of some of
his lost hack work. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate student</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Illinois</ENAMEX> at
Springfield stumbled upon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> teleplays by the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> Prize-winning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>'s only known forays into the genre--while researching his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">master</ENAMEX>'s thesis, Yoknapatawpha 
               TV , at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University</ENAMEX> archive.
The teleplays, adaptations of undistinguished short stories by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>,
aired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953 and 1954</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lux Video Theatre</ENAMEX> , a dramatic series sponsored
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Lux soap</ENAMEX>. To appease <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">censors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX> eliminated a suicide
from The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooch</ENAMEX> , and to update the appeal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shall</ENAMEX> Not
Perish , he changed the setting from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean War</ENAMEX>. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> pages of both teleplays are available on the Web but, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & Observer</ENAMEX> remarked, "based on the response of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX> might have wished these scripts had remained lost."

            
               Red,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>, and Tawny
            

            It is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commonly</ENAMEX> taught that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> invented the concept of race and color-coded the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>. Not according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Shoemaker</ENAMEX>, an assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of
history at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Wisconsin</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eau-Claire</ENAMEX>. In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> issue
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Historical Review</ENAMEX> , she debunks the standard accounts of how
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Indians</ENAMEX> became "red." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traditional</ENAMEX> explanations include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
encounters with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> wearing red paint, or else the creative labeling system
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">naturalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolus Linnaeus</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shoemaker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">cites English</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diaries</ENAMEX> and treaty records from the 1720s
to argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> came up with the label themselves. The
transcript of a peace treaty between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chickasaws</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherokees</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1726</TIMEX>,
for example, features the phrase "red <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" only within speeches by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX>. Besides, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shoemaker</ENAMEX> writes, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> at the time usually described
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> not as red but as "tawny."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sampras' Secret</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX>-obsessed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX>, went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> to figure out
the science behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Sampras</ENAMEX>' power serve. Top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> have found that the
best serve comes from the tip of the racket. But why? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX> put his own racket
in a vise grip and hooked it up to instruments designed to measure the bounce
of a ball dropped from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 centimeters</NUMEX> onto the strings at various points. He
found, as he reports in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Journal of Physics</ENAMEX> , that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sampras</ENAMEX>'
famous serve is generated by a "dead spot" <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five centimeters</NUMEX> from the tip of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">racket</ENAMEX>, where the ball doesn't bounce at all. The explanation is basic physics:
At the dead spot, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> of the ball's energy is transferred to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">racket</ENAMEX>, which, were it in full swing on a tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, would return the energy
to the ball, guaranteeing a power serve. For returns, however, the dead spot is
no good; it would just absorb all the ball's energy.

            
               Braving
the Elements
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> bickering over who gets to name certain disputed elements of
the periodic table has ended in a compromise befitting the new world order--or
almost. According to a recent article in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> all claimed proprietary rights to the elements <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">104 to 110</TIMEX> until
("chemistry's high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>") handed down its decisions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will claim
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> 104 (rutherfordium, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Rutherford</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">106</NUMEX>
(seaborgium, after nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glen Seaborg</ENAMEX>); the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> get element
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105</NUMEX> (dubnium, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Institute of Nuclear Research</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dubna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>);
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">107 to 109</TIMEX> (respectively bohrium, after <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> quantum
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">physicist Niels Bohr</ENAMEX>; hassium, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hesse</ENAMEX>, where it was
discovered; and meitnerium, after <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lise Meitner</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Element 110</ENAMEX>
remains under dispute.

            
               Poetry
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers</ENAMEX>
            

            Who says
a creative-writing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFA</ENAMEX> is a sure path to permanent unemployment? The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> law
firm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mishcon de Reya</ENAMEX>--whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star attorney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Julius</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> wrote a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">polemical</ENAMEX> book about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T.S. Eliot</ENAMEX>'s anti-Semitism--has hired its first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>-in-residence. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Sunday</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lavinia Greenlaw</ENAMEX> will be paid

         
      
   
