
   
   
      
         
            The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">94-Minute Man</TIMEX>

            A dearth of breaking news
helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> win a clean sweep of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> shows. His
"encyclopedic" press conference (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> )
was Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">midweek</TIMEX> cancellation of the deadline for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> troop withdrawal
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> was Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, and his disarming chat at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> with
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of affirmative action ranked as Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.

            The
commentarians mostly thrilled at the style--not the substance--of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">94-minute</TIMEX> press-conference marathon. Nearly every show replayed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
decorum-breaking response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who tried to snare him with a
sticky-tape question about his race initiative. By the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> viewing, you sorta
saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s point. None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> did.

            Ordinarily, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> complains about the president
avoiding them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s wordy outing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peeved</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Thomas</ENAMEX> ( Inside
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ) because all the talk proved that he doesn't have anything to
say. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ) found the silver lining: If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> doesn't have anything to say, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> must be in good shape. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">begrudgingly</ENAMEX> credited the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> with "outlasting"
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) slathered on the praise, calling
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>-question romp a "virtuoso performance." Playing to character, two
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> sters found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> mean (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>!) and
filled with "self-pity" and afflicted with a "thin skin" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX>).

            Riffing
off the press conference, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits reprised</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s line that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame duck</ENAMEX>. "Lamer than most," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Germond</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ), because he isn't feared or liked by anybody in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.
Instead of noting that anybody who can control <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>'s news with a press
conference, a foreign-policy announcement, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> with domestic dissidents
is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame duck</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits indulged</ENAMEX> in psychobiography: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is frustrated
because "the end is now in sight" for his presidency (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Beirne</ENAMEX> ) and he has yet
to establish his "legacy" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton Kondracke</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ). Because they will be chewing on the legacy thing
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three more years</TIMEX>, the commentarians recently ordered a crate of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dentures</ENAMEX>.

            
Reversing his campaign pledge to bring the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> home from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX> earned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> near-uniform praise from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> ( This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) stroked the prez for saying,
"I was wrong" to promise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> would come home in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1998</TIMEX>. "Nobody in
this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> believed him when he set that deadline," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Germond</ENAMEX>, voicing the
majority viewpoint that the promise was an obvious campaign lie. But not
everybody loves a mensch . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> )
barely disturbed the consensus by accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of having "deceived the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>" and leading the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> into a "quagmire."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bosnia</ENAMEX> plan will require congressional approval--a cinch, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> said,
because he has already drawn down <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27,000</NUMEX> to about
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,500</NUMEX> and no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> have been killed. "Deadlines are a bad idea," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ), because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> would treat one as the first
day of hunting season, locking and loading in anticipation. The only consensus
criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is that he lacks an "exit strategy" from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. Look for
an etymological rundown of the phrase in a future <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> language
column.

            All praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for expanding his national dialogue on
race by meeting at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> with several leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doubters</ENAMEX> of affirmative
action. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hume</ENAMEX> called it the "legitimizing moment" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who disagree
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. "A step forward," concurred <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX>, that once again proved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
to be an "aerobic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listener</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX>). The lone dissenting view came from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blankley</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late</ENAMEX> 
               Edition ), who recounted how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> all thought on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> meeting that they could do business
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. They soon learned otherwise.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carney</ENAMEX>
( The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) counseled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to mix "policy
initiatives" with his racial jawboning if he wanted to accomplish anything.
Kondracke implored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to prepare for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> will strike
down set-asides based on race. He suggested preference programs based on
economic status instead.

            

               Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shut Up</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> urged the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to augment his racial dialogue with discussion of black racism, jury
nullification, hate crimes perpetrated against white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
and violent imagery in rap songs.

            
               At
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stretching Technique Is Called "Yip-Yap</ENAMEX>": How slow a news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> was
it? Meet the Press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> took his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas vacation</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days early</TIMEX> by letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse L. Jackson Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Schlessinger</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Cuomo</ENAMEX> run amok in a long segment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
morality. Russert regained consciousness at show's end when he introduced a
historical segment on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Frost</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> visit. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evans</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Novak</ENAMEX> took a holiday, too, with an inconsequential visit from guest
Art <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchwald</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> chatted with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sesno</ENAMEX> on Late
Edition for no good reason. And on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> ran out
the clock with silly segments on what hypothetical gift each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX>
would give to various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, and what hypothetical gift they would give
to each other. The prescient <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> wisely took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> off.

            

               Note to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>: If you say it on
NewsHour don't repeat yourself on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Punditus Interruptus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Week</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> were unusually civil to one another in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> , foiling "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" 's plan to tabulate
their numerous interruptions of one another in an attempt to calculate who is
the bigger interjector. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> cut <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> off only twice. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt interrupted Novak</ENAMEX>
once. Blame the good manners on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
