
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Art
Fraud
            

            A handful
of art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> are accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX> of plagiarism at worst, and
ungraciousness at best, in failing to credit their scholarship in his recently
published epic survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Visions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' book and an accompanying TV series
appeared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>, and while both were met with enthusiastic reviews, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>, the art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>,
provided neither footnotes nor a bibliography, and made scant mention of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>' work. Now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Education</ENAMEX> cites complaints
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Wallach</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William & Mary</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Nemerov</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford University</ENAMEX>, who claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> presents, but
fails to credit, their readings of paintings by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Cole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Remington</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time-Warner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">et al.</ENAMEX> are making megabucks from your
research," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallach</ENAMEX> fumed to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art historians</ENAMEX> in an online discussion.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallach</ENAMEX> has written a letter of complaint to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>.

            
               In
Defense of Cloning
            

            A group of
self-proclaimed humanists--including selfish-gene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dawkins</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">novelist Kurt Vonnegut</ENAMEX>, philosopher <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Isaiah Berlin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> co-discoverer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Crick</ENAMEX>--have come out in defense of cloning human beings. Reacting to claims by such figures as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and the pope that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolly</ENAMEX>, the cloned ewe, represents a moral
threat, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amherst</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Academy of Humanists</ENAMEX> have
issued a declaration applauding cloning technology and dismissing religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luddites</ENAMEX>. Published in the current issue of the secular humanist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journal Free Inquiry</ENAMEX>, the declaration asserts that "the moral
issues raised by cloning are neither larger nor more profound than the
questions human beings have already faced." In an accompanying essay, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX>
suggests cloning could in fact be fun: "Wouldn't you love to be cloned<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" he
asks. "I've never admitted it before, but I think I would."

            
               Pigging
Out
            

            New evidence from pig farms
suggests that eating disorders may be genetic, not cultural, in origin. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have long accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogue</ENAMEX> and
Glamour of creating unattainable images of female beauty that have led
to rampant anorexia. But according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Higher Education</ENAMEX>
Supplement , <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>, in an attempt to meet increased consumer demand
for lean <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>, have over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> been breeding <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">thinner pigs</ENAMEX>--some of
which display symptoms of anorexia. The prevalence of "wasting pig" and "lean
sow" syndromes among skinny <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">swine</ENAMEX> suggests that self-starvation may be a
recessive genetic trait. "With intensive breeding, an increasing proportion of
defective genes are inherited," reports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Owen</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of agriculture
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Wales</ENAMEX>. Still, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX>, as in human beings, individual
anxiety may be what triggers eating disorders, even among the genetically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">predisposed</ENAMEX>. Explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen</ENAMEX>: "Stress-induced situations for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX> would include
early separation from the sow and having to mix with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX> from outside their
own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, which leads to bullying until a new social order is
established."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> Wars
            

            A previously undistinguished
bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Jacobean</ENAMEX> verse has achieved official recognition as the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>. Thanks largely to the efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vassar College</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Foster</ENAMEX>,
who speculates about literary authorship using an electronic database of texts
of early modern literature, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">585</NUMEX>-line "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Funeral Elegy</ENAMEX>,"
as it's come to be known, appears in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riverside</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton Shakespeare</ENAMEX>
editions, both released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foster</ENAMEX>--who also analyzed Primary
Colors <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and accurately identified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Klein</ENAMEX> as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>--discovered the elegy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> and, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last October</TIMEX>'s issue of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMLA</ENAMEX> , wrote that it "is formed from textual and linguistic fabric
indistinguishable from that of canonical <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>." But many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>
disagree. The current <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PMLA</ENAMEX> contains arguments against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s
authorship on both lexical and aesthetic grounds. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> calls the poem a
"work of unrelieved banality ... lacking a single memorable phrase"; others
suggest other possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Cary</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">noblewoman</ENAMEX> who was a
dilettante <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>). Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.J.M. Tobin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the
Riverside edition, observes in his introduction to the poem that it has "none
of the metaphoric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> that makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare Shakespeare</ENAMEX>."

            
               Witch
Hunt
            

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> who has
openly admitted to instructing undergraduates in pagan rituals is no longer a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for a deanship at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University of New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Paltz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Education</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosemary Keefe Curb</ENAMEX> was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">finalists</ENAMEX> for a job as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> of arts and sciences
until a local <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Paltz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> acquired a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lesbian Nuns</ENAMEX>: Breaking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silence</ENAMEX> , a book Curb co-edited that contains such statements as: "I've
never been initiated into a coven, but I like to call myself a witch." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>,
after receiving negative coverage from the local press, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> scrapped
its search without making a hire, announcing that none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">finalists</ENAMEX> met
"current institutional needs."

         
      
   
