
   
   
      
         
            Who Won <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War II</ENAMEX>?

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">declared Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">victor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> II. This even though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weapons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and the sanctions remain in place. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
is now "better off" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ), having divided the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) and gained "a new
international legitimacy" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ). The
return to the status quo ante has politically isolated the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot; John McLaughlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ). <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX> was awarded
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, for insinuating itself into the dispute and re-establishing its
power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> moaned
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>'s events marked "the beginning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> axis," in
which the impoverished <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> would rearm the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> in return for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>.
Safire all but promised <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Armageddon</ENAMEX> would soon follow.

            "I think
we've got a better audience worldwide," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nazar Hamdoon</ENAMEX>, the languid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX>. Better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>? Did he win sweeps week with his performances
on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans & Novak</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doyle McManus decoded Hamdoon</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> had played a successful bait-and-switch game on the West:
First, he conjured up the bogus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> crisis--complaining about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
domination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and ejecting them--to attract the world's
attention. Then he changed the subject to the unjust imposition of sanctions on
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Enlisting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> in his cause, he successfully moved world
opinion toward lifting the restrictions.

            Swallowing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> bait whole were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doves</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>, who once again called for an end to the
sanctions. Dying <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were "something the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> should think
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>," said conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Novak</ENAMEX>, tapping his long-hidden well of compassion.
Clift, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX>, and others also sympathized with the starving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>, on
whom the sanctions have fallen the hardest. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> displayed a statistic
claiming the sanctions had contributed to the deaths of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 1.4</NUMEX>-million
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> since the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I. That</ENAMEX>, of course, set off a
squabble about the validity of the numbers and a fumbling calculus of how many
lives had been saved from chemical and biological warfare by keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> "in
his box" since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> no credit.
The peaceful resolution revealed him as weak, was the consensus view. "As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, he didn't feel he was potentially powerful
enough to exercise" his options, said former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX>, now
opinionizing on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> . Almost alone supporting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang , NewsHour</ENAMEX> ), who said the
"commando <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX>" calling for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s scalp must understand that
assassinating him was "never a possibility" during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War I</ENAMEX> and isn't "a
possibility now."

            Presaging
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s clichés, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Novak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) said
that only a renewed "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process" could bring stability to the
region. Pissier than a skunk, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> rejected the linkage between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disturbance</ENAMEX> and the civil war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>. "Back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years ago</TIMEX> there
was no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> process and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> were with us because they were afraid--they
were being attacked," he said.

            The commentariat left nothing but furious gnaw marks on
Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, the fertility therapies behind the "miracle" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCaughey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">septuplets</ENAMEX>. Their problem is that the survival of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> decanted the
necessary conflict from the story. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> did work in
an abortion angle, exclaiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would never regulate fertility
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> had decided that "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> is
nothing."

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Piscataway</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, civil-rights settlement (in which civil-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> paid off a fired
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> to avoid a potentially unfavorable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruling), also
sputtered on the shows. Defending the settlement were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>
News <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad</ENAMEX> cases make bad law"), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> ("An indefensible case"),
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Page</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ("This is not an affirmative-action case
in the view of the civil-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>").

            In a
rational world, the loopy charge that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> had traded
campaign donations for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Arlington Cemetery</ENAMEX> burial plots (Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) would have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">damaged Insight</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> owned by convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sun</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myung Moon</ENAMEX> that published the story), the radio mouths who repeated the lies,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who exploited the story. Instead, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> blamed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for being the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who would do that sort of thing,
even though he didn't do it. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> were really ready to believe it," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX>. It took root, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ), because it
had a "ring of truth" to it.

            

               Breaking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> reported on
Late Edition that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would make a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> recess
appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Lann Lee</ENAMEX> to the job the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> won't confirm him for,

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fun Fact You Wouldn't</ENAMEX>
Know Unless You Watched the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> Shows: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triplets</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX>, quintuplets. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>? A singlet .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wacky Tangent</ENAMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX>: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Bode</ENAMEX> scolded the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> 
               Magazine for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 9</TIMEX> fashion spread he said endorsed the
now-discredited fashion trend of "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin chic</ENAMEX>." Maybe it's been a while since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bode</ENAMEX> has partied till <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 a.m.</TIMEX>, but to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" 's eyes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> look
like nothing more sinister than extremely tired and slender party trash,
not emaciated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junkies</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
