
   
   
      
         
            

            
               That's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> to You
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> may become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>. Concerned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> of the famously
ineffectual city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>'s are discussing a plan to lure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> away from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a fifth</NUMEX>
mayoral run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>. The strategy: offering him a six-figure salary to teach
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> politics at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>-area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>. In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard University</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>, were said to be entertaining the proposal--as was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>. But after
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reported the details of the negotiations in early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, both sides appeared to back off. A letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> berated the
local academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> for endorsing a "thinly disguised payoff." "I think
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> might end up in the movies," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> quoted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> as saying.

            
               Closing
Down the Shoah
            

            The
brouhaha over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>'s still-unfilled chair in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> studies continues. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> up with
the bickering and indecision, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Lipper</ENAMEX>, who donated the money through his
family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>, has decided to pour <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1 million</NUMEX> of his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX>
pledge into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Medical School</ENAMEX> instead. According to reports, the
school's <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> studies search <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> has disbanded. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Goldhagen</ENAMEX>,
the author of the controversial <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willing Executioners</ENAMEX> , had been
a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for the proposed professorship, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> got
bogged down in infighting. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This fall</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX>
will have another chance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duke</ENAMEX> it out when he comes up for tenure in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>.

            
               Fun With
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>
            

            
Traditionally, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> have believed there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> existing
portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX>, a rather unflattering sketch by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>. But a debate now raging in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Literary Supplement</ENAMEX>
suggests otherwise. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claudia Johnson</ENAMEX> wrote an
essay in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 13</TIMEX> issue, arguing that an unsigned, undated portrait owned
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> is most likely of the prepubescent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>. She cited the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard James Wheeler</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Rice</ENAMEX>
Portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Ill-Conceived Controversy</ENAMEX> , who claims that
Electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Facial Identification Technique testing</ENAMEX> performed by independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> has all but confirmed that the portrait is of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Curators</ENAMEX> and
costume <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> remain skeptical. "It is a pretty portrait, and one can
understand how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (including some gullible <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>) wish it
to be an early image of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our most-loved novelists," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aileen Ribeiro</ENAMEX>,
a disgruntled costume <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>. "But on costume grounds the portrait cannot be
[of] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX>."

            
               Profit or
Perish
            

            After an
uprising by angry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor of the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Arkansas</ENAMEX> has
reversed his decision to close the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s press. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John White</ENAMEX> had announced that he
would shut down the money-losing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>. "University presses are expected to
be self-sustaining," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> explained. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> across the country
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protested</ENAMEX>, noting that most university presses operate with a deficit. Among
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> was its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller Williams</ENAMEX>, an accomplished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>
who read one of his poems at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> inauguration (and is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of country music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda Williams</ENAMEX>). A recent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> gift from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyson Foundation</ENAMEX>, established by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that owns <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> poultry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">business Tyson Foods</ENAMEX>, should help keep the press on its feet.

            
               Mold
Over
            

            A twin
plague of lice and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fungus</ENAMEX> has attacked the undergraduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> at the
University
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>, the epidemic has
devastated the entire collection. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eighty thousand</NUMEX> books were placed in
quarantine in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, then sent to a local deep-freeze <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> where a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weeklong</ENAMEX> sub-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> treatment was used to exterminate the lice. A thorough
cleaning followed to remove the mold. The volumes are available again but won't
be returned to the stacks until the damp <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> itself gets renovated. It may
be just as well: The medical press reports the book-eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fungus</ENAMEX> can cause
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hallucinations</ENAMEX>.

            
               Reading
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comprehension Made Easy</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are
most likely to remember what they've read when the text is printed with a
ragged right margin and a solid line running straight down the middle of the
page. That bizarre finding is reported in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Scholarly</ENAMEX>
Publishing 's latest issue, which cites a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> study on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> retention of
information. Other exciting patterns tested included: "justified + no rule,"
"flush left/ragged right + no rule," "justified + middle rule." Can a new
speed-reading manual be far behind?

         
      
   
