
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teacher's Pet</ENAMEX>

            If there is one region where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s popularity has probably not been affected by the recent
wave of scandals, it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>-dominated south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">District</ENAMEX>, which just held a special election for the seat of Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Tejeda</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> who died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tejeda</ENAMEX> received
special mention in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> himself
has carried this district twice--his focus on education jibes perfectly with
the work-driven ethic of a place to which so many come precisely because they
believe in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American dream</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, special elections
pit all comers against one another on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> ballot. In the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
District, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> vied for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tejeda</ENAMEX>'s seat. The top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finishers</ENAMEX> in this especially acrimonious campaign, the labor-endorsed state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ciro Rodriguez</ENAMEX> and the conservative, pro-life ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio City</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Juan Solis</ENAMEX>, will face each other in an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> runoff.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ciro Rodriguez</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> , which ran during the special election, responds to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solis</ENAMEX>'
challenge, to his niche appeal in a district that is also home to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
bases (with presumably more conservative and fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>), by playing
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>'s strength--education. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> has a
strong track record on the issue: Not only did he make it his priority during
his tenure in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX> and through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years</TIMEX> as a school-board member
before that, but he has also identified it as a key issue in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> round
of campaigning ahead of the runoff.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> was the only one
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> candidates able to afford television advertising (his successful fund
raising has been the subject of much invective). This spot opens in the school
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">library</ENAMEX>, with him making a direct grab for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s coattails that
simultaneously showcases his own focus on education; it then moves to close-ups
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tejeda</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district</ENAMEX> is
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 9 percent</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>, but the spot makes this politically correct
nod to diversity and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> enlisted at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> that are the
lifeblood of the area.

            A wider shot of the student
audience reinforces the overwhelmingly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> character of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and the
district at large. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>'s pledge to meet the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s challenge to
"make our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> the envy of the world" is followed by a question that implies
far more than it says: "Are you with me?" The call for solidarity reaches
beyond the issue at hand to tap a deeper sense of ethnic and cultural
identification. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> (like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tejeda</ENAMEX> before him) is considered a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> success story, a local who overcame cultural, class, and
linguistic barriers to rise to positions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in the area. His appeal
aims to strike the balance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> politics, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, and patriotism that
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tejeda</ENAMEX>'s hallmark through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his years</TIMEX> in office.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> affirm their
support in a scene double-exposed over an off-center shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> walking
down a school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallway</ENAMEX>. Overlapping frames are one of several gimmicks the ad
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> uses to get around the fact that the spot was shot not on film but on
videotape, which tends to look flat, metallic, too much like the local ads for
discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and used-car lots. Clever edits, angles, and--as we'll see--a
series of quick cuts give this spot some depth and visual interest.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> walks down the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hall</ENAMEX>, he is identified first by name, then as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who "led the fight to
improve south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>." Repeating visuals flow fast and
furious--a shot of an empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>; of someone donning graduation robes; of
the empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>; of the faces in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>; of the robes. A bigger budget
might have brought us visuals of a college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>, of "our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>" actually
"compet[ing]," of the "better jobs" they might get. But this political shoot
saved money not only by using tape, but by finding all its education visuals in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>. The visuals aren't particularly narrative, but they work. So
does the plain, almost nonpolitical language. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> draws a direct link
between education and jobs--no Clintonian rhetoric about the "new economy,"
"the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX>," or that "bridge" here.

            The next scene, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>
deep in thought by the window, recalls the black-and-white photos of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> in a virtually identical pose in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>. What could seem at
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance self-important strikes a chord nonetheless--and in this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
district, this kind of visual cue can't hurt.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ciro</ENAMEX> is "taking a stand"
now, we are told. He is working to bring "the cost of college into reach for
working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in the robes and the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> whose photograph
(in another cut-rate scene that works) is double-exposed over a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallway</ENAMEX> of
empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lockers</ENAMEX>. As the smiling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> finally puts on his mortarboard, we know
where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from the empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallway</ENAMEX> have gone--to college.
We hear the most political language yet, a near cliché about "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
dream." The spot's directness thus far papers over the tired language--and the
camera moves swiftly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> facing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student audience</ENAMEX> again, asking
once more: "Are you with me?"

            It's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">straightforward</ENAMEX>, empowering conclusion to an argument that is as much about
pride and shared experiences as it is about the more tangible issues. Political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> have given the edge in this race to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who best
addresses concerns about education, economic development, and the security of
those who depend on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>'s military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX>. But an increasingly ugly race
to the tape suggests the intangibles might make the difference. Each candidate
has sought to outdo his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> in claiming closeness to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Tejeda</ENAMEX> and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. This spot doesn't overtly link <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose mantle
he is trying to win. But by focusing on the populism that made the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">28 th District Tejeda</ENAMEX>'s own, it hopes those watching will make the
connection.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
