
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bombs</ENAMEX>

             

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vivisection</ENAMEX> continues, as the commentariat tears into his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> policy with both
hands. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) notes that
congressional support waned after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> made his case, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>
realized that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s "ends and means don't coincide." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
smells "a [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>] who doesn't believe in his own policy," adds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX>. "
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'Contain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>' is not a ringing bumper sticker," scoffs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
Late <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edition</ENAMEX> ).

            Just as
there was no consensus on how to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pronounce</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>'s name, there was no
consensus on how to regard the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 th -hour</TIMEX>
diplomatic mission. (The commentariat did their gabbing before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> delivered
his deal.) A sunny <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week With Sam and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cokie</ENAMEX> ) announces, "I guess I'm a dove <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>," hoping that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diplomacy</ENAMEX> backed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber squadrons</ENAMEX> will cow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> into accepting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>'s
terms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ), who's been dressed for combat for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, retorts that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> wants to hand the reins of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign
policy to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>, then we ought to anoint him <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> )
think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wants <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> to negotiate a "fig leaf," permitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> to bow out of war while retaining some shred of credibility. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ) argues the reverse: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fears that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> will come back with an
imperfect offer that, for political reasons, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> cannot
refuse.

            The live <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> meeting (which became a town
beating) sent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> scurrying for thesauri to find synonyms for "fiasco"
and "disaster." Many connect the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> miscue to Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> troubles. Preoccupation with the scandal led a harried and nervous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to send his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX> into a sausage grinder, say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Borger</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ). A
reluctance to appear in public forums for fear of drawing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> questions
compromises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "can't compartmentalize these things the way he wants to."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> has subtitled Wag
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> and is blanketing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> airwaves with its
broadcast.

            Will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> invoke executive privilege to veil conversations about the alleged
hanky-panky with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica?</ENAMEX> "A political nonstarter," states <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gang</ENAMEX> ). "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> did for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> privilege what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> Strangler
did for door-to-door <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesmen</ENAMEX>," quips <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> parallels continue on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe diGenova</ENAMEX>
faces off with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spinner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanny Davis</ENAMEX>, demanding that the president
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confess</ENAMEX> to having hired private dicks to investigate private citizens
(including himself and his law-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner wife</ENAMEX>).

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> offer varied interpretations of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX>'s interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> , though all agree that
he is too competent to have misspoken (and all claim to be his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) reports the consensus view that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX>, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>, is distancing himself from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Others suggest that the
remarks must be interpreted as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> steps toward a bawdy version of "I
didn't inhale." No one cared to speculate whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would ultimately
admit to necking, heavy petting or, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dieu</ENAMEX> , frottage (a k a dry
humping, a k a outercourse).

            Spurred
by the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>' conference held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>
confer Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> status on the state budgets. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> are acting
like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrats</ENAMEX>, shelling out for costly early-childhood and education
programs. Why? Because that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fish Cheer</ENAMEX>: 
               Late Edition twice
rolls footage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> silencing a distressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> with the refrain, "<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-2-3-4</ENAMEX>, we don't want your racist war." But even
an amateur lip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> could discern that one chanting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> was not using
the word "racist" but another two-syllable word, which begins with an "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">f.</ENAMEX>"

            
               Stutter
Step: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> is reduced to near
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incoherence</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, apparently the victim of a balky <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TelePrompTer</ENAMEX>. Returning
from a commercial, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> turns to the camera and pauses. With falling
expression he stutters, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uh</ENAMEX> ... The question is ... uh ... the following ...
What is the question? ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uh</ENAMEX> ... The question is ... <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Uh ...</ENAMEX>" Finally <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
turns to a smiling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Wright</ENAMEX> and spits out, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uh</ENAMEX> ... What about all this?"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> redeems himself later with the observation that, in a recent
appearance, playful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tariq Aziz</ENAMEX> chose a beret just like the one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> wears in the infamous video where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schmucko</ENAMEX> gives her the big hug.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Singing for His Supper</ENAMEX>: Why does
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX> still rate invitations to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> shows?
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, he recycles the same suit and bow tie and evasions on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nation and Meet the Press</ENAMEX> . He chiefly concerns himself with abusing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">archenemy Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>, though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> chastens him by reading back a
series of quotations that document how, not too long ago, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">professed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr Fan Club</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> attempts to build sympathy
for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, though he refuses to discuss his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s account of events,
specifics of her proffer, her legal strategy, her future plans, her definition
of a sexual relationship, or anything else of interest. Why does he bother to
appear? Perhaps to plead for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> defense fund, which, as prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recipient</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> did in the most shameless manner imaginable.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
