
   
   
      
         
            Slick Willey

             

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX> did not.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> cannot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> will not. But, say the commentariat,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> just might sink the unsinkable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slick Willie</ENAMEX>.

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday talkers</TIMEX> hesitantly suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s account of presidential
gropings, Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">69 Minutes</ENAMEX> may turn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. "
'Beware the ides of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>' ... <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a bad day</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius Caesar</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a bad day</TIMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>," warns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ). Looking ahead to
the interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) predicts an
"excruciating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX>" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> interview will make ripples"
because it puts a "human face" on the scandal, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) is confident that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s testimony will be no
"watershed."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> is a more believable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, explain
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, because she's an appealing, attractive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Harris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Thomas</ENAMEX>, Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ). And
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> carries no right-wing conspirator baggage: She's a through and through
Dem with impeccable left-wing credentials (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday ; Gigot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>). Instead of
being a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jezebel</ENAMEX>-like "temptress" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX>, Inside
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ), she's an archetype of the blameless sexual assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
comes off like a miserable "cad" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ), and
for him to place her hand on his tented trousers after she'd pleaded for a job
was surely a tacit suggestion of casting-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> "quid pro quo" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> ). "Despicable ... repellent ... an ugly episode" says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hume</ENAMEX>;
"abusive," agrees <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Ireland</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization for Women</ENAMEX>, tells Late Edition that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> speaks the
truth, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a "sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predator</ENAMEX>." This reverses <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>'s stance from last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX> when she told the shows that, even if true, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> allegations were
not evidence of sexual harassment.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> )
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thinks Ireland</ENAMEX> may be a "leading indicator of opinion" among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women voters</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> that may desert <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in droves.

            
What will <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> do the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> after? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are split. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) predicts that, when
asked about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will break his silence: "He'd be crazy
not to." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) replies that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will give only a
vague statement denying "wrongdoing." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press ) guesses that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> will continue its "stonewall" by
claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s allegations, which have been known for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, are old
news and deserve no comment.

            There is
little talk of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, though it was her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>' filing that
make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s testimony public. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> note in passing that the voluminous document shows the weakness
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' case. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) says the legal importance of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> testimony comes chiefly from her claim that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>
fund-raiser encouraged her to perjure herself.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> distress repeats as Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. The divided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s
selection of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist candidate</ENAMEX> paved the way for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lois Capps</ENAMEX>'
congressional victory in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a traditionally</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>.
This is a district which only "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> had won since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX> was
running <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>," announces habitual double-dribbler <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> on both
Capital <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gang and NewsHour</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX> take more guff
from the quotable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>, who characterizes them on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> as more
concerned with "re-election" than the "revolution" they promised <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> don't define the agenda, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> surely will,
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX>.

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s call to increase the tobacco tax. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> thinks it'll go through,
though he sees it as doubly evil--a reduction of freedom and a tax!
Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>'s apology in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> (see

                  Slate
               's take on future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> apologies) for scrutinizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
sex life, which he claims started the whole scandal. (Brock appeared on both
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation and Meet the Press</ENAMEX> as part of his <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Apology Tour</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'98</NUMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krauthammer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blankley</ENAMEX> both portray <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX> as a marginal self-promoter
who overstates his historical role. On several shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s plan to spend
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million to $50 million</NUMEX> on a continuous picture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> engenders much
laughter.

            

               What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Can Learn From STDs: The most</ENAMEX>
unlikely simile of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Harris</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in</ENAMEX>
Review . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tailgate</ENAMEX> is "more like herpes than <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>," because though not fatal,
it promises many painful flare-ups. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disgusting</ENAMEX>!" says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwen Ifill</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ).

            
               What Debate Shows Do When
There's No Debate: On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> enjoys a
furiously heated nonargument with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mort Kondracke</ENAMEX>, which reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundit</ENAMEX> Central
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Marshall</ENAMEX>'s question about which blade of a scissors does the cutting.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Navy</ENAMEX> saved us from war, rages <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> in angry response to the
suggestion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>'s diplomacy ended the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> crisis. No, it was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diplomacy</ENAMEX> backed up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondracke</ENAMEX> roars back. No, no, no! It was force
backing up diplomacy, insists a fuming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>.

            
               Oh ... That Explains Why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Finger Smokes:</ENAMEX> 
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> spends <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 minutes</TIMEX> in a
straight-faced discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>'s jokey suggestion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
actually ... Satan! Kondracke: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "represents the moral decline of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> ... [he's] a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'d</ENAMEX>' devil." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> finds the most truth in the
comparison: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX>'s suggestion is "perilously close to the truth." "Charming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rogue</ENAMEX>, closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huck Finn</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Satan</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dissents Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
