
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starred</ENAMEX> and Feathered

             

            Having only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> new
sexcapade development to chew on--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> story about first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>'s testimony to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentariat</ENAMEX> turns
its searchlight away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silent Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and onto <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schieffer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> ) pronounces the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s savaging
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> "an all-out attack." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Rangel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahm Emanuel</ENAMEX> complain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s "slash-and-burn tactics" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rangel</ENAMEX>, Face
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> ) and his "innuendo, rumor, lies, and leaks" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Begala</ENAMEX> is asked
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> times by the persistent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> )
why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has yet to give a full account of his dealings with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> times a cheerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Begala</ENAMEX> refuses to answer, chattering on about
the need to "investigate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>" and fuming unconvincingly about
"leaks and lies" (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuel</ENAMEX>, above).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>, visits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> for
"one reason"--to defend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s "integrity." He reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
"attack dogs" have, in the past, pre-emptively leaked damaging stories in hopes
of framing the opposition. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) reprises
this point, alleging that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s leak to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>'s
testimony could just as easily have come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chamber</ENAMEX>.

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
handling of the investigation, the commentariat is evenly divided.
"Storm-trooper tactics," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ); "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Overstepped</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bounds</ENAMEX>," complains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton Kondracke</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) sees a supreme
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perversity</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> suborning perjury, she charges. Meanwhile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) maintains that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> can't be the source of
the leaks because if the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> wanted to leak something, he'd
leak it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>. Novak mournfully reports that the phone never rings.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) defends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> as a mousy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> who
"plays by the book."

            
Refusing to dance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
music, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> 
               With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cokie</ENAMEX> ) puts it
all in perspective: "Are the leaks the question, or are the facts the
question?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina Totenberg</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ) notes that the
presidential love gifts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> is reported to have repossessed and then given
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> are the first "concrete" pieces of evidence. "Devastating," says pithy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kondracke</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> stresses that the repo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s testimony is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> inside
revelation of a cover-up. Still, notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ), the
strategy of silence and smearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has been "effective." He points out that
these sorts of tactics worked pretty well for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiro Agnew</ENAMEX>, too, until the facts
eventually "did it."

            No one much cares to discuss
morality during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this third week</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tailgate</ENAMEX>, though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX> ( This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) grump about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
blasé attitude toward extramarital fellatio in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-hater
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ), for one, doesn't care if it's
"on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> carpet," though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> tampering and perjury concern him
greatly.

            The press
also takes a mild drubbing from within: A mad "rush to judgment" is how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ) describes the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few weeks</TIMEX>, though co-panelist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX> demurs, "no one on this show used the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-</ENAMEX>word."

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, receives almost the same attention as
Tailgate, though there was far less disagreement. It is "always possible to
make matters worse," warns a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lugubrious</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ). Many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> caution the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> to look before a leap. We need to think out
our "endgame" before we begin any military initiative, argue <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gergen</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> (both on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX> also talks of the
importance, at this early stage, of articulating "the goal of bombing." Gergen
wonders whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have the stomach for war; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't ready for
"mutilated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and bombed-out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>," he predicts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> agrees that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is in favor of an attack but "unprepared to go to war."

            The only true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX> is
closely-trimmed conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ), who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> a
ground invasion. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits side</ENAMEX> with bushy-headed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ), arguing that only air strikes would be politically
palatable. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isolationist Buchanan</ENAMEX> refloats an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> position: We
shouldn't be too worried about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s hands.
Kondracke screams back that he's "used them before, he'll use them again."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> replies that nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> will keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> at bay. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> even
uses the word "deterrence," though he doesn't use "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mutually Assured</ENAMEX>
Destruction," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bakelite</ENAMEX>," or "hula hoop."

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distressed Novak</ENAMEX> gets off the best line on Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, the budget: The "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
Party was put on this earth by God to cut taxes ... and they're not doing
it !" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> notes that if you "understand <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics," you'll realize
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s budget proposal will rise and fall with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Big</ENAMEX> Intern
Scandal.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ours May</ENAMEX> Have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trouser Problem</ENAMEX>, But Yours
Is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drunk</ENAMEX>: No one knew quite what to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s thrice-repeated
warning that an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> would bring on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War III</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s a drunk, concluded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Thomas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Germond</ENAMEX> (both on Inside
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ). "Inebriated bluster," agreed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, "of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that is
no longer great." Clift, on the other hand, cannot believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> was in
the bag <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> times he gave these warnings.

            
               Somebody's Not Telling
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX>: On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ben-Veniste</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rips Starr</ENAMEX>'s leaky <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archibald Cox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Jaworski</ENAMEX>, the two
chief <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben-Veniste</ENAMEX> worked with, never leaked
a thing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben-Veniste</ENAMEX> makes no reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>'s scoop on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gang</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cox</ENAMEX> leaked information to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> in background briefings
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years ago</TIMEX>. Maybe these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> should have lunch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sometime</TIMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
