
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planet</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Bill Lann It</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s rope-a-dope
performance before <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>'s investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> earned
Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> honors. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno "</ENAMEX>took a beating" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> )
and "didn't give <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an inch</NUMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Duffy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ) or "flinch" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ). Then, reported
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, she "shellacs them" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina Totenberg</ENAMEX>, Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ) in
a "masterful performance" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) and "wins the
moment" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Page</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> reversed the standard
narrative arc of congressional hearings, in which belligerent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> make
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> look stupid, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Thomas</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>'s pugilistic secret? She "bores them to death" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Totenberg</ENAMEX>).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>' appreciation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s idiot savancy stopped short of direct
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comparisons to Forrest Gump</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chauncey Gardener</ENAMEX>. They neglected to make this
connection only because they failed to think of it, not because they respect
her.

            
Discovering the bright side of the hearing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX>), who snooted out these meager truffles: By
calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Freeh</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> for questioning,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> kept alive the controversy over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision not to appoint an
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. Also, the increased scrutiny will give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX> new "freedom"
to continue his campaign-finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s embrace of the global-warming
treaty was Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">treaty</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton won't submit</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> for
ratification any time soon, was pronounced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> ) and a political liability to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>--especially
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>--because it is opposed by business and labor. All
agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is doomed if the treaty becomes his signature issue. Several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liasson</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s Late
Edition ) compared the treaty's political impact to that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration's first-term health-care initiative: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> endorse big-think
issues like these in principle, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX> after they get wind of the
specifics.

            
Conservative commentarians damn the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyoto</ENAMEX> treaty because they reject the
global-warming science and fear the treaty's economic repercussions (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
Krauthammer, Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>
salute it for its political ambition. "Bold move," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>. It will "get
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> used to the idea that they've got to do something" about global
warming, offered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>. Showing off his homework, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krauthammer</ENAMEX> alleged that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> supports the treaty because the closure of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Germany</ENAMEX>'s dirtiest
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> has already brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> into compliance with the coming
emission standards, which are set at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> levels.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s threat to make a recess appointment
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Lann Lee</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s civil-rights division
and the indictment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Cisneros</ENAMEX> dueled for the Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> slot. Partisan
squabbling over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s impending recess appointment subsided with this
face-saving news: It now appears that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will make an "acting" appointment
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>, which is supposed to clock out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">120 days</TIMEX>. Why the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> took
solace in this retreat is a mystery: The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">120-day</TIMEX> limit can't be enforced,
whereas a recess appointment would end <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.

            The fall
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cisneros</ENAMEX> was labeled a "tragedy" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liasson</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duffy</ENAMEX> restated the pertinent question, which nobody on the other
shows addressed: Where did public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cisneros</ENAMEX> get the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> to pay off
his ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>?

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charm School</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks ago</TIMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans & Novak</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX> for his good
talk-show manners. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s charm-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ribbon-winner</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>,
whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> called "very restrained" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> hearings he chaired. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> was
also "restrained on our program," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX>, adding that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>'s
composure at the hearings disproves the "contention at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> that
he's a wild <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and if they provoke him he'll blow up." Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> should
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invite Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latrell Sprewell</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Cameron</ENAMEX> onto his show for
charm-school lessons.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doggie Style</ENAMEX>: Names
proposed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> shows--

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Par</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shoes"</ENAMEX> (so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will have Shoes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socks</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shredder</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>"
(as in "come, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>" and "stay, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>").

            Rahm
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuel</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank"</ENAMEX> (as in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sesno</ENAMEX>, the host of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> , who asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuel</ENAMEX> the question).

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Punditus Interruptus</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX>
bitch back and forth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> about who is
interrupting whom. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>," which can claim impartiality because it
cares not for either commentarian, will start counting interruptions. At the
end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, the lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offender</ENAMEX> will be forever barred from indignantly
demanding of the lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offender</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can I finish?</ENAMEX>!"

            
               Chyrons: Why haven't
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> compared <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Latrell Sprewell with American legend Ty Cobb</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cobb</ENAMEX> beat
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX>, opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">umpires</ENAMEX>, clubhouse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waiters</ENAMEX>, and store <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX>. He is said to have killed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a
brawl and once stomped a crippled heckler in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX>. ... Earning
frequent pundit miles over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, who
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">telepromptered</ENAMEX> in identical performances about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week , and Capital Gang</ENAMEX> . Should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> be praised
for staying on point or ridiculed for being a robot? ... 
               This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week regular</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> turned gangsta rapper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, saying, "Anybody who
comes between me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> dies." ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Week</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham</ENAMEX> challenged the legality of recess
appointments in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> when she sued the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> for using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to
replace her on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodham</ENAMEX>'s suit, which
was rejected, recess appointments are considered constitutional. ...
Will busted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> for inconsistently insisting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Lann Lee</ENAMEX> be
approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> because he's "qualified," even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> opposed
the confirmation of the similarly "qualified" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snared</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>'s trap, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> could only gibber.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
