
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leak Soup</ENAMEX>

             

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, as the commentariat all but ignore other news. Pundits "can only cover one
story and chew <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX> at the same time," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chortles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Germond</ENAMEX> ( Inside
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ).

            Who
leaked? the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> ask. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wags</ENAMEX> are "heavy betting" that the president
is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Thomas</ENAMEX>
( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ) notes that pre-emptive leaking of damaging
information is SOP for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. The widely cited rationale for
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> leak is to publicize a "road map" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ) or "master script" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX>, Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> )
for future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> not wishing to contradict the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s sworn
deposition. Subtle manipulation of the press is what "smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> do," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>.

            But there are other, better ways of transmitting the
official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> line, contend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann McDaniel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> )
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> argues that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> would not needlessly admit the existence of presidential love
gifts, thereby undermining the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story of the Seventh</ENAMEX> Commandment that it is
peddling. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina Totenberg</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ) is alone in her suspicion
that the leak was loosed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> representing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trooper Danny</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX>. Given the vociferous denials from all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Broder</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ) concludes that the leak is an "act of
God."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Clinton</ENAMEX> survive? A few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX> readjust their odds upward. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ) thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s strategy of making a speech on a popular
subject <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> is working. Some suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may never come
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clean</ENAMEX>--and he may get away with it, despite his earlier promise to promptly
explain his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gergen</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> ) predicts that so long as the economy keeps chugging along, only
being found in bed with "a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> or a live <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>" can unseat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            Not so
fast, say the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, charting the land <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s path. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> might be undone by the possible discrepancies between his testimony
(helping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>'s idea) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>'s (the "helping
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>" idea came via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>, but it was originally <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liasson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>
News <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ). Or by the deposition to be released by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ). Or by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>'s testimony--that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
placed her hand on his erect, but clothed, penis (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> ). Or by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star witness</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Tucker</ENAMEX>, a
convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ).

            
Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is those stupid <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s disastrous championship of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> statehood bill is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ridiculed</ENAMEX>: Almost no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> voted for it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> has
banned the measure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. All agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> leadership
was suckered into supporting it by high-pressure lobbying and poll results,
mistakenly believing that this was the way to win <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) demands to know why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> is so "full of fear and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trembling</ENAMEX>." Many opine that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have become impotent, but no one
can explain why this is so. Also, decide the commentariat, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> doesn't have
a good presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Billion</ENAMEX>
Dollar <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' appearance before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krauthammer</ENAMEX> side with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>--government
regulation can only bring grief. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> )
applauds regulatory vigilance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Chung</ENAMEX>'s decision to turn <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s evidence
is Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. No one knows that he'll say, but everyone agrees that his testimony
could become a Very Big Deal.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Derivatives Trading</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Peterson</ENAMEX>
( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ) begins a discussion of the film version of
Primary Colors by citing the conventional wisdom that it paints a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glowing</ENAMEX>, shamelessly partisan portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panelist Evan Thomas</ENAMEX> hasn't
seen the film, but on the basis of conversations with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, he maintains that the film is anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peterson</ENAMEX> then chimes in
with the observation that you come away from the film liking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. Has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Peterson</ENAMEX> seen the film? Well ... no, but his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Practice Makes Perfect</ENAMEX>: Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX>) double dribble <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>.
During a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>'s testimony, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> comes
out with the bizarrely malapropos comment that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>'s elocutionary
style reminds him of nothing more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Jordan</ENAMEX>'s measured diction. On
Capital <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gang</ENAMEX> , the topic turns to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>, and sure enough--and
just as inelegantly--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> brings up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Jordan</ENAMEX> again. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NewsHour</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX> asks, "Is this a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>? Sometimes I
wonder!" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days later</TIMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday , Gigot</ENAMEX> still has no answer,
asking, "Is this a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>?"

            

               Funny, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Reportedly Said</ENAMEX> the Same
Thing: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ) wows his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX>
with the news that he had bumped into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>--well, actually,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cosmos Club</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> were
there too, facts confirmed by the husband-and-wife <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s Late
Edition and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , respectively. The verdict<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "Pretty ...
attractive, alert, upbeat," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX>; "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darling</ENAMEX> ... young and cute ... a
nice, cute, flippy sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">gushes Cokie;</ENAMEX> "young," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>. Pundit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>, for one, is worried that peppy, likable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> might try to take
its job.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
