
   
   
      
         
            Go Ahead, Give <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Opponent the Finger</ENAMEX>

            
               No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> , produced by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Message & Media</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Struble, Oppel</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donovan</ENAMEX> Communications
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim McGreevey</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>.

            This is a great political
spot: It's creative, it's fun, and it's effective--or at least, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first half</TIMEX>
of it is. No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> , produced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Message & Media</ENAMEX> and
Struble, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oppel</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donovan</ENAMEX> Communications, goes full tilt at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> Gov.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Todd Whitman</ENAMEX>, who's heavily favored to win re-election.

            This isn't a frontal attack,
if you're being literal--the spot shows only the back of her (look-alike's)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> turns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX>'s instant-recognition advantage against her:
One look at the distinctive do and tony threads and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are bound
to think they've pinned the tail on the right donkey. The spot also plays off
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX>'s relentless cheerleading and ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nauseam</ENAMEX> bragging about being No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:
She brandishes a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Styrofoam</ENAMEX> hand emblazoned with "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#1</NUMEX>" and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> map.
Index finger proudly raised, the hand's relentless bobbing is meant to grate
and does a fine job of it.

            Effectively asking if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX>'s satisfaction translates to yours, the ad emphasizes the separation
between this patrician <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX>. Her voice is annoyingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WASPish</ENAMEX>, and she seems to be standing on a stage, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> level above the hoi
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polloi</ENAMEX>. No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> reiterates what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> already know--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s
been privileged for generations; simply put, she's out of touch, and her No. 1
and your No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> aren't the same thing. She doesn't know what her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>'s
polling obviously shows--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> is on the wrong track.
How can this be, with the economy on the upswing and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> income-tax
cut, her centerpiece promise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX>, now fully in place? As the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">narrator</ENAMEX> points out, unsourced headlines and a sharp fade to sepia stressing
the point, the tax cut came with a price tag: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We're No. 1</ENAMEX> in property taxes"
(which rose when income-tax rates dipped); <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">No. 1</ENAMEX> in "pension-bond debt" (there
was a firestorm of criticism when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> borrowed from pension reserves to pay
for the tax cut); and finally, No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>-insurance rates, the sleeper issue
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'97</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX> race--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> was late in responding to it, and it's eroded
her lead.

            The spot now becomes
abruptly conventional, showing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim McGreevey</ENAMEX> backdropped
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> flag in what appears to be an official setting. Even so, the visual
contrasts continue. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGreevey's</ENAMEX> in his shirtsleeves, not in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armani</ENAMEX>; he's
looking us in the eye, not giving us the back of his head (and his policy)
while playing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>; he speaks our language--even if it sounds formulaic
("we need to change our priorities"), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">it isn't Whitman</ENAMEX>'s mechanical palaver.
His denunciation of gimmicks notwithstanding, the spot offers one of its own--a
distracting back-and-forth between color and black-and-white that's pure ploy.
His issues--"cut waste ... improve our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> ... take on the insurance
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>"--tested well in polls and, wiser for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>' experiences,
he is careful to avoid specifics.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGreevey</ENAMEX> here is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">un-Whitman</ENAMEX>: He doesn't reek of old money, and he isn't a snob. He's a protest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who--and perhaps this is why the second half of the ad is so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ho-hum</ENAMEX>--is safely bland. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> don't forget <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half</TIMEX>, this sassy
spot might actually cut through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> market, where it's notoriously
difficult to convert <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> into engaged and interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> is
still the favorite, but if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 1</ENAMEX> has its way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> will see her as too
much of a good thing.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
