
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Starr Is Reborn</ENAMEX>?

             

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUNDIT CENTRAL</ENAMEX>" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. The possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> apparent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> lacks the necessary political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acumen</ENAMEX> is Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. And, though some predicted that her <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> of fame had
expired, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' decision to file an appeal sneaks in as Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.

            Everyone agrees that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
desperately wants to refurbish his public image--he gave up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepperdine</ENAMEX>
deanship, hired a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and exchanged angry notes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>--though the commentariat is giving long odds on his success.
Discarding the deanship was "thoughtful and reasonable," admits <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ), but it was more political compromise
than homage to principle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disassociating</ENAMEX> himself from right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX>
is an admirable but "belated" move, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ).
It's too late to win hearts, believes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s historical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> will be fixed by the legal argument he ultimately
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marshals</ENAMEX>.

            And
exactly what form will this argument assume? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> will write a report that is
"complicated at best," believes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ). Upon
receiving this report, predicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will hold a hearing to "put a
finger to the wind." If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s favorable poll ratings persist, talk of
impeachment will fade. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> ) predicts a
report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will be ready by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of summer</TIMEX> and believes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> may
ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to present it orally. If so, he'd better hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Smits</ENAMEX> to present
it, because the camera is not his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, retorts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina Totenberg</ENAMEX>
( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ) offers a similar sentiment: On television <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
looks pasty; in real life he's "a chipmunk of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> ) thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> will indict <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and present his evidence in
court. This will make him look like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX>, notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> ( This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ).

            Almost everyone is baffled by the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> gave only
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$353</NUMEX> to charity <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> sums up the consensus position that, at times,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> seems "tone insensitive." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ), in defense, note his expenses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>--a fancy wedding for one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and tuition for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> others at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> also takes flak for his
visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> tornado disaster sites. Late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edition</ENAMEX> 's (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>
juxtapose images of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s recent visit to disaster territory
(casually embracing a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>) with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>'s (dyspeptic
speechifying from behind a lectern), prompting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> to
seriously question <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s political viability. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>
problem"--he suffers by comparison to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>--quips <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liasson</ENAMEX>.

            A vocal
few find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s missteps charming. It's absurd that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> seem to
want a "moist-eyed ... commiserater in chief," complains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>. Maybe we
shouldn't encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s desire to embrace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>, chortles <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blankley</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s political ineptitude may actually be an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">asset</ENAMEX>, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are so fed up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slick Willy</ENAMEX>'s slickness, argues <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ).

            
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> seem surprised at the
persistence of Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, the continuing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> saga. This story will be
around for the remainder of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidency, claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>. Several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> may win her appeal, though all admit that any
trial will occur after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s presidency (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Will; Taylor</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX>,
Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ). An upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> case, which will clarify
legal principles in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case, piques the curiosity of a few
court-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylor; Blankley</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ). Gigot
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ) thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> are inept, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Totenberg</ENAMEX> believes
they are more interested in serving right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX> than her
interests.

            
               A Show
About Nothing: 
               Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ians spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the final minutes</TIMEX> of the
discussion on the moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> . Occasional poor taste is
partly redeemed by great wit, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Thomas</ENAMEX>. Among other laudable qualities,
the "anti-Semitism is well-done," opines <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krauthammer</ENAMEX>.

            

               He Moves in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mysterious Ways: Proving</ENAMEX>
himself as adept with a parable as with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Largent</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okla.</ENAMEX>, explains the link between abortion and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>. If only <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe vs. Wade</ENAMEX> had ended differently,
argues <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 million</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> to pay
as we go.

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Way</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Highway</ENAMEX>:
Exercised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Blitzer</ENAMEX>'s ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) suggestion that the Jones
appeal is naked political machination, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donovan Campbell</ENAMEX> charges
Clintonites with hypocrisy and offers, "Let me give you <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> real quick
examples." An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unruffled</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blitzer</ENAMEX> counteroffers, "We don't have that much time.
Why don't you give me one?"

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
