
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tramp</ENAMEX>?

             

            The commentariat cleaves the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Scandals</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> issues <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the mud-storm surrounding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' readiness to receive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s report; and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bennett</ENAMEX>'s about-face on publicizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' amorous life.

            There are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost as many</NUMEX> opinions on Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> as there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Germond</ENAMEX>
( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ) defines the pro-Willey end of the spectrum. Noting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s initial reluctance to testify, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germond</ENAMEX> dismisses talk of impure
motives as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> "trying to throw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX> in our eyes."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Middle-of-the-roaders</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Thomas</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s story remains convincing but see some
truth in anti-Willeyism: There "are no clean test-tubes" in this scandal, says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>. At the other extreme, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> libs (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kondracke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX>) make quite a show of pitching tent in the
anti-Willey <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s credibility has been destroyed; the questions about
her motives have been devastating, they maintain.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> follow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Goodman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s Late
Edition ) in excusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s anti-Willey smear campaign as
"inevitable" while characterizing it as far from "appealing." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> )
share outrage over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s eagerness to release <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX>-related
correspondence while failing to answer scores of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>-related queries
(remember her?). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clift</ENAMEX> contends that there has been no character assassination
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, only the release of facts. Krauthammer detects class bias
in the sympathy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> evinced by the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> who refused to rally
around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>.

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>'s hunger
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report--finds all agreeing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> must avoid
looking cheap or nasty. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, the widely respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' "ace in the hole," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ). But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> is filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> "full
mooners," he adds, who will make the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> look clownish. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) declare that impeachment proceedings occurring
after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> elections are less likely to unseat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) insists that a late start will permit the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to "go full bore" without fear of offending short-memoried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
with their partisanship. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp's threat to invoke executive
privilege is widely dismissed as a foolish delaying tactic.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Issue 3,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Bennett</ENAMEX>'s decision not to detail <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' love life for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, is
portrayed as the triumph of politics over sound legal strategy (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>,
Capital <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gang</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>).

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood Fever</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks ago</TIMEX>, Inside
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ian Evan Thomas</ENAMEX> disputed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Peterson</ENAMEX>'s claim that the film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primary Colors</ENAMEX> had a pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> bias, even though neither had actually
seen the film. Now having viewed it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> reports ( without
blushing! ) that the film is sympathetic to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peterson</ENAMEX> asks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Germond</ENAMEX>, who has not seen the film, to give some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> commentary based
upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Germond</ENAMEX>'s exposure to TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailers</ENAMEX> for the film. Some characters
seem well-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>, responds the perplexed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germond</ENAMEX>. Rounding out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Mathis</ENAMEX> says she wouldn't mind seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Newman</ENAMEX> win a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Actor Oscar</ENAMEX>
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. This would be quite a trick, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newman</ENAMEX> was not nominated this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.

            
               Will the Commentariat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resign First</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX> prefaces his Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
commentary with a sigh: "I had my usual experience. I thought, my God, this is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gonna</ENAMEX> do enormous damage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and sure enough the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> people
think exactly the opposite." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX> begins his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX>
soliloquy by airing his own self-esteem issues: "There have been so many things
that I thought were going to have tremendous political consequences ... they
haven't happened."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milli Vanilli Redux</ENAMEX>:
You heard it here <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>-- Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is lip-synced! There
was a very creepy <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moment about 20 minutes</TIMEX> into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s installment: The
camera cut away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Mathis</ENAMEX>, who was holding forth on school uniforms,
to a presumably contemporaneous shot of the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mathis</ENAMEX>' voice-over
continued but the visual was of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krauthammer</ENAMEX> chatting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peterson</ENAMEX> as a nodding
and still-lipped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX> looked on.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
