
   
   
      
         
            Waiting for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX> to Deal

             

            With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in recess, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> on vacation, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> relatively quiet, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> served moldy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leftovers</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving weekend</TIMEX>. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision whether to
appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising
phone calls. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> and political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests unanimously</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>
wouldn't.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) expressed the consensus that such a decision
will set off "<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War III</ENAMEX> between congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>," and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> will surely appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to investigate
the alleged link between campaign contributions and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Babbitt</ENAMEX>'s rejection of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> casino license. Once authorized, that
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> will follow the money back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and
investigate the phone calls anyway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX> explained.

            Offering the only new spin on the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>, guesting on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> . He
insisted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> must appoint, comparing the sneaky <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> donations
to the rampant spying and other efforts to influence <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government concealed the extent of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> penetration, injuring democracy and fueling conspiracy theories in
the process. Unless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> comes clean about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
influence-peddlers, the tragedy will repeat, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> said.

            The
pundits combined the ongoing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economic meltdown with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Rim</ENAMEX>
economic summit to frame Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer ) and Alan Murray</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ) marveled at the
difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX> and earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> summits. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> would arrive at the meetings and concede the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX>
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX>. Then they'd submit to public browbeatings from the tigers
for running such huge trade deficits. Roles were reversed at this summit,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> noted. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are pandering to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
for bailouts and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> is flowing into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> markets.

            
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> recited the economic arithmetic
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> meltdown: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Desperate Asian</ENAMEX> economies will dump goods here,
benefiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>--but hurting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>--and reducing our
inflation. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> exports won't fall because <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> isn't an important export
market for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> goods. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is rich enough to bail itself out. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>
( The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) denounced the "crony capitalism" of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and
predicted that the coming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> bailout will run into the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ) called the
bailout welfare for undeserving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> )
represented the pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF caucus</ENAMEX>, citing the success of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> bailout.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
dropped to Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 1</NUMEX>. Suffering issue fatigue, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX> could only repeat themselves. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ) still thinks we have no alternative but to assassinate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) still thinks we have no alternative but to commit
ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) still thinks that the diminished
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> gives us no alternative at all. In such a situation, description
substitutes for opinionizing. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam blinks</ENAMEX> and so does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Repetitive Pundit Syndrome</ENAMEX> took its toll on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Beirne</ENAMEX>. On
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NewsHour</ENAMEX> , recorded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Beirne</ENAMEX> made sense when she argued for
a unilateral strike against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. Her logic? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> "want to
appease whoever they think--between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>--is going to
be the ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victor</ENAMEX>." Therefore, a show of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> will rally the region to
our side. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next evening</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Beirne</ENAMEX> had fused
her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> salient <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> points--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> smells like corporate welfare
and a unilateral strike against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is warranted--into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unified Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
Theory. She said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> reliably says the correct things about foreign
policy and economics, and then reliably blows it by deferring to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">internationalists</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Beirne</ENAMEX>'s theoretical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overreach</ENAMEX> proves that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>--like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>--can only work a fixed number
of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> before they become reckless.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yuck Yuck</ENAMEX>: We should back the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
proposal to rename <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Washington National Airport</ENAMEX> in honor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>, said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shecky" Kristol on This Week</ENAMEX> , just to "annoy" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> like
Stephanopoulos every time they land in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Surfacing</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> plumbed the upcoming global-warming treaty
conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> for its political content. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> left has gone
international to win a "phony treaty" that curbs greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>
alleged, because they can't accomplish their goal domestically. He added the
non sequitur that nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> is more of a threat "to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> than global
warming." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX> predicted that no breakthrough would emerge from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Eisenstat</ENAMEX> was attending as lead <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob X</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rowland Evans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>-bound guest the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX> all pretended to be reasonable people
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans & Novak</ENAMEX> . After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> left the set, Novak
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">congratulated</ENAMEX> himself and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> for exhibiting such good talk-show manners.
Predicting that he would "get a lot of heat" for treating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> with
respect, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> was "more measured and a lot less
confrontational and provocative than a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> we talk to
regularly on this program."

            Yes, yes, the measured and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">polite Farrakhan</ENAMEX>. Has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> never attended <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>'s rallies?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> is always circumspect in the first act. But when the groundlings
grumble for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">red meat</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> act, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> abandons the smiling visage
and the angel-of-peace routine and spews. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Novak</ENAMEX> want to capture
the real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" suggests that they accompany him to one of
his rallies. His transformation from reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to demagogic bigot is as
frightening as it is predictable.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
