
   
   
      
         
            News from academe

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Typhoid Alexander</ENAMEX>
            

            After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2,000</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of speculation, the mystery of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>'s death may have been solved by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>. The legendary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Macedonian conqueror</ENAMEX> died in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylon</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">323</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 32</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Poisoning,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>, and heavy drinking have all been cited to explain the peculiar
physical symptoms that accompanied his death. The strangest of these is the
claim by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX> did not decay for several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>--an assertion usually written off as myth. But according to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>
issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Oldach</ENAMEX>, an infectious disease <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Maryland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Borza</ENAMEX>, a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX>,
have a diagnosis that accounts for all the odd phenomena: <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">typhoid fever</ENAMEX>. Not only would that explain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>'s fever,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chills</ENAMEX>, and severe
bowel distress, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> say, but the disease can induce a rare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">complication</ENAMEX> called "ascending paralysis," which looks like rigor mortis even
though the afflicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> may not yet be dead.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transatlantic Crossed</ENAMEX>
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">much-anticipated</ENAMEX> CD-ROM from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.E.B. Du Bois Institute for</ENAMEX>
Afro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Research</ENAMEX> reflecting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> of scholarship on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transatlantic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> trade was attacked at its unveiling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary College</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> faulted the
CD-ROM for failing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) to address the cultural impact of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diaspora</ENAMEX>;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) to provide a definitive list of the voyages; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) to mention the names of
any of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> transported to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">slave ships</ENAMEX>. Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> disagree, saying that the CD-ROM brings together information on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27,000</NUMEX>
voyages undertaken by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and that it revolutionizes
our understanding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> trade. For example, the CD-ROM makes clear that
half of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> died not during the middle passage, as has been commonly
assumed, but at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> before embarking. The CD-ROM will be available
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
Press for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$195</NUMEX> beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>. For more on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois Institute</ENAMEX>,
read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis Gates Jr.</ENAMEX> in

                  Slate
               .

            

               
                  Who <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Loves Cheerleading</ENAMEX>? We <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Cheerleading</ENAMEX>!
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheerleading</ENAMEX>, it turns out, is one of the most dangerous college sports for
found that cheerleading was responsible for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> of the injuries
suffered by female high-school and college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> leading to paralysis or
death. The good news for cheerleading is that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> now recognize
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cheerleading</ENAMEX> as a sport (as opposed to an activity); there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 7</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheerleaders</ENAMEX> around the world; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> are pushing for <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX>
status.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret of Life</ENAMEX>
            

            Are
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> trying to steal a natural resource from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>? In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bethesda</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute of Aging</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Max Planck</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Demographic Research</ENAMEX> joined <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> for a massive study of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 80 and older</TIMEX>. No sooner had work begun than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> began to cry foul. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of trying to
mine the secret of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>'s famed longevity in order to exploit
it for Western commercial ends. "These long-life genes are the most valuable in
the world," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> in early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>. "It should be us who markets them, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>." As a result of
growing protests, research was suspended for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months in the spring</TIMEX>.

            

               Another Reason To Get That MBA
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s top business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are discovering new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> for their venture
capital funds: their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> , MBA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwestern University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kellogg School</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Michigan</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University</ENAMEX> can apply to their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> for support of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up to</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> to get their business projects off the ground. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> aren't
giving away the money; they expect to turn a profit on their investments within
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Projects</ENAMEX> these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have backed so far: a candle and
toiletries business, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that makes backpacks for in-line skates, and a
firm exploring laser technology for eye surgery.

            
               Egghead
Exam
            

            A
tenured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of English at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers</ENAMEX> has refused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>'s request
that she take a neurological exam. After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> complained to the
administration about her behavior in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra</ENAMEX>
Flitterman-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> was asked to sign a release form requiring her to be medically
examined before teaching again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>. According to a recent article in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Targum</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, complaints about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flitterman-Lewis</ENAMEX>
included "bringing too many personal issues to class," failing to adhere to her
announced syllabus, and singling out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> "for ridicule and contempt."
Flitterman-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX> 
               Targum that she was not given an
opportunity to defend or explain her behavior and that "There's no evidence
beyond hearsay that I'm incompetent." She will not be teaching at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers</ENAMEX> this
fall.

         
      
   
