
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Courting We Will Go</ENAMEX>

             

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUNDIT CENTRAL</ENAMEX>" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> news is that, by
winning in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and moving against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>
lands on top <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. He's a serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, not the rogue we once
thought, admit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>. The nuclear standoff between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>--Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>--frightens just about everyone. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>--the death of a
conservative--provokes a flurry of pronouncements on the life and times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Goldwater</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
flawless string of legal victories--he has won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> decisions against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> so far--legitimizes his investigation in the eyes of many. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
is "on the wrong end of a no-hitter," quips <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ). What is more, continues <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> opinion given
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">midweek</ENAMEX>--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> are not protected from
testifying--provides specific and independent confirmation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has
credible evidence. In light of recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> victories, to argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rogue prosecutor</ENAMEX> is now to argue that "we have rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> too," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ). But, adds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gang</ENAMEX> ), we should remember that even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> are compelled
to testify, it is unlikely the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> Über -loyalists will spill very
much.

            Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentariat</ENAMEX> believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is likely to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indict Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. It's mostly a move to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> testify under oath,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">believes Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schieffer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late</ENAMEX>
Edition ) both note that recently released court documents unmask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> arguments that legal battles impede <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s official duties. This is in
direct and egregious opposition to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> and more public statements holding
that it is business as usual in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> sums up the common belief quite
nicely when he labels Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>--nuclear weapons tests in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>--"scarier than hell." The question for the world, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenberger</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ), is "How do we put the genie
back in the bottle<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            Who is to
blame for the nuclear standoff? Not the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> have been at each other's throats since "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> was in
knickers," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> disagrees:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> share equal blame for treating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shabbily</ENAMEX> since the end of the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. And let's not forget that
both the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> are highly volatile and unstable,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cautions Hunt</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentariat</ENAMEX> agrees that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Goldwater</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) was a giant
in modern political conservatism and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) was an endearing straight-talker.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> are wowed by his basic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-ness: "an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> original" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ); "an honest
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ); "a genuine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriot</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ); "a genuine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ); and "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Page</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ).

            Even on the heels of his
death, a few voices pipe up about his frightening bellicosity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Thomas</ENAMEX>,
Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton Kondracke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ). Others
note that he voted against the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Civil Rights Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>.

            Most
legacy talk, however, concerns his influence on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gigot</ENAMEX>'s mind, he is
the "most successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loser</ENAMEX>" in political history--his failed presidential run
defined a conservative agenda that was eventually elected in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haynes Johnson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ) credits him with bringing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbelt</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> goes against the flow to argue that
Goldwater retarded the conservative movement by not finding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> under his
robes for the poor and the religious.

            

               Have <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Stopped Beating Your Spokesman</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Bakaly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>, gave his inaugural <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> show
appearance to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> , only to have interviewers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Snow</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> run the oldest play in the book on him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bakaly</ENAMEX> says "no" to several
Snow questions, all of which essentially ask: Have you decided when to deliver
a report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hume</ENAMEX> follows by asking whether this means that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is committed to eventually delivering a report (thereby indicating that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has credible evidence of impeachable malfeasance). Bakaly, looking
positively dyspeptic, answers: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Uh</ENAMEX>. ... That's probably more accurate, without
making a definitive statement." Possibly, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bakaly</ENAMEX> meant to give the impression
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has a good hand without formally stating anything, but more likely
it was an unintentional snafu.

            
               Read
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chaucer Lately</ENAMEX>? The entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> laughs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX>'s
views on whether the title "intern" qualifies as a de facto double-entendre. He
contends that, in common conversation, "intern" can signify something akin to
sexual receptacle, ergo no respectable young thing would accept the job
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>'s most laughable observation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delight</ENAMEX> in double-entendres is
a largely contemporary fascination.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
