
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fish Called Lucent</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Underwater Alt</ENAMEX> ,
produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCann-Erickson</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent Technologies</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Underwater Alt</ENAMEX> (the
"alt" in the title is for "alternative"--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> saw several executions of
this spot) is the newest ad in a series by advertising powerhouse
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCann-Erickson for Lucent Technologies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that was once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lab</ENAMEX>.

            At the most obvious level,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Underwater Alt</ENAMEX> is just chyron writing on a computer screen. As the
tap-tap-tap of the spot's message glides across the screen, the keyboardist
provides the voice-over at the same speed he types. We don't see the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">keyboardist</ENAMEX>--we intuit him based on the visual and audio clues.

            "This is a demonstration,"
our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator types</ENAMEX>. A demonstration of what? The screen and the clacking keys
suggest it has to be something high tech. As we cut from a close-up to a wider
view, we're informed that the product is "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent wireless</ENAMEX> systems and
technology." In fact, no one specific product is hyped.

            Water edges into the frame
from below, as if the computer screen is not just a computer screen but also a
big, clear bowl. The rising tide distorts the words ("this is now just about
the only place") and then swamps them ("where you can't stay in touch."). As
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> fills the screen, a goldfish swims by.

            "Any questions?" our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator types</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> turns to face the camera, as if it might have one, and
then swims away because, of course, we can't communicate down here. The fish
swims into the next scene, across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> name and into the last frame,
complete with name, logo, and a reference to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Labs Innovations</ENAMEX>" (there's
equity left in the old corporate identity).

            Finally, the spot delivers
an explicit message: "We make the things that make communications work," says
and types the keyboardist. At the same time, an air bubble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">burps</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>,
making it seem as if we're listening to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>'s thoughts.

            The brand-name advertising
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Underwater Alt</ENAMEX> aims to associate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX> with the futuristic, high-end
segment of the communications web. And by soft-selling the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX> is
inventing the future for everyone (except for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>), the spot disarms potential
technophobes by banishing techy talk and visuals.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
