
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>

             

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX> has been drunk
and the fireworks exploded. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s real test as a special
administrative region of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> begins.

            
Politically, the façade of the old colonial government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>--a strong
executive, a weak <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>, and an efficient but politically neutral civil
service--will continue. Economically, the stock market and property booms will
continue in the short term if money still flows in from the mainland and
elsewhere. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> ahead, though, is bumpy. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> needs to control rising
costs and create jobs quickly for a large number of unskilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>.

            More clues about post-1997 <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> will become evident at
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Congress of the Communist Party of China</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this autumn</TIMEX>. If
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> emerges more
confident of its power, this will give <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> more leeway to run its own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX>. If not, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>'s autonomy will suffer. More than ever, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX>'s fate will be intertwined with that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, because the buffer provided
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">150 years</TIMEX> has been removed.

            Some
rollback of democracy is inevitable, as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> will not tolerate an
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> run by outspoken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and longtime human-rights
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> like those in the last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislative Council</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Legco</ENAMEX>") elected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
That is the main reason <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> disbanded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1995</TIMEX> council and formed the
so-called provisional <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Legco</ENAMEX>, which is dominated by appointed pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has already ensured that it will have
the final say in important matters by appointing those with proven loyalty to
top administrative positions. Next, it wants to make sure that it can influence
the outcome of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislative Council</ENAMEX> election, promised by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1998</TIMEX>. It could
do so by arranging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> into small, industry-based electoral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. This
would amount to a de facto shrinking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>. However, it would be
justified internationally as being akin to the electoral system that existed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> prior to the democratic reforms introduced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>'s last
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Patten</ENAMEX>, in the face of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> objections.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>
will further sideline independent-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Lee</ENAMEX> and opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Szeto Wah</ENAMEX>. The danger is that the
voice of lower-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> will not be heard in a government machinery
dominated by big business and mainland <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> will calculate that
the historically shallow roots of popular political movements in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> will
limit the magnitude of this risk.

            Overall, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> will still enjoy more political
autonomy than the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. There will be open, public debate
of issues, as well as civil disobedience by political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>. Chief
Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tung Chee-hwa</ENAMEX> will also be able to negotiate with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> for a
degree of administrative leeway unthinkable for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> on the
mainland.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">judiciary</ENAMEX> , run by respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, should be able to remain
independent, except when it is handling highly sensitive, politicized cases in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>'s central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> is at stake. For the press, there will be
self-censorship, but heavy-handed interference from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> seems unlikely.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> important check against any abuse of power
by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> is international attention. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have
urged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to conduct fair, competitive elections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. There will also
be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s political and human-rights situation in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Congress</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, and other international
forums.

            For
business, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> is still a good place to make money , an increasing
amount of which will come from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>'s gross domestic product is
expected to grow by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997 and 1998</TIMEX>, up from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.7</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. Unemployment has dropped to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.6 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between February</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1997</TIMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.3 percent</NUMEX> in the same period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has encouraged more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to come to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> to fill the commercial vacuum left by departing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jardine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> have
taken stakes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong Kong Telecom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dragon Air</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Light & Power</ENAMEX>.
More strategic takeovers are likely; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong Kong Electric</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong Kong Bank</ENAMEX> are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime targets</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> alone, big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> affiliated
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministries</ENAMEX> and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17.5 billion Hong Kong dollars</NUMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">U.S. $2.26 billion</NUMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and the stock market. Such large-scale fund
raising has confirmed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s unique status as the Wall Street of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            The stock
market will continue to prosper in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming months</TIMEX> if more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> money
rushes into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>-based brokerage estimates that inflows will
grow to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75.94 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24 percent</NUMEX> more than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. Part of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">torrent</ENAMEX> has moved into the local property market, raising prices by as much as
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> for prime residential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">blocks</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half of this year</TIMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tung</ENAMEX> has vowed to crack down on property
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX> , but many think his bark will be worse than his bite. The
government itself relies on revenue from land sales to finance its budget,
while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are too heavily exposed in property lending to allow any property
downturn. Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tung</ENAMEX> is likely to impose some short-term measures, such as a
capital gains tax, to show that he is serious about tackling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s
housing shortage , which is its most visible economic problem. In his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> policy speech following the handover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tung</ENAMEX> promised to accelerate
government land sales, with the ambitious aim of raising the proportion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowners</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s long-term
prospects are mixed . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> has not invested enough in
technology and developing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human resources</ENAMEX> to meet the needs of its increasingly
service-based economy. Instead, capital has gone to property investment,
inflating asset prices and making the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> the most expensive in the world. The
issue will become more pressing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as an estimated 40,000 to 50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>,
mostly unskilled, come to settle <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>. Others say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> has enough
vitality to adjust itself to the needs of the future and that the government
does not need to intervene. Tung, however, has indicated that he wishes to
support manufacturing, even though the sector accounts for a mere <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s GDP (depending on what definition is used). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tung</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> salvo as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> is likely to include the introduction of
policies to help develop long-term, high-tech industries, a special challenge
in a place where short-term financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> and property <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> have
helped many to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX> overnight.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">© July</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford Analytica Ltd.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred St.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">OX1 4EH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX> Any
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reproduction</ENAMEX> in whole or in part without the written consent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analytica Ltd.</ENAMEX> is strictly forbidden.
            

         
      
   
