
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Scrotum 
               Tightening
            

            Just in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomsday</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> publisher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Picador</ENAMEX> has issued a new
"reader-friendly" edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulysses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> are
declaring it a travesty. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> alleged improvements include punctuating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Bloom</ENAMEX>'s famous monologue and rewriting knotty sentences. Some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danis Rose</ENAMEX>'s changes may seem merely cosmetic--the famous evocation of the
"scrotumtightening sea," for example, appears as "scrotum-tightening." But, as
a reviewer in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> noted, adding that hyphen "loses the contractive
effect on the male appendages of an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early-morning</TIMEX> dip." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indignant Joyceans</ENAMEX> also
quarrel with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose</ENAMEX> for fiddling with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>'s use of dialect (substituting "Cor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blimey</ENAMEX>" for "God blimey") and slicing the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oxen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>" chapter into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
separate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX>. Perhaps the most vocal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> has been <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston University</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kidd</ENAMEX>, who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> also exposed legions of errors in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans Walter Gabler</ENAMEX>'s
so-called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corrected Text" of Ulysses</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kidd</ENAMEX>'s own <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-volume <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton</ENAMEX>
edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulysses</ENAMEX> is due out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov</ENAMEX>'s
Blues
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov</ENAMEX>'s taxonomies of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX>, long disparaged as armchair
entomology, turn out to be top-drawer science, according to a recent article in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX>, the émigré <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> held a part-time
job at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Comparative Zoology</ENAMEX> and published the first
attempted classification of an obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of blue <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX> known as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polyommatini</ENAMEX> . For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov's</ENAMEX> study attracted more attention from
literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> than from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, lepidopterists <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Johnson</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zsolt Balint</ENAMEX> embarked on a new study of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX>, and then compared
their results with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov's</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duo</ENAMEX>'s findings are published in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nabokov</ENAMEX> as
Lepidopterist: An <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Informed Appraisal</ENAMEX>," in the current issue of Nabokov
Studies . Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> generic names established by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nabokov</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> were
deemed still valid, and the two mistakes could be attributed to his not having
had enough samples. In recognition of this achievement, the lepidopterists have
christened some recently discovered specimens of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polyommatini</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokovian</ENAMEX> names, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madeleinea</ENAMEX> lolita .

            
               Suicidal
Tendencies
            

            Using the
same data, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> leading medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> have reached opposite
conclusions on the consequences of legalizing assisted suicide. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last winter</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Journal of Medicine</ENAMEX> surveyed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX> and found that, despite euthanasia-friendly laws, the country
had experienced no significant upswing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>-assisted deaths. An
accompanying editorial argued that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> experience should alleviate
fears that legalizing assisted suicide would lead to "widespread involuntary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">euthanasia</ENAMEX>" performed on society's weakest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. A new report in the
at the same questionnaires and claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>-assisted deaths in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX> have in fact skyrocketed--by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27 percent</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">questionnaires</ENAMEX> also revealed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX> says, that an alarming number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">physicians</ENAMEX> had administered fatal doses of painkillers to "fully competent"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> without their approval. Now each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> is accusing the other of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">masking</ENAMEX> political commentary as science. For more on the assisted-suicide
issue, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>."

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showalter Fan Club</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Showalter</ENAMEX>'s recent polemic, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hystories: Hysterical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epidemics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Media</ENAMEX> , argues that such supposedly organic illnesses
as <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Chronic Fatigue and Gulf War</ENAMEX> syndromes are simply psychological disorders.
The claim has so angered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chronic Fatigue Syndrome</ENAMEX> sufferers that they've turned
out in large numbers to heckle <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Showalter</ENAMEX> on her book tour. They've also erected
a Web
Site devoted to debunking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Showalter</ENAMEX>'s arguments. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> section, called
"Handling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Showalter</ENAMEX>," suggests questions for sufferers to ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> when she
swings by their local bookshop, such as: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Elaine projecting</ENAMEX>? Isn't it true
that those who have emotional problems often project their problems onto
others? And so, aren't you yourself doing this?" Other recommended questions
include: "Are you psychiatric<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How well is Elaine?</ENAMEX>" On another page,
which features testimonies from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've had run-ins with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Showalter</ENAMEX>, one
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, contributor recounts asking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> to sign his copy of
the book--with an apology.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX>
Talk
            

            A recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>
claimed to rebut <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noam Chomsky</ENAMEX>'s theory that our capacity for language is
hard-wired in a particular--and uniquely human--module of the brain. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three cognitive</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Rochester</ENAMEX> played
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-minute</TIMEX> audiotapes consisting of short nonsense words (such as "bidakupado")
for a group of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-month-old babies</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX>, they found, listened longer to
subsequent tapes that didn't contain these words than to those that
did--suggesting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> had "learned" the words. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rochester</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>, the findings suggest that our language-learning abilities may have to do
with our general cognitive prowess, not with any particular language "module."
But a gallery of letters published in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 23</TIMEX> issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> says this finding hardly undermines <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chomskyan</ENAMEX> linguistics.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Pinker</ENAMEX> argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rochester</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> fail to comprehend
that "learning words and learning grammar are ... different computational
problems." In other words, it's not our vocabularies but our ability to string
words together that is a distinctively human evolutionary adaptation.

            

               Veritas
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University</ENAMEX>
owned up to some embarrassing real-estate deals. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past eight years</TIMEX>, the
school acquired <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $88 million</NUMEX> of real estate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Allston</ENAMEX> section of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> without revealing its identity to prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX>. At first, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> excused the ploy by saying that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community members</ENAMEX> had known they
were dealing with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 billion</NUMEX>, they would have demanded
exorbitant premiums. After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menino</ENAMEX> raised a ruckus, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>'s communications <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> admitted
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> had committed a "breach of trust," and promised to be more "up
front" in future maneuvers.

            

               --Compiled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lingua Franca</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Review of Academic</ENAMEX>
Life . Click here
to visit their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> or to subscribe.
            

         
      
   
