
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX> Go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Map</ENAMEX> , produced
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goddard</ENAMEX>*Claussen/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">First Tuesday</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Climate Information</ENAMEX>
Project.

            The ad agency that helped
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scuttle Clinton</ENAMEX>'s health plan with the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX>" spots is back with an
attack on the global-warming treaty, which is scheduled to be signed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Map</ENAMEX> , produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goddard</ENAMEX>*Claussen/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">First Tuesday</TIMEX>,
is different in style from the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX>" spots, but similar in
fundamentals. Its message is simple and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX>, and its visual elements
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">linger</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX>'s mind long after the ad ends.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> shot is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">graphic</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The World According</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>"--which exploits the national
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> suspicion that "good" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will always be outsmarted by "clever"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>. The isolationism that prevailed until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 years ago</TIMEX> was rooted
in--and reinforced--that belief, and it has yet to fade. Why does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX> vote against us when we pay most of the bills?

            The graphic dissolves to a
world map, and a hand appears to grasp a pair of scissors. The voice-over
informs us that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is "preparing to sign" the global-warming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treaty</ENAMEX> and the image warns us that there's a catch--or a cut. Just as campaign
spots confer legitimacy to their charges by citing a source, this one quotes
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> as saying that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">132</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> will be exempt from the treaty.
The scissors snip <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> out of the map to reinforce
the point. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will be "forced to make drastic cuts in energy,"
the spot says, while these other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> do nothing.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>--and later,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>--are clipped out for good measure. The free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">riders</ENAMEX> are all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North African</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX>. Sub-Saharan <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, which are also
exempt from the emissions portions of the treaty, aren't singled out. One
reason may be that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> of the spot include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Chamber of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>. Another is that all but the most xenophobic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> recognize that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX> is so economically desperate that it can't afford to sacrifice
anything.

            Citing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> again--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Energy</ENAMEX>--the voice-over explains that
the exempt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> are "responsible for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX> the world's emissions." In
fact, the treaty does shield the developing world on the grounds that advanced
economies like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> have already harvested <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than</NUMEX>
their share of the gains from industrialization.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Map</ENAMEX> suggests
that the treaty is a hidden form of foreign aid--one of the most unpopular of
all federal programs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> has already voted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95-0</NUMEX> against an exemption
for developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, although the resolution was carefully worded not to
demand equal cutbacks for those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> because this would leave many
low-energy-consuming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with little or no right to burn any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>.

            As the hands hold up the map
with gaping holes where there were once <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> assumes that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> has been played for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> again. No wonder the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration has been debating whether it should even send <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyoto</ENAMEX> conference.

            The ad offers to provide
additional "facts" with a toll-free number (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">888-54FACTS</ENAMEX>) and a Web address
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">climatefacts</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>). The list of sponsoring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> goes beyond auto
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, who are almost certainly paying the bulk of the broadcast costs,
to include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, and small business. There are other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> not
themselves in rare agreement. For big business, populism has its occasional
uses.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Broadcasters</ENAMEX> are required to
accept ads for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, but not for issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> briefly refused to continue
running this spot because, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> alleged, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Fonda</ENAMEX>,
didn't approve. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> denied that accusation and the spot is back on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>,
but it understandably infuriates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX>. Depending on your point of
view, the ad is either edgy or diabolical. But nobody can deny its
effectiveness. A map with holes in it is a mnemonic for the global-warming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treaty</ENAMEX> and its supposedly glaring loopholes. Whenever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> hear of the
treaty again, the first thing they're likely to think of is that map--just as
the phrase "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> health plan" came to trigger the picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX> being denied the right to choose their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>.

            The health plan lost. If
this spot is any indication, so will the treaty. Complex proposals and
positions don't fare well in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-second</TIMEX> debates--especially when
the negative spots are as well done as this one and as well grounded in
ingrained popular attitudes. So look for warmer weather ahead.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
