
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clownin</ENAMEX>' With the Commentariat

             

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUNDIT CENTRAL</ENAMEX>" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>'s
prosecution of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> on wiretapping charges. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
will actually pass a health insurance reform bill. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> is the related
question of whether this particular session is a do-nothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Mostly,
though, the opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> decides to spend time trading bons mots. With
relative stillness <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, and the world of international diplomacy (excepting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>,
unfortunately), the commentariat must clown about to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>'s
attention. From the standpoint of wit, rather than substance, it is a good
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>.

            Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>'s timing--he began his wiretapping
prosecution just as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> began her testimony for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>--is highly suspect.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) think it poetic that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> is caught up in a politically
motivated, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mickey Mouse</ENAMEX> charge, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is using her against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in the same way. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) note that the main issue is still the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
behavior.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Amajority of the commentariat</ENAMEX> thinks that HMO reform
strikes a chord with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in a way that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> and campaign finance reform
did not. The big dispute between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will likely be over
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> can sue their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>, predicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Borger</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ). A bill will surely be passed--and soon--predicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
has recently been accused of doing nothing of importance recently. This is
true, say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Bechloss</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> ( This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ). The reason
is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are generally quite content, say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doyle McManus</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> )--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> don't want to rock the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>.

            

               I Work in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics; COBOL Programming Is</ENAMEX>
Just My <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hobby</ENAMEX>: The surest proof that political talk shows lack fodder this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> dedicating <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first 10 minutes</TIMEX> of his program to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX> bug. Can someone please tell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX> why exactly the
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> feel comfortable holding forth
on a supremely technical arcanum? Worse still, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX> threatens to become the
preferred <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Think Question</ENAMEX> for TV talk shows over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 18 months</TIMEX>, as
modeled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interrupting IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Rossotti</ENAMEX>'s thoughtful discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> legislative reform, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX>
bursts out with: "Are you ready for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>? Are the codes in your
computers all changed now?"

            
               While
We're on the Subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Y2K</ENAMEX>: The biggest howler of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ), who suggests that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> bug might
have a silver lining because it puts computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX> to work. A majority
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> believes that during a severe depression--which certainly doesn't
describe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> right now--it's important to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do make-work
(digging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ditches</ENAMEX> or restoring hiking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> will also do). But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>
doubts you could find a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> who would classify a slew of COBOL
programmers fixing antiquated mainframe systems as either a consumable good or
service. Of course any sane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> recognizes the importance of paying computer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> to fix oncoming problems (just as it is important that plumbers fix
antiquated pipes), but the use of their time is a cost, not a benefit.

            

               Wait and See? But Won't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Producers</ENAMEX> Be
Angry? Said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Bode</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ): "We're going to
skip [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWIR</ENAMEX> ] the possibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> testifying
at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s trial and--blah, blah, blah--for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, and I think our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> probably will be happy to hear that we are going to skip it. We'll see
if it happens."

            
               Good
Point: 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> 's round table signs off by predicting the outcome
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> final. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX> was right (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> won), but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>
admits he picked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> just because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> would be insufferable if they
won.

            

               But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Which Lady Republican</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) reports: "One lady <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> said to me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, 'If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> switch places, the murder rate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
would triple and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> would be indicted.' " On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> he
relates another borrowed quip (from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris Udall</ENAMEX>): "When <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> form a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">firing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX>, they form a circle."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson Admits</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beating Drug-Addicted Wife</ENAMEX>! In a discussion on the effectiveness of
anti-drug ads, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) says, "I have not used any drugs
since I saw that frying pan ad." (Later during the show she proposes to pay
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> per minute to keep his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yap</ENAMEX> shut. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> chip
in. But can these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> compete with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s deep pockets?)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">McGrory Chimes in:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary McGrory</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ) on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who once
covered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and recently gave an interview discussing a shared but
unconsummated moment with him--"[<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Journalists</ENAMEX>] are supposed to talk about news,
not things that didn't happen. I mean we have enough with completed passes, we
don't need to go into incomplete passes."

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
