
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sid Vicious</ENAMEX> and the Sex Pistol

             

            
Pundit-turned-presidential<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-spinner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, who testified before
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>, is Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> subpoena
prosecutorial overkill, the commentariat diagnoses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> as having a chronic
case of political "tin ear," and gives <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> subpoena
achieved the near impossible by making "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sid Vicious</ENAMEX>" a sympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>,
adding, "you can't investigate the press" and hope to come out on top.
"Absolutely stupid," agrees <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
"played right into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> strategy" by calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Duffy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ), making the independent
counsel the issue instead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sex Pistol</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX>.

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accuse Clinton</ENAMEX> of subverting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> investigation, but their pro-prosecutor
flyer plummets when fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Limbaugh</ENAMEX> agrees with them. (Pundit
Central to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limbaugh</ENAMEX>: Read your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McLuhan</ENAMEX>. TV is cooler than radio. Tone it down a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tad</ENAMEX>, or at least bring a froth cup when you appear before cameras.) Former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Thornburgh</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) defends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
tin ear for politics as precisely what you want in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. Yet even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thornburgh</ENAMEX> acknowledges that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is "overmatched" in his duel. He doesn't
understand the game, and the law prohibits him from fighting back in
public.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) takes the long view of the
investigation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has placed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in "a very serious box," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>
says, where he is vulnerable to charges of perjury, suborning of perjury, and
obstruction of justice. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> scoff at the trial balloon
reported on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS Evening News</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and semisourced to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> only played kissy face.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Gordon</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ) calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>'s deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>--Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>--more a "truce
than a final settlement." Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> (notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> of Late
Edition and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) fall in line
behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX>, expressing relief that there is no war and applauding the
agreement in principle, but predicting that the whole conflict will be
revisited in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of months</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX> strafe the deal, because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX> did the legwork. "This is what happens when you
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">subcontract American</ENAMEX> foreign policy," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is now "hostage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ). Fringe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> complains on his show that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is still "frozen into a military response" to the crisis,
when the proper response should be more diplomacy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Issue 3,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Paxon</ENAMEX>'s announcement that he's leaving politics when his term ends,
so shocks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> that some of them (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Beirne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gang</ENAMEX> ) accept his advertised reason--the standard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> lie that he
wants to spend more time with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Beirne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> should be disbarred
for their simple-mindedness.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Go-Round</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Duffy</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review :</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> was investigating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
for investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> for investigating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>."

            
               Ad
Hominem of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Week</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang : "Bob and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldine Novak</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and are so because, in
large part, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> didn't spend time on them when they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>."

            

               How to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Watch Washington Week in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back</ENAMEX> to front. The show vainly leads <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX> with a
high-minded story designed to appeal to good-government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s
top item (yawn): the scuttling of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX>. As usual, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> doesn't get around to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>'s real thing (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>) until the
closer. Even though <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week</ENAMEX> 's treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> is
inordinately polite, it is worth watching--but only if you don't watch the rest
of the show <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.

            
               
                  This <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADM</ENAMEX> ? Less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> abandoned the serviceable name of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> for the overfamiliar <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> 
               With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam &</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cokie</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> the show switched to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> . Fending off its diligent and talented copy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, Pundit
Central rejects the new name as too long and too inelegant for even a first
mention. Henceforth, this column will refer to the show as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX>
until either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> wins top billing.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
