
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinky Stuff</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Press</ENAMEX> is publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Art of Desire: Erotic Treasures From the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey Institute</ENAMEX> , an exhibition catalog accompanying the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> survey of
the erotica collected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 50 years</TIMEX>. The book,
complete with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> illustrations, follows closely on the heels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James H. Jones</ENAMEX>'
hostile biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Kinsey</ENAMEX> and seems designed, in part, to counter the
bad impression left by that book. While the catalog does contain some
potentially controversial material, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rezso Merényi</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mouse Kiss</ENAMEX> , a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX> etching of "a grand-scale vagina juxtaposed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>," the selection, made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey Institute</ENAMEX> itself, mostly highlights
the highbrow elements of the collection, such as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chagall</ENAMEX> lithograph
displaying some mild <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">buttock fondling</ENAMEX>. In order to "sustain a celebratory
tone," write the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators</ENAMEX>, "representations of certain sexual practices or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fantasies</ENAMEX> (those judged by common consensus pathological) were ruled
inappropriate for our overarching agenda." The truly weird stuff can be seen
only by appointment. (Here's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey Institute</ENAMEX>'s Web site.)

            
               It Isn't
All Relative
            

            Recent
discoveries prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Einstein</ENAMEX> was indeed the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to explicate the
general theory of relativity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Historians</ENAMEX> of science have long questioned
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> truly discovered the idea, or whether the honor goes to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Göttingen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hilbert</ENAMEX>, who submitted a paper on the subject
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> turned in his work. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>'s paper was
published <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilbert</ENAMEX> maintained that he was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to have solved some
key field equations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>, furious, charged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilbert</ENAMEX> with plagiarism.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> was right. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilbert</ENAMEX>'s proofs, found this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Max Planck Institute</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>, reveal that crucial steps were missing at the time of his submission,
which were filled in only after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> came out. In an article in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> , the research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that scrutinized the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drafts</ENAMEX> concludes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilbert</ENAMEX> "revised his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>'s work." It's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> big
blow to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilbert</ENAMEX>'s legacy: His audacious attempt to ground all mathematics in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">finite</ENAMEX> number of axioms was upended by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gödel</ENAMEX>'s incompleteness theorem in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX>.

            
               Mine
Kampf
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
mining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> has discovered that <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.5 million tons</NUMEX> of coal lie buried beneath
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newstead Abbey</ENAMEX>, the family estate of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is poised to begin
digging on the dilapidated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nottinghamshire</ENAMEX> property. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> are
concerned that the fragile 800-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">purchased by the Byron</ENAMEX>
family from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry VIII</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1540</TIMEX>) might collapse if the excavation proceeds. The
strongest protests come not from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>, however, but from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
ones. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron</ENAMEX>, who led the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> armed forces in their fight for independence
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1824</TIMEX>, is considered a national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scholars</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX> are leading the campaign to protect the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abbey</ENAMEX>'s romantic ruins. In response, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midlands Mining</ENAMEX> promises that no harm will
come to the abbey, which provided a moody backdrop to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Childe Harold</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Juan</ENAMEX> .

            
               Body
Conscious
            

            The hot
topic at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Language Association</ENAMEX> meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> will be Disability
Studies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scholars</ENAMEX> in the field decode and debunk the literary tropes that
rhetorically separate "normal" from "abnormal" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>. Essays to be delivered
at the conference, which will take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this December</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>, include
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Sacks</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P.T</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnum</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postmodern World</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Of Angels</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pig-Faced Ladies</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Disordering Victorian Desire</ENAMEX>." Much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> champion
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Awakening</ENAMEX> and lesbian-studies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> vaunt <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Well</ENAMEX> of
Loneliness , disability-studies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> promise to uncover a slew of
founding texts written by the differently abled. One such work is the
long-forgotten <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1841</TIMEX> memoir <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Narrative of the Experience and Sufferings of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Dodd</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Factory Cripple, Written By Himself</ENAMEX> . A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> student
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California at Irvine</ENAMEX> will present an analysis of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Londoner</ENAMEX>'s autobiography at the conference.

            
               Early
Music
            

            An
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50,000-year-old</TIMEX> fragment of bear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX>, found at an excavated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Neanderthal</ENAMEX> hunting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">present-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slovenia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, may be the oldest
known musical instrument. It contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> circular punctures that eerily evoke
a flute. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paleontologist Ivan Turk</ENAMEX>, who discovered the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX>, recently told
Scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> holes are "really well rounded and
just about the right separation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> to put their finger on." And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fink</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicologist</ENAMEX>, thinks the hole spacing proves that the
bone-flute was "inescapably diatonic," suggesting that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-tone "Western
scale" may be much older than we thought. (His analysis
is posted on the Web.) Based on the fragment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fink</ENAMEX> speculates that the original
flute contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least six</NUMEX> holes and was close to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">16 inches</NUMEX> long. Not all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anthropologists</ENAMEX> agree. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T. Temple Tuttle</ENAMEX>, an ethnomusicologist at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University</ENAMEX>, feels the holes conform to "a number of scales," including
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Indian</ENAMEX> system.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empire Strikes Back</ENAMEX>
            

            A
book-review <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> says she was pressured to retire this past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> after she published a negative review of a book that claimed to defend
science from postmodern critiques. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">review</ENAMEX> was of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Superstition</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Left</ENAMEX> and Its <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quarrels With Science</ENAMEX> , written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
Gross and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Levitt</ENAMEX>. The article's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">curator Paul Forman</ENAMEX>, accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gross</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levitt</ENAMEX> of trying to place "science back
on its pre-postmodern pedestal." After the review was published, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>
received a flood of angry telephone calls and letters, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
in question, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Livingston</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Mason University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Trefil</ENAMEX>, for
instance, complained that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forman "</ENAMEX>gets into material he does not appear to
understand. ... You couldn't possibly have published a better parody of what
passes for scholarship in the postmodern world.") In an interview with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle for Higher Education</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levitt</ENAMEX> took credit for launching the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">letter-writing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>: "I was mad as hell that such an irresponsible review
had run in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> ," he said. After reading the complaints,
Science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Bloom</ENAMEX> formally reprimanded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX> and
took away control of the book-review section.

            
               Earth
Loses Its Balance
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Geologists</ENAMEX> say that the
concept of continental drift may need to be revised to account for some sudden
reshufflings that took place in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s past. Basing their theories on evidence
found in magnetite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grains</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caltech</ENAMEX> posit
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that 550 million years ago</TIMEX>, continents at the poles scooted toward the equator
while equatorial continents shimmied to the poles, all within a mere <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 million</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. (Typically, a continental shift takes much longer to complete.) What
caused the flip-flop? The stability lent by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> opposing supercontinents,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gondwanaland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodinia</ENAMEX>, was disrupted when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodinia</ENAMEX> began to fracture. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s
balance was thrown off, and a massive migration was required to regain
planetary equanimity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Kirschvink</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caltech</ENAMEX> geophysicist, suggests that
this upheaval may have enhanced the workings of evolution. "Each time you
disrupt an ecosystem, you break it into small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, where evolution
works fastest," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirschvink</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
