
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Scent of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woman</ENAMEX>
            

            Two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thousand years</TIMEX> after her death, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleopatra</ENAMEX>'s famously irresistible fragrances
are available again. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
archaeologists excavated a perfume <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>, which dates back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleopatra</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reign</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 miles</NUMEX> south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dead Sea</ENAMEX>. Among other things, the archaeologists
found grinding wheels and vials containing dried pollens. Inspired by these
findings as well as by ancient perfume recipes preserved in the writings of
Pliny the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elder</ENAMEX>, a fragrance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irene Saltzman</ENAMEX>, has re-created
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> historic
scents for popular use. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saltzman</ENAMEX> insists her recipes are as authentic as
possible. She uses no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and imports many of her ingredients from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. The perfumes are available for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22</NUMEX> each.

            
               More
Archaeological Updates
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pompeii</ENAMEX>, destroyed by a volcanic eruption in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.D.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX>, faces
further destruction, this time from tourism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> reports
that the site, which attracts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 million</NUMEX> visitors a year, suffers from extensive
vandalism, theft, and chronic funding shortages, as well as from pedestrian
wear and tear. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only 17</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 800</NUMEX> excavated villas are currently open to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is considering various preservation
measures, including corporate sponsorship of individual villas on the site.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiat</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobile</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>, is interested, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> oppose
the idea of "privatizing" the national heritage. ... Archaeologists
digging under the ruins of the residential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> tyrant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nero</ENAMEX> earlier
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> stumbled on an astonishing find: a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-foot-by-6-foot</NUMEX> fresco, faded
but almost completely intact. The mural appears to be an aerial view of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> as
it looked before the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Fire of A.D. 64</ENAMEX>, which the megalomaniacal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nero</ENAMEX> is
believed to have set himself.

            
               Scratch
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'n' Sniff</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Doctors</ENAMEX>
have developed a smell test for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX>. It has long been known that the
breath and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> odors of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> suffering from serious mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX> are
distinctive, but now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> have developed a skin-sweat test for
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX> and are working on a breath test. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> of the test are a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of clinicians at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highland Psychiatric Research Group</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Inverness</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, working alongside sniff-science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneer Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Dodd</ENAMEX>, who founded
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX> for olfactory research in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodd</ENAMEX> who helped to
develop the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> generation of electronic noses, which produce electric
signals in the presence of various molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">compounds</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodd</ENAMEX> is optimistic that
smell tests could become a front-line diagnostic tool. Eventually, he says, the
electronic nose could diagnose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> over the telephone.

            
               An <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Affair</ENAMEX>
to Remember
            

            
Presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> sex-scandal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX> has
chosen a sometime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> of presidential sexuality to help him write his
memoirs. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Education</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collaborator</ENAMEX> will be legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annette Gordon-Reed</ENAMEX>, an untenured professor
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University</ENAMEX>'s law school, who swept to prominence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> with the
publication of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Hemings</ENAMEX>: An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Controversy . Hailed as the definitive account of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s long-rumored
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love</ENAMEX> affair with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Hemings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon-Reed</ENAMEX>'s book argues that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> should give credence to the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> and their
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. (For 
                  Slate
               's take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon-Reed</ENAMEX>'s book, click
here.)

            
               And if
You Believe That ...
            

            Several
con-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> schemes have emerged in academia. One scam, reported in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle of Higher Education</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, involves a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> posing as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Development Bank</ENAMEX> or as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>. He telephones <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and invites them to a
conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>. Soon, the invitees are being asked to wire money to
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">courier</ENAMEX> claiming to be on his way to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to deliver the conference
invitations. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> claims that he has been robbed en route and is stranded
without money or his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> ticket in an airport somewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. Moved by this plea for help, the duped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> promptly wires the
individual a loan of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $3,700</NUMEX>. After learning that one of its members
had been taken in by the scheme, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East Studies Association</ENAMEX> posted a
warning on its Web site. ... Another scheme, reported by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last May</TIMEX>, was the case of a fast-talking ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convict</ENAMEX> who
convinced dozens of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> that he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> of esteemed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX> race
and sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Edwards</ENAMEX>. Among those fooled by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> Degrees
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Separation</ENAMEX> -style setup was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Julius Wilson</ENAMEX>,
who lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$175</NUMEX>.

            
               Deleuze
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodo Birds</ENAMEX>
            

            High <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> theory has
finally conquered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s book market. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, postmodernist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-FranÃ</ENAMEX>§ois <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lyotard</ENAMEX> published <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Postmoderne</ENAMEX> expliquÃ© aux enfants
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Postmodernism Explained to Children</ENAMEX> ), and the book became a must-read
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate students</ENAMEX> everywhere.

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s book was recently published in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> based on excerpts from the
works of the even trendier and more arcane <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilles Deleuze</ENAMEX>, the late <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> philosopher and celebrated author
of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Anti-Oedipus</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacqueline DuhÃªme</ENAMEX>, a former model for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Matisse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Eluard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pablo Picasso</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Queneau</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DuhÃªme</ENAMEX>, who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> makes her living as a graphic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> and illustrator, calls
her book (in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bird of Philosophy</ENAMEX> . The title was inspired by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deleuze</ENAMEX>'s cryptic musings: "Don't you think that philosophy is as pretty
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>'s name?"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trojan</ENAMEX>
Virus
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deadly Ebola</ENAMEX> virus may turn out to have a medical use, according to a recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> . A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of virologists at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Michigan</ENAMEX>
Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann Arbor</ENAMEX> has reportedly identified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebola</ENAMEX>'s molecular attack
strategy and is hoping to exploit it to battle <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. The
virus insinuates itself into its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' bloodstreams by using a glycoprotein
(a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sugars</ENAMEX> attached to it) to disable the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>'s immune response
and blood vessels. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> would like to affix the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebola</ENAMEX> glycoprotein
to a harmless virus carrying therapeutic-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> or genetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cocktails</ENAMEX>.

            
               Rain
Forest Crunch
            

            Classical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> may be contributing to the despoliation of the rain forests.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard F. Fisher</ENAMEX>, a forest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas A&M University</ENAMEX>,
a growing demand for flutes, clarinets, and oboes made of rare tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>,
including the endangered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M'Pingo</ENAMEX>, grenadilla, and rosewood, is wreaking havoc
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South American</ENAMEX> tropics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> explains the dangers in this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientific American</ENAMEX>: Harvesters clear-cut wide swaths of forest
to reach the remote <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> grow. This encourages <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> to
move in and begin farming the land. Moreover, the prized <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 years</TIMEX> to
reach maturity and have proved resistant to plantation cultivation. One
enterprising instrument <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boosey & Hawkes</ENAMEX>, has devised a way to deal
with the problem: Make the precious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> stretch further. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
environmentally sensitive oboes and clarinets contain a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamburger Helper</ENAMEX>-style
mixture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M'Pingo</ENAMEX> sawdust, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon fiber</ENAMEX>, and epoxy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glue</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
