
   
   
      
         
            Not a Matter of Whether But of When

             

            As unchecked leads flowed
from unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, the TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> played <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>,
but shied away from playing executioner on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) seemed rattled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>' collective vehemence,
calling their swarming an "electronic lynching."

            On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, the talking heads on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> reigned somber and sincere. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) camouflaged his glee by saying that the
scandal was now in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s hands. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ) was
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of many weekend <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX> to repeat the stock formula about how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> had made this deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>: He would curb his sexual
desires while in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. If he had violated that deal by having sex
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> recited, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> would hold him accountable. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>) panel lashed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for returning to
form by giving "lawyerly, hair-splitting answers" to straightforward questions
when what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> wanted was his outraged denial (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX>). Meanwhile,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Duffy</ENAMEX> measured the evidence against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and doubted that the
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> could prove obstruction of justice.

            By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> were smelling smoke but decided
that the press still hadn't "found the fire" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Thomas</ENAMEX>, Inside
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ) sensed an
element of "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> tragedy" to the story, although he didn't specify whether he
was referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oedipus Rex or Antigone</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Germond</ENAMEX>
found it easier to cast aspersions on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in ... golf, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vernon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>, than on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> himself, demanding to know why the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> fixer
helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in her job search and to find an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina Totenberg</ENAMEX>
joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liasson</ENAMEX> in hollering for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> just to tell the truth.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kondracke</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) made it official: This crisis, he
declared, is the biggest to hit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> "since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>." He prophesied a
scenario in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> would appoint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dianne Feinstein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>.
Capital <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gang ster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>) embraced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kondracke</ENAMEX>'s view, predicting a
"prolonged impeachment" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and saying that it was not a matter of
whether but of when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would be driven out. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sworn Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> surprised all by turning <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> statesman on the issue, arguing that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> shouldn't be impeached because he lied about having sex. (Perhaps he
prefers a crippled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to a clean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> got off a
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">well-polished</ENAMEX> line, insisting that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1600 Melrose Place</ENAMEX>" isn't in the same
neighborhood as <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> came for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, feeding off new allegations unearthed by television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>: He had
been seen "alone" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>. There were
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>" to encounters. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) repeated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> were talking about resignation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> appeared on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>), Late
Edition (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> 
               With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>) to
advance the cause of impeachment--by fielding and deflecting questions about
how his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> would entertain such proceedings against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. But
even right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Snow</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) branded talk of
impeachment irresponsible.

            Resignation is another
thing: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) framed the question in terms of
"survival" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidency. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> saw the end coming in a
matter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> blushed at the prospect; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>,
who kept going on about "moral turpitude" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, seemed more
interested in having the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> crucified for his sins than in having him
impeached. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> also described the crisis as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>," all but predicting
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Sunday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> would find themselves choosing between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Distancing</ENAMEX> himself as far from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as he could, Stephanopoulos
urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to deliver a make-or-break speech from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>,
hold a press conference, and address <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Such a presidential Chautauqua
would do no good, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would have to tell the truth,
and the truth isn't on his side.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s misadventure put
lesser issues in perspective: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defiant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> bailout. Even free-lance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Rodman</ENAMEX>, who was
suspended by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX> for missing a practice, was able to see his
troubles through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lens. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX> told reporters he was doing fine, "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is having a bad damn week."

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
