
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle Kingdom</ENAMEX>

            Topic A on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> talk
shows was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Campaigngate</ENAMEX> coming in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> tussle
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> a distant <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>.

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton Kondracke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> staked the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center ground</ENAMEX> as
usual. We should "engage" the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, he said, but we should also "criticize
them." The weight of pundit opinion may have tilted ever so slightly toward the
"criticize" part of this elegant formula. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> appeared on both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
Late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edition</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> to advocate punishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> for
its human-rights violations, high trade barriers, and arms sales to rogue
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. This Week <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> needs to "stand up for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> principles" instead of "kowtowing" to the
visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> dissed his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> a
bit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> "has gone too far to roll out the carpet." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
"are playing us like a fiddle," he said.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment heavies</ENAMEX> weighed in strongly enough to
tilt the overall <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> balance back toward "engage." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Eagleburger</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) said that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should stay the successful course. Late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edition</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blankley</ENAMEX> declared that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> issue is a debate between "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>" and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>," making clear he prefers the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>. "Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> recognize that
there is a relatively small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">zone</ENAMEX> of policy dispute," he said.

            The latest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Campaigngate</ENAMEX> angle
got chewed over with the revelation that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> had leaned on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of the Interior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Babbitt</ENAMEX> to benefit one set of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> over
another regarding permission to build a(nother) gambling casino. Consensus:
This is a big deal, definitely special-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> material. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> predicted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' "everybody does it" spin
will be unspun by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, who just volunteered to appear before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>, challenging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to do the same. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX> fended off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Schieffer</ENAMEX>'s suggestion that the president
might be guilty of obstructing justice. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> graciously attributed the
administration's late delivery of subpoenaed documents to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
"sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigators</ENAMEX>," who know how to slow the process down.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> devoted the show to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campaigngate</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
talking heads bobbing in unison for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half hour</TIMEX> on the deplorable state of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX>. The "cynicism is reaching a new level," said the dependably earnest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> ventured on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> that a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">campaign-finance</ENAMEX> law would pass before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Broder</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Myers</ENAMEX> reacted like he was nuts.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> appeared on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> to explain that everything <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> does,
it does for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. "We need to innovate," he said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> times if he said it
once. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday , Hume</ENAMEX> (a part-time computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> concurred with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX>, citing the market's right to
determine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) painted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that rules with an "iron
fist" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX>).

            While there was plenty of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> shows to palaver about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s emerging
child-care initiative (and her <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> birthday), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
stock-market crash, and the reform of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, the shows were silent about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Million Woman</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. This was odd, seeing as each show makes it a point to have
a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX>. Maybe the march's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> should have held their
demonstration in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> live, instead of in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uncomfortable Truth</ENAMEX> :
Both <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Bode</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow</ENAMEX> noted the death of ace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Devroy</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> in their wrap-ups, but only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">panelist Williams</ENAMEX> was willing to disturb the dead in journalistic fashion,
saying Devroy "shouldn't have chain-smoked."

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
