
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Flowers</ENAMEX> of Banality

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poinsettias</ENAMEX> took Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">honors</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , and The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> displayed festive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Euphorbia</ENAMEX> pulcherrima on their
sets. None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> spoke about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, which are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spurge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> spoke for
themselves.

            Attempts
to elevate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55-billion</NUMEX> (and climbing) bailout
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> to Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> fizzled despite the attempts of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> shows-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>
News <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer , and This Week</ENAMEX>-- to put
it there. 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">columnist Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> cemented the consensus
opinion that the known risk of lending the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Koreans</ENAMEX> billions was far less scary
than the unknown risk of doing nothing ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ).

            Besides <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, the main theme of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> gabfests was
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year in Review</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> happily recycled their hoariest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> sound
bites in a road-rage rampage of drive-by analysis. Their quick and dirty
targets: the balanced budget; the booming economy; the campaign-finance
scandal; the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>; the stock market; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> ;
race; sex in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s economic meltdown; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>; the menace of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> press; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s good luck; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s
rotten luck; porn on the Internet; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft; Dolly</ENAMEX>. The more formulaic shows
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ) offered predictions for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> and "awards" (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Worst Politician</ENAMEX>,
Biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Loser, Brightest New Face</ENAMEX>) to disguise their lack of enterprise, while
the more somber programs dodged hard work with toasts to their last 50 years
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ), their last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ), and their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> ).

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
was the public's growing disdain for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and politics. As in previous
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> leading conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentarians</ENAMEX> celebrated political apathy
as an indication of "national health" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) and "a
sign of contentment and success of a society" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX>, Inside
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ). Giving the conservative theme greater legitimacy were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ifill</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary McGrory</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ), who
attributed the new apathy to the new prosperity. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX> is more important
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Paula Jones</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGrory</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Beschloss</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> )
linked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s lost vitality to the end of the imperial presidency, while
other <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> yakkers (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Schieffer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Carter</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodman</ENAMEX>) pinned it on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> who have failed to frame
our pressing problems (race, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> insolvency, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s issues) in
political terms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Kearns Goodwin</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) cited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s conservation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon B. Johnson</ENAMEX>'s war on poverty during
a time of prosperity as examples of how a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> can mobilize the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with a
public challenge. Now, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> ), we have a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who endorses contradictory initiatives like teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curfew</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">midnight basketball</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L Is for Legacy: Gwen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ifill</ENAMEX> double dribbled her observation that the L word currently haunting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is "legacy," not liberalism ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ).

            
               Say Something Twice, Why
Say <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It Again</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> triple dribbled his astonishment that a new
opinion poll will crown <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> ever
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour , Capital Gang , Face the Nation</ENAMEX> ).

            
               Go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> designated fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Most Boring Person</ENAMEX>" for his "predictable and platitudinous
commentary" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">on This Week</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tongue Bath</ENAMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wrapping up Evans & Novak</ENAMEX> 's "interview" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>,
serial flatterer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> offered this stroke job: "I was surprised [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>]
showed a lot of charm, maybe even charisma."

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
