
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bomb Bay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>

             

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUNDIT CENTRAL</ENAMEX>" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s nuclear tests are
Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Chung</ENAMEX>'s confession that he deposited <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> military funds
into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> coffers takes Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Scrapping in the distance for
Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> status are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s antitrust problems, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> unrest, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> peace talks.

            The
commentariat polishes its worry beads over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> tests. (See
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Week/The</ENAMEX>
Spin" for more on the framing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Asian</ENAMEX> nuclear issue.) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Eleanor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clift</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) calls the explosions "a giant finger to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>" But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> sanctions, which are required by law, won't sway <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> from its
path or stem nuclear proliferation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has "a lot of sticks but no
carrots," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ). All agree
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-8</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>' refusal to back the sanctions weakens the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
position.

            At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">midweek</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> blamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence
establishment for failing to predict the blasts, but by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>
agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s intention to light up a few nukes was obvious . The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BJP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s ruling party, is merely making good on its recent campaign promise
to test the devices (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ).

            Sympathy for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> abounds on
the shows. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Barone</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) defends <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s right
to test its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, citing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' "de facto military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>"
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s biggest regional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX>. Fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Group ies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mort Zuckerman</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carney</ENAMEX> decry <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> neglect of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> as justification for the tests.
"It's kind of hard to blame [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>]," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> ( This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ). The way out? Let <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> join the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">club</ENAMEX> by signing and honoring
the test-ban treaty (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>). The
world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> this out after it ruffled feathers with its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> nuclear tests earlier in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kristol</ENAMEX>
draws just short of calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> "a helpless, pitiful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>" as he
extracts this moral from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s tests: "The signal has gone out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
is not serious" about policing rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. He also compares the tests to
similar intransigence on the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. "I don't think you can
keep this genie in the bottle," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ). The
consensus is that too many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, among
others--have advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> technology for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to police the
beat effectively. "We can't stop <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> from supplying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>!" gripes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX>.

            
Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>--the report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> military
contributed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Chung</ENAMEX>--redeems <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX> When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the beginning of last summer</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearings that he would prove a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> effort to subvert the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
electoral process, he was characterized as an overreaching conspiracist. Now
he's considered a prophet (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> ). The conspicuous absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spinners playing
"defense" on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> shows adds substance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chung</ENAMEX> report, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ) contributes the overstatement of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> when he fuses the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> money story with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> tests: "Did the
[<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>'] frantic pursuit of money lead to the endangerment of the world
through nuclear weapons<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockin</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carney</ENAMEX>: Responding to a
question about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>'s impact on popular culture, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carney</ENAMEX> announces
that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guided by Voices</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, riff-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rockers</ENAMEX>, are his favorite
band.

            
               Double
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dribble</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Habitual</ENAMEX> double dribbler <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> sins again. He declares on
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer and Capital Gang</ENAMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> got away with berating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>--unlike
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>--has no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.

            

               For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundit Completists Only</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">profiles Meet the Press</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> and surveys the competitive
world of the pundit shows in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snow Blind</ENAMEX>: On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>
News <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sunday Tony Snow</ENAMEX> inserts his foot in his mouth while questioning
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loyalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Mankiewicz</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
scandals. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mankiewicz</ENAMEX> insists that there is no proof of scandals, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">responds</ENAMEX>, "So convictions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> don't rise to the level of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">scandals?</ENAMEX>" What convictions? asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mankiewicz</ENAMEX>. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Espy</ENAMEX> has only been indicted. Gibbering, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow</ENAMEX> prudently changes the
subject.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
