
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hoop Dreams</ENAMEX>

            
               Around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX> ,
produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Beinstein</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA Entertainment</ENAMEX>.

            Come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">playoff season</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> takes no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>.
Basketball is everywhere, and excess is everything. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> are
Brobdingnagians, and their conflicts, aptly epic. They're on your screen and in
your face, these icons, chattering relentlessly about success, shoes, hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>,
shoes, pop, phones, shoes, shoes ... when suddenly, the prattle stops and you
get a break. It isn't a break from <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>, and it isn't a permanent break.
But for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 seconds</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Around the World</ENAMEX> gives you the hype without the
talk, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intravenous feed</ENAMEX>, if you will.

            A lively guitar and plastic
colors animate this <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Grand Tour</ENAMEX>, which begins with an overhead shot of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">globe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> in the foreground. A young black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> dribbles a basketball
across an improbably bucolic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>
behind her. Cauliflower clouds scud by and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> take wing. The dribbler pauses
at water's edge, then lofts the ball toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Liberty</ENAMEX>, who reaches for it.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruddy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s red, white, and blue togs seem to reinforce
the message: This is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s game. 'Twas a time when <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> was the
national pastime. No longer.

            But the statue misses, and
the ball sails over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>, past a curious <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Ben and the Arc de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triomphe</ENAMEX>. Clearly, we'd fumbled the point. Basketball isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s preserve:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> loves it too. And it transcends color and gender: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> who grabs
the ball, dodging a spry <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eiffel Tower</ENAMEX>, is white and female.

            Seeing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> in the
background, you know what's coming. The ball's on the move again. Destination:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, where a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> lobs it past the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX> and an inquiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sphinx</ENAMEX>.
Then onward to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, the next pause on the tour, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Wall</ENAMEX>, which
invites the backboard. And again, there's a shot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, climbing into
the sky after unloading ... basketballs? Not likely, given that they're made
there now.

            We pull back into space, and
the spinning globe morphs into a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> around it outlining a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> and a hoop. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constellation NBA</ENAMEX>. "I love this game."

            
               Around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX> is
an engaging spot, fast-paced and eye-catching. That said, it's worth looking
beyond the platitudinous fuzz about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> being the world's game and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ultimate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unifier</ENAMEX>, to the fact that it's a prime <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> export. While satellite
technology has increased the sport's reach, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> domination of its every aspect
has increased <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>'s appeal among the capitalist underclass, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">have-nots</ENAMEX> who see and crave the trappings. How long before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> has
franchises from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zurich</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX>? Everyone wants a piece of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX>. And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> wants you to know that it's sharing.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
