
   
   
      
         
            The Not So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>

             

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUNDIT CENTRAL</ENAMEX>" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            The opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> has eyes
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> issue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> testimony. Well, actually they
take a moment to discuss the politics of homosexuality too.

            No one
disputes the legal finding--affirmed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX>--that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> cannot refuse to testify before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. As to the safety
of current and future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>, however, the commentariat is evenly split.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carney</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) all argue that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX> are imperiled. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ),
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Kudlow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) accept the appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s argument that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service will not be hampered. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hume</ENAMEX> suggests the inability to "engage in
felonious conduct" in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> should not cramp any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s style.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clift</ENAMEX> agree--for once--in their prediction that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will
legislate some form of protection for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> from a compulsion to testify.

            And what will the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> have to say? The commentariat
cleaves <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">roughly</NUMEX> along ideological lines. Safire, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Lewis</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Harris</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ) think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s
spirited effort to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> away from the grand jury
proves that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> will give damaging testimony. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> ( This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ) thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> might testify that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> met with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 28</TIMEX>--timing that not only contradicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sworn testimony (that he
never met with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>) but suggests they met to discuss legal
strategies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> predict the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>' testimony will prove unimportant.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clift</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> already has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">logs</ENAMEX>--their testimony will only be corroborative. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gang</ENAMEX> ) claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> have nothing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">damning</ENAMEX> to relate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) is sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> saw no
crimes. It looks like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is just on a fishing expedition--he has no solid
reason to question the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>--charges <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>.

            A number
of opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mafiosi</ENAMEX> suspect that--since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> testified and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> are testifying--we are in the "endgame" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> battle. A
typical comment is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX>' ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ): "I think we're now
talking about the endgame. We're going to get this testimony, get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> either with immunity or without immunity, and then go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>." (Question for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX>: What about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX>?) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundit</ENAMEX> Central
cautions <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to beware of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> bearing predictions (especially the
prediction that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s testimony is imminent). For example, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month</TIMEX> ago
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Duffy</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ) predicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> would
testify in "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next couple of weeks</TIMEX>" and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> ) said she would testify "very soon." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three weeks ago</TIMEX> Novak
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) announced, "this thing is coming to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>," while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gergen</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) guessed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> would testify in two
or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX>.

            
Recent newspaper advertisements suggesting that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homosexuality</ENAMEX> is a curable disorder are distasteful to most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, agree
almost all the commentariat. Conventional wisdom is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who
funded the campaign intend to mobilize conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> and to raise money
for conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> notes that the ads are correct in one
sense: A small number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have indeed practiced then left the homosexual
lifestyle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) diagnoses this as an
instance of the rule that divisive social debate conducted in the political
arena will, at some point or another, become ugly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> ) thinks religion can, in fact, allow many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to resist their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">homosexual</ENAMEX> urges.

            
               Render
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unto the Representative What Is the Representative's: On Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gang</ENAMEX> , the discussion turns to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, homosexuality, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>,
whereupon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> prods <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R-La.</ENAMEX>, for his
opinion on the moral status of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX> responds that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> and
politics should not mix but affirms that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible 1</ENAMEX>) is very old; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) has been
"effective throughout the inception of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>"; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) is variously interpreted;
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) presents a road map to a successful life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX> does
not seem to notice the obvious conflict between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Points</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 and 4</NUMEX>, nor the factual
difficulties raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Point</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> is dumbstruck by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s slippery
deftness but gets off this quip: "I have no idea whose side you're on or whom
you're defending but I know you just endorsed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Testament</ENAMEX>."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meta-Meta</ENAMEX>: 
               Late Edition features
a video clip of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Blankley</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> giving their thoughts
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal just after it had sprung (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months ago</TIMEX>, in case
you're counting). Then the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> were asked to comment on these past thoughts
(none found any errors, of course). As far as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX> knows, this is the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> instance of talking heads elevating their own comments to the status of
newsworthy chat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fodder</ENAMEX>. This makes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX> quite anxious, since
reviewing the commentariat is his job.

            
               But Then Who's Watching
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ), during a discussion
of the politics of homosexuality, tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blankley</ENAMEX>, "You know and I know that
there are letters going out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> all over the country
saying, 'The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> are coming, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> are coming. Raise money.' " Blankley
replies, "And there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX> going out in other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to
raise money: 'The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX> are coming, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are coming.'
"

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
