
   
   
      
         
            Press on Press

             

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUNDIT CENTRAL</ENAMEX>" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            The commentariat elects
itself Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Sunday</TIMEX>, prompted to self-reflection by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Brill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> criticizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s media dealings. The upcoming presidential
trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Political wrangling surrounding the tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead</ENAMEX>? Not dead?--is Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.

            An
admission: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, like most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, hasn't read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX>'s article. The
fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX> found himself without a clear sense of the article's
focus or length after sitting through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours</TIMEX> of TV commentary is no
compliment to the opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press ) pronounces it a "brilliant" piece, which analyzes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s "rush
to judgment" during the scandal<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'s first week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press ) criticizes its conclusions, but agrees that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>-page article is a
laudable effort to "put the press under a microscope." On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Snow</ENAMEX> doesn't want to talk about the press--he believes the "key
allegation" is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> improperly leaked. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Coniff</ENAMEX> reads the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX>-page
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> as an argument that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> calls up his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>," and they do his
bidding. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> assures her that the "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-something" page article makes no
such claim.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX> went to the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper of Record</ENAMEX>, which tells him that: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX>'s article
addresses early press coverage of the scandal; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> interviewed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> admits to meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brill</ENAMEX> disagree over
whether such meetings were illegal; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>)<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> used overeager
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> to squeeze <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> himself appeared on several of the shows to
discuss Point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Clintonians, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahm Emanuel</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ), made
appearances to call for an investigation.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Juan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) speaks for many when he argues that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> is "one-sided ... distorted," because it ignores <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> behavior.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s article, appearing in the inaugural edition of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine Brill</ENAMEX> publishes, is more publicity stunt than serious journalism. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wolf</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blitzer</ENAMEX> asks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s motives in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">granting Brill</ENAMEX> an interview. He's somewhere between naive and idiotic, agree
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">panelists</ENAMEX>. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> also fret that talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> will
obscure the big issue--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s behavior.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) thinks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is "being a little bit wussy," on Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, his agreement to visit
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> will be satisfied if he uses the occasion to
lecture the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> about the importance of human rights. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) thinks our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy is dictated by
commercial, not strategic, interests. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gang</ENAMEX> ) would like to see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> use its economic muscle to force human
rights reforms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ) shares these goals, but thinks
increased trade will prove a more effective strategy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Issue 3,</ENAMEX>
the viability of the long-suffering tobacco bill, confounds everyone. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) is amazed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> is getting away with
opposing a tobacco bill. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwen Ifill</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ) reports
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have been emboldened recently by a widely circulated poll
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter attitudes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) quips that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are "for [the tobacco bill], but don't care about it." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> notes
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are in a win-win situation--if the bill dies, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> can be attacked as pro-teen smoking; if it passes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
can claim credit. In the absence of legitimate campaign issues, he predicts,
this could become a relative biggie.

            

               Opinions you can carry in your pocket:
Add "saves need to follow news" to the list of reasons why one should watch
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert to Woodward</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where</ENAMEX> are we in this
story [presidential scandal]? What should the public know or think about this
story: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>--understandably flustered by
this unenviable task--takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">56 seconds</TIMEX> to say, in effect, that l'affaire
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is but one episode in a larger scandal.

            
               It's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, what channel
is this? During a rare religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> convention provides the news peg), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> mentions a biblical
passage urging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to submit to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> jumps in.
Will happens to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> with him at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> sound <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> , and
intends to read the scriptural passage in question! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX> also quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scripture</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> to buttress their arguments,
apparently from memory.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
