
   
   
      
         
            Telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hearings to Shut Up</ENAMEX>

            Wall Street came in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>,
surprisingly, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> talk shows, which dwelt primarily on Campaigngate
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>--the same topics they chewed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. Why? Oh, partly because
the stock market was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> story--a mountain that, from the
foreshortened perspective of TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, loomed smaller at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week's end</TIMEX> than
nearby hills; and partly because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentariat</ENAMEX> will always prefer
political stories to financial ones (perhaps sensing that their views on the
latter are especially baseless). Also, TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>--even of talk shows--prefer
stories with good visuals (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> in a colonial hat). How often
can you play tape of that damned bell at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX>?

            
Congressional hearings delight the commentariat as a reliable source of grist,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> did not care for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX>'s announcement that his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">campaign-finance</ENAMEX> investigation is closing shop. Both conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brit</ENAMEX> Hume
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Page</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> )
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">berated Thompson</ENAMEX> for failing to put a better "focus" on the hearings. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>
himself insisted on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s Late Edition that his hearings had revealed a
"pattern of illegal foreign money" as well as "money laundering." But Hume
delivered the consensus line that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> had doomed the hearings from the
get-go with his overly ambitious opening argument that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> government
had engaged in a "broad-based conspiracy" to buy the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> presidential
election.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Daschle</ENAMEX>, appearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX> , found the hearings insufficiently bipartisan. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> had shuttered the hearings because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> was "too bipartisan." Having portrayed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> as a political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incompetent</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> weren't completely ungrateful. They lauded him for
presenting a "picture" of (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloria Borger</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> ) and a
"window" on (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Oliphant</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ) standard-issue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> corruption. It's a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for rent,
if not for sale," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borger</ENAMEX>.

            Bowing to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' prerogative to shape the news, the shows feigned interest in Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>'s public promise--reprised in person on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX>-- to
allow a vote on new campaign-finance legislation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. By contrast, genuine
enthusiasm greeted the unfolding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Babbitt</ENAMEX> story, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schieffer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> ) both predicted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babbitt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court ambitions would be ruined by accusations that he had blocked a casino
license for an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> at the behest of another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> that had given money
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.

            
The consensus on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s state visit was that
it was a "win-win," in the words of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) declared that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> got it
right" by simultaneously criticizing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s human-rights violations and
toasting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s centrist approach produced a "domestic
consumption summit" for both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX>
Kondracke, and the talk-show <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chorus</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> benefited from the summit
because he emerged a co-equal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s and didn't really give up anything.
Likewise, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> benefited because he engaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> and didn't really give up
anything. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> ( This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ) were lonely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissenters</ENAMEX>, taking the view that warm relations with a
hideous human-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">violator</ENAMEX> are not especially praiseworthy. But the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Friedman</ENAMEX> expressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>' consensus on
Face : The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> foreign policy is business, and "[w]hen
it comes to business, we engage."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s blessing of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> crash attracted only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>. Everybody urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to buy stocks
for the long term. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> remains "the envy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>.

            
               Emerging: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> Perot
gave identical performances on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press and Late Edition</ENAMEX> ,
sounding off about his usual themes. He did introduce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> new subject: the
impending rewrite of the patent laws that (he says) will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> to
steal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> inventions. The topic went nowhere because his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> had no idea
what he was talking about. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> all but cheered when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Richardson</ENAMEX> drew a line in the sand over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s ouster of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX>
seemed ready to suit up for <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War II</ENAMEX> as he enthusiastically summarized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>'s position. "There is no negotiation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> is in
non-compliance, and he must comply."

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
