
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter Sunday</ENAMEX>

             

            Left for dead by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commentariat</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is Issues <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> as he rises
from the dead to defy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s near-unanimous predictions that he would soon
resign.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> aren't half as shamefaced as they should be. This Week 
               With
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> asks her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> what went
wrong with their predictions from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> weasels, saying that
his prediction of a departing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was contingent upon the allegations being
proved true. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s phenomenal bounce in
the opinion polls reminds him of the surge in the polls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> enjoyed after
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX> eruptions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s numbers
collapsed after the surge. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are suspending judgment, not making
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgment</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> says, a sentiment that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s Late
Edition ) shares. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> attempts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangest</ENAMEX> dodge, blaming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s survival on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who failed to go in for the kill.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) lays out
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s winning strategy: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deny</ENAMEX>" the allegation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
fellated him; "delay" the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s judgment of the crisis; and "attack" his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX>, mostly special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> but also the alleged "right-wing
conspiracy," the press, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> herself. (For 
                  Slate
               's take
on how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spun the crisis, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>.")

            The attack
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> echo, makes it sound as if he, and not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
received a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington kiss</ENAMEX> from an intern. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney Frank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, ridicules <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Energizer Bunny</ENAMEX> of independent
counsels." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ) calls him "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector</ENAMEX>
Clouseau," while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) describes him as
"obsessed, inept." There's "not a lot of confidence" in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, adds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>.
Blasting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> but defending the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> ) is alone in praising <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> as "slow and conscientious." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) complains about the unfair leaks emanating from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, an odd gripe coming from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, given that their
business would shut down <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> if leaks were plugged. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) rips the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s coverage of the scandal, calling it
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doonesbury School of Journalism</ENAMEX>: reporting what could be so."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX>, was switching the debate from a question of whether he committed
perjury or encouraged anyone else to commit perjury to the less troubling
question of whether or not he had sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. "As long as the story is
about sex, it's on his side," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liasson</ENAMEX> says. Why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> still doing so well
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women voters</ENAMEX> in particular? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina Totenberg</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> )
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giggles</ENAMEX> (literally), "We've accepted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s foibles all along." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) defends the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s right to shag all the strange
he wants--and to lie about it afterward. The other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">panelists</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liasson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Snow</ENAMEX>--laugh at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> as if he were a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moron</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union</ENAMEX> speech set the stage for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s comeback, agree the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>. "A
perfect moment for him" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ). "For <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">74 minutes</TIMEX>
reality was suspended on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Bode</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ). A "home run," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ), though he
adds there is no way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will pass his ambitious new programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> gloats
about his prescience from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, when he said he didn't think extramarital
sex (and its complications) was sufficient to force resignation.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) blames the diminution of the
scandal in the public eye on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> (!), whose "libeling of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>"
has convinced the public that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liars</ENAMEX> and incompetents.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lies, they aren't surprised and don't care.

            But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s not home free, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX>. All the "little needles" of doubt pricking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> have injured his presidency, inverting the natural order. Now
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> want the wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to stay where he is, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
want his tainted flesh out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> so they can regroup for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">midterm</ENAMEX> elections.

            

               He's Not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One of Us: Talking</ENAMEX> to his
"fellow" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> about the upcoming presidential press conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
Stephanopoulos tips his hand: "You <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> will make him look good."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emphasis</ENAMEX> added.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Genius or Idiot</ENAMEX>? Idiot, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Dershowitz</ENAMEX> on
Late Edition . He forfeited attorney-client confidentiality and thereby
compromised his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s rights by volunteering too much of his conversations
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> on the shows. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph diGenova</ENAMEX> applauds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, saying that he has hired another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> to handle the legal issues
so he can shape the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> battle for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Punditus Interruptus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Final Chapter:</ENAMEX>

               Capital <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gang sters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> signal an end to their rude
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> with some of the most polite behavior ever witnessed on a
political talk show (outside of the prissy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week</ENAMEX> , of course).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt interrupts Novak</ENAMEX> only once, gently, ending the official Punditus
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Interruptus Tally</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunt</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX>. Not only do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Novak</ENAMEX> make nice,
they are nice to others too. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> sweetly at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> can speak. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> lets her speak! Earlier, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> actually
ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ed Carlson</ENAMEX> if he could interrupt! No, she said, "you may not." He
sat patiently as she talked.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Punditus Interruptus II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sequel: One</ENAMEX> moment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> is asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> to "stop baiting" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX>.
The next he is snapping "Shut up!" at her as she tries to get a point in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">edgewise</ENAMEX>. It is unseemly behavior, even by the eye-gouging standards of
political talk shows. But don't feel sorry for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clift</ENAMEX>. Staying on that show is
like staying in an abusive marriage.

            

               Novak Outs Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> breaks a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">journalistic commandment on Capital Gang</ENAMEX> by revealing that <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>
special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archibald Cox</ENAMEX> leaked information about his investigations to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> in background briefings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years ago</TIMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
