
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kid Stuff</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toughest Job</ENAMEX> in the
World , produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young & Rubicam Inc.</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advertising Council</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc./The Coalition for America's Children PSAs</ENAMEX>.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toughest Job</ENAMEX> in the
World gives us a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. This isn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> trying to
shrug off the shroud of scandal. This is a hard-working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, an engaged parent
trying to do the best he can in a world where the odds are stacked up against
him and others like him. The issues the spot focuses on--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> and development--are what the public really cares about, say the
polls. The picture it presents of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> values--is one that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has been trying to push for at
least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s luck would have
it, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Avenue</ENAMEX> and big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have partnered to extend the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
re-election themes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> at no cost to him. These ads,
created by the nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad Council</ENAMEX>, will be run free on television, radio, and
in print as part of a public-service campaign on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. And this
flagship <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60-second</TIMEX> spot does at least as much to promote the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
family-values image as it does to jump-start that public-service campaign.

            Recalling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris-Bob Squier</ENAMEX> spots for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'96</NUMEX> election, this one opens with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at a
podium complete with waving flag. It moves on to shots of oil paintings of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, implying that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who's doing the
voice-over, were also charged with doing "the toughest job in the world." The
consequences of failure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tells us, "could be serious."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cresting</ENAMEX> around that
portentous pronouncement, our expectations are confounded by what comes next.
The job in question isn't the presidency, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tells us: "It's being a
parent." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appropriately</ENAMEX>, the camera no longer focuses on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> alone. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">home-video</ENAMEX>-style shot of him with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea</ENAMEX> (who's
clearly going to be seen more in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term than in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>) is followed
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>, seen next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, talking of "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and all
the other pressures facing our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>." The ensuing images and words evoke
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of her favorite themes: a wider investment in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> (it takes a
village, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid</ENAMEX>) and the importance of reading (one of her--and the
administration's--major education initiatives).

            Shots of a politically
correct mix of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> with her teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, of an adult
reading to a youngster, are followed by a series that shows <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first couple</TIMEX>
interacting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on whose behalf they are crusading. Where the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shots</ENAMEX> was in black and white, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is in vibrant color--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aim</ENAMEX> being, of course, to equate involvement with warmth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> speaks
of the "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350</NUMEX> wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>" that have come together "to help parents
raise good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>," an idea that infuriates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologues</ENAMEX> on the right, especially
when it comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, speaking to the camera and via
voice-over, invites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> to help: This isn't just about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> doing the
best they can; everyone, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> alike, can "make a
difference." An e-mail address and a phone number invite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> to take up the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gauntlet</ENAMEX> and become involved.

            The
images of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> together, of their obvious bond,
speak volumes about their commitment to family values. What would have been
powerful in an explicitly political ad is even more powerful in an ostensibly
nonpolitical context. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, this kind of image-making couldn't have come
at a better time: The scandals aside, he was recently attacked in an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX> article about the adverse effects of welfare reform on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Edelman</ENAMEX>, was once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> on the issue
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was responsible for bringing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Defense Fund</ENAMEX>). This spot leaves little doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>,
like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> for which he is speaking, is "fighting for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,"
that he's trying to do well at the toughest job in the world. It might also
help him do better for himself.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
