
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marathon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>

             

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUNDIT CENTRAL</ENAMEX>" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> summit having
wrapped up, the commentariat dedicates itself to a thorough post-mortem. The
entire opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> applauds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> for his human rights comments, but a
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> find fault with his other statements. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is the
continuing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr-Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> drama.

            Question
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>: Have you ever watched an entire marathon--from start to finish--on
television? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX> hasn't either. He suspects that, sometime during the
middle of the race, network <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> simply unplug their mikes, relax with
a mai tai, and plug back in at race's end. This is what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr-Clinton</ENAMEX>
opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> is up to right now. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s scandal opining, even by the
standards of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two months</TIMEX>, is noticeably meandering.

            On Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators reprise</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s main
point--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> deserves praise for being tough on human rights. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) claims credit for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s tough stance on behalf
of the entire commentariat--"I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would have [talked tough]
without the prodding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> in our position."

            A few notes of discontent
rise over the applause. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) are horrified by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s stated belief that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> is the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. We can
work with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>, believes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>, but we don't have to pretend we approve
of him. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> bone of contention is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s statements effectively "deny
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-determination</ENAMEX>" to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> is joined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>, who think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coward</ENAMEX> to give pro-mainland statements.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ) gives the standard human rights justification for expanding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX>: Rising profits will lift human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> vividly criticizes
this approach: He doesn't believe that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> labor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> are
going to feel those lashes a lot less seriously because profits are rising."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) thinks that, whatever one thinks about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> cannot do much to change matters. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gergen</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) believes the trip shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, is the most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> right now.

            
Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">developments</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> testified, and a district <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> threw out the case
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX>. No one knows what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> said. Everyone thinks the
district <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s opinion, which used harsh language about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s tactics,
further erodes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s credibility. The opinion also strengthens <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s hand, notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ), because she
can reasonably refuse to give a preview of her testimony, since the opinion
holds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> misused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s preview.

            A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> wonder whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will take the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth</ENAMEX> if subpoenaed. Others guess when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> will deliver
a report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Blitzer</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ) ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX> this very question about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
different times, but he declines to respond in each instance. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>
agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> doesn't want the report until after the elections--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben-Veniste</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ) gets off the crack that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> awaits a
report as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX> awaits the sun."

            A number
of shows also weigh in on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN NewsStand</ENAMEX> 's retraction of a story alleging
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> nerve-gassed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> defectors in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laos</ENAMEX>. A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>
argue that the story was not only untrue but also the work of anti-military
left-wingers. Others argue that a competitive news environment is to blame.

            

               This <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is What I Think, Except When I</ENAMEX>
Don't: It is conventional wisdom <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is in the middle of a
legal losing streak (he also lost a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> case recently), exposing him
to charges of being a rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX> believes this may make no
difference, since "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]t doesn't matter how corrupt you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messenger</ENAMEX> is,
or how partisan, if the case [presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>] is strong itself." Is this
the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> who argued the exact opposite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month ago</TIMEX>? Yes it is! At
that Flytrap moment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> had won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> legal victories and lost none. Gigot
argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s victories had "a political echo or consequence" in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, namely they make impeachment proceedings more likely. Well, which is
it: Do swings in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s reputation affect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> or not? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX> would have us
believe the following: If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> rises, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> falls; but if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> falls,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> doesn't rise.

            
               Double <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dribble Is</ENAMEX>
Back: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> repeats the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary McGrory</ENAMEX> quotation on both
Capital <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gang and NewsHour</ENAMEX> , even mentioning <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">McGrory's Pulitzer</ENAMEX>
both times. The bizarre bit is that this particular quotation--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "rises
to the occasion" during important presidential moments--seems noticeably
ordinary.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
