
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprite</ENAMEX>'s Spite

            
               Jooky , produced for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola Co./Sprite Brand</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lowe & Partners/SMS</ENAMEX>.

            This spot wasn't made for
Jooky, the kooky product it seems to promote. It was made for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprite</ENAMEX>--a fact it hides well. Only at the end of the spot is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sprite</ENAMEX> mentioned;
only then does one realize that the string of clichés--sun and sand, beach
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">towels</ENAMEX> and bikinis--invited you to suspend disbelief through the viewing, and
that you fell for it.

            The thump of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>
beat urges that you "open up a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jooky</ENAMEX>," and someone does. The screen fills with
purple bubbles (a detail that, in retrospect, suggests a consumer-research
finding that purple isn't the soft-drink color of choice). Then come the
ubiquitous images--dude on surfboard, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> being tossed in blanket, crowd
cheering--that link the product (be it deodorant or dentures, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> or a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beverage</ENAMEX>) with that oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persuader</ENAMEX> of them all: sex. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jooky</ENAMEX>" and "nooky"--get
it? The jaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> mocks the gag, then promptly buys it. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>,
studies have shown, believe themselves impervious to the pitiful ploys of
advertising. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, studies have shown, are not--in fact, they are
especially vulnerable when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> play directly to their skepticism.

            "It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in a can":
Here's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poseidon</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> just beginning, emerging from the depths. He
bears his burden of blonde and cans with ease. A hot young thing swings on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tire</ENAMEX>, offering you her drink. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock</ENAMEX> makes short work of a pile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jooky</ENAMEX> cans.
Hard bodies dance toward the volleyball net: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jooky</ENAMEX> is fun and fruity"--it
"make you really kooky." The mandatory buffoon in the mock-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Superman</ENAMEX> outfit
romps on the sand, his one thought (you got it) captured in a comic-book
bubble.

            Bit by bit, the spot winks
at its own satire. The jingle trips the light fantastic, promising the earth
(Jooky "make you manly, mahn," in a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> accent thick enough to thaw).
What we get instead is a trip in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jooky</ENAMEX> in hand, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">volleyball</ENAMEX> player
falls flat on his face. He smiles beatifically, and--forsooth! He has a missing
front tooth.

            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> fraying at the
edges? Absolutely, the transition seems to say. Borrowing a
political-advertising technique (a shot of a television, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>'s
spot playing, as a sign that we're being manipulated, that what we're seeing
isn't real), it takes us into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grungy</ENAMEX> living room, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> unbuffed slobs
respond to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jooky</ENAMEX> commercial just ending on their TV set. This pair falls
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plumb</ENAMEX> in the middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jooky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target group</ENAMEX>: no dates, no sun, no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX>. What
they do have is the storm raging outside--and the cheap college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> they're
sitting on. Can <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jooky</ENAMEX> transport them to sunshine and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the men
raises his can and looks within. He's searching for the beach. The other tries
to open his can, and breaks the lift tab. It's happened to all of
us--hard-to-pop cans, not hard bodies, are the reality of soft drinks. "Mine's
busted" becomes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jooky</ENAMEX> epitaph.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Image Is</ENAMEX>
Nothing," says the chyron. But of course, it's everything in a spot that turns
sunny visuals against soft-drink <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>, using the images to make the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">long-overdue</NUMEX> point that they are a stupid reason to pick a drink. The grunge
feel reinforces the invitation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX> against yuppiedom--"trust your taste
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">buds</ENAMEX>," it says, "not commercials." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>image as image is powerful indeed.
So is the message: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sprite</ENAMEX> must taste good if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can risk advertising
it this way. We hardly notice that the disclaimer mentions "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>," the
very <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that's helped inure us to the images being satirized here. Or was
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX>? Initial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">impressions</TIMEX> notwithstanding, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jooky</ENAMEX> ends up making
intention and product crystal clear: It's taking on a whole genre on behalf of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX> that promises only good taste, not the good life.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
