
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Newt</ENAMEX>-ered?

             

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUNDIT CENTRAL</ENAMEX>" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s public riffs
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s moral shortcomings are Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Chatter about the indictment
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX> and the release of his taped prison phone calls captures
Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> press conference--memorable for the answers
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> didn't give--is Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.

            
International news, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> vote to expand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, and the European
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>'s further move toward a common currency, makes nary a ripple.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s departure from his freshly cultivated
nicey-nicey image is largely unexpected and brings <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snickers</ENAMEX> from consistency
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mavens</ENAMEX>: "Was that the new old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> or the old new new <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gingrich?</ENAMEX>" asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> )
is not surprised at all: By playing the attack <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> is simply
"reverting to form."

            Why such an aggressive
strategy? It's the only way to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> realize that this isn't about sex,
it's about the rule of law (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-haters, moralists, religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--want
"red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ; joined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>). Personal attacks are
advance work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s report, a preliminary strike against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
sky-high approval ratings (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> is simply more comfortable being mean--at heart he's a "bomb thrower"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clift</ENAMEX>; joined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton Kondracke</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ).

            Of course,
notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ), there's much risk in playing the villain.
Explicitly personal attacks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> provide exactly the "background
music, the wallpaper" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would want as a backdrop. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s
attacks, which came off as terribly partisan, mitigate damage to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s popularity caused by some of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s more embarrassing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">developments</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) joins the chorus noting
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is blessed to have such inept <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> (last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s target was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>).

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>--who was publicly flayed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX> for
calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a "scumbag"--is flayed again, this time for releasing tapes of
phone calls between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX>, then incarcerated, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. It may be
legal, admits <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ), but it's a rotten thing to
do. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> was also stupid to so tendentiously edit the tapes he released (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ). He did not include sections in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cleared Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, once his law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, of any wrongdoing in the matter
that initially landed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> in the stir.

            Gigot
thinks the tax fraud proceedings against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> are legitimate and ordinary,
while everyone else regards the indictments as trumped-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>crimes meant to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">squeeze Hubbell</ENAMEX> into giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> what he wants--cooperation. Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
doesn't want the truth at all, ponders <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>; maybe he'll just squeeze
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> fabricates something that hurts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>
won't break easily. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) compares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s
understanding of loyalty to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mob</ENAMEX>'s concept of omertà .

            The presidential press conference, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> refused
to answer scores of questions about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>, was important to the commentariat
for one chief reason. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> finally said with words what he's been saying
with actions for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX>--he has no intention of further clarifying his
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> or anyone else. This won't work, says
Stephanopoulos, speaking politically: "You can [avoid questions] in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> press
conference. You cannot do it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half years</TIMEX>." Speaking ethically,
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>, this is "disturbing." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> shouldn't hide from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> behind fancy-pants <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.

            Opinion
was varied about the merits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s performance. He's usually tiptop at
fielding tough questions, agrees everyone. Most saw <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s conference as
another rhetorical masterpiece in his career of gems, but a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> thought
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> looked angry and nervous.

            

               A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nice Head-Shrinking Never Hurt Anyone:</ENAMEX>
Based on the presidential press conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX> senses that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
may be having difficulty separating myth and reality. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, continues <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX>,
has come to regard himself as a latter-day <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Valjean</ENAMEX>, a decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> hounded
by inexplicably cruel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) thinks it odd
that, at the same press conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> refused even to affirm that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is above the law. Maybe he just "couldn't bring himself to do that,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
