
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lame Duck Soars</ENAMEX>

             

            Dismissed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame duck</ENAMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> commanded their
unanimous respect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to reign as Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is back!"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cheered Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spun himself as a
loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> by getting "caught" on videotape dancing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, on
a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> beach. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> were split on whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> deliberately
exposed himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>' lenses. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> insisted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> didn't know about the cameras,
because "no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> wants to be photographed in a bathing suit.") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">luxuriated</ENAMEX> in the good news of the budget surplus and introduced his plans to
expand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and support child care. "It doesn't get any better than this
for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Borger</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ).

            Although
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new modest social programs were recognized as "warmed-over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ), all saluted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for the "terrific" politics. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s "cradle to grave"
proposals (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ) were likely to paralyze
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, because nobody wants to go on record as being against child
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ). Unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> slip out of the
sleeper hold, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> initiatives will serve as "wedge issues" to
separate the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in the minds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> election (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
Blankley, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ).

            
"They're scared <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stiff</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Gramm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, appeared
more stupid than brave when he walked into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' trap on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Nation</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm</ENAMEX> compared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> to a sinking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> that
shouldn't accept any new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> loyalists <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Donna Shalala</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> ) responded with the
administration's line. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> isn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> , they said, it's a
"lifeboat" for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.

            The budget
surplus, which is providing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> with excellent cover for his new social
programs (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gergen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ), was declared
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illusory</ENAMEX> and temporary by <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, who failed to
note these seemingly obvious truths <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> when the surplus was Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> stated without dissent that the surplus is an accounting trick: If
the balance sheet were to include the trust funds (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, etc.), the
real deficit would stand at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $140 billion</NUMEX>. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX>
predicted (fervently hoped?) that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> flu would soon strike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, evaporate the surplus, and vanquish the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> juggernaut in the
process.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Khatami</ENAMEX>'s televised
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overture</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> earned Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> honors, though this unfamiliar
topic strained the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>' omniscience. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX> described it as the "one
glimmer of light coming out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) asked, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Is Khatami the Gorbachev</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>?"

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> economic crisis (Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) was a bit of a stumper too. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ) came to the studio prepared,
cribbing from his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> column: According to a
popular <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">liner</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>, the ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, which owns toll <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, "[has] everything--but a sense of shame." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Friedman</ENAMEX>
also previewed the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX>'s economic troubles might cause the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indigenous populations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> to attack the
ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> who dominate commerce in those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. How might China
respond to such an ethnic war? he asked.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX>! The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> name of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> show is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week With Sam and Cokie</ENAMEX> .Reports that the show
will soon change its name to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> 
               With <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Milk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cookies</ENAMEX> ,
broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bugs Bunny</ENAMEX> cartoons between magic tricks, and host a studio audience
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cub Scouts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brownies</ENAMEX> are unconfirmed as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" goes to
press.

            
               Who's
Minding the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Show</ENAMEX>? The closing credits of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in</ENAMEX>
Review listed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Arnold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Birnbaum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Broder</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brownstein</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">The night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Wright</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Borger</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Friedman</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Murray</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Favorite Lies:</ENAMEX>

               Late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edition</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sesno</ENAMEX> cited his desire to spend more time with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> as one of the reasons he had decided to step down as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> of
the show.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Punditus Interruptus</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week 4</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> stepped on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> held
his fire, making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> the interruption <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4-2</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
