
   
   
      
         
            That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feel-Good Feeling</ENAMEX>

            
               Star-Spangled
Bonds , produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter Mullett Films/Kershner & Co.</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Savings</ENAMEX>
Bonds.

            
               Star-Spangled Bonds
strings a series of luminous limnings aimed straight at the heart. It taps--and
markets--the image of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> as the land of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, of opportunity and
prosperity, of freedom well earned and much valued. Nothing novel about the
advertising techniques here: But they're put to effective use, and are unlikely
to offend in this era of peace and plenty, where the political battles in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> seem so completely irrelevant that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> are hard pressed to
elicit strong reactions from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>. Not that the spot raises the
specters of isolation and apathy, of course. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star-Spangled Bonds</ENAMEX> '
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is involved, concerned, and while the spot does draw explicitly on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s speckled history, it is careful to take the edge off.

            Set, appropriately, to the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star-Spangled Banner" (à la Jimi Hendrix</ENAMEX>), and presented montage-style, the
spot <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> the collective memory for its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>. There are shots aplenty from
times of war and protest: the curve of a fighter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iwo Jima</ENAMEX>, in black and
white; a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Black Panther</ENAMEX>'s finger snap; battlefield comradeship; a civil-rights
clash; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dun</ENAMEX> and dunes of what appears to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Desert Storm</ENAMEX>; an
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> rally; then the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War Memorial</ENAMEX>, in sunset silhouette.
And there's plenty of fuzzy stuff--a shot of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> playing with fluffy white
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pigeons</ENAMEX>; of a fiercely bespectacled towhead whooshing down a slide; of a happy,
freckles-and<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">-ice-cream-spattered</ENAMEX> face. No in-your-face politics, perhaps, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and their rights remain sacred in the public eye--even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> didn't dare oppose the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> plan of health care for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
paid for by cigarette taxes, part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>'s bipartisan budget bill.

            Threading the collage is the
word "freedom," presented on the unlikeliest of canvases--on a scrap caught on
a wire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fence</ENAMEX>, on the black-leather back of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biker</ENAMEX>'s jacket, on a green road
sign. In each case, the word is first brought to life with a few images, then
rounded off by a question that is answered by the images that follow. For
example: A shot of the wire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fence merges</ENAMEX>, via the pigeons in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, into
sepia scenes--winged feet in the wild <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>; an ancient merry-go-round--and
comes to brief rest on a sign emblazoned on the side of a bus: "What is it?"
The montage continues, familiar scenes reminding us what freedom has come to
mean. It's about popping a wheelie on your mountain bike, framed by the Golden
Gate. It's about acing a race, tasting the rain, reaping a new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">harvest</ENAMEX>,
mourning a loss, watching a rocket blast into space. This is freedom hard-won,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> of wars and sacrifice and struggle. "How much does it cost?" "How do
we protect it?" The unlikely--and more than slightly jarring--response reminds
us that freedom is as tenuous as it is precious, that the current sense of
plenty must be zealously guarded: "Take stock in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>," we're told. And,
against a shot of a savings bond, backdropped by a waving flag: "Buy U.S.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savings Bonds</ENAMEX>." A discordant note, this one, but an effective reminder that
there's more to the feel-good feeling than just feeling good.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
