
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inscrutable West</ENAMEX>

             

Favored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> trading status--the privilege that allows an overseas <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> its goods at the lowest possible level of tariffs in the giant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
market--is an annual struggle. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> favors renewal. On
each occasion, a significant section of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is unconvinced. This pattern
has repeated itself for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>, no matter which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> controls the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. In every case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has prevailed and MFN
status has been awarded for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another 12 months</TIMEX>.

            Although
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s dispute may be more intense and the final margins closer than last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will not derail <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">MFN</ENAMEX> status unless <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> commits an
act of monumental folly over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few weeks</TIMEX>. The rules favor the occupant
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> law, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early June</TIMEX> to
declare formally his support for MFN renewal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> then has a maximum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> to decide whether it wants to reject the presidential preference. Even if
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> vote against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFN</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> can veto the
legislation. In effect, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFN</ENAMEX> rejection requires not merely a simple majority,

            In the past, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has come nowhere near even a simple
majority in either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>. In part, this is because the various pressure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX> hostile to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> have known that success was too unlikely to merit their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mobilizing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. It also reflects the enormous pressure brought to bear by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> business community, which is aware that placing restrictions on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> trade would lead to swift retaliation from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. Even in the
aftermath of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> massacre, the power of corporate interest has
always prevailed over other concerns. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can be quietly confident that it
will do so again.

            However,
MFN renewal should not be interpreted as a sign that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> relations have
resumed a more intimate path, or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
"constructive engagement" approach are in retreat. In fact, the opposite is
true. Policy toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> remains the most difficult and divisive aspect of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign relations. Successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFN</ENAMEX> renewal simply reflects the peculiar
circumstances that affect this element of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> debate. Moreover,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> of a closer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> relationship have been forced to compromise.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had hoped that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would vote to make MFN status a permanent
fixture <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, thus ending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this annual</TIMEX>, largely symbolic fight. Any such
aspirations were abandoned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months ago</TIMEX>.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is engaged now in a
defensive strategy aimed at preserving what it can of the
constructive-engagement ideal until congressional pressure eases. For the
moment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has largely succeeded in limiting the damage. However, three
factors--which could surface at any time--may derail his ambitions:

            
               
                  Campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX>
               : The campaign-finance scandals that have tarnished <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">term</TIMEX> could spin out of control. The most politically explosive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accusation</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> attempted to influence the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> elections in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> through covert campaign
contributions, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were warned about the practice
but did not act. If either the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> investigation or congressional
hearings substantiate these allegations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> will have little
option but to distance itself from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> would, in turn, react
furiously.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
               : The
imminent return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>-administered territory to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> rule has
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">galvanized anti-China</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. They will insist,
through legislation and other means, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>'s behavior toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
become the yardstick by which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> determines its level of cooperation
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The high profile and emotive power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> issue will make
it very difficult for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> to ride roughshod over such
demands.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>
bid
               : <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> is keen to be included in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>
and, subject to certain conditions, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. State Department</ENAMEX> would like to
facilitate its application. However, a majority in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> either favors a
much tougher stance toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> or rules out its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> membership altogether.
The position of those seeking further trade-liberalization concessions from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has been strengthened by recent increases in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s huge trade surplus
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> law
does not require the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to request congressional support before
supporting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> bid. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would risk legislative revenge if he
tried to pursue the issue in the face of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> majorities against him in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, however, believes that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> were to spend political
capital on pushing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>, he could prevail--as he did
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> ratification. Should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> decide not to try, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> will
react badly to what it will perceive as prevarication. Should he try and then
fail, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> will conclude that it is dealing with a weak <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.

            

               Mutual 
               Misunderstanding
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> views the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that can influence <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s emergence as a major
global political and economic power in both a positive and a negative
direction. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng Xiaoping</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> actively sought to cultivate a good
bilateral relationship. Hard-liners, suspicious of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ideological influence,
asserted themselves in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1996</TIMEX>, when missile tests in the Straits of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>
were timed to intimidate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> as the country
held its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> direct elections to the presidency. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> responded
by deploying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> naval <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in the region. Since then, the hard-liners have
played a less prominent role. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX> broadly favor cooperation, but
lack the late paramount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>'s dominating influence. It is thus very
important to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> that relations remain on track until the planned exchange
of formal presidential visits, which could happen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as next year</TIMEX>.

            The uncertainty over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy means that this cannot be guaranteed. The conflict in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
has its ironies. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1992</TIMEX> presidential election, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> for "coddling" the "butchers of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, by contrast, generally favored constructive engagement with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
while liberal and protectionist <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> usually opposed it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protectionist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have stayed in place, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and many
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have swapped positions. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policy-makers</ENAMEX> often find
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> politics quite incomprehensible, but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
must find the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> equally perplexing. It will be some time before
both sides establish better mutual understanding.

         
      
   
