
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Warriors</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
made an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourlong</TIMEX> appearance on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , marking the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> anniversary of the show that invented TV talking heads. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
on his agenda was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> takes the view that there will be
"consequences" if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> doesn't start behaving. The rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commentariat</ENAMEX>--unconstrained by the ability to actually do anything--made even
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">noisier</ENAMEX> threats. The official sound bite of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>--offered up by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
and aped by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX>--was that this confrontation pits <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> against the world,
not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several weekend</TIMEX> warriors
were ready to fly to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> and grease the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> themselves. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Friedman</ENAMEX> made this position respectable in a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> piece that called on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> out with a "head
shot" before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> "starts tut-tutting and rushing to his
defense." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> was not engaging in metaphor, as you can see by clicking
here.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> elicited a gasp from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> when he too demanded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s "assassination." "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G.I.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill" Kristol</ENAMEX> concurred: "We need to go in and get" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>, even if it requires
ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> , even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>--who ardently
opposed the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>--endorsed unilateral <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military
action, noting only that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> will "take hits for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>."

            In general, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> seemed
almost giddy in anticipation of battle. There was no talk of body bags. Late
Edition 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> grabbed the obvious war-is-the-health-of-the-state
angle. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> had told him, "Thank God for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>!" Anthrax
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cocktails</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> and the unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, please.

            There was
similar unanimity <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> on Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: the fast-track trade bill, which
teetered on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits gabbed</ENAMEX>. The virtues of free trade
are a given among the commentariat. So instead of debating the merits, they
analyzed the political shadows cast by the legislative battle. Why are so many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> deserting their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and why are so many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> deserting
their free-trade principles? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>' answer, which may even be correct:
labor-union cash and hatred of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, respectively. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Broder</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
Shield on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> all noted the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15-million</NUMEX> debt. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaigngate</ENAMEX> has left <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> angry and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stingy</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s failure to rally <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> has reduced him to a
"prophet without honor in his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NewsHour</ENAMEX> . Fast track's ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, said
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> in a somewhat stagy display of his newfound powers of
objectivity. Why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>? He'll get the credit if it passes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will get
the blame if it loses.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> that his weekend
speech to a gay-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was an all-American blow for civil rights,
although he confided that he didn't think the gay alternative should be taught
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. This Week <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bennett</ENAMEX> seized on this comment to insist
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s gay-rights position isn't really analogous with civil
rights. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>--who confessed he hadn't heard or read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
speech--said on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> was behind a
"left-wing agenda to change <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s attitudes" about sexual orientation.
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Minutes</TIMEX> later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> upgraded it to a "radical left-wing agenda."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett reprised Quayle</ENAMEX>'s talking point twice, calling the speech a "signal" of
the "new agenda for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> may or may not be
correct that gay rights is at the center of the liberal agenda. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s
lockstep sound bites are confirmation that the issue is now at the center of
the conservative agenda. And yet even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are careful to express a
degree of acceptance that would have been considered radical just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> urged a sort of tolerance for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> that stops short of
"approval and endorsement"--which sounds suspiciously like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "don't
ask, don't tell" construction.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
credited the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican</ENAMEX> sweep of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s election to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) a good economy and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
the abundance of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> backed this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> line.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> party line was, of course, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is turning
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to get back into the game
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rehiring</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, who could save the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> by "triangulating"
policies in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> direction. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are now <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>,"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>, hinting at a broad political realignment.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundit Bites</ENAMEX>: Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX> was billed on Late Edition as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX>." This is a new chyron for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>, who used to insist that he and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coalition</ENAMEX> did not serve <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> but "the name that is above all names."
... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> 's recent efforts to uplift the debate with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> round tables that aren't pegged to the news (race in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> last week
and "the media--is it fair?" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>) leave "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" hankering for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> -style shouting matches. ... "I will run for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> someday," threatened <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> .

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
