
   
   
      
         
            Back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Line of Fire</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back</ENAMEX> ,
produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Schipp</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Hessing</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> .

            Martial music and an
outrider-flagged motorcade herald <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s return to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> ,
the show that gave him enough currency in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
to take not one, but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stabs</ENAMEX> at the presidency.

            The motorcade circles the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Capitol building</ENAMEX> in the opening shot, creating an immediate association between
the spot's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> and that bully pulpit. We assume we're seeing a
presidential motorcade--complete with police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escort</ENAMEX>--returning from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>,
the drumbeat-punctuated music enhancing the weight of the scene.

            Is this a promotional for a
report on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidency? Apparently not. The subject of the ad, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">narrator</ENAMEX> tells us, is "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> of the conservative right"--a description
that doesn't fit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, even at his most vacillatory. But the helmeted riders
around the limousine, the fluttering flags atop it, the stoplights freezing
oncoming traffic--all create an undeniable sense of moment. Which important
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologue</ENAMEX> are we talking about here? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>?

            Wrong again. This person
"served" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX>, and did so "with
distinction." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> mention is our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> hint that the spot might be
promoting unreconstructed <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> dispels
any suspicions of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> revival by telling us that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in question
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">challenged Bush</ENAMEX> in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> bid for the presidency, and himself ran "twice
... for the highest office in the land." Bingo, says the politically literate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>--it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>! (So what if he isn't overwhelmingly presidential?
Surely he's controversial enough to need that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> battlewagon we now
see behind the limo? And so what if the next campaign is too far away to
warrant a motorcade .... well, there must be some explanation.)

            A spit-and-polish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> waves
the procession onward (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the</NUMEX> in-joke here is that it now seems headed toward the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> building <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> blocks from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>). The road clear, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">swivels</ENAMEX> to allow a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to cross the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. It's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, almost regal in his
acknowledgment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>'s attentiveness. But wait--wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> in that limo?
Was he at the street corner all along, watching the pretentious parade go
by?

            As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> moves to join <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crossfire</ENAMEX> co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sununu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Press</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldine Ferraro</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voice-over</ENAMEX> tells us that he's "back, and working for a
living." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>'s dropped out of the presidential motorcade for now--as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, he's back at that desk at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, pummeling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> of every other
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. Though the buildup is sharply amusing in retrospect, it has succeeded in
making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>'s return to television an event. A markedly different "inauguration"
from the one he'd reached for, no doubt, but worth a drumroll all the same.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
