
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midterms</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Single Girl</ENAMEX>

             

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUNDIT CENTRAL</ENAMEX>" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s decision
to retain new legal help is Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s rejection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s fast-track request is Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, and upcoming midterm elections--Issue
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>--spur the opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> to wonder how the ongoing scandal will react with
congressional races. The post-mortem on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> primaries and ballot
initiatives straggles in as Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.

            The
biggest development of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ), is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s
revamped legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. Her new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> are "famous for cutting deals,"
reports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Peterson</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dumping Ginsburg</ENAMEX> is a
pretty sure sign that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> is eager to negotiate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> again, agrees
almost everyone. This, warns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Beirne</ENAMEX>, could spell "real trouble" for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is so spooked by the prospect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cooperating</ENAMEX>, believes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Mayer</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ), that it is
beginning a quiet smear campaign against her. She is not a very credible
witness as it is, observes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Matsui</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif</ENAMEX>:
The tapes contain inconsistencies, and her affidavit contradicts the tapes on
which she anyway admits, "I'll lie any time in order to get ahead."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supremes</ENAMEX>' unwillingness
to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> an expedited hearing--Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>--is generally taken as a small to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">medium White House</ENAMEX> victory. It will delay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation still further,
note all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Beirne</ENAMEX> wonders whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s cooperation
may eliminate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s need to quiz <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ) lobs out the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is pursuing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX> so doggedly
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> knows who authored the infamous talking points given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>.

            Will this
hiccup lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to offer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> a preliminary report? Most likely, think
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ).
Definitely, predicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ).

            
Will scandal shape the upcoming congressional
races? It's "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> problem, not yet a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> problem," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Germond</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ). But really, who cares! All the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commentariat</ENAMEX> wants to know is: How will the races shape the scandal? Incumbents
are wary about rocking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> with scandal hearings.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> wants <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to deliver nothing until after the
elections (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwen Ifill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bloom</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ). In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>'s comments on the shows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
should be construed as signals from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> asking him to withhold a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, charges <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX>. But after the election, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blankley</ENAMEX>, there is a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99.99</NUMEX>
percent" chance that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will pursue any case <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> can
deliver.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> primaries and ballot initiatives demonstrate
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are content with the status quo (career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
won big) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) it doesn't take money to win elections anymore (millionaire
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neophytes</ENAMEX> lost big). It just shows that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> who aren't
under house arrest will win, quips <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX> (the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX> to lose was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> under house arrest).

            The vote
on <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 227</ENAMEX> is evidence of the public will, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX>--the people
reject screwy ideas such as bilingual education. It shows only that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s own bilingual education system is unpopular, dissents <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ), and says nothing about other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>'
programs. The defeat of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 226</ENAMEX>--labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> can still make political
contributions without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> approval--contradicts the idea that money doesn't
matter in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, argue <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ).

            

               They would have fired him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>: The entire pundit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> is, of course, pleased that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> will no longer haunt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and sound stages. Careful what
you wish for, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayer</ENAMEX> cautions her fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>: You'll miss his clownish
antics when he's gone.

            

               
                  Omnia vincit amor (unless you work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX>): Brit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hume</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) speculates on why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> might not cooperate:
She still has a hopeless crush on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Though she was crazy for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> until recently, thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Frum</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> and the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> ), she now understands that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will never abandon
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>. Accordingly, she is willing to turn on her formerly
beloved.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> girls, er, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ) cites the astounding fact that until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> a male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> had not won a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> primary for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Broder</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ) trots out the
equally astounding fact that this is the first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> gubernatorial race
between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>!

            
               Not that there's anything
wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>; some of my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>: Lapsed lawyer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor</ENAMEX> ( Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ) on cover-ups and obstruction of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX>: "Lawyers do things <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> that would strike the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> as
a cover-up."

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
