
 
     		
 	
 		well my view i work for a financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		yeah and i love my credit card uh you end up with more consumer rights by using credit cards than
 	
 	
 		what do you mean by that
 	
 	
 		uh what i mean is say you pay for something with a check your check clears you're out the bucks
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you pay for something with a credit card you dissatisfied are dissatisfied with it you take it back and they say sorry we you can't take it back if you know you can leave it there and then just have your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> charged back
 	
 	
 		oh what's your favorite credit card do you use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> how come
 	
 	
 		get your money back
 		Visa
 		well that's the kind we offer
 	
 	
 		oh that's a good reason that's a good reason
 	
 	
 		and uh we're just offering a a new card that gives you one up to one percent back of all the charges that you make
 	
 	
 		now
 	
 	
 		cash back you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		i was gonna say i know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> does that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> and we're starting to do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX>'s gonna do it too
 	
 	
 		we are
 	
 	
 		who all right who puts out your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> card
 	
 	
 		uh we do  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America First Credit Union</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		who is we
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America First Credit Union</ENAMEX> and you're gonna offer the cash back just like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> does huh well i i'll tell you that works because i use my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> card more than any other credit card for that sole reason
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		did you get much back
 	
 	
 		hm  yeah  unfortunately i use my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> card more than i ought to not a great deal i get i get about a check for about fifty some bucks at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> usually
 	
 	
 		well good for you that must mean
 		and it's one percent so you spend <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about five thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		i shouldn't tell that to you
 	
 	
 		that's pretty good
 		well i i do better than that everything goes on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> and then i've got a business too that i use it for charging computers on
 	
 	
 		well i tell you then then i have an exact account of everything i've bought it's all printed out
 	
 	
 		it is nice
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and as long as you keep your statements then you know exactly what you've spent and if you know when you bought something because often i won't remember
 		and i can go back you know i'll remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> so i can go back to my my credit card invoice and there it is it tells me the exact date and everything
 	
 	
 		well how many cards have you got
 	
 	
 		well i have a whole slew of the them but i really i use i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> um but my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> is an automatic draw from my credit from my
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> a debit card yes i don't like those
 	
 	
 		yeah and so i don't either because it's gone although they don't debit it until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the month</TIMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really that's interesting
 	
 	
 		um but it still automatically comes off that month if i time it right then any like  my
 		my date is the twelfth so if i charge something on the thirteenth then i don't get that bill till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the month</TIMEX> and it's not due till before the twelfth of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next month</TIMEX> so i can put off paying for something for free for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		with a debit card
 	
 	
 		no not with a debit card with my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> card i can and and i use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> more than any other because of the cash back
 	
 	
 		oh credit
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> and then i have all the different department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> but i just really never use them and i try desperately hard to pay it off each month
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		because the the cost to use it is terrific
 	
 	
 		
 
 		is it <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">twenty percent</NUMEX> interest
 	
 	
 		uh it varies from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen and a half</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty one</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and that's that's tremendous amount
 	
 	
 		our card's thirteen and a half
 	
 	
 		oh you're kidding me
 	
 	
 		uh with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> fee
 	
 	
 		how do you get one of yours
 	
 	
 		well you have to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of our credit union
 	
 	
 		and what credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> is that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America First</ENAMEX>
 		it's we're the
 	
 	
 		oh but see you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and you'd have to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> of the state
 	
 	
 		oh okay i was thinking about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> he said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> and he'll do that but that's you're nowhere near us wow  that's a neat idea though perhaps some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around here will catch on and do it too
 	
 	
 		uh do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mervyn's</ENAMEX> and all those have you noticed that they all have started issuing their own credit cards
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh yeah they have for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> but you can still use the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> big ones <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard Visa</ENAMEX> and now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> you can still use those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um</ENAMEX> at almost any department store
 	
 	
 		what do you think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> not taking anyone but theirs
 	
 	
 		they have not done that for years
 	
 	
 		yeah do you like that or do you think that's fair or
 	
 	
 		i don't know i used when i was a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>  i worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it i'm just  i'm so used to them not taking anybody but theirs they'll take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> but see they back <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> too so it doesn't bother me because i use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> most of the time
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's theirs
 		ah okay
 		let's see
 		do you think that uh the move towards plastic is a good thing
 	
 	
 		i think i
 		
 		
 	