
 
     		
 	
 		uh well uh to begin i guess uh space
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		is uh real important i think so it's real vital to the future of
 		not only our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of time</TIMEX> i guess so
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i i agree it's it's definitely new frontier stuff
 	
 	
 		uh
 		so
 		uh but uh
 		i'm not too up to date on the space
 		on the space frontier but uh
 		but i guess they're going going pretty far into it now um Star Wars is not too far  i don't think but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i i worked on some of it at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> once upon a time
 	
 	
 		oh have you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so what do you know about it
 	
 	
 		well actually i'm i i'm quite versed lately i get on a computer network all the time and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are talking about about the current space program all the time
 		they're talking about new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> that they're designing now that
 		you know are just like science fiction you know it's like they take off you know and then they land with the with the
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know the afterburners are going you know not like space shuttle landing you know gliding down but straight down to the landing pad
 	
 	
 		really
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">VCX</ENAMEX> or something like that also called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Delta</ENAMEX> Clipper
 		which is a decent name for something like that
 	
 	
 		well
 		well i don't know you think you'd you think you'd uh go up in space you had a chance
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i think i would i think that'd be neat
 	
 	
 		would you
 		i think i would just just sitting here talking talking about it if the time came it'd be real nervous
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'd be scared i think that'd be worse than
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Flags  roller coaster</ENAMEX> that'd be
 		pretty hairy
 	
 	
 		well you know i had a car uh uh a tire come off of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> so you know that's like i know what it's like to
 	
 	
 		yeah imagine
 	
 	
 		
 
 		depending depending on what was left of my technology to get me home
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		well i guess they're talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> going to the moon and stuff now or where ever
 	
 	
 		yeah they're talking about doing that again too
 	
 	
 		and opening up those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> or what ever filling them i don't know if we'll ever see that but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well least uh have a space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> supposedly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and they're gonna put
 	
 	
 		that's all  beyond my imagination really but science fiction books
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean you look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jetsons</ENAMEX> you know a cartoon show and it's not too far fetched what what they all had in those cartoons so you never know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and they had stuff on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jetsons</ENAMEX> from that cartoon that you would never imagine would come
 		become possible and now you we have lot of those so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you never know what what may occur but
 		as far as me seeing it no
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know i don't know but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think it's real vital important for the future you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> to come so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i it's it's it's something definitely that uh
 		yeah it's it's uh got the extra little oomph of interest
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm sure it'll draw a lot more interest too once it becomes you know like it's more possible
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when they start showing the drawings and all that i'm sure you know when they
 	
 	
 		yeah i wish uh like uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> or or uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald Douglas</ENAMEX> or something like that was supposed to buy a a space shuttle sooner or later
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and just make it you know purely commercial
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'd go up you know and do things and
 		you know
 	
 	
 		so did they scratch those uh that Star Wars deal you know the one we was all worried about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and all that
 	
 	
 		oh no it's still probably going but i don't know whether it it research will go on
 	
 	
 		yeah but the economy the way it is all over them they probably cut back on
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		on that because it's not
 	
 	
 		well they're they're gonna be cutting back so much on just you know the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> we've got in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> we have here
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i know and then
 	
 	
 		but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s still gonna have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> they're still gonna be subs and things
 	
 	
 		yeah and we don't know who's handling handling them now so that's a whole different story now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		latest i heard it was just gonna be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> itself that was gonna have them
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		at least that was you know that's what everybody says oh yeah yeah we want only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to have them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now they say yeah yeah you're republic you don't want those you don't want those  give them to mother <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> over there from one of those little
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX> or whatever they're splitting it all up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and one of them crazy crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> get a hold of you never know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that's taken over for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> he's supposed to be uh
 		he's supposed to be on our side isn't he or pretty much
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hopes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think we went through him though to get to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> on a lot of subjects so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but that way  you can't never tell that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know you know kiss some butt but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		
 
 		
 		
 	