
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
  
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Miss Nancy</ENAMEX> we should be in business now did you hear the questions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> uh brought up
 	
 	
 		good
 		yes
 	
 	
 		such as how much time well i'll ask how much time do you spend with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and how many do you have
 	
 	
 		we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they're both grown and married and with we have uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> so we see them at least once a week and we see our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>  um
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about every other week</TIMEX> and uh we babysit quite frequently so we're a fairly close-knit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> we're together a lot on special <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and uh and of course with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		well you're very fortunate uh my  my uh i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam Holland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		she's her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> builds pianos so it's kind of hard for us to visit with them as much as we'd like to because we've we one thing we do have together is we're both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> i play in several symphony <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestras</ENAMEX> and she is uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a a concert uh harpsichordist and travels around good bit in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> builds forte pianos which are harpsichord sized pianos
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pianos uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh that's why they're over there and then i have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who lives in um  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warrington Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i get to see him maybe once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> so i really we've lost
 		you know i'd like to have an everyday contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh as as well as you do for that matter and my youngest my youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and so they
 	
 	
 		oh you don't get to see any of yours very often
 	
 	
 		i don't hardly get to see any of them she works in these um  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> type casinos she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> both do they work uh they're really both um
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		play <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who play on stage
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they're running lights right now and audio and that thing for plays and things that go on but anyhow uh what what do you what activities do you do with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> when you are together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh most the time well right now it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> season and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cowboy fan</ENAMEX> as is our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		she watches that and i play with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>  i enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> but now like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there's the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> space exhibit is here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and it ends uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> so she and and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i went over into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> to see the space exhibit and this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> space exhibit my goodness i would am surprised they would bring anything over here
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah it's
 		oh it's been here for quite some uh some time i think it came here in either <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's very interesting very interesting and it's been very well done uh and this uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Sunday</TIMEX> they're coming over after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cowboy</ENAMEX> game and uh uh we're going to go take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> to see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> lights and go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>'s village
 	
 	
 		i'll bet why
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh then when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s over we have a pool and he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> come and a lot of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and we have cookouts on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> uh and uh
 	
 	
 		well that sounds like you have really wonderful activities that keep you together yeah
 	
 	
 		we we do a lot with with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and we we always have we've taken a lot of trips with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> when they were younger uh we're very family oriented we um
 	
 	
 		well that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		we like being with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> seem to enjoy being with us and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> enjoy being with us so which that keeps us very very young with all these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> passing in and out and eating and seems like i've
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		the only problem is it keep you pretty busy keeping everything going doesn't it
 	
 	
 		well it does  i'm worried about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Christmas Eve</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they all pass through and then they all end up spending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> so that we open our presents on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas day</TIMEX> and they go out to the other you know the in-laws in between some of this but they're all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		beautiful
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with us and uh then have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> dinner with us and then go to other in-laws and in things so we see a lot of them but we enjoy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> because
 		they all start arriving by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about eleven o'clock</TIMEX> and we open presents <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about five o'clock</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> and you know and uh then
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> are coming down so there's gonna be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> of us
 	
 	
 		that's great there was a question the question now to ask is it difficult to find time and you seem to be making out all right
 	
 	
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
 		yeah sometimes i'm a little exhausted  but
 	
 	
 		well tell me what what do you think of uh of the current trends of how other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> spend time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and so forth
 	
 	
 		oh i think i think the trends are going back to spending more time with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are definitely uh spending more and more time i don't think they're leaving them with babysitters uh you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think i think family quality time is becoming much more important than it was there for about uh i don't know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight or nine years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		seems like it went through a spell there where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> weren't that big a deal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> kind of went and did their thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> did their thing and uh
 	
 	
 		well that's no that's exactly what i was gonna say if of of because i find now that i spend more time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> in detail i know more about them and watch their growth
 	
 	
 		yes um-hum
 	
 	
 		and how they improve and and learn much more so than my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> when when your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are growing up you just take them for granted and you go ahead and do your thing and holler at
 		
 		
 	