
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh  okay  all right i'll start uh funding
 	
 	
 		well i guess  you could go first perhaps on this one
 	
 	
 		i think that in light of the seriousness of it of the fact that that uh by what uh
 		i think they said by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year two thousand</TIMEX> there'll be at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> is it <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five thousand</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or more
 	
 	
 		is that what it is statistically
 	
 	
 		uh yeah will be dying from it and i know uh what is it uh over in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> it's just  already in horrendous uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right truly an epidemic
 	
 	
 		yeah it really is so in light of that i think that that we're probably going to have to increase the funding for research i think that uh i don't know if they have it but it looks like to me that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> could go together
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and have like a joint <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research program i don't know if they already have one of those where everybody could put in their input
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do you know if that exists <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in a cross country kind of collective
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 		i don't know i don't i don't hear about research that much except in the terms of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is doing
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> that show you know the benefits and things that they put on for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research i do i did hear about uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX> and um
 		how rampant it is over there
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and i know uh in talking to i have a relative that works for uh state welfare in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that are coming in with it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh it i mean it it's it's tragic it's just absolutely horrible and it's you know it's not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> it's you know heterosexuals it's you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> it's
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know go in for blood transfusions so i mean it's starting to affect everyone
 	
 	
 		do you think that the visibility um is part of what is keeping it in the limelight the fact that the funding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> are being discussed so so regularly um is because um
 		of  the nature of the disease the fact that it's such a terrible way to die and so on
 	
 	
 		i think that probably partly is it i think that it is has received so much more publicity since we have had well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors athletes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		everything coming down with it i think that uh i do agree with someone when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Johnson</ENAMEX> announced
 		uh there was a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman spokesperson</ENAMEX> for the gay community
 		that came out and said that you know it would not be receiving this much publicity if it wasn't for someone like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Johnson</ENAMEX> and it would be you know very interesting to see
 	
 	
 		it's true it's a different level of publicity um-hum
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right and i think it it i think it makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> more aware that it hits other than just the gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		but i do think that that
 		in light of the fact that it's going to hit all of us i think what are they saying by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX> i think it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> is supposed to have it
 		you know it it because it it is it's spreading so rapidly
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i agree with you i do believe that there should be a greater amount of uh funding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> set aside for it but i
 		i know that the visibility of it is part of what's causing it to get this attention now and i would hope that the emphasis would continue over the long term i mean i'm surprised to see
 		the numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um people</ENAMEX> who for example who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> and have died are even greater than the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who who have died from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't realize that
 	
 	
 		on on a regular basis that the statistics are higher and yet
 		it's such a benign kind of a thing it seems like it's been with us for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and it's such a
 	
 	
 		well it is i know that i i heard another conversation regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> the fact that that you know <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> is not receiving this and yet is is cancer growing at such a rapid rate
 	
 	
 		that may be the other issue that it's it's it's reaching epidemic proportions and we have
 	
 	
 		you know it it
 		you know and i think that's what is scaring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is that it is reaching such epidemic proportions you know where
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> on the rising is it rising as rapidly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know as for instance <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> you know uh it
 	
 	
 		yes and i don't know that it may not be
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't know either you know it's it's just uh
 		and granted i i do think that because of the publicity and because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know getting it and everything
 		i think that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are more aware of it than you know say if you know someone just dies with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> which is it's a tragic way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean you know it's tragic that it's that way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum i i look at the community resources that were dedicated to um those with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in terms of transitional living environments and um  volunteer services and those sorts of things
 		
 		
 	