
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well seems to me that part of the problem with public education may just be the wide disparity in what's being offered i don't know what you've experienced
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		um i agree i think that our education system needs revamped i and i think a lot of the ways they're going about it are not going to work i don't think just shoveling more money
 		into the education system is the answer um
 		i know that here they keep saying oh we need more money and more money and more money but i don't think i don't think that's the answer i think we need to take a different approach to how we go about it um
 		are you familiar at all with the voucher system
 	
 	
 		i've heard of it
 	
 	
 		um i'm in favor of that i think that you know every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> i think if we were given so much money in a voucher
 		and we're able to choose which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to take our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to i think that would put competition between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> some incentives to make
 		you know to do a better job and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> to have their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> being better and and i think it would put a lot of pressure that's needed on the education
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> so that they would you know do better rather than just getting into their jobs and getting their tenure and not having to put forth a lot i don't know what do you think about that
 	
 	
 		well part of the deal is uh  in addition to the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> there're all these other alternatives such as the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and the religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and the home schooling and
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some of these other options that uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are looking at but uh to ensure that everyone has a chance the public education system has got to do the job
 	
 	
 		right
 		right i know around here um
 		the home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is an option the only the only private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> i think there's probably one
 		well there may be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> for the elementary age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they are you know down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> so for me that's not really an option are there very many private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well there're a number of them what happens is we have a number of school districts and those school districts
 		that are considered quality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> stay in those school districts that are not quality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can afford them opt out and are going to the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that are sponsored by by the one of the religions
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		so see then that does put a little bit more um pressure on your public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to perform what happens to those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> where nobody wants to go to
 	
 	
 		well there's always <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> end up going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> who can't afford to go anywhere else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		who will end up still going to
 		that particular school
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and and can't opt out because they don't have the money to
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		go to private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> here are very expensive
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh and how about the religious are they expensive or what
 	
 	
 		i i don't know much about the religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> about the only really religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> around here are the ones operated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> but it seems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> uh get the greater share of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than the religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		oh huh does it what do you think about the salaries that our education
 		um that that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and and such make how are they down there do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> feel pretty good about them or are they
 	
 	
 		well
 		well you know salaries for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> i think are low everywhere um
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> never end up making much money
 	
 	
 		no not
 	
 	
 		if you're if you're good in an area and are not dedicated you can make far more money being in that area rather than teaching in that area
 	
 	
 		do you have year around school
 	
 	
 		no do you
 	
 	
 		they don't
 		uh they do in this area
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> don't go to it but they were talking about starting it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> but there's quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> around here that have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> around school um
 	
 	
 		well they've been talking about that a few school districts are going to start experimenting with that but
 		it hasn't really gotten going yet
 	
 	
 		oh oh i'm i'm not sure i think that's the answer either  do do a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> there that teach during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter months</TIMEX> then have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> jobs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> as far as i know they're doing something else but i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		specifically
 		you know what they are doing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of course if if it interrupted it here then it would mess up lots of sports and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> and other things that rely on that
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		you know long vacation period
 	
 	
 		right yeah that's kind of the situation here because a lot of there's a lot of farming it's kind of a
 		we live in a farming and a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> you know area and and those the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at least when they get junior high and high school age are needed to to help out with those kind of jobs and so they don't
 		do it with the junior high or the high school
 		uh age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> it's just
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		done on the elementary basis so far here but i don't know there's there's a lot of questions a lot of concerns i think our education system
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> is a good one i really do i think it it it's a
 		
 		
 	