
 
     		
 	
 		okay what do you think about uh this health insurance business
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i watched something on TV <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of months ago</TIMEX> by uh General ex uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Surgeon General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koop</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he talked about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s system and it appears to work fine for the normal colds and things like that but the expensive stuff heart uh operations and things they have a
 		managed scarcity and they said that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> there were as many
 		heart uh trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> as there is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> there's as many uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> that are equipped to do hospital uh heart operations as in the entire area of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and that's kind of spooky
 	
 	
 		well i uh
 		i understand what you're saying and there's probably some truth to that i think that uh generally i don't
 		welcome added government responsibilities however when a
 		anybody can't police their own profession it eventually leads to that and i think the costs and the uh
 		the way the medical profession has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> i uh being in my own business uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last six years every year</TIMEX> there's been at least minimum <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">twenty five percent</NUMEX> increase in health insurance costs
 		and
 		i think eventually the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that can afford health insurance as as it is now getting squeezed and squeezed tighter uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think they're asking for it i i think the medical profession is just
 		just pushing until there's no option but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> take it over and uh
 	
 	
 		do you think that it's just the medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> what about you know you know how expensive new equipment and technology is that's where i think most of the cost is coming
 	
 	
 		well i i think a lot of it is uh i i don't
 		disagree totally with that but uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this last summer</TIMEX> uh when we were on vacation tore up her knee and uh
 		uh it it was ligaments ligaments uh in her knee as it turned out uh she came back that uh we were out at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape Hatteras</ENAMEX> when this happened and uh she got home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the leading orthopedic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who has handled football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and is as good as they come i mean he knows knee problems okay i mean if anyone does this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> knows it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well she goes in and he says well i think this is what it is but uh you better go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and have one of these MRI things <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> for this uh
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Magnetic uh Resonance uh Imaging</ENAMEX> type thing and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> said well uh do i need that and he he says well uh
 		you know it it'll help me diagnose this i mean uh you know i i suggest you go have this thing insurance won't pick this up unless you're in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		now <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a thousand</NUMEX> uh uh dollars for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> routinely send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in for anything now for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> they didn't have this and they solved these problems
 		and you know i said to her well look you know if you feel you got to go go but i i think a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i don't know what it is but there's no doubt they get kickbacks to fill these machines up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and day
 	
 	
 		in
 	
 	
 		and even if they cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred two</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred five hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX> at uh roughly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a thousand dollars</NUMEX> every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX> uh that's ridiculous
 		i i don't care what anyone says those you know the costs are not it's a picture
 		it shouldn't cost more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> bucks for something like that you know reasonableness but they aren't reasonable fifty a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> they don't have to pay them back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> time you you know
 	
 	
 		you know yeah i'll have to agree with you there but there's another problem and that's the
 		how litigious our society is if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> makes a mistake he can be sure that he's gonna to be hauled into court
 	
 	
 		well i think that should be that's that's a another problem but that's part of our legalese problem and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> eventually will address too just you know because it's out of control i i agree with you
 		you know uh i was on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> or i i didn't make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> but there was a deal where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> was gonna be sued for malpractice on the death of an infant
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> after it was born and he was the one that delivered it and they got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> he introduced himsnelf as snake so-and-so he says well anyone have trouble awarding <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five million dollars</NUMEX>
 		and i says yeah i got problems with that i mean you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five million</NUMEX> bucks isn't going to bring this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> back you know i mean as sorrowful as it is
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh you know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> is wrong you know it he should be pulled from his license but <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five million dollars</NUMEX> and away he goes because insurance pays for it
 		you know it it it it doesn't make logical sense to me but uh
 	
 	
 		no it doesn't
 	
 	
 		uh that's
 		
 		
 	