
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> do you subscribe to Lori
 	
 	
 		well we have probably too many  we've got not enough to keep up i mean too many to keep up with we get uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes Fortune Newsweek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Living Texas Highways</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geographic</ENAMEX> i think i think i've got them all
 	
 	
 		oh gosh yeah
 		uh-huh well i i take um right now i've kind of a whittled mine down i just take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston City</ENAMEX> magazine
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you know how i used to subscribe to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Texas Highways</ENAMEX> that's one of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> for the money going
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean it's such a bargain what what i mean what is it like twelve <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		it is
 		something like that yeah
 	
 	
 		and then the photography's beautiful
 	
 	
 		it is
 	
 	
 		yeah it's matter that's i thought about it not too long ago that uh  i had seen an issue and i thought gosh i ought to give my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> but i of course now it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> i haven't done it so maybe next year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i know i had i had uh found myself about i don't know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>
 		in the in a situation where i i literally had more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> coming in than i could read and i thought this is crazy so i
 	
 	
 		right
 		you know it's not so bad if they're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> but like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> which i really enjoy um comes out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> and so it's really hard to keep up with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well i i took <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> for i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i enjoyed it and it and i it you know it has just you know a wealth of information i mean it's therefore similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
 		but whenever i got to the point that i just i just finally said this is just insane because i had so many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> i let them all lapse
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then once they were all gone and of course that took a while i didn't realize how much i had paid up on some of them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh then i decided well i you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> offered me a special thing to come back at a reduced rate you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s did and so i you know little by little i've i've you know subscribed to a few more again  but uh i take the newspaper everyday
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i've got plenty of reading material
 	
 	
 		yeah well we get the newspaper on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and that seems to be enough
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		because we'll just turn on the news otherwise and see see what the latest is
 	
 	
 		well you sound though kind of like me though but i mean it's i'm i have
 		always plenty of reading material around my house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when i go to visit my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> it drives me crazy because i i always have to be sure and put something in my suitcase to read because honestly i wonder these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't ever read
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> just a you know it's just it's it's appalling to me they have nothing to read
 	
 	
 		well maybe that's what you ought to get them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah really well uh well actually i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> i did give them a a subscription to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and they never said a word about it you know and so i thought well maybe they weren't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really i'd
 		they're not into that
 	
 	
 		maybe they weren't into it you know that's fine but it's just it's so different than
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i just i require reading material that's all that is to it
 	
 	
 		right right
 		yeah um
 		you know one thing i hate i don't know if this is really on the subject but when they call you the different places call you to sign up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at this you know and they try to give you this big bargain and and you're like no we already subscribe to enough <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> at the time and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah well i um  you know i had as a matter of fact the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> whenever i let it lapse
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they had sent me all these you know final notice things and i just you know didn't send them back in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so finally once i did decide to subscribe again
 		i sent in a a thing that said hey you know i mean it was whatever the the uh subscription rate was i think like fifteen dollars
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month later</TIMEX> i got a thing in the mail saying well hey as a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> you can now get it for twelve and they had a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one eight hundred</NUMEX> number i called up and i said hey i want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> bucks back
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right
 	
 	
 		so they extended they said they were gonna extend my subscription for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> but they're pretty competitive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 		but um i find at times
 		i have numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> piled up  and i'll just sit down you know one <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> or something and try to catch up on them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i mean i you know i enjoy it i guess you know um
 		as far as comparing that to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> it's so much easier to listen to either the radio or to watch TV to listen i mean to know what's going on rather than to read an article
 	
 	
 		oh it is it is and it just but at the same time you can  you can get information i mean there there
 	
 	
 		in a magazine
 	
 	
 		the variety and you can get different types of information and and you know television is is geared so much to
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Blow</ENAMEX> and quite frankly i mean there there are items of interest to me that you'll never find on television
 	
 	
 		exactly yeah that's true the other thing is um some magazines
 		
 		
 	