
 
     		
 	
 		all right well we'll go ahead and start with you and your opinion
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well um
 		in
 		and i think what it is in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is that we have this uh
 		despite all the complaints we have about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> we essentially
 		have a great deal of faith that despite uh any election things really aren't going to
 		change  dramatically
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		based on any given election and there really no one gets all
 		excited over politics um over the the i mean you think of some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> where they've changed uh
 		um you know it'll have a a coup or some ridiculous form of government there may change uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every few years</TIMEX> like for an example would be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but here it's it's very stable and i  there's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		nothing really to get all that excited over but maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should get a little excited and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and make some changes
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i think that has a lot to do with it like you said you know unless there's something really controversial no one ever votes
 	
 	
 		right right yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will vote presidential elections
 	
 	
 		just
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um you know a local election that may have some great import but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know over all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't have a whole lot to to worry about when it comes to politics
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i think that has a lot to do with it that and they're just lazy kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah they're that
 	
 	
 		i for instance i haven't voted since i was eighteen just like i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty two now</TIMEX> and i don't live at i live out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that i'm registered to vote in and it's just
 		and like you said unless there's something really important i just don't take the time
 	
 	
 		yeah well that that's just it i'm i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four</TIMEX> and i'm in the military
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i'm a um registered to vote in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and i only voted once it was in uh well the last presidential election
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know and that was just because you know it's  it's too much of a hassle to get the absentee ballot
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		or even to to drive back there which is what i did that time i actually went and visited my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> and voted the same time but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um in my position i  well in addition to that and the local political scene i don't know enough about it anymore to even feel that my vote means anything
 	
 	
 		right and for me i'm just afraid
 	
 	
 		because i don't know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		right exactly i'm afraid i'd vote for somebody who i didn't even you know agree with
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		just because i wanna vote or whatever
 	
 	
 		right right but i i think um
 		that's all things that
 		that
 		it's all my own laziness though
 	
 	
 		yeah oh i agree that's probably same thing
 	
 	
 		because  <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all i should take the time to find out about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> i probably should talk to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and who do live there and get the feeling for what uh
 		for what they are you know have been doing and uh or for what what they feel the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are doing and uh
 		um maybe do a little looking into it myself it's not like any of this is any big secret
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but it's just a question of taking the time and it's they're
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		higher priorities right
 	
 	
 		right you know i think it's really interesting too like with this the latest election in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> where there was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who had been part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ku Klux Klan</ENAMEX> how much yeah how much interest that brought and how many people
 	
 	
 		right <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Duke</ENAMEX> yeah
 		yeah that was interesting there was quite a few people
 		in this area that had contributed to his campaign
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm in upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and this is kind of a redneck area what the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> um printed they somehow got a list of all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>'s contributors
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and they printed a list in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> of everybody that gave money to that campaign
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		you wanna talk about getting getting even with them you know that was i thought that was beautiful  that's justice
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		yeah  well i think it's interesting how it takes something like that though
 	
 	
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		i think it's interesting how it takes something like that to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on edge about ah politics
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah oh yeah
 		yeah you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you think about having somebody uh somebody like that in power and the
 		you know and that shocks them all but then
 		um flip side of that is the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go around um harboring their own
 		racist racist practices and race race you know you ask those same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> um how they treat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and all that and you probably would not get a very favorable answer out of them
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i agree
 	
 	
 		but the idea the merit the thought of somebody who publicly was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ku Klux Klan</ENAMEX> is pretty repulsive being in a position of power like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well is there anything you think we can do to make it better or to uh
 	
 	
 		what we can do to make it better right that that's hard because
 		um i thought in the last or not not this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s election but the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> that they were gonna that there was gonna be some serious turn around of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> and all that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are finally fed up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	