
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh so my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is it i'd have to agree with that they're my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> too been a little disappointing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i'm telling you you think they'll sign <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		i really don't i just don't think
 		you know with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> getting all that money <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty seven or  twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine million</NUMEX> or whatever it was i just don't think that they're gonna be able to sign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruben Sierra</ENAMEX> and it's just gonna be a shame for you know our area
 	
 	
 		right yeah i think it's gonna have a big effect if they don't on the other uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> players
 	
 	
 		oh i do too i just the main thing is that
 	
 	
 		i think that's gonna be the big problem
 	
 	
 		it's just gonna have an effect on the the team you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		we just can't seem to
 		you know i think we've been in this spot i think we finished <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> once or maybe even twice i don't know i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i haven't been to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> just
 		it's just too disappointing i just watch them fall <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Incaviglia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i liked him but of course i understand baseball decisions are all just decisions like that have to be made by someone glad it's not me making them
 	
 	
 		right i think they're just want a stay mediocre and
 		draw their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> out there and then be happy with it and not have to pay the bucks to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contender</ENAMEX> in here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well they say as long as they draw up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greave</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentine</ENAMEX>'ll be there
 	
 	
 		but
 		right
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		so and that's the name of the game too you got to make money you know they pay these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> so much money now it's just
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's frightening you and i should be so lucky to you know to go out and swing a bat and get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two thousand dollars</NUMEX> every time you swing the bat or something like that
 	
 	
 		that's true but uh
 		they're talking about trading him if they're not able to sign him
 		and uh use the money that it would take  to sign the guy
 		you know to pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX> or
 		you know what it what it what they what else they need
 		because they've got the hitting but they need the pitching
 	
 	
 		yeah they really do
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i think they uh
 		i think they need them all i just don't understand i understand the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">somewhere</NUMEX> because big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and you know
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> a pro <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> can go out there in the afternoon probably make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five thousand dollars</NUMEX> just by doing a personal appearance at a
 	
 	
 		oh i know
 	
 	
 		at a at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> or something or sporting goods <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> but i realize the difference but i just don't understand
 	
 	
 		yeah it's sure aggravating when you go out and bust your butt working you know your day job and
 		you can work your day job the rest of your life and not bring home as much money as they bring <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in one game
 	
 	
 		oh i know i tell you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's real aggravating but
 	
 	
 		but i one thing i don't understand is why
 		a group you know headed up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> would buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rangers</ENAMEX> and not really get behind them because i tell you we need a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> looks like our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> are coming back but
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so that's that's going to be a big help to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> but you know in the past <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a dozen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> all we've had is the uh
 	
 	
 		it's always got yeah it's always
 	
 	
 		yeah the soccer team
 	
 	
 		it's always wondered me why i mean they act as though this area is not you know a big metropolitan area but you think we'd someday get an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> in here that could afford to buy the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> we need
 	
 	
 		oh i know that's a
 	
 	
 		just real aggravating to  because i've lived here you know since well i was born and raised here so i've been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> since
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about seventy seven</TIMEX> so it's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>  it's about to get you know as bad as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubs</ENAMEX> or whoever you know
 	
 	
 		oh i know
 		i've been one
 		yeah i've been i've lived here since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy four</TIMEX> and i've really been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> for the longest time and
 		excuse me i don't miss a time picking up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> and checking the box scores i mean i follow them and i follow them like i follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavericks</ENAMEX> and like i follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> but and i want to see them win because
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know damn it they the fans deserve it i mean it you know we have pretty uh great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in that stadium
 	
 	
 		right
 		i'm telling you
 	
 	
 		i love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan Ryan</ENAMEX> i guess you probably love him too
 	
 	
 		right i think this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'d go crazy if they ever got a even a play-off team
 		time i mean it would be packed and they got that new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> they're building so at least at least that'll be exciting  when we get that but
 	
 	
 		oh i do too
 		it will
 		well where do you think they're heading this year
 	
 	
 		uh it's hard to say it's gonna be depending on where the what they do with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruben Sierra</ENAMEX> and
 		uh i mean i'm getting tired of them going into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> saying you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Witt</ENAMEX>'s the answer and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Brown</ENAMEX>'s the answer and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that's getting old you know these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have been pampered i mean
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's time to to either you know put out or shut up
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Witt</ENAMEX> gets forced into wins like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seventeen</NUMEX> games or whatever and they have the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">later ten</TIMEX> game winning streak and they give him all kinds of money and then he just goes right down the tube
 	
 	
 		and
 		right and
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greave</ENAMEX> they're about to get you know they're about to get old but i like this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Johnson</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	