
 
     		
 	
 		how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mavericks</ENAMEX> doing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh so-so
 	
 	
 		so-so
 	
 	
 		yeah they're not doing too good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> they're they they think they kind of started off with a rocket there at the beginning not in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> but i mean just when uh just in general
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		just kind of come down to an even slump but they're not doing too good this year
 	
 	
 		story with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarpley</ENAMEX> is he uh is he history altogether
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh yeah
 	
 	
 		that's kind of in a
 		oh tough situation they're handling
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm kind of surprised that they uh that they that they hung onto him as long as they did
 	
 	
 		really they they gave him every chance possible with him
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh they gave him more than more than uh more than i would have
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i wouldn't i wouldn't have put up with it after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time i'd have said get out of here
 	
 	
 		uh-huh uh he's talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> but uh
 		i feel  i don't know they seem to get involved in those substance abuse problems and it's a tough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> for them
 	
 	
 		oh i know it you follow follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavericks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well you know because i follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz</ENAMEX> fairly closely and then you know we're in the same conference
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know keep tabs on them a little bit
 	
 	
 		how's the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz</ENAMEX> doing this year
 	
 	
 		they're doing well i uh
 	
 	
 		are they
 	
 	
 		they're in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> and just won the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> games they beat uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> tonight
 		it was a close <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> beat them by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> points or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> points but yeah they're doing they're doing great uh they had this little incident i don't know if you heard about it with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Malone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaiah Thomas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there was a i guess they played <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about the first two minutes</TIMEX> of the game <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaiah</ENAMEX> drove in and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX> went up to block the shot and really fouled him hard so hard that it put him to the floor and he had like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> stitches above his eye
 	
 	
 		whoa
 	
 	
 		and uh they in reviewing the tapes decided it was a flagrant foul
 		oh i guess they decided it was flagrant foul at the time of the ball game and ejected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl</ENAMEX>
 		and then he got a he got a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten thousand</NUMEX> dollar fine and one game suspension which is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about another thirty five thousand</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no kidding
 	
 	
 		so it was a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty five thousand dollar</NUMEX> deal for him and i i believe it was unintentional he fouled him hard but it wasn't like he had you know malicious intent to go cream the guy
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so there's been a big buzz about that how how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>'s the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> to begin with and when something like that happens to one of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> they're all all claiming that uh
 	
 	
 		my goodness
 	
 	
 		you know it was totally uncalled for this unnecessary violence when they've been guilty of that kind of thing for years
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laimbeer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX> are about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> worst
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hatchet men</ENAMEX> in the league  so
 	
 	
 		yeah that's for sure
 	
 	
 		anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah i didn't even hear i didn't even hear but i haven't picked up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> probably or a sports page in
 		
 
 		i venture to say in about a month
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah i haven't had a chance to so
 	
 	
 		you've you've been busy huh
 	
 	
 		yeah just been extremely busy but no i didn't i didn't even hear about that i didn't even see it on the news so i must have missed that one altogether
 	
 	
 		well yeah it it was probably  more local interest obviously but
 	
 	
 		no  something something like that they usually they'll usually you know play that just about anywhere
 	
 	
 		yeah and everybody's interested in seeing the little well it's just the nature of the human i guess to like to see a little violence  i think
 	
 	
 		oh especially excessive violence where somebody gets hurt especially oh it's just so but we're raised we're raised on that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		everybody's raised on that
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		on the negatives of life i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i've had about enough of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Johnson</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> though
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess where he's uh appears he's touring with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jabbar</ENAMEX>'s thinking of coming out of retirement to help fund the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research and
 		i don't know you hear both those stories
 	
 	
 		yeah i heard those
 	
 	
 		i guess that's a nice gesture on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jabbar</ENAMEX>'s part
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		might as well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's going to take a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do that though  it's going to take a lot of research
 	
 	
 		what do you what do you think about that do you do you think that he got what he deserved or
 	
 	
 		you mean as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i mean you know he  he got to pay to pay to play as they say
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah but he's he's paying pretty hard
 	
 	
 		yeah i did see it  circumstances but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		i guess
 		i guess maybe we'll
 		you know some good come of it because of this
 		you know it's a notoriety and focus that it'll have on the disease
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true he definitely he definitely opened it up and showed a different side of it
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> are going to do without him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> they they're doing all right now from what i see but
 	
 	
 		i don't think they'll hold together
 	
 	
 		yeah he's uh the was the heart and soul of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		no i believe you're right
 		i believe you're right
 	
 	
 		anyway what other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> you follow any
 	
 	
 		no that's about it i i i just really i mean when it gets down to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end end of the season</TIMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mavericks</ENAMEX> are doing good i'll stay up with them but yeah i i'm dedicated to a point
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know just like i'm more dedicated in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> i guess than anything
 	
 	
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> are a lot more popular aren't they
 	
 	
 		well yeah well i was raised on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mavericks</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		i i was raised with the old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> Chaparrals
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> though
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was that was uh i guess the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro team</ENAMEX> that
 		that they had here
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 		
 		
 	