
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 		well what kind of music do you like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i play piano and organ and have since i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and i sing in church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> and have done that since i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and still sing now
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		and uh i play cello
 		in high school and college and occasionally play as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> but i don't have a cello and i rarely ever practice so it's like adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that's i teach school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult groups</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or something when they are in dire need of somebody
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i still pick it up occasionally
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is a music major he's uh in performing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> horn he was an all state <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> horn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> all through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so there's a lot of music in our family
 	
 	
 		well that's terrific i think it's wonderful that you got that that you play an instrument that you passed it on to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>  i uh  um as as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> reluctantly took piano  for for uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>  and you know  looking back i'm i'm really happy that i had that experience because certainly i i learned some basics about music that i would've been completely ignorant of had i not had those lessons
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i i wish now of course you know in  in hindsight that i had  uh uh uh kept it up but i didn't but nonetheless i i do have some uh rudimentary knowledge of uh
 		the scales and the keys and the chords and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera
 	
 	
 		um-hum  do you do anything with music nowadays
 	
 	
 		other than buy it  prerecorded
 	
 	
 		no  you you buy it and listen to it huh
 	
 	
 		exactly yeah and and uh what i i i am kind of i've got a real nice stereo system that i've invested too much money in and you know all the latest gadgets and but i do enjoy good music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i've got quite a wide uh
 		repertoire  i mean i've i've got everything from classical to jazz or rock and roll to blues i mean it's just i i cover the whole gamut and it depends on the mood i'm in uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and for instance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> and the newspaper i  for some reason like to listen to classical music  and uh other times it you know just something completely different will strike me i i like almost everything except rap
 	
 	
 		i i do too i don't really care that much for rap  the only thing i i've liked
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		with rap is is when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at school uh will take information and they'll learn it by making a rap out of it and then i think it's useful otherwise i don't have any use for it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well it's  it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time something that has come along that makes me feel  that you know i am obviously of another generation this is a there's gap between me and rap music  and  i guess
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum i understand
 	
 	
 		you know that's just i don't relate to it at all but then again i'm that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it it's definitely a a huge hit with the younger people
 	
 	
 		they seem to like it
 	
 	
 		they do
 	
 	
 		well my eldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> took piano for  oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years</TIMEX> and lost interest but he learned enough that he can still sit down and play and enjoys doing that and has a keyboard
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> uh took piano for a while she also played bassoon and then she  has taken dance well she took dance from the time she was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about five</NUMEX>
 		on up through <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of college and
 		she got so involved in dance and that sort of thing that she let the instruments kind of slide behind
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and but yet she still enjoys uh music and still enjoys dance and you know for exercise she wants aerobics to music and that you know that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well you sound like you've got a very talented family
 	
 	
 		well they do have quite a bit of musical ability which is is nice uh we do enjoy good music and uh
 		like  however uh with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> going through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in college right now they are the ones that have the stereos we we don't seem to have much stereo one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> we will
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh it
 		yeah yeah really well um uh  uh what was i gonna ask i was there was a question that's on the tip of my oh yeah  as far as a voice did you ever have any uh uh voice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> either or lessons
 	
 	
 		the the only ones that i ever had were actually through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> where they had uh
 	
 	
 		or
 	
 	
 		a voice teacher uh offer lessons at sort of at a discount you might say for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> who were interested so i did that a couple of times
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but as far as as any other training no i just it was uh what i learned through singing in choirs and um  my other music piano and the organ and the cello
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine the reason i ask a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>  both took voice for oh i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four years</TIMEX>  and they sing like angels they have the most they you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're just beautiful and i wonder how much of it is innate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> and how much of that is a a function of of how much they've learned and and retained
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well there has to be some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> there there has to be some voice
 	
 	
 		something to work with
 	
 	
 		something to work with right i mean you can only overcome so much but there are tricks to make
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	