
 
     		
 	
 		well uh down here in we've got um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		trials by uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> in criminal cases and the sentencing can be done by the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> normally although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> can sometimes do it how do y'all do it up there
 	
 	
 		um we usually do it uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> comes to the verdict and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> does the sentencing
 		um i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> can recommend something but
 		in  you know in some cases like uh murder in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> degree but i the ultimate decision is the is the decision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> once the
 		verdict has been reached the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s dismissed
 		and there's a separate hearing for sentencing
 	
 	
 		we've got a lot of these uh in federal court they have a uniform sentencing
 		guidelines that pretty well leave it up to the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to assess the punishment in a certain range
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think it's curious that  the sentences that are handed down are usually not served
 		i think that's a big problem with the criminal justice system but
 	
 	
 		right here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area if you are sentenced to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> or less to incarceration in in the uh penitentiary
 		you will never make it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">penitentiary</ENAMEX> and you'll serve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> and then be released because of the jail overcrowding
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i i understand the jail overcrowding issue but
 		i i think in in in that case as as as in so many all they ever do is discuss the problems and they never do anything to solve them
 		i think that's why this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s in the shape it's in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> but i i don't really believe that a jury
 		should do the sentencing i think
 	
 	
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has a better idea of what is
 		probable ranges for that particular type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> where a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> is just doing it for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		yeah i just don't believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> have the
 		the knowledge the scope and the knowledge  to to handle the sentencing whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> does
 	
 	
 		well you know in in civil cases they can have uh as few as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> agree on a verdict but criminal normally requires unanimous
 		they might make a change on that and that might make for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer</NUMEX> mistrials
 	
 	
 		that's that's certainly true
 		i just i i mean i don't agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> doing the sentencing but i do agree with trial  trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> i just think that's critical
 	
 	
 		course in civil cases trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> doesn't necessarily work if you have a big complex uh business type case where a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> could get totally lost
 		in a lot of those cases <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> decide to just try the case before a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and just not have a jury
 	
 	
 		right well i think that can that makes sense too because it looks like it would be awfully hard to pick
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> that could follow something as in in a civil case i mean that was really complicated and had a lot of technical issues in it but they  there are a lot of criminal cases a lot of murder cases and
 		that  that are really very complicated and they seem to be able to get through those
 	
 	
 		and you had up there <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> that case of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> who poisoning her various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> what was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">it Blanchard</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blanche Taylor Moore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Blanche yes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we've we've been reading about that
 	
 	
 		yeah we uh have you have you heard about  trial that we've got going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> with the uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that's accused of molesting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at a day care center
 	
 	
 		no i don't remember reading about that
 	
 	
 		well that's the uh that's probably one of the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> malestation cases in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s history
 		this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> it it's a trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> but it's really going real ragged i don't understand how they're doing it
 		and they got they he had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and seventy eight</NUMEX> charges against him
 		and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>'s managed to get it reduced to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety three</NUMEX>
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> in that case they've just absolutely sequestered them
 		nobody even unless you were paying attention at the very beginning you don't even know their names and they uh uh from what i've been reading in the paper they are the ones who are gonna
 		do the sentencing in that
 	
 	
 		we've got a case going here where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is accused of poisoning his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arsenic</ENAMEX> now and the jury the case went to the jury <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s deliberating right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arsenic</ENAMEX> is uh this this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blanche Taylor Moore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was very clever she did it very slowly over a large period a long period of time at least it was
 		it was done very slowly over a large period of time
 		and since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> has
 		found her guilty now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> did the sentencing in that and she's appealing but
 		i'm assuming that she's guilty because i really believe in the jury system
 	
 	
 		well the collective wisdom of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> usually prevails
 	
 	
 		yeah hopefully they're smart enough not to be hoodwinked by
 		illegal ploys by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	