
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay i guess we're ready to start well i guess what part of  what part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> do you live in oh okay well i'm also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Texas</ENAMEX> what about yourself
 		okay
 	
 	
 		the reason i ask is the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> conversations i've had or have been out of state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um  have you always lived here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		no i've lived here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost five years</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and i'm a uh before that i was at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester New York</ENAMEX> and i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well you are seeing quite a different climate and quite a different neighborhood
 	
 	
 		that's right but i like it
 	
 	
 		you probably have enjoyed getting away from the snow
 	
 	
 		well i missed it at first but now i go back there and i'm a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wimp</ENAMEX> about the cold  so i like it here it's nice
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's good i
 		i have lived
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> essentially all my life and around in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i have traveled up in the northeast and around and have enjoyed it but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know i'm not sure i would want to take on those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> i'm getting older and
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		uh not sure that's really something i wanna do
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i live uh over in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Highlands area</ENAMEX> if you're familiar with that area
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um tell me where that is um
 	
 	
 		okay uh you
 	
 	
 		i probably do know but i don't know by that name
 	
 	
 		this is pretty well where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> and Audelia Skillman cross
 	
 	
 		okay sure
 	
 	
 		we're just north of uh
 		White <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rock Lake</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah i know that area that's a nice area
 	
 	
 		well we have some very nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house homes</ENAMEX> here in this area um
 		my particular i guess they want us to describe the area so um my particular area the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> run <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">anywhere from about sixty five</NUMEX> eighty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> on up to probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a million</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's quite a range
 	
 	
 		yes um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> that were
 		here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>  were smaller now they've gotten larger and larger as
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		as they've developed the land and of course it's pretty static right now and all the values over here have dropped off because of the economy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		well i am um i'm gosh i'm barely in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i'm just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Addison Airport</ENAMEX> up on the tollway
 	
 	
 		okay
 		uh okay
 	
 	
 		and i guess we have a similar situation i mean we've got houses <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> away that are probably <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">around seventy eighty thousand</NUMEX> and then we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bent Tree</ENAMEX> right across the street
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so i don't i don't even know how high those go but some of those are pretty big
 	
 	
 		yes those are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a million</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah  so it's that's the strange thing about i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> because back where i'm from you wouldn't have that sort of a variation at all
 		they'd all be pretty similar to one another within a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple miles</NUMEX> so
 	
 	
 		well we have suffered from real lack of land use planning in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> not as bad as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but  exactly what you're describing is what happens all over
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah i've noticed that
 	
 	
 		well now do you live in a a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot home</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh we've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> let's see we moved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years ago</TIMEX>
 		and it was it had previously been unoccupied but it had existed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>
 		this is a whole block of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> that uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builder</ENAMEX> built all of them and i guess he he did some crazy thing to get some extra money from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> and then ran away
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
  
 	
 	
 		type of deal so the whole block was all foreclosed
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and so some were vacant for quite a while before they you know they finally sold them because there were so many
 	
 	
 		well your was your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in good shape was it damaged
 	
 	
 		yeah no the only thing that we were worried about was the air conditioner because they'd have it just running constantly with the doors and windows open
 	
 	
 		oh it was oh
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah so we just you know we bargained to get an extra warranty on that
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and um we're really we haven't had any problems and you know we had originally thought we'd have to get a fix up special or something because being from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> we figured we couldn't afford anything
 		but the prices are much lower here and this was definitely not a fix up special but i'll tell you it takes all my time
 		between we put in our own sprinkler system and i just finished repainting the exterior and you know making drapes and buying furniture it's just a money pit really is
 	
 	
 		yes i
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		am familiar with that i where i live is a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that's seventeen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> when i bought it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we bought it from someone who was in it but before they had it i found out after i had been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> it had it had sat empty for the better part of a year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm not sure what happened but i do know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> that we bought it from had done virtually no maintenance for for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		i i
 		i found a lot of things which
 		
 		
 	