
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what what how do you get your main source of current events
 	
 	
 		well until until recently i was taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and i thought that was a good way but i have about
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> that i get that keeps me up on things you know it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> late but uh that's how i'm staying up
 	
 	
 		i either watch the news or i or occasionally occasionally i'll read the paper
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh do you like how it's presented on the news
 	
 	
 		um no i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s a little bit too manipulative
 		they  allow you uh uh they they try to lead you too much i believe and and sometimes they're not very
 		open i i don't know i think they're a little bit biased sometimes like for example the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> rape case the the coverage on that was
 	
 	
 		it
 		it
 	
 	
 		you know when it first happened it was he was guilty he was guilty he was guilty and you you you know they they they try to have you form opinions or whatever
 		and and then i didn't i didn't like the things uh the things that were going on when we had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX> and stuff like that you know basically i i i think they don't present the
 		the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of of everything
 	
 	
 		so it it makes you feel like they're uh wanting you to take their opinion
 	
 	
 		right uh it's it it's uh it's instead of reporting the news uh it's more like an editorial i believe on a lot of issues
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i've noticed that too and it's kind of distressing isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they just i've noticed that they do it just with subtle little words uh usually uh just
 		that sway the whole uh report that you know by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just a couple of</NUMEX> words
 	
 	
 		well when i when i was in school i um
 		i i was a communications major so i'm i'm i'm i'm i'm i'm well aware of the little subtle words and persuasive speaking and
 		and so forth
 	
 	
 		so communications huh were you looking into becoming a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i was and um um i went i ventured off in a whole entire different field field um i work with the state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i um
 		work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of State Treasury</ENAMEX> in retirement disability uh calculate benefits
 	
 	
 		i bet that's a interesting job
 	
 	
 		yeah so the
 		and so i and you know work is you know working for state government you you hear all about current events about about things going on within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> itself so that that's another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> that i i i i where i keep up with current events and
 	
 	
 		yeah there's one that i'm reading right now it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Week</ENAMEX> it says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> to account for the the benefits that
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX> now says you have to show as a liability it's going to cost them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five billion</NUMEX> after tax charge in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety three</NUMEX> to account for that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's a lot of money
 	
 	
 		and it'll drop their earnings by a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> forever more
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's a lot of money
 	
 	
 		yeah it is and yeah you have to stay up on stuff and i bet in your your job that you have to do you read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no well no i i i i i primarily deal with the state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> but i i find interesting tidbits in what the news reports as far as
 		the like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>'s budget and stuff like that and i i really know what the budget is and and and
 		uh uh when they were saying we were so poor and they couldn't pay taxes and to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> their income tax refunds and stuff like that and you know i'm well aware of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of assets the that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> has and it's it's it's it's just funny
 		you you know so that's that's that's that's so i don't have a whole lot of faith in in you know the news of course it's they they get what they hear from but you know it's not always i i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> percent reliable
 	
 	
 		do you can can you think of anything that could be done to make our news media more accurate and objective
 	
 	
 		i think they need to do a little bit uh go into a little bit more depth uh and before they would just report like somebody wants to make a statement or something like that because i mean another example is the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> issue or whatever that you know someone said oh i found a cure they immediately the headlines on the news or whatever is so and so has found a cure for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months later</TIMEX> it's discovered it's not you know it's
 		uh before they before they come out with something like that they need to to research the the the matter i believe a little bit more
 	
 	
 		i guess they do that so they don't get scooped you know so they have the big story
 	
 	
 		well that that
 		well yeah i i think i it i think the  the
 		
 		
 	