
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		um we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> at the moment we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and we also have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> that's a strange combination  i visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> is an an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">outdoor cat</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um we've had him for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> it's really a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> when we first talked about getting one my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> isn't really fond of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we went ahead and got this one for my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandma</ENAMEX> and it's turned out to be a very good pet she or he is
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um you know he stays outside he doesn't try and come in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and trip you up and he just he's almost like a dog our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> will come down the road and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> will come running out from
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		the fields we live in quite a rural little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and and he comes running he can hear our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>  so he is more more you know like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> it's really a good animal
 	
 	
 		oh
 		does your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> try to run away at all
 	
 	
 		no we haven't had a bit of problem with that the only um
 		incident we had about like that was when he was just a kitten um on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> we lost track of him and i don't know whether he followed some trick-or-treaters or you know they scared him or what but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he uh was gone and we thought for sure he was gone and he was gone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> and then he yes and then he came back and he had a crooked paw so apparently he had
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yeah apparently he had broken his foot somehow but he did come back so
 	
 	
 		well that's great
 	
 	
 		yes yes and how about you
 	
 	
 		we have a dog
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> it's about medium size and she's uh an indoor dog
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		oh fun
 	
 	
 		and she is yeah she's like our baby
 	
 	
 		oh now is it is that's that's not still considered a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not technically we consider her a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> i she still acts like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		do you oh real active and
 	
 	
 		yeah oh very
 	
 	
 		oh what's oh what's her name
 	
 	
 		too active
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Samantha</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh oh that's that's a nice name we um our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> is named
 		we named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">it Duchess</ENAMEX> and then we found out it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>  but it was too late to change so  and now is is that the only pet you have
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh that's neat
 		yes
 	
 	
 		oh the what kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> is it
 	
 	
 		she's a mix between a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German Shepherd</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Husky</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh pretty
 	
 	
 		yeah she is really pretty and she's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchdog</ENAMEX> we live in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom apartment</ENAMEX> and she will growl and bark at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> walking by or she hears any footsteps
 	
 	
 		ah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh oh that's good
 	
 	
 		yes it is good it's nice to have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> apparently allow they allow pets
 	
 	
 		yes we it was hard to find um <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> out here we live in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State University</ENAMEX> and it's hard to find <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> that take <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> so we're way on the outskirts of town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		because and we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ground floor apartment</ENAMEX> with like a private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> that we can just open up the door and we play <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Frisbee</ENAMEX> and ball and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		how nice
 	
 	
 		so that she gets some exercise we go for walks
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that sounds ideal because yeah they do need especially  dogs they need to run and jump and oh well that's great i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		we had a um our little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> we've only had it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six months</TIMEX> and we got that for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> for his birthday and
 		it's named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buttercup</ENAMEX> a little yellow yellow parakeet  yeah they chose that and i <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other pet we had had an experience with over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> it's a kind of a funny thing we
 	
 	
 		oh that's a good bird name
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> had given her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> each <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a a a</NUMEX> a bunny rabbit for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		yes and and then her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> had them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of months</TIMEX> and they you know kind of tired of them like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do and and she said do you want these and
 		so we said yes we'll take them and and take care of them for a while and she said now you know when you don't want them i know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that just loves them and he'll take them anytime you want and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we were a little bit reluctant with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and the bird already to take on some more  but so we took these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> rabbits from them
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two weeks later</TIMEX> um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> went out to feed them and and he said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> i i think the white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bunny</ENAMEX>'s sick
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		and so yeah we went out immediately and lifted up the hutch lid and that mama rabbit the white one
 		had had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>  uh yeah eleven oh so that was quite a surprise and
 	
 	
 		how many
 		oh my goodness
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so we went from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> bunnies to fifteen in a matter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>  but that i guess that was her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and i i'm not real
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		knowledgeable about bunnies but they all died and i they all did and she well she didn't take care of them and i've heard sometimes that with their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> their first
 	
 	
 		oh they all did
 	
 	
 		you know litter that they do that but  yeah it was it was really a really hard experience
 	
 	
 		oh that's sad
 		
 		
 	