
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		okay where does she live
 	
 	
 		uh on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rutherford</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Rutherford i don't know that
 	
 	
 		it's um corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>  uh just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		west of Mayfield
 	
 	
 		it's oh oh south and
 		okay yeah i know where you i know the area right that's kind of on the other side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> so our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> probably never went to school together or anything
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh okay
 		oh they're they're little ones
 	
 	
 		oh well i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in college  by now uh
 	
 	
 		oh  let's see we're on government whether we think it's honest  or can be
 	
 	
 		right right  is it possible to have an honest government i'm beginning to think it's not what about you
 	
 	
 		i i don't think under the way the system is right now it is
 	
 	
 		i don't either i i think uh even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have good intentions and i think crime uh power corrupts or something or to a certain extent you know
 	
 	
 		and ultimate power ultimately returns  corrupts
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems like um maybe more of them come in with good intentions but it's just so enticing and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corners</ENAMEX> being cut and the special deals available because they're in on the know you know
 	
 	
 		i don't know if there's enough money that you could pay them just you know
 	
 	
 		love them
 	
 	
 		x amount of money to keep them honest i just i just don't uh
 	
 	
 		right i mean you even see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on a small scale
 		cheating when they have certain positions you know what i mean little bit little bitty positions and in your own home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and they'll cheat somehow or you know bend the rules use their power so maybe it's just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s inner nature
 	
 	
 		right
 		we had uh here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> we had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> a major uh
 		corruption on on our county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commissioners</ENAMEX> and there were several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> uh including the one i was in that lost everyone of their county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commissioners</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh my word
 	
 	
 		i mean it was to the point of not just losing their job but going to jail
 	
 	
 		oh wow what were they doing taking some oh no oh gosh yeah right
 	
 	
 		oh they were taking kickbacks
 		yeah  just a little here and a little there and major amount here and major amount there
 	
 	
 		right oh
 	
 	
 		but i think there was something like you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forty commissioners</ENAMEX> that ended up going to jail
 	
 	
 		um  we haven't had that big a scandal in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> but we do have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">convention center</ENAMEX> were falsifying records other words they'd go out and have a big lavish dinner and then put somebody's name down that they supposedly had entertained
 		but that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> wasn't even anywhere near there you know sometimes they weren't even in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> one of them had had <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and died and i mean that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our biggest</TIMEX> scandal for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		uh that that's small scale i don't know you know i really don't know what could be done
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't either uh to make it totally honest uh i think there's always there's always gonna be some way somebody can cut a corner uh however
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		the things that have gone on gone on in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX> we can't afford too many of those you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> mess and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> and L we can almost not afford such terrible corruption
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		the cover-ups and
 	
 	
 		right right i think that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> were up to their necks in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Contra</ENAMEX> thing and it kind of makes you feel bad that the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would be lying to you like that but uh
 	
 	
 		i uh i don't know i just uh i'd like to believe that there is some way
 		that
 		our political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would really go there and look out for our interests i think that's what upsets me worse than that they're getting a little you know uh on the side that
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that it seems that when they get up there it's it's what if i vote your way what it'll do for me rather than this is the way my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> want it
 	
 	
 		that's right but they stay there
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right and this'd be for the best for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> overall  you're right it's just a i don't know i guess that's where they stay in uh
 		and they try to stay in office but then they always please the money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too they need money so much because they're constantly having to run run for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> again and
 	
 	
 		run
 		maybe and then you think if well if it was longer terms then they would never have  try to please the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i don't know it is a big problem but i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are kind of depressed and cynical about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> now don't you
 	
 	
 		i don't think that they anyone has a lot of respect or faith in the government
 	
 	
 		i know it's really terrible i mean there was a time i mean where i remember when i was real young i just loved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX> i thought he was great oh you know i had some some of them seemed like kind of uh heroic people
 	
 	
 		well  i wonder if they really were or if we just really didn't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	