
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um  capital punishment i i know that's kind of a touchy subject i i personally believe that there is a need for capital punishment
 		um especially you know in some of the the real violent type murder and and crimes i feel like that it's a it's a justifiable punishment  do you
 	
 	
 		i certainly agree with that we have <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> has now become one of the most
 		crime oh our crime rate has just exceeded all
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		possible goals or whatever and we keep coddling all of our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> incarcerated we have to have certain amount of space for them
 	
 	
 		oh dear
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm with i think we just must keep this capital punishment and i don't believe keeping them on death row for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five years</TIMEX> is answering any of our problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i agree i think it just it jams up the system and you know we spend <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands of dollars</NUMEX> keeping them there and
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and i feel that yeah it's not fair to the public and it's it i think it's a terrible shame
 	
 	
 		well it's not fair to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so um
 	
 	
 		now do you have um what types of capital punishment do they use or in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> what is legal
 	
 	
 		um
 		the lethal dose of uh you know slip in it i think they maybe should get back to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> hangings
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		no no i don't really mean that but if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could see what was really happening
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i think it would deter this more than than going in with the needle and injecting them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum  now we in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> they have uh either the firing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> or the lethal injection are the two methods that are that are used here and i know um
 		not too long ago it's probably been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years</TIMEX> now that um one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> chose to die by the firing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> and
 		and i well i think that was the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that died here was by the firing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> and um
 		so i know those are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> forms of punishment they use now but you know just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> we had a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that was on death row for for killing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> and her fifteen month old baby
 		and then they came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two days ago</TIMEX> and and said that something had
 		not been done right with the trial and so now they've they've just have have to start all over again go through the same process all over again and oh i think that's ridiculous i just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what a waste of money and time and resources and you know oh
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		since our have you ever served on a jury
 	
 	
 		no i have not
 	
 	
 		that is one of the most um
 		well i think everyone should at least once
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it was uh i've never been on capital punishment but um i wonder if these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were guilty until proven innocent if we would not gain or more from our attorneys
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		i don't know i i've been called to trial duty but i never they canceled it you know before i got there so i've never never had that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well it certainly is a responsibility
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but i think that uh we need to demand more from our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> when they withhold information we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> cases going here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them were murder the well finally the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> admitted to having smothered his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> even though he loved her dearly
 	
 	
 		oh no
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so he goes up for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> with with a possibility of being out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is charged with um poisoning his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arsenic</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		and it was a a apparently it went on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a year</TIMEX> they're a very wealthy family
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		oh it just
 	
 	
 		boy
 	
 	
 		it it you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you wonder why why this happens
 	
 	
 		yes well i don't know about your situation there but here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> they're
 		we're having to build new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> because there is no place to put to put these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> they're just the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> are so full and so we're spending more and more money building new ones when when all these you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> are on death row and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's just you know
 	
 	
 		well we let our our previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> wanted to put a tent uh you know just build
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 		
 	