
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		all right
 		uh what kind of hobbies are you into
 	
 	
 		well i'm quilting and uh pressing fact i was pressing a
 		the uh pieces for a quilt block i will stop start stitching on  when the phone rang
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so where uh what are you into woodwork
 	
 	
 		uh no uh tole painting and uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		folk art
 	
 	
 		yeah i saw something uh you've seen these old wooden school desks the old ones
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i saw some uh
 		or one anyway in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> here
 		oh i don't even remember where i was
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three weeks ago</TIMEX> that had been uh
 		painted with that looked like maybe just a flat finish and then tole painting on it and the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and borders and trims and stuff and it was just real pretty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah we we used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hillsboro</ENAMEX> and i there's a
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> that i knew that had a uh gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and she gave art lessons and i've taken lessons there and got into it and
 		tried a little bit of landscaping so
 		painting is pretty interesting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how long you been quilting quite a while or
 	
 	
 		no not uh not a real long time since about um
 		i guess it was in probably nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eight</NUMEX> when i got into it
 		and i belong to a quilt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guild</ENAMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> we just meet once a month but
 		uh we've had a project going this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last almost a year</TIMEX> now where we uh when i joined the quilt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guild</ENAMEX> there was just
 		i made the
 		i think the thirteenth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> and we just wrote down the names of the
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> and then we all drew for uh
 		a month
 		and everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guild</ENAMEX> makes a block
 		for the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who's turn it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that month</TIMEX> and we have the uh
 		privilege of selecting a pattern or
 		of colors or providing the material and the pattern
 		or some of them just say
 		uh for instance the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> is what they call a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> sampler
 		and she gave us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> piece of uh fabric to use in it and then we have to come up with something else to go with it
 		and when they're all put together needless to say they've got enough for a block and our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guild</ENAMEX> has grown now to where we have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> members
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and so uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> is when i get the blocks
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has picked the
 		the pattern that he wants and the colors so
 		it'll be it'll be interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah it sounds like it  i've seen some beautiful quilts around i i've got some that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> made and i still have
 	
 	
 		oh goodness those are those are really
 		family heirlooms and
 	
 	
 		yeah i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that uh she made when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> with the you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raggedy Ann</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX> patterns on it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's some of the stitches you know have come loose on it but
 		you know i still keep it though
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		do you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no i i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JC Penney</ENAMEX>'s uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that i'm in a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout troop</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Rita</ENAMEX>'s church by uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">635</NUMEX> and the tollway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Godfrey</ENAMEX> that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> who's doing this his son's in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout</ENAMEX> troop
 		and he contacted us and he he suggested that all the adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> do this and turn the money in
 		that they collected for the phone calls to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troop</ENAMEX> so we you know pick up a little extra funds that way
 	
 	
 		oh well that's good
 		it really is that's a
 		a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund raiser</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it's you know easy way to pick up maybe a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> and get enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
 		involved
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it has been pretty quiet on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">switchboard</ENAMEX> lately uh for a while i was getting calls pretty often
 		and then they when the switchboard went down for a while and then after it started up again well we haven't uh it hasn't been real
 		active i was a little bit surprised when i uh picked up the phone <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> and got the recording you know that it was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		was back on and i have lost the number in fact maybe you could give it to me that you call in uh to make to make a call
 	
 	
 		okay
 		okay you got a
 	
 	
 		and uh just a let's see if i
 		get over here where i can get to a
 		pen
 		um
 		i may get an incoming call anytime but uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	