
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i tell you what uh my my uh notion of camping is uh
 		uh well i haven't been very far out see i've been in the uh hill <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that's about as far as i've gone as far as camping so i haven't done any really really rough rugged camping
 		but uh yeah to me it's the uh pitching a tent and i mean we we're talking real roughing it no cabin no johns nothing just being out there in the woods yeah that's it exactly no uh i don't
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Boy Scout</ENAMEX> huh yeah do you do you backpack <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> camp
 	
 	
 		no actually the only camping i ever did was was when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout</ENAMEX> and uh as much as i would like to you know to do it i
 		you know don't really have the time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> but i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and i'm waiting for them to get a little bit older then we'll start doing some camping
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s twelve and he's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Boy Scout</ENAMEX> and he went on his first backpack <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five miles</NUMEX> i've gone with him on uh some other things where we
 	
 	
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		we kind of called it car camping where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is you know a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundred feet</NUMEX> away or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i did not go on the backpack i'm uh my back wouldn't allow me to  carry that so
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		he got the backpack in and carried the whole thing and do it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Boy Scout way</ENAMEX> and he came back tired and wore out but what i didn't my scouting was not as involved as i'd want i got the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> and that was it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i'm hoping he'll go all the way his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troop</ENAMEX> is very active and there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about as many</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">dads</ENAMEX> involved as going out camping and canoeing as there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		that's great
 		yeah that's great
 	
 	
 		it's an important part are you involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Guides</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no not yet but i'll tell you i i know i was when i was smaller i started out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Guides</ENAMEX> and then went into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cub Cub</ENAMEX> for a very short time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then we kind of i kind of got away from it for a while and then uh when i got back into it again i was ready for for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> and i joined joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scouts</ENAMEX>
 		but i tell you i i sure uh recommend it for any any any young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy girl</ENAMEX> too i mean i i really enjoyed my time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scouts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		does
 		we've done rent a tent in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> once where it was a state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and they have very nice manicured
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well paved <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and beautiful uh
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathrooms</ENAMEX> within walking distance and you rent a site and they rent a tent that's and you put your tent well one tent's already up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's not very rough at all you have electricity and running running water right there but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i think for a family outing it's good
 		uh but you know if you're with a bunch of uh preteen and and young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> who really want to rough it yeah i i'd recommend going the old backpack method
 	
 	
 		you mentioned the word rough my idea of rough my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s idea of roughing it is if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> only has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday Inn</ENAMEX> to choose from and she just feels like she's being imposed upon
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i kind of at my age i kind of like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car car car</ENAMEX> uh camping
 	
 	
 		yeah i can understand that
 	
 	
 		uh uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> uh their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are out of college by gosh they're already into this uh well car camping plus they will leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few miles</NUMEX> away
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh but they're they're they're enjoying that so uh we've gone cabin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camping</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh where there's a uh you you uh have all the conveniences but you camp in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> and that's not camping at all in your opinion
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i hope you find more places to go camping
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm really looking forward to it you know i i really did enjoy my experience and i i'm hoping my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>'ll enjoy it as much as i did
 	
 	
 		have you checked checked into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">State Park system</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no not yet but i tell you i i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> she hasn't she really wasn't uh well her family
 		they used to go camping quite a bit when she was younger then as she got older they kind of stopped going and and she's expressed interest in going and doing some camping so
 	
 	
 		sleeping on the ground that whole bit huh
 	
 	
 		but probably yeah probably not that rough we're probably talking probably tents
 	
 	
 		screened in shelters work her up to screened in shelters that's a good place to start from in a yeah a cot and then slowly break her in i don't think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> would even consider going to a tent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> again at all it's just
 	
 	
 		yeah with cots with with cots yeah and
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time we did go that thing uh there we came back from an event and turned the lights on around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp site</ENAMEX> and there's a skunk right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		and without thinking i picked up a stick and threw it at it as it as it was starting to voluntarily walk away why i didn't let it but i threw a stick at it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-oh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it turned around and if a skunk give you a dirty look it did and i said i done made a mistake
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i said please skunk go on and he looked looked at me a little bit more then wandered on off very very slowly as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> headed for the nearest tent to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we'd go down to the coast every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> and we've noticed some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> camp out on the beach on public beaches and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		really
 		i didn't know you can do that
 	
 	
 		uh public beaches <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">State of Texas</ENAMEX> beaches not where it's city owned property
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh not like Corpus
 		
 		
 	