
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay go ahead and uh tell me what you're looking for in a job now
 	
 	
 		oh
 		one thing that i look for is um well maybe not the most most important thing but benefits like um
 		health insurance for my family
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and another thing would be um
 		reasonable reasonable work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> uh good working environment
 		um
 		right now i think it's we're supposed to talk about uh our current situation i'm a post doctoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		a a what
 	
 	
 		a post doctoral  fellow um i
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i'm it's for the training beyond your doctorate degree
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i get the same benefits as the  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> at the university i work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Iowa</ENAMEX>
 		and
 		i i like i like working at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> one of the benefits there is you get
 		a lot of flexibility in when you work and when you wanna take time off for example <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Christmas</TIMEX> i have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three weeks</TIMEX> that i get to go out west to visit my family
 		and so that's pretty good you it would probably be hard to have something like that in another type of job
 	
 	
 		so you like having having the flexibility to be able to take off time when you want to that's important to you
 	
 	
 		oh yeah besides just some besides some semester breaks the there is also other um  other times too um  like during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		does uh recognition from others and a sense of contributing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s success does that rank pretty high for you
 	
 	
 		oh yes and that's one of the reasons i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> too because you do get credit for your own work um
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> here especially especially he used to work in industry but he couldn't stand it because
 		um  he felt like that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> at uh at this aerospace place space <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> where he worked uh his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> got credit for all the um achievements that he made
 		so that's why he came back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's kind of a rip when you feel that way
 	
 	
 		and
 		so i think at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> you get often get credit for more you know your name gets on what you do like when you publish articles and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hey David</ENAMEX> what's your doctorate in
 	
 	
 		um  it's in physics however um
 		you know there is several several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> within physics i i studied sound acoustics and the subject for that is called acoustics
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and i'm specifically interested in the acoustics of speech i'm working now at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National National Center for Voice</ENAMEX> and Speech that's located here at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Iowa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you're kind of interested in this thing that  we're participating in then
 	
 	
 		oh i found out about it because i attended um  a conference for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acoustical Society of America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and uh  the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the session where i presented a paper um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um was it Mister Godfrey</ENAMEX> he um was uh  he he he gave me a a thing and said to try and find others to help join for this project
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hm</ENAMEX> and so you're enjoying all the benefits that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> would  at the moment is there
 	
 	
 		oh i couldn't say that
 	
 	
 		well i meant as health and uh
 	
 	
 		um
 		i i don't get a the salary for one thing
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		nor the job stability post a post post doctoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> is only for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> but the ultimate goal usually of a post doctoral fellowship is probably to go on and accept a position at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
 		so this is
 		um  you know the economy with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> and everything um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> around the time i was graduating um there was just were not very many opportunities available
 		so this was the best thing because um my post doctoral fellowship like this um um is a good thing on your resume for when you apply to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		okay uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> is one of the things that i i suppose so you don't want to be out in the weather and
 		uh the environment like construction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> for you it's better to be inside air-conditioned warm warm
 	
 	
 		uh yeah especially uh with the humidity here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> yes i i i would uh definitely want a indoors job
 		um  do you have a um
 	
 	
 		i work as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> yeah yeah and i've got a degree and a bunch of different certifications that go along with
 		
 		
 	