
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		where did you go on your last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		let's see uh the last vacation i started to started to take i say
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> was with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine uh we were going to go down to uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Padre</ENAMEX> and we got down there and it was rainy and yucky and we decided just turn around and come back
 	
 	
 		oh now that's someplace i've never been i'd like to go down there
 	
 	
 		yeah it's
 	
 	
 		see i've only only lived here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> so i haven't had a chance to go down there
 	
 	
 		yeah yes
 		it's it's a it's a really fun place it's
 		as long as it's not raining
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what do you do down there
 	
 	
 		oh
 		sit out by the little  on the beach
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh there's lots of really good places to eat and uh
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		i haven't
 		really had a chance to check out any of the the real entertainment or anything but uh
 		uh
 		it's
 		there's lots of you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> to do things on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Padre</ENAMEX> itself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		hm
 		well i'm getting ready to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> we're going to do some skiing so i'm real anxious to do that
 	
 	
 		i have never been skiing
 	
 	
 		oh it's a lot well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i've ever gone and it was so much fun
 		i really enjoyed it i took a lesson <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day and then the second day</TIMEX> i was up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">beginer</ENAMEX>'s slope
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but it looks it it you think that
 		that uh
 		you wonder what those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are doing on the mountain you know but you get up there yourself and it's so much fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		makes makes you feel like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> again
 	
 	
 		and the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> make it look easy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you're going hey how do i stand up bump
 	
 	
 		so i'm really anxious to go skiing again
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you you remember how you were when you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and you went down a sled
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well that's the way you feel on skis
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's how i felt when i tried to go water when i the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i went water skiing so
 	
 	
 		oh now see i haven't done that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i haven't been water skiing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water water</ENAMEX> skiing's a blast
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you just a a little bit of of uh
 		upper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> stamina just to to hold on to the ropes so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> doesn't jerk your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> out of socket and
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you have a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well where all have you been on vacation
 		have you been to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disneyland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh with with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> i've gone down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> i think it i think they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disneyworld</ENAMEX> down there
 	
 	
 		yeah i haven't been down there
 	
 	
 		long before they ever put in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPCOT Center</ENAMEX> and all the fun stuff
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC and</ENAMEX> and all
 	
 	
 		oh now see i haven't been there either
 	
 	
 		all all through that area uh and i've been up through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellowstone</ENAMEX> and all the national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> up that way
 	
 	
 		gee you've been around a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah and we went as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> on that trip and i've been all over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> there's there's
 		there's nowhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i haven't been i don't think
 		except some of the far west <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> little
 		pin holes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		have you been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX> Caverns
 	
 	
 		yeah i've been there
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		at least once
 		uh the the only place i haven't been really is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well you didn't miss anything i've been to both places you didn't miss anything
 	
 	
 		the the two
 		yeah
 		the the
 	
 	
 		just lots of people
 	
 	
 		the only thing that really i've i've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> but i've never vacationed there
 		got on an airplane here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and landed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 		and uh then got on a cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> went up and down the coast a couple of times
 	
 	
 		oh shoot you went on a cruise
 	
 	
 		yeah my
 	
 	
 		you've done everything
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> took me on a cruise when i was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it was such a good deal they just couldn't pass it up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it it wasn't that great of a cruise actually it was it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> and i was fairly bored at at my age it it wasn't that much fun because there weren't a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> on there at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that time of year</TIMEX> i was it was during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the school year</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		oh
 		but i'll bet it was interesting out there on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> in the water and everything
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah seeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX> and stuff like that it was great at the time though because i got out of school for a week
 	
 	
 		yeah you still uh-huh you still learned a lot
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well then you haven't been to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Disneyland</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> then have you
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		well now that's someplace you should go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's really neat
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i moved over there i lived there for a little while real close to there and we would we would just like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five miles</NUMEX> from there and we would drive down there and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> and they were on the newspaper route and they'd keep giving them uh
 		passes to get in
 		
 		
 	