
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we're set
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		what changes do you feel have happened
 	
 	
 		oh i guess the first thing has been the right for the right for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to vote i think that has been a major change and also the fact that um there are so much many more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the work force nowadays
 		than there were and that's probably going to increase you know
 	
 	
 		right increases increases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> doesn't it
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		it increases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		it sure does yeah there's a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the work place nowadays
 	
 	
 		well and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have kind of had uh in the past the real subservient role
 	
 	
 		role right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		that's changing
 	
 	
 		uh well we we still do to some degree but uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh i think it's not as much as it was
 	
 	
 		yeah right yeah i i agree it
 	
 	
 		i and especially i think with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> increasingly working they're going to have to demand more from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> because there's just impossible impossible to keep up on everything else
 	
 	
 		definitely has changed
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		have more of an active role in taking care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> more of an active role in taking care of the home
 	
 	
 		well you know they've been talking about and i don't know um what the status is on it but you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> get maternity leave
 		and stuff like that and i know that they've there's been discussion about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> also getting maternity leave
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		to help out but you know i haven't really heard much about that recently
 	
 	
 		well you know there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that won't give maternity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> maternity leave for that very reason
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh in fact i know the school districts down here you they don't have maternity leave um you simply have to take accumulate accumulate your sick leave
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and take your sick leave
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i don't know uh if bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> do but when i was employed with the school district i didn't have maternity leave either and that was the reason because they
 		thought was showing prejudice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and not to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		huh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		that's a bummer though  i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 		you have to save all of your uh vacation time
 	
 	
 		you got to take some time off
 	
 	
 		you do you have to save all your vacation time and that's usually how it's uh happened but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what do you see uh changing in the future
 	
 	
 		i think that we're probably going to see a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> um run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right and and top level
 	
 	
 		and we'll probably i'm sorry right right upper management more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in upper management and probably uh we'll see more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> in political roles
 	
 	
 		maybe top level
 	
 	
 		more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> and i think you know roles like that
 	
 	
 		that'd be kind of nice
 	
 	
 		well we've got in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we have a a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> and we had a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and she just her term just ended
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		and uh so i think we're probably going to see more of that
 		in the future
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's probably good a little more integration
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh maybe not so much that we sit on the back burners and
 	
 	
 		right
 		you know i mean and that's fine with me but sometimes i mean i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s libber by any means but i do there are issues that you know as far as like equal pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and that kind of stuff i
 	
 	
 		i think
 		right
 	
 	
 		totally am for but i don't get into the um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		the real  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> libber  movement you know
 	
 	
 		no i don't either
 		i don't think they're ever going to prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are equal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we just function differently
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i'm not capable of lifting what uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can lift and you know that type of that type of thing but uh one of the big changes uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		they're doing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> is uh and they're probably i'm sure in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> since you're big places a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are uh
 		working right out of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with their PC's or their lap computers or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i've heard of that um i haven't really talked to anybody that's
 		you know too involved with that but i mean i think that is a like the cottage industries
 	
 	
 		i think that
 	
 	
 		is is that what you're talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> working out of their homes
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah um i think it's wonderful
 	
 	
 		right you only have to check in with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> once or twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		course they're talking about uh
 		that we're going to be able to do our grocery shopping and
 	
 	
 		oh i know by the phone and all that
 	
 	
 		banking and everything like that so uh
 		it'd be kind of exciting in some ways to
 		to see a little bit more of that and some ways it might be kind of scary
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		think anybody could do it but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah i wouldn't mind just calling up the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and giving them my order and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		going <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour later</TIMEX> and picking it up
 	
 	
 		right but then you know there's the process of selection would you have to give them  the brand and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know when you shop you usually compare the prices and
 		would be nice though
 		
 		
 	