
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		you think about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is a nasty terrible disease and you die from it so i think that uh they need to look into it and it's kind of like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> i don't you know how
 		many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> have we tried to find a cure for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> i think it'll probably be as difficult
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh how about yourself
 	
 	
 		um well i'm
 		certainly in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research and i think probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> could spend a bit more money on it than it does i think that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because besides the fact that
 		it's a deadly disease that it's a contagious disease so that it's
 		um although it is not killing that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now it still
 		has the opportunity to get out of control and become a huge problem
 	
 	
 		yeah they say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are infected with the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> virus and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah i think
 	
 	
 		that's in the world or in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> you
 	
 	
 		uh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> America
 	
 	
 		oh really hm that's whose figure is that
 	
 	
 		yeah and they they have millions
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i've just heard it on the radio sometimes you hear things that on the radio that  you know could be true or couldn't be
 	
 	
 		okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh do you feel like
 		this is a i guess they're spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a billion</NUMEX> or so a year on this <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh do you think they should spend more
 	
 	
 		um
 		i
 		i think they should actually although probably perhaps not a an incredible amount more than what they're doing and i don't necessarily
 		think that they should  uh fund <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS AIDS</ENAMEX> research and you know in the process neglect <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> research or whatever
 		i think that it would be a good thing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to increase funding for medical research in general
 	
 	
 		what do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mister Johnson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		magic
 	
 	
 		what right uh
 		well i am sorry that he has the virus
 		i'd
 		um
 		i don't know i don't
 		i think it's very strange that  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> hasn't um questioned him  more strongly to
 		you know about gay sex or intravenous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or anything like that
 		as they probably would for a lot of other people
 	
 	
 		do you think he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> that he's being called by a bunch of other a bunch of the media
 	
 	
 		um
 		well
 		not not really though i mean i think he's probably doing the right thing for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		his position but i don't think it's
 		anything exceptional that he's doing it's  what many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have done already who are just less famous
 	
 	
 		you know i took advantage of the opportunity when you know he came out i i talked to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> about it you know it's something that i hadn't done hadn't done before uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh well that's good
 	
 	
 		i'm glad that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Johnson</ENAMEX>'s changed his tune on uh safe sex to abstinence or i i was glad he did that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> because a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would have ended up dying because of what he was promoting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh let's see what are some of the other questions
 		i you don't
 		uh let's see
 		i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that have the disease i guess you might might not
 	
 	
 		um yeah i do my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> does for instance
 	
 	
 		is it pretty nasty
 	
 	
 		and um yeah yeah it is he's actually um
 		he had <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> related <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> for a while and he is now in full blown <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> and really not doing very well
 		and has various
 		brain tumors and
 		that sort of thing
 		so that it's it's a very nasty thing
 	
 	
 		yeah it sound awful
 		is it just that the immune system ceases to function properly and
 	
 	
 		um yeah that's that's basically it that
 		um
 		the immune system can
 		at first slow down and you know the white blood cell count goes down which is and that's <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> related <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> but then
 		when things get completely out of control and it basically hits bottom that's <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		and in that case you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are prone to getting any kind of you know weird <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> that only <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> got before and yeah that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		
 		
 	