
 
     		
 	
 		okay i now say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Texas</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> i said that and somebody said well i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh  well that is a different thing isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah i was really surprised then i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> but usually it's just right around here
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		well what what do you like in a restaurant
 	
 	
 		well i guess i'd i thought well i guess i'd have to say the food  well
 	
 	
 		i know number one that's definitely it
 	
 	
 		you know if the food's good then that's you know that sort of makes my decision i you know if i really have something good although okay the food and then the other thing i'd say is atmosphere's real important to me you know i don't like really noisy places and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you know yeah  you know i used to like to go to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s because i like kind of lively fun places and the last time we went there it was so horrendously noisy that i don't know if i'll ever go back it was awful
 	
 	
 		yes
 		
 
 		well when a when a
 		i know one of my pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">peeves</ENAMEX> is that you know they have the music on so loud and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to talk loud and then it's just so noisy that you can't visit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 		oh i know
 	
 	
 		you know and normally when i'm eating out i you know with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i wanna sit and talk i mean
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's the half the fun is the conversation right
 	
 	
 		right
 		you know and i don't mind some noise but if it's
 		bearable for me so um
 	
 	
 		i really think <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> are all overall getting noisy and noisy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just screaming i say that because i  the time i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> you could be in a tiny little restaurant everyone talked lower they still seemed to have fun
 	
 	
 		i'd
 		uh-huh well i don't know why i in fact i've been to places where i've asked them to turn the music down and and they say well they you know they can't that that's the the atmosphere they want to promote and i i don't understand that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i don't either
 	
 	
 		you know it's like that doesn't make sense to me what you know what is the fun of that
 	
 	
 		i know  i can't and uh another one you can tell i go to cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> now that i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in college and i'm going we we go all the cheapies but uh we go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cheddar</ENAMEX>'s a lot there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by us
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they'll just blast the TV where in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> where you have to wait till they call your name you know and and i'm not that  excited about some <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game or whatever they're
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's just so loud you can't even visit while you're having a drink or anything
 	
 	
 		well another thing that is not my favorite thing is um  you know like if they have um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">birthdays</ENAMEX> and then they all scream  you know  clap and scream to birthday i get tired of that too
 	
 	
 		oh they all screaming run screaming in and singing yes
 		they do too i think
 	
 	
 		so you know that that uh
 		the atmosphere does make a difference but usually i tend to go well for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons i go for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> also thinking now there's certain types of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> that i like you know like i love <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food and so i go to i like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i would go for that um i think did i say what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> do you prefer or do you
 	
 	
 		oh golly uh i like most kinds of food really i'd never go to a barbecue place i mean i i don't mind barbecue but that's one that we just don't go out to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but what you know i like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> and i love <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um we don't i don't even think we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> we uh i used to go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of them i thought they were great
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i like most everything i like seafood too course it's hard to get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seafood restaurant</ENAMEX> but another thing to consider is the uh help you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh their attitude
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh uh i think and uh
 	
 	
 		i i agree
 	
 	
 		some of them you know they come up with all this phony stuff too hi my name's Bill i'm your waiter for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> oh God i'm tired of that
 	
 	
 		right right
 		right just wait on me and
 	
 	
 		right i don't care about right we don't have to exchange backgrounds but um price is something to consider
 	
 	
 		i'll be happy
 		
 
 		that's true that's true um and i and i generally speaking go to moderately priced places you know places and it does matter um
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		you know depending upon what my budget is for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> as to where i go i guess um but that's yeah that's right i uh price is definitely  a consideration
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh the more expensive the restaurant the more i want the have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waiters</ENAMEX> to really wait on you and be good you know  remember
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well they should be i mean in theory i guess
 	
 	
 		really really i think so well we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> and talk about great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> oh
 	
 	
 		yes there's probably no place better i i you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> is just fabulous
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh i know and uh  really we we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Palace</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and you know supposed to be one of the better ones in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and uh our dinner that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> you could choose one that had like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> and it was thirty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine dollars</NUMEX> a dinner but my gosh it was worth it it was just beautiful surrounding and at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one time</TIMEX> there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> waiting on our table
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yes
 		yeah i've been there it yes i have
 	
 	
 		oh really that's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i i'd been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> before it was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i'd eaten there and i thought it was worth every penny
 	
 	
 		ah
 		it is it's a fabulous place
 	
 	
 		and uh i really enjoyed that then i'd enjoy that more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brennan</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think it's better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">still Brennan</ENAMEX>'s is so lovely and the service is so wonderful
 	
 	
 		well they're all lovely i mean basically you just can't go wrong and um the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is just so good i i i i love <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> and i
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		oh i know and they're lighthearted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there but
 	
 	
 		exactly it's just a
 		
 		
 	