
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay well
 	
 	
 		there we are
 	
 	
 		all right um um well uh tell me about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that you've got
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> um hatchback nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and i had a hatchback a nineteen seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> version before this one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i'll be honest with you i have never found any automobile that has been more conscientiously constructed and and uh put together and it it does its job
 		all i have to do on my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> is change the oil and the filter <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">every thirty five hundred miles</NUMEX> and i i did have to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> front <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new front tires on at fifty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousand miles</NUMEX>
 		but that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> just purrs like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> it was built i get forty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two miles per gallon</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> and right between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty eight to thirty</TIMEX> driving around in town it's a uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five</NUMEX> speed straight stick machine
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i can carry more in that uh that trunk area in my little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> than i can in the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and i have a large um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontiac</ENAMEX>
 		and i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty nine</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cougar</ENAMEX> which really is i'm saving because it's it's old but it's in beautiful shape
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i can carry as much in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> or more than i can in in those other bigger cars
 	
 	
 		well that's very interesting i've had i've had exactly the same experience with the one that i've got it's a and surprisingly it's also an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and um
 	
 	
 		LX
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm still there
 		um i'm sorry what
 	
 	
 		it was an LX
 	
 	
 		yes it's an LX it's not a hatchback but it's um it's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> yours is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> door
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> door yeah and very very comfortable car big roomy trunk uh and uh and very happy with it and i must admit it's you know if if if uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah my only consideration were were you know buying another car just to tool around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and and make you know brief trips and things like that i i would very very seriously consider buying one
 		uh i think they're extraordinarily reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> um my my real concern with with uh
 	
 	
 		yes we are
 	
 	
 		uh why i'm not sure i i want to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> is because i have to make a kind of a a steady um trip down the road
 		about once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> because i'm divorced and i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that lives down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		well hm
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i drive down interstate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety five</NUMEX> and it's just an absolutely wild highway
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety five</NUMEX> is wild in any car there's no doubt about that
 	
 	
 		yeah and
 	
 	
 		because i i i run over to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal City</ENAMEX> or used to i'm retiring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of this month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i'm very much aware of the crazy driving that goes on over there
 	
 	
 		and you well you've got it and uh so having precious cargo in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with me
 		as you can well imagine it's very hard for me to imagine that that uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX>'s going to be as safe a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> as as the one that i've got got my eye on which is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in in fact  quite frankly i've owned a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX> in the past and uh i've i've they're expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> to keep up when they need service but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've found that i've had a lot of luck with them uh course i'm a mechanically inclined kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and i always wind up getting under the hood and finding out all the things that
 		you know need to be taken care of and so forth and i guess that's one thing that that recommends the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> to a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is is there's just very little that you have to do under the hood and
 	
 	
 		yes it just just sits there and purrs and you all you got to do is the main major thing of changing that oil and that filter i get <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six hundred miles</NUMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank</ENAMEX> of gas
 	
 	
 		oh i know it's really amazing
 	
 	
 		yeah beautiful beautiful machine
 	
 	
 		it's
 		absolutely incredible
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so um yeah anyway i've been looking at the prices of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and and and so forth and i think that it's it's very surprising some of these very expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Volvos</ENAMEX> can be gotten for a lot less money than you would think if you're willing to
 	
 	
 		is that right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		buy ones that are about the vintage of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that you and i currently own
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 	
 	
 		well a brand new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX> costs what thirty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		well certainly some of the top end ones you can still get get uh even the the low end wagons um for less than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we get you know in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> area of course being as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">affluent</ENAMEX> as it is there are lots and lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealerships</ENAMEX> down here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so there're lots and lots of them available in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> at any <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any week</TIMEX> and i sort of you know scan the paper and look at them and so forth and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so um  anyway and that's that's the other thing is that i've i've never really been too terribly much of a new car <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i think i've bought one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> in my life and i've tended to um
 		to uh buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that are you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> and sometimes even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four and five or six years old</TIMEX> this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> that i have i bought used and
 		in fact it had an extraordinarily low amount of mileage on it i've just rolled seventy <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousand miles</NUMEX> and it's a seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> i mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an eighty four</NUMEX> so
 	
 	
 		well my my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eighty four</NUMEX> just has seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> on it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i've made many trips to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia Beach Virginia</ENAMEX> where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> lives and things like that and i drive it
 		
 		
 	