
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Brian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi how you doing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		fine thanks
 	
 	
 		good good glad to hear that i understand are
 	
 	
 		
 
 		are you a total banner
 	
 	
 		total banner no i i believe that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and i as an individual and private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> have a right to to bear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and to have a gun as long as i uh am responsible with it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and protect the safety and welfare of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 		and so that they're not playing with it and so that they can't hurt themselves or anyone else playing with it i think that education with a gun is is critical and important
 		um however i do believe that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> ought to be maintained and and controlled that you can't go out and just buy one off the corner and do whatever you want with it because people
 		that are angry or have concerns or want to get seek vengeance right away have easy access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and in the heat of the moment they can go and do some damage that can hurt themselves and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so
 		on a scale of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> i i think i would rate myself as a in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the six or seven</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		but i think that there ought to be some control but i still think that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> have a right how do you feel about it
 	
 	
 		okay
 		well so let me make sure so so you think that uh maybe a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five day</TIMEX> waiting period for handguns or that stuff would be legitimate
 	
 	
 		well i don't know if a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five day</TIMEX> waiting period would be legitimate uh that uh
 		that might cool down some tempers i think a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a one day</TIMEX> would be sufficient the reason i say that is there's an awful lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who go to gun shows
 		and if you see an awful lot of exhibits and things and if you would like to purchase a gun if that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five day</TIMEX> waiting period were in effect that you wouldn't be able to purchase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at that gun show
 	
 	
 		uh you just you'd be able to buy it but they'd just have to mail it to you i suppose huh
 	
 	
 		well i don't think you can mail thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> through the mail i don't know  i think that's a against the law ever since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> was
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		well
 		
 
 	
 	
 		assassinated so how do you feel about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		let's see i think that gun control has come up because there's been some crazies that killed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 		and i think that's the problem that we need to address is why these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to kill other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> rather than the instrument they particularly used in the assault whether you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well do you think that there will continue to always be crazies
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		then uh
 		how do you propose that we prohibit those types of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> from gaining access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well we have some laws on the books that uh don't allow convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX> to purchase <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> if i understand correctly and
 		uh i would agree a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a short</TIMEX> waiting period would be appropriate to uh take care of the heat of the moment type things but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think banning semiautomatic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX> is a a bit on the extreme side
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a total ban on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> would just leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> who don't care what the rules are anyway
 	
 	
 		okay do you uh do you feel that there is a need in the world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to have a an automatic handgun
 	
 	
 		the only purpose for handguns is to shoot people
 		in my opinion or or you could do it just for fun you know kind of like a game but uh
 	
 	
 		well i think that the the police uh or law enforcement have a need because of the tight quarters they might find themselves but the public i don't know
 	
 	
 		i think that i should have a right to own a handgun not a automatic semiautomatic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uzi</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no uh but i think a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> needs a way of defending themselves
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indiana Jones</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> came after him with that big knife
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and just he took care of him just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> shot
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yes that's true and he uh saved himself in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the in the</TIMEX> in the process also
 	
 	
 		that's right so how's work going
 	
 	
 		very fine very very
 	
 	
 		they don't let you take <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> to work do they
 	
 	
 		no they that's uh that's prohibited where we work although down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh you do have a right to to wear and carry <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> with you at all times
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's still uh that's still you can still do that down here
 	
 	
 		can they be
 		is it concealed or does it have to
 	
 	
 		oh you can't no it it should not be concealed
 	
 	
 		has to be on the hip
 	
 	
 		it has to be on the hip  has to be in sight so that uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah that you're not uh a menace or
 		a problem to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> how about where you live there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		can a
 		
 
 		
 		
 	