
 
     		
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		do you do you have uh some strong feelings one way or the other about about the care of the elderly
 	
 	
 		well yes i do um this is a a question that hit pretty close to home uh i had to go through this with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> about
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX> he was his health was failing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh he was adamant about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things one was that i take care of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that he not be put into a home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we talked  about some length and i respected his wishes he uh
 		stayed at home as long as he could and then uh he died in a hospital but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that my position was is that uh you you need to find one that you can really have confidence that they are taking care of the
 		of their uh of their clients
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um
 		because i've heard about the many abuses and because he had heard of so many abuses he just didn't want that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		well  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> work is in speech pathology
 		and uh so so uh i've thought about this more than once uh you know dealing with
 		uh  you know i'm concerned we're gonna have a geriatric uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> it's gonna be you know phenomenal
 	
 	
 		yeah almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> all all over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> percent isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah  uh  and um but i have been amazed and and in talking with uh some of my fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 		it looks as though um nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> are not going to be the only option anymore and uh  in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 		uh where a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are hoping uh to work as an in the home type uh uh approach approach where
 		where the uh where there's the speech you know the speech therapist or whether it's a nursing uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> or someone plans to uh work
 		out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s home and take the responsibility away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but yet allow the the loved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to stay you know at home with the family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>  uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it  it's it's difficult for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> especially in the case of uh of of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> and and uh some of the more degenerative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> to uh say
 		uh uh leave them to to have them at home because then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> becomes completely uh
 	
 	
 		they're captives
 	
 	
 		exactly yeah and and did did you experience that with your with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> or not
 	
 	
 		uh we had a at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> stage we had care somewhat like like what you're talking about we had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visiting Nurses Program</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they sent somebody in and it it was a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a nominal</NUMEX> charge that this uh
 		it started out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> would come in i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and eventually got up to the point where they were coming by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they would try to get him to exercise they would try to uh you know they would check him over temperature
 		you know the basic checks
 		try to get him to talk and be motivated and uh that's what we went through
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh up to a points things seemed to be working and then i i think he he became discouraged
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they did not know how to take care of that and then um at that point i think it mostly a psychological problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh but yes i agree there's a lot of options there could be a lot of options
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think it's time that uh we decide to do something about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		definitely you know uh one of the other subjects on the on the switchboard and this is one that i've that i've been thinking applies here uh  where where uh
 		young ones young
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">kids uh</ENAMEX> graduating from high school whether they should do a community service type work this would be an excellent example of somewhere uh someplace where
 		um the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> could be more involved  you know more than just leaving it only to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> there is a lot the communiky the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> can do to uh enhance the or or assist the lives of those who are keeping a loved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		i suppose at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> would fulfill this need
 	
 	
 		possibly before i don't know now
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX> whatever because typically these were close-knit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s large metropolitan areas or even
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in most even even the rural areas now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are not quite as close as they once were
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the mobility factor the factor that uh
 		oh we're living longer and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are less trusting all these things tend to destroy this type of system but i agree with you it it might be some possibilities there
 		although dealing with geriatrics
 		is something a lot of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just aren't emotionally prepared to do
 	
 	
 		oh i agree that's a that's a good point
 	
 	
 		i think they would have to have some training some
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	