
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well what kind of books do you like best
 	
 	
 		well i alternate between uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle Steele</ENAMEX>  is one of my very favorites and uh then i try to go into one of the self improvement books
 		um
 		we we take books every once in a while in our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and go through them um
 		i love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Peck</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Road Less Traveled</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh yeah i've heard of that one i don't think i've read it
 	
 	
 		oh it is
 		it is wonderful
 		i i thoroughly enjoy that
 		what do you read
 	
 	
 		well uh  i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Clancy</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and i read i just finished a book on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novell Netware</ENAMEX> uh that's computer stuff i do a lot of computer reading and uh i'm just finishing another one up on uh statistical sampling
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		so i do more work kind of related reading than uh just for enjoyment
 	
 	
 		i i try to keep a book going all the time uh
 		i try to read when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> wake up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and then before i go to sleep so i probably get oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifty</NUMEX> pages a day read
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that's pretty good
 	
 	
 		and i just you know i don't feel like
 		in in fact this morning i was almost late for work because i'm almost at the end of this book and i didn't wanna put it down
 	
 	
 		oh i've had them like that before too
 	
 	
 		but i like i like mysteries
 	
 	
 		mysteries any particular writer
 	
 	
 		uh yes i like uh
 		um
 		oh i'm drawing a blank
 		uh
 		he wrote the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bourne Ultimatum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ludwig Ludwig</ENAMEX> yes
 	
 	
 		Ludwig yes
 		and uh
 		i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Archer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what does he read write
 	
 	
 		he is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> who writes some mystery um
 		well i guess they're they're a type of mystery they're usually some part he's a ex-lawyer
 		so or he he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who no longer practices but his are all have some part of the law uh enveloped in them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so you kind of learn something as well as enjoy enjoy yourself
 	
 	
 		right and then uh the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> that came out with uh
 		
 
 		oh the one that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">starred</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders Raiders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost Ark</ENAMEX> stuff
 	
 	
 		no no it was the uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's late i'm tired so i'm not thinking too well
 	
 	
 		what
 		what time is it there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten thirty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> here
 	
 	
 		oh it's  uh it was his first book it came it was on the top of the list um
 		he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Presumed Innocent</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		oh i haven't seen the movie  read the book but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and then his he came out with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one
 		uh
 		a sequel to it
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and both of those i've enjoyed real well
 		but i i like that i love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle Steele</ENAMEX> and and  you know if i wanna get a fantasy and
 		get away from it all
 	
 	
 		is she
 		is she kind of racy
 	
 	
 		no no she isn't at all her books uh
 	
 	
 		just feel good
 	
 	
 		you always cry
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		i mean it's  it's always good for good tears
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh one book that she wrote that's good for both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is Fine Things
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F I N E</ENAMEX> things
 	
 	
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX>'s a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of hers
 	
 	
 		well it's it's one that you know it's it's always gonna make you have a good cry and you dow it's gonna turn out good and you're gonna be happy in the end
 	
 	
 		oh well that's nice
 	
 	
 		and i said you know i don't want anything too real anymore i have enough of that in my own life i want i want happy fantasy like
 	
 	
 		yeah uh you mentioned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LaDonna</ENAMEX> uh do you are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 		i i do my share of it i i certainly can't say that i understand a lot of it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's that's always a challenge so do you do my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> talks with other people
 		
 		
 	