
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well do you exercise regularly
 	
 	
 		there is well i am a school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and uh there uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that went through our school district i teach in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Highland Park</ENAMEX> who uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		who uh does aerobics at uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> and i say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> them <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YWCA</ENAMEX>  turn that off please i am recording
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> just turned on something noisy anyway uh she comes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and there are a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and we exercise regularly and for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> and we do it twice a week
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		and uh we do uh aerobics for cardiovascular fitness for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> and then we do stretching and toning and cool down
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">another thirty minutes</TIMEX> so it is an hour and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i take uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two mile</NUMEX> walks
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as often as possible and uh not on the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> that i do aerobics but if if he wants to he jogs but i uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i we take the fast walks and we walk <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple of miles</NUMEX> and come back to the house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so we we take it seriously we enjoy doing it i enjoy my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> it's a lot more fun to exercise with somebody than it is to do it by yourself
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 		yeah yeah uh-huh
 		
 
 		well i use to exercise regularly and i haven't lately  i have goofed off i guess um i use to also take an aerobics class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three days a week</TIMEX> before work but um
 	
 	
 		oh oh oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess my job change my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s job change and it's just not easy to get up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the morning</TIMEX> any more so um
 	
 	
 		oh i understand that
 		i've never been able to do it before
 	
 	
 		no  well the problem is that i am so tired at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX> i just wanna go home and not do anything so yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i am too i just make myself i get up at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five thirty</TIMEX> and i am at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven thirty</TIMEX> and  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> isn't over until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">uh four</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and our class but it's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that is the big difference because
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there are other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around said uh you'd better hurry go get dressed you know there is motivation around there and then uh we can we can change right there in the building i don't have to drive and fight traffic and get anywhere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh  yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i just go and we all exercise and until then you know i have belonged to exercise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> and oh i've gone to uh  oh like um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh these gyms you know that that like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> or and uh where they offer the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh rec <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> really where they offer aerobics and i've done that before but it always had to be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late at night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		after i've got home and after dinner and you are just kind of going ugh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i have tried it immediately after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> like try to get some place and exercise from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five to six</NUMEX> but then by the time you get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and you fix dinner you are eating so late
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right that's difficult really is
 	
 	
 		it is it's really hard with our life style when you work um
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah i know well i know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch</TIMEX> but you know by the time i i get over the gym and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and go to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and shower and get back to work it's probably <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> or more and that's just too long so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five minutes</TIMEX> for lunch
 	
 	
 		yeah  yeah that doesn't really do it does it  yeah
 	
 	
 		that's out for me
 		no i don't think so
 		but uh and they're nice because if we are running late it usually uh if things are kind of hectic at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are running late they kind of wait on us you know because they know we are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and coming
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well that good
 	
 	
 		whereas and uh another place you are paying a lot more money and uh it it they're gonna to start whether you are there or not i mean you know
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		so this has worked out real nicely in fact she charges us <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two dollars</NUMEX> a session
 	
 	
 		well that's not much
 	
 	
 		hum-um so it's it's we like pay her for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> at a time because that is like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> in uh uh school uh you know report card period and so it is like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty four</TIMEX> dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every six weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's not bad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it beats memberships at some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> that's for sure  they are real expensive
 	
 	
 		you're not kidding
 		i know we belonged um  for a period of time to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Signature Club</ENAMEX> for about a year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean we were paying a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> plus a month for our family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> and at first we used it and then it got where we weren't beginning to get out money's worth
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they offered lots of things but we weren't taking advantage of them because we didn't have the time to so we decided to forget that that was just a waste of our our money
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 		well we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> through work and its its probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a hundred</NUMEX> and fifty dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> which isn't bad
 	
 	
 		oh no hum-um
 	
 	
 		but i uh i don't know i still just don't don't end up going because there isn't at a convenient time or i don't know something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i need to do something if only walk the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> or something i need to start doing that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it does make you feel better and the hard thing is getting going
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		and if you have somebody who will do it with you like for a long time my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> didn't want to walk because he wants to run uh jog
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he decided that uh maybe you know uh if i was you know would be willing to walk
 		
 		
 	