
 
     		
 	
 		being up up there maybe maybe you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> don't have as uh big a problem with air pollution as many do you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		we we we have a terrible air pollution problem
 	
 	
 		do you really
 	
 	
 		our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> are extremely uh hazardous and during ah certain
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wind directions because we get the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary Indiana Chicago</ENAMEX> pollution
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we can look out on the lake and just see the brown haze uh coming up along the lake
 	
 	
 		that's horrible
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they do post uh uh warnings for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart diseases</ENAMEX> or respiratory problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		during that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> season in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> it's not as severe
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh if the wind comes basically from the south it can be really bad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact uh started some litigation against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> because of the air pollution we were getting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ah i don't think it's gonna go very far but it it was uh a way of ah triggering uh awareness
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		so what's the conditions like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i i haven't seen air pollution quite on a quite on a level that we had in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> uh i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> and and i've lived there most of my life and
 		we used to have those uh you know the posted warning days uh however in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> now
 		they have the emissions control law which has really cut down probably only once
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every couple of years</TIMEX> do we ever have pollution so bad that they have to post post warnings now you know as far as health concerns uh due to that emissions the the emissions uh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh control on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> seems that all of our all of our ah smog was caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> rather than industry
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> has a a law in which we need to take our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> when we apply for a new license tag
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're tested for uh their pollution control equipment
 		and if they don't qualify then they have to take it to a mechanic and have it gone over and then verify that it's it is drivable
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so they've they've tried to do a lot of that and i you know uh there seem to be  at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least</NUMEX> in certain little pockets and we were talking earlier about Madison
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX> has one of the nicest uh bike uh road uh sharing programs of of any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		in all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> has probably the most extensive number of uh bike <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> for recreational use of any of the states
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a real</TIMEX> promotion of of biking
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um there are still a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who'll insist on on driving their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> uh to go everywhere
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i find that a little irritating because i don't think it's always so necessary
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah it it becomes it uh maybe to you and i who have grown up in some in some uh
 		uh some more uh beautiful parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> uh i think that that uh we become a little more aware uh rather quickly of
 		of what's happening with air pollution and how uh how horrible it really is um i i notice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> seem to say well sure there's air pollution but you know
 		really how bad is how problem how bad could this problem really be um
 	
 	
 		send send them to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> and we'll let them try to drink out of some of the lakes and try to fish in some of the lakes that have been suffering from
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		uh the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> and they'll they'll they may wake up you know how would you like to own a piece of property where your lake is going sour because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um you right
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's a really a serious issue for those of us up in this ah sector up up here
 	
 	
 		do you find that um or or do you hypothesize that that most of the uh smog or or air pollution comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> or does it come mostly from industry up there
 	
 	
 		i think it's mostly vehicles although  it does come from some of the industry of of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i don't know exactly where it emerges from when it it's up in the ah northern sectors of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> that causes the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that i'm a little uncertain of but i do know that uh it is a problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum i had talked with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> i i grew up uh i was born in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Muncie Indiana</ENAMEX> and and grew up a little bit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Terre Haute</ENAMEX> and i had asked them before uh i went back to visit
 		recently <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year ago</TIMEX> and i asked them i said did you ever realize the air pollution that was
 		
 		
 	