
 
     		
 	
 		where do you like to go to eat out
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well my favorite place to go is a a little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> place called um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Night</ENAMEX>  and i guess that the reason i like to go there is because i like the the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> they serve and we've been going there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's an older spot it's not a real fancy type
 		you know establishment but it is it is enjoyable and and kind of cozy and it's it's quite small
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's that's where we like to go and how about yourself
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i go to this place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denton Texas</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocco</ENAMEX>'s it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> restaurant
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh well i guess <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i went there is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight years ago</TIMEX> i'd i'd just moved back from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and went over there you know with my parents
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i got married we had our our wedding dinner there
 	
 	
 		oh how fun
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things i like most about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocco's</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there are real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know they're not all you know hoity-toity and all that good stuff
 	
 	
 		oh um-hum
 		uh-huh oh so there's good service good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and good food huh
 	
 	
 		sure
 		excellent service uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is is always hot and there's always enough
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah that's
 	
 	
 		you know  i hate when i go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> and i spend twelve bucks for a meal
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and you know i got to spend another twelve bucks to find the appetizers
 	
 	
 		Tiffany yeah right and and then when you go home you're still hungry  <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> that's huh that's interesting you know i've never been to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> and i know  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> in law was saying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> she knew of a place little place down in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about thirty miles</NUMEX> from here that was a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> she said and
 		and uh we were discussing going there so i that sounds good how about fast food do you eat fast food much
 	
 	
 		yeah i got cans in my cupboard
 	
 	
 		i mean in a restaurant
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 
 		well uh let me put it this way the nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven Eleven</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about forty miles</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yeah we're out in the country
 	
 	
 		oh yes you are
 	
 	
 		and uh fast food for me is fuel you know it's like i buy the cheapest stuff i can find that'll hold me over till i can get home
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right right
 	
 	
 		usually i don't
 		go to fast food <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> because if i leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i generally pack my own lunch
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh oh
 	
 	
 		i i cannot stand cardboard food
 	
 	
 		right  right i agree
 	
 	
 		you know i mean you know it's nothing fancy for lunch but i you know i got celery and carrots and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pears</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> that'll that's real huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's real food you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> will make me either a you know like a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham sandwich</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">turkey sandwich</ENAMEX> or something like that uh you know we raise hogs and butcher our own meat
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right uh-huh
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		we have a wide variety of uh
 	
 	
 		boy i'll say yeah i  i was just thinking um  we have another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> here that's um
 	
 	
 		stuff available
 	
 	
 		oh it's probably it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about ten miles</NUMEX> away from from where we live and i know it's
 		it's pretty famous around this area it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mattox</ENAMEX> and and they have you know their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> that they they um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butcher</ENAMEX> and they serve there and it's it's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's only open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days a week</TIMEX> and there's always just standing room only waiting to get in it's it's an excellent uh place to eat there they serve
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and a good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> and and like you say the service is good and
 		a real nice atmosphere and  i know that's a place around here that that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like to go to
 		we we are just in our little little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that's close to us it's just starting to get a lot of eating type establishments they
 		well it's probably been within the last oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> that we've even had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah you you go to restaurant row
 	
 	
 		no we don't yet
 	
 	
 		got you your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza Inn</ENAMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taco Bell</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger King</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sonic</ENAMEX> and all that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		not yet not yet we're we're working towards that we're not but it's not quite that bad yet i hope that
 		i don't know i hate to see that
 	
 	
 		well that's that yuppie food it it it makes you have to eat bran
 	
 	
 		yeah  right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i i went seen my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and he gave me you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pieces of news one was good one was bad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		the good news uh the bad news was i was gonna die
 	
 	
 		uh oh
 	
 	
 		the good news is that i uh i i don't have to eat bran <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">muffins</ENAMEX> or jog
 	
 	
 		because you're gonna die anyway huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you know uh the have you seen any of the statistical reports on the the
 	
 	
 		yes i have they say it doesn't really make a whole lot of difference but
 	
 	
 		well yeah they say you you might extend your life of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum  but it
 	
 	
 		but it takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four months</TIMEX> to get in shape so
 	
 	
 		and it's painful
 	
 	
 		oops i got a call
 	
 	
 		oh okay well it's been pleasant speaking with you and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh</ENAMEX> call
 		right
 	
 	
 		keep going to that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> place and i'll try one here  thank
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 		
 	