
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 		all right well i guess well which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> have you got right now or
 	
 	
 		well i got a couple of them i at the moment use an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AST 286</ENAMEX> and i got a leading edge and i got a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> one and had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> one but
 	
 	
 		my my just a couple
 	
 	
 		what do you have
 	
 	
 		um i've got an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omega</ENAMEX> and i've got a uh generic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">380</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">486</NUMEX> machine yeah it's very very generic
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		what did you do put it together
 	
 	
 		yeah and and uh upgraded it and put things in there and dibbled and dabbled and  now now it's now it's a fast machine  that's all i got to say for it  hm
 	
 	
 		well that's
 		yeah
 		yeah what do you use it for what do you use it for
 	
 	
 		uh work uh i'm a contract programmer
 	
 	
 		oh yeah what kind of programs do you
 	
 	
 		um anything
 	
 	
 		yeah okay i i mean like business programs or
 	
 	
 		uh i've done business programming scientific you know scientific applications like you know  petroleum science stuff and uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> test equipment and i did the i i did one that was a demonstration of a touch touch screen for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that sells uh touch screens
 		it was kind of fun put a little bitty portable computer in there and a plasma display and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and make it look like things like uh you know attack <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">simulators</ENAMEX> and don holds
 	
 	
 		well that's
 	
 	
 		all sorts of little things you'd think you'd want to put your finger on the screen for
 	
 	
 		well that sounds interesting
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		matter of fact uh i guess you do uh you get a lot of graphics in there i imagine huh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah definitely
 	
 	
 		that's that's where the speed helps out
 	
 	
 		uh yeah unfortunately the little portable PC that was plugged on the back was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only a seven and a half</NUMEX> megahertz <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eighty six</NUMEX> it's like slow
 	
 	
 		yep that'll that'll slow you up  well i i do uh uh programming for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNC</ENAMEX> turret presses and
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> cad cam system type things and uh
 		really need a faster system uh i got a new line that i i sell metal fabricating equipment and cad cam systems and tooling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera and
 	
 	
 		um-hum well i know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that upgrades uh for reasonable cost
 	
 	
 		uh
 		who is that
 	
 	
 		uh his name is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TQ</ENAMEX> or something like that
 		and my notebook is somewhere around here
 		see if i can make my telephone cord stretch far enough
 	
 	
 		what i've tried to do is get this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> to
 	
 	
 		uh but he's uh up in hm
 	
 	
 		give me one  that's how i got my other ones by selling their product for them they not only give me a demonstrator but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hardware</ENAMEX> as well as the software
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh that works
 	
 	
 		and as they and as they go to the next one i just keep the that's why i have so many different levels of PCs around at the moment
 	
 	
 		uh here it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ATS</ENAMEX> Computers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ATS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and where are they at
 	
 	
 		uh do you know where uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Custer</ENAMEX> is okay he's
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		uh south of Renner
 		on on Custer
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and there's a little bitty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> that looks kind of like or strip kind of center
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know where you mean there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX> and all that kind of stuff uh on that one corner that's about Lookout there i think isn't it
 	
 	
 		right it's it's it's just south of there it's a little place looks like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know little guy in there he  he uh gives reasonable prices
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		like i i traded my uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three eighty six</NUMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four eighty six</NUMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six hundred</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		really well that's a good deal
 	
 	
 		yeah it was pretty reasonable
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh uh he and he does a good job and he says he he uh guarantees everything he has sells
 	
 	
 		uh there's a lot you ever go over by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucky Computer</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		i used to when i was putting shop floor computers together for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i'd go and get their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> and
 		put them together and go and interface the stuff with our systems and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		haven't been doing much of that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year or so</TIMEX> so i i don't know where those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> but i would assume
 	
 	
 		uh they they're up there in that mall uh just below <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> or that strip strip center
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		they're still doing business
 		big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> apparently
 	
 	
 		yeah they
 		i tell you those prices have just unbelievably come down
 	
 	
 		um-hum well yeah i was amazed that i was able to get this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four eighty six</NUMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six hundred</NUMEX> even with a trade in you know it's like wow  that works i'll go do that  and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that thing screams now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah i
 		yeah i was kind of surprised how rapidly they bypassed the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three eighty six</NUMEX> that wasn't alive for but maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um-hum well i thought was funny that they kept pushing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">386</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SX</ENAMEX> even though the the price difference is about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollars
 	
 	
 		is that right that's it
 	
 	
 		yeah it and when it comes on the manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten</NUMEX> bucks
 	
 	
 		i'll be darned
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		huh well
 		
 		
 	