
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay we're supposed to talk about vacations
 	
 	
 		right so um
 		well uh what kind of vacations do you like
 	
 	
 		well uh i haven't been to many places but i have a opportunity to go to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris France</ENAMEX> um with um with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> she is her
 		um her family you know lives there and she's only been there once her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> lives there so i'm hoping to go i'm praying i get to go um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh that great
 	
 	
 		yeah it's that will be probably the most exciting place i'll ever get to go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have you ever been to um like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um no actually
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		why have you
 	
 	
 		i was just curious i was just wondering what it was like
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		no um no i have been to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> once and to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>
 		and um yeah
 	
 	
 		Tahiti
 		Tahiti huh
 	
 	
 		no no Haiti
 	
 	
 		oh Haiti
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		where's that
 	
 	
 		it's um
 		well it's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>
 		and it's the western <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of an island with the eastern <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dominican Republic</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i was down there with a program from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> that i went to
 		where we would just spend like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> in a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> most of them third world countries
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and study the language and then do a little service project
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so yeah that turned out to be a really good experience for me
 	
 	
 		so what did you do when you were in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um well see i went there when i was in high school actually and i mostly went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and visited some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of my family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		hung out with them worked a bit on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of their farms
 		and
 		i also went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> camp
 	
 	
 		what did you do on the farm
 	
 	
 		um
 		uh uh well not that much
 		just uh
 	
 	
 		oh you just kind of sight just kind of uh
 	
 	
 		right i mean i wasn't a great asset to them or anything
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i you know drove a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractor</ENAMEX> helped them weed beets and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> and i went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> camp thing included working at an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s home
 		and that was pretty interesting
 		and while i was there i visited my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> who were staying for their vacation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in Nantes
 		which is on the west coast like right across from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		um
 		so uh where in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> are you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		hum how long do you plan to be going for
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> last time she stayed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> but we're only going to stay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum great
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		we're going to take a cooking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> there so that might be fun
 	
 	
 		a what
 	
 	
 		cooking class you know <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> cooking
 	
 	
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um
 		what else are you planning to do if anything
 	
 	
 		museums you know go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		did you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um actually no i don't think i went to any of them uh the closest thing i did was go
 		some like uh restored castles and stuff that there is some on that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">west</ENAMEX> coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">France</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and i went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vineyard</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um that's neat
 	
 	
 		yeah that was nice
 		um
 		hum
 		
 
 		but so um
 	
 	
 		say what about have you ever been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no i haven't have you
 	
 	
 		no
 		no
 	
 	
 		okay  well um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well where have you gone first
 	
 	
 		i'm wanting to go there oh God where have i gone if anywhere um
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean well what'd you
 		
 		
 	