
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so are are you a news person
 	
 	
 		uh i really am i enjoy i enjoy listening to the news and getting as much as i can although you know i'm a full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and i work full-time too so or not full-time but i work quite a bit and so  so i mostly depend on the radio
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know on the way to work i like i like to listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX> uh All Things Considered
 	
 	
 		yes great show
 	
 	
 		yeah and i like to listen to that and catch you know you i don't get i don't get a lot of uh sometimes i don't get the current events you know because that show kind of has feature stories that might not  directly deal with uh
 		you know some important issue on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah so so the real the real current news and the hard news
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is is not a there's not really enough of it there
 	
 	
 		right that's right yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i've had i've had that frustration too and i end up switching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> from time to time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah do you like you like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX>'s uh programming
 	
 	
 		uh in general you know um i watch
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> uh and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		well i i  subscribe to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		you know i sort of can't get enough of this
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and i when i travel elsewhere i'm often amazed at the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> how little they have
 	
 	
 		how how how oh yeah oh yeah
 	
 	
 		of of world world events and national events
 		well in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> what are the what is the newspaper situation
 	
 	
 		well  we don't we we have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a big</TIMEX> newspaper situation uh
 		because we used to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> up until uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX> and a uh major um a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> just closed down they closed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and said well we can't put any more papers out and we're done
 	
 	
 		hm
 		was was that the the better paper or  compared to the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought so it was a it was a more effective paper as far as i was concerned it it had uh  uh it got to the news you know and gave you the dirty facts pretty quick and easy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh which i like i don't i don't like to you know i like to save the editorial information or the  the politically uh weighted information you know for the for a different section i like just to get to the you know find out what's happening
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		pretty quick uh and i feel that the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> uh uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> is the one that's still here the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Herald</ENAMEX> is the one that closed up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning News</ENAMEX> was was is is okay but you know you have to wade through a lot of editorial
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">garbage</ENAMEX> as far as i'm concerned you know  many times it doesn't  doesn't reflect my own opinion and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		but if you if you were to look at the front page of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning News Morning Times</ENAMEX> rather uh would would you would you see  things about what's going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no no that's the problem uh you you know you see you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troy Aikman</ENAMEX>'s knee surgery on the front page you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		whoever <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troy Aikman</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> or for the for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> uh you know you know you know what i mean that there's uh  local news that
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh that really a lot of times doesn't doesn't change
 		change my life one way or the other  so uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i guess it's current events but not the kind of current events that changes the world
 	
 	
 		right right yeah not something you'll you'll uh be interested in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years from now</TIMEX> by any means
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know how how about you uh i guess in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> D C you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> that are pretty
 	
 	
 		yes um i i rather like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pretty effective don't you
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i also get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and you know each of them covers different things in in different different different in different ways and so it's
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		uh you know if i only looked at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them i would have a different perspective clearly would have a different perspective on the world
 	
 	
 		right yeah uh i i i have a question uh does does does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> uh i i've kind of gathered lately that uh maybe their information is not just only related to business is that is that a correct assumption
 	
 	
 		that that that is certainly true um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they will they will have articles like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days ago</TIMEX> they had a a nice article on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> you know theory of relativity
 	
 	
 		oh oh
 	
 	
 		you know that started on the front page and ran ran in into the full almost full page inside
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now these are feature kind of articles all all the all the um
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		you know the bulk of the paper certainly is about business kinds of activities
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but but there's some very good other articles
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you'll find in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">in the Journal</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum do you find that you're uh  uh disappointed or pleased with uh uh the performance of like network coverage of news
 	
 	
 		um  i wish it were in more depth um that doesn't mean to say longer just more facts would be nice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> has has you know was was pretty good during the war
 	
 	
 		oh yeah definitely
 	
 	
 		um
 		and they were you know sort of had a unique vantage point for for doing that reporting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you know it's not it's it's uh never quite
 		
 		
 	