
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well we have an easy subject today i guess  easier than trying to straighten the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> out which was yesterday
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh that was a would be difficult yeah i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on immigration
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't get that one  thank goodness oh well you know i've been i went to back to school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> and i tell you i haven't done much entertaining since
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		i know i  i don't have the money to entertain so
 	
 	
 		that's another consideration
 	
 	
 		exactly i mean even <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hamburgers</ENAMEX> you know when you get all the fixings with it it's kind of uh  expensive
 	
 	
 		well i know and uh time seems to be such a element nowadays
 	
 	
 		exactly you've got to get things that it can be done ahead or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> has to be clean that's the worse part to me
 	
 	
 		yeah that way i have to get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to help me with that because i'd never never be able to entertain otherwise
 	
 	
 		oh yeah do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> oh well that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> less thing to mess up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>  yeah i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i have uh one that's in uh college and one that's uh in high school
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah that's true do you have it
 		ah well i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and so i've got plenty of pet hair to contend with
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh yeah i've got that too i have everything in the  we're a family of slobs on top of that  so the cleaning really is the worse for entertaining
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
 
 		well i guess they wanted us to talk about the the recipes i mean what do you what do you cook
 	
 	
 		right
 		well one of the easy things  uh when i did used  to entertain that i like to make is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> it's real easy and i can make it ahead of time and then just stick it in the oven
 		to uh to heat up you know so i don't really like to actually cook when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are already there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		exactly i like to be able to entertain and not be killing myself while
 	
 	
 		right and it makes me nervous if they're all in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen messing</ENAMEX> and i'm trying to cook stuff you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um so that's one thing that i used to make a lot
 	
 	
 		see usually we just like like you said i like to do something i can do you know and just put it in the fridge but i i'll make a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mushrooms dish</ENAMEX> or you know uh easy stuff i don't i i i don't do that much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		that sounds good we've done shish kabob several times and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> always like that but it's a lot of work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> are so hard you have to kind of parboil them a little
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then um season the stuff and marinade it and then stick it on all those things
 	
 	
 		so you'd think it would be easy but it's actually you know quite a bit of work
 	
 	
 		at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX> it's not so bad because you can throw it on the grill and it doesn't take very long but boy the prepreparation of cutting all that up in the right sizes and washing it and like i said parboiling some of the hard stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		exactly
 		well that's the problem for me like cooking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> because you know they always have tons of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		yeah it chop forever
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		i've never done that for um party
 	
 	
 		well  i'll do it when we have a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over but not a lot it's too it's too much for that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i know
 	
 	
 		but i mean i've been known to go over to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>'s and and uh buy a a pan of uh ready made like enchiladas or or something i didn't like the enchiladas very much but they had some um
 	
 	
 		oh are they good
 		someone said the lasagna was good
 	
 	
 		the lasagna is very good and i've made that as well
 	
 	
 		i think it must be good because i have an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> that bought some for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i thought golly she she she cooks a lot too and i if she bought it it must be pretty good
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah and you know when you i mean when you've got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> on on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> that you work it's almost impossible
 	
 	
 		oh well it is
 	
 	
 		so you know that's that's for me the easiest thing to do get something
 	
 	
 		i don't think i ever had something on a day i worked oh well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that's horrible where do you work
 	
 	
 		oh i have
 		um over i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Central</ENAMEX> over it's at say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LB</ENAMEX> yeah  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> and i work for a liquor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distiller</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Central</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Expressway</ENAMEX> is it
 		oh do they give you any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christmas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes they do  we get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bottles
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well that's nice that's the another expensive part about entertaining if you plan to drink i mean that is really expensive
 	
 	
 		exactly no we have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and that's about it
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have nowadays
 	
 	
 		yeah it's just too hard to get yeah to get all the you know the different kinds of oh this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> likes gin this one
 	
 	
 		for big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> at least
 		i know you could could spend <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well over a hundred a hundred</NUMEX> fifty dollars getting all that stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so anyway
 	
 	
 		well what do you do for desserts
 	
 	
 		oh dessert um sometimes i buy it  i have through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> i used to make this really neat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX> that was was with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crackers</ENAMEX> and pecans on
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you bake it and then you put whipped <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> on the top it's just delicious um sometimes you can get it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luby's</ENAMEX> restaurant
 	
 	
 		oh that's sounds good
 		hum i uh let's see i usually make a well something easy stuff as usual but you know the things that you can buy the ready made crusts and and then put like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh uh we'll have a chocolate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nut pie um pie</ENAMEX> and you know
 	
 	
 		um
 		you make up the homemade filling but you use the oh that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		exactly so
 	
 	
 		i can't even remember oh i used i used to make a cheesecake with a easy recipe using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle Brand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> you know but it was it was pretty good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there was a time when i made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Boule</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> Truffle
 	
 	
 		oh see and i just don't i don't dare try all that stuff because i don't even know if i like it to begin with  if i don't like it it doesn't get made around here
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		oh that's the way i am we haven't bad a baked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> dinner since we've been married for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five years</TIMEX> my i hate baked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> for dinner  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> loved it they're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> and they live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and that was one of their big
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		deals was baked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you had to suffer through it when you were there
 	
 	
 		oh God yeah they'd have it a lot of time for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i couldn't stand it because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> always say
 		
 		
 	