
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh i guess i basically consider consider mykelf kind of conservative uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> how about you
 	
 	
 		um i'm more of a liberal or at least uh in between moderate more of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh okay
 		uh uh what do you think about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and the economy
 	
 	
 		um
 		the economy is is doing badly and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> isn't looking good as a result
 	
 	
 		i think i heard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that he finally admitted we are in a recession
 		uh it's it's long time forthcoming for him to say that
 	
 	
 		at
 		well well the recession started a long time ago question is is when whether and when it's going to end or has it ended yet but it's the economy's certainly not healthy
 	
 	
 		especially down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> where we had a big a bunch of problem with real estate down here and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if
 		yes that's been one of the areas for for for problems in that we've had it more lightly in that respect but not without without uh without significant problems
 		uh i think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perpetual Savings Bank</ENAMEX> went under here it's one of the biggest in the area
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		hell we've had so many changes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that uh the names of them are no longer the same they got one called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCNB</ENAMEX> and we're supposed to think of it as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCNB</ENAMEX> and not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Carolina National Bank</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh oh that's part of the recent merger
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's merging with uh something else from the south and gonna be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Southern</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First National</ENAMEX> or something i don't know
 		
 
 		anyway i think the solution in my opinion is to have something political to talk about is for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to get out of business and leave us alone rather than get into business what's your feeling
 	
 	
 		uh i'm not sure but what um  what that's intended to to mean uh and
 	
 	
 		uh
 		regulations controls
 	
 	
 		um
 		as a whole i'd rather avoid government regulations and controls ah
 		ah some are some are necessary and i mean in some ways
 		what we're going through now is reaction to to all that developed during the eighties
 	
 	
 		yeah look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> they they were probably doing pretty well back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> and seventies making a profit or least getting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> support
 		once they pulled out the controls look how many went under and say bye-bye
 	
 	
 		yes that's certainly true i'm not sure whether it's bad or not um my sense is that
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		that airline costs costs of flying are still are lower still lower <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> than they were before all this began um
 		but we can maybe reach a point where there the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in the field is too few and uh where where government oversight uh is needed
 	
 	
 		and trucking industry when they pulled the plugs away from from that a lot of the safety that used to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> disappeared the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">truckers</ENAMEX> will run on thin tires and
 		they'll stretch the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and they'll do without insurance and they and i think that when it was control there was
 		better safety but i don't know if the accident ratios will prove that out or not
 	
 	
 		i guess i don't know either but i there is a role for safety regulations likewise in airlines
 		and i think for the most part though that that's uh continued for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> the safety record <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is as good or better as it was in the seventies
 	
 	
 		
 
 		change of subject let's jump to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> what's the feeling over there on the east coast about what's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> doing and
 	
 	
 		uh well i guess the feeling as much as i hear by is that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> is is is done for
 		unfortunately oh unfortunately in a way at least everyone admires him uh but uh the future is with this this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> this whatever it's called infinite um
 		commonwealth uh with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i wonder if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> knew how far it'd go when he climbed on top of that tank
 		actually it's amazing if that one little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> pulled the shit trigger and shot his head off
 		i wonder what would've happened
 	
 	
 		yes things would be different
 	
 	
 		it would be it would've been a total different
 		one little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteen year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>
 		decided whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> communism failed or made it  well maybe i'm too far off in saying that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it would've it would've made a difference had there been violence ah
 		the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> still wouldn't have survived but it was it was to been bloodier than it's been through this point
 	
 	
 		hey i wonder what happened to all that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> over there
 		you heard that one haven't you
 	
 	
 		the rumor is that much of it has been expended
 	
 	
 		gone spent
 	
 	
 		
 
 		ah
 	
 	
 		you said expended oh it's been spent then
 	
 	
 		um they were rumors i i don't know what's happened
 	
 	
 		i don't either uh i don't either
 		ah wouldn't surprise me if some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	