
 
     		
 	
 		uh it seems like an unusual subject <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of the year</TIMEX> but uh it's it's camping
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really when was the last time you went
 	
 	
 		the last time i went camping was about uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of October</TIMEX>
 		and we went up to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Bonham</ENAMEX> and really enjoyed it had a real good time with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> we do an awful lot of camping
 		how about yourself
 	
 	
 		well i haven't been in probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years</TIMEX> and the last time we went was in um well i guess it was it was like hunting season and we went down to like a hunting ground and a lake <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lake Sam Rayburn</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes oh
 	
 	
 		which is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		very good i bet it's pretty over there
 	
 	
 		it is real pretty um let's see do you do a lot of fishing and
 	
 	
 		what do you think what kind of camping uh are you talking about do you go out and is camping for you in a motor home or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> or do you actually put up a tent the whole bit
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the ones that you pull along and then pop up is it pop up
 	
 	
 		oh okay so you have yeah
 	
 	
 		pop up
 	
 	
 		a pop up trailer huh how fun we have a tent
 	
 	
 		yeah what do you have
 		a tent
 	
 	
 		yes  so i guess we really rough it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really
 	
 	
 		and we really enjoy that uh one thing uh i've done all sorts of camping i've i've camped uh
 		in the snow on a glacier i've camped uh
 		basically almost anywhere even to a point where we've had to backpack in and everything you carried in
 		was what you had to use to sustain you for that that camping trip and had to pack it back out
 	
 	
 		so you're a serious camper
 	
 	
 		well we enjoy it yeah  but since i've been married and with a family uh
 		we have to go where there's restrooms  and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playgrounds</ENAMEX> and so forth so
 	
 	
 		well that makes sense
 	
 	
 		we really enjoy it but also while i was growing up we did have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> and uh i've camped in in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> and in a tent and in in log cabins and so forth too so
 		a lot of different things and yes i to answer your questions earlier yes i we do enjoy fishing and i do go fishing haven't done a whole lot down here we recently moved from
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky Mountain</ENAMEX> area up in uh northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> down to here because of work and uh haven't been able to
 		enjoy fishing like i used to up there which which is uh clear water fishing and streams and and rivers uh
 	
 	
 		but when y'all went camping is that what you normally i mean what did you normally do
 	
 	
 		we normally yeah we did we did a lot of fishing but mainly what we did is we did a lot of hiking and exploring and just going out and seeing what there was to see uh in the area
 	
 	
 		i guess probably just where ever you live at then has a lot to do with where what you're gonna do when you go and you do actually camp
 	
 	
 		oh yes that's true that's true and
 	
 	
 		did you ever like travel around to what's that the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KO KOA KOA</ENAMEX> camps whenever you ever done that
 	
 	
 		no we never did that they  although i've stayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KOA</ENAMEX> campgrounds uh we've never done that just to go around and camp
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> personally i when i when we were growing up and when we were uh going camping i thought that was little too structured of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp ground</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um you know that was mainly for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motor homes</ENAMEX> or
 		or had <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailers</ENAMEX> or so and so on and so forth where you know we really wanted to go camping in a tent and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KOA</ENAMEX> is is is geared for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have a hook up
 	
 	
 		um hum
 		they actually travel from what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city state</ENAMEX> to state
 	
 	
 		right exactly
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i started out basically camping when i was when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> and we did an awful lot of that as as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scout</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> as i mentioned earlier
 		we went into wilderness areas and we camped in the snow in in uh snow caves and
 	
 	
 		that's probably where i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> started was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		all right and you got a lot of that in huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what do you like to do when you go camping
 	
 	
 		um well let's see i just i mean i just like to go and normally normally i go with a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and we just kind of go and hang out and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just do fun stuff roast marshmallows
 	
 	
 		enjoy it huh
 		tell scaries or scary stories around the fire and and so on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah or um take a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">deck</ENAMEX> of cards if we if we can actually see and um play cards and stuff
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah you know that uh lot a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i've talked to have said well isn't camping boring don't you get well don't you uh get bored and not have anything to do but i've found out that
 		actually we we really enjoy getting away from the television the telephone
 	
 	
 		yeah it's relaxing
 	
 	
 		and yes exactly get out getting out and enjoying nature and each each other's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> when we're out camping
 	
 	
 		plus you um kind of makes you appreciate some lot of the things you take for granted
 	
 	
 		yeah  like like
 	
 	
 		running water your hair dryer curling iron
 	
 	
 		running <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and a and a private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> and
 		yes
 	
 	
 		well what about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> do your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and everything like to
 	
 	
 		yes they really do they have a great time and like i mentioned uh the we've we've been been camping a couple of times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and the last time was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> and we went up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> Bonham
 		and there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX> for them and so they have swings and they have slides
 		
 		
 	