
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		now where do you live
 	
 	
 		i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well we're pretty close then
 	
 	
 		you bet
 		well see our subject was gun control
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i'm sort of uh prejitice prejudiced on this subject because that's my vocation that's what i do for a living
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because i'm a i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s sales rep and i sell hunting and shooting supplies
 		working working for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> so
 		i would guess i would be sort of pro
 	
 	
 		well  i guess we have something in common then because i don't think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pro pro <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> but uh
 		okay
 	
 	
 		that are the problem it's it's the people
 	
 	
 		no
 		i agree <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		i mean they're just an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inanimate</ENAMEX> object until they are in the hands of
 		someone who is
 		who is violent or has a a sick warped mind
 	
 	
 		i agree with you <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> percent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX> i'll tell you that somewhere i saw a bumper sticker <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> i'd like to see more of them i think uh speaking from my my viewpoint think it read something like uh when <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are outlawed only outlaws will have guns
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and i think that sort of speaks for itself i believe uh
 		in some gun control
 		but i think it's and i you know in selling to the industry or selling for the industry to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> i think that it's the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
 		stand that should be taken and i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> now or to buy a gun now an individual just has to go in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and and show his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> license and if he
 		has a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> license and if he lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> he can go to any gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> and buy a gun merely by filling out a yellow form and and paying for the firearm and leaving
 	
 	
 		with it at the time
 	
 	
 		right it would be it would be handy if they had you know computers being like they are if they'd have some kind of a
 		computer program on a national level where you could just dial an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> and
 		and run a check on someone
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i would be for something like that
 	
 	
 		yes it would uh but then
 		too the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
 		who have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> already um some of them they may have had this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> for twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before they
 		uh become mentally unbalanced and use it
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		and otherwise i mean if someone is going to get a gun
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and is determined to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and commit some some act
 		they're going to get it whether they can walk in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and buy it or if they have to break into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> or
 		something you know they're going to get one
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		but uh no you and i i think have the same idea that  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are not the problem
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i've heard a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say why i wouldn't have a gun in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> they're too dangerous
 		ignorance is what's dangerous
 	
 	
 		you bet absolutely
 	
 	
 		uh i have uh many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> and they have all been raised in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> with loaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> they have been taught
 		the danger of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> how to handle them
 		um from the time  well i had a granddaughter that
 		i raised and from the time that she  was um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
 		she knew that the gun that i had was not to be touched and that it was dangerous and i never had to worry about her
 	
 	
 		well that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		but
 		uh anytime that she would have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> come i would put i had a closet that would lock and any gun firearms that were loaded we usually keep a uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twelve</NUMEX> gauge <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX> loaded and then my handgun
 		and anytime that there were other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i had i put them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> that locked just for safety sake
 	
 	
 		well that's great we've always done the same thing and
 		being in the business i've sold <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty seven years</TIMEX> i'm fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years old</TIMEX> and i've sold <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty seven years</TIMEX> worked for some major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Winchester</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that and
 		and i always consider a a firearm i know they're very dangerous but i always consider everything a sporting firearm and i realize that
 		just as you say some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't think of them as that but that's how i think of them being that i'm in the business but main thing is just be education and communication on the subject
 		and that's something we have always tried to do
 		and
 		i'm a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> in that
 	
 	
 		yes i think that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that find <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and shoot themselves or another child
 		uh if they  if they knew what they were playing with
 		they wouldn't do it
 	
 	
 		absolutely right
 	
 	
 		because they would my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> one of the when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> were just very very small
 		he was
 		educating them about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and he took a watermelon out and set it up on
 		uh this
 		little rise out on the desert where they live
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	