
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay you know what happens is
 		i've tried i was out because of surgery <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> so i tried calling a couple of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock</TIMEX> calls and i got a person from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and a person from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and a person from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> so i thought
 		sort of need her calling <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">really early in the morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		early in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and you got somebody from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh well i'm from Mesquite
 	
 	
 		out of town
 		so  that's why that's why i've been making been making it a habit of calling in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but anyway uh
 		the topic was the
 		most important benefit of your job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> besides salary and how satisfied are you and everything i'm sort of self-employed so uh i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i am too for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in my life um-hum
 	
 	
 		really i'd be at a a little loss for words on this as far as i'm concerned most definitely uh most important benefit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> would be hospitalization and of course retirement and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i've worked for a large Fortune 500 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> before and have had the luxury of uh benefits and um at a very  small cost
 		and uh  then got out on my own through no fault of my own i was with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safeway</ENAMEX> and they left the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>  or left the um north part of the state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i find myself in the insurance industry
 		and i am finding i although i don't sell group insurance or major medical i sell supplemental health i'm finding that every place i go to talk to them about my product
 		it's they're in such a dilemma about um the major medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> market right now it's just not very desirable
 		um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well that's very true i can understand that because
 		i'm a just a small business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i run a
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but uh they're all straight commission <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesmen</ENAMEX> so they all provide their own
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		insurance and it's been that way since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteen seventy four</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is just a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> office i have myself plus my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> and she comes in at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> leaves at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she's on her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s insurance program and i just uh
 	
 	
 		so you're fortunate in that manner
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		well um i think some of the benefits that are being made available nowadays like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 401K</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> is beneficial i was not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> or that was not available when i was employed
 		but uh i did participate in a stock program and uh
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		and that really worked out well for me when i had been with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen years</TIMEX> and now have a a you know a small retirement set aside which is
 		allows me to go on commission sales
 		and um and do it you know comfortably
 	
 	
 		oh that's neat are you married
 	
 	
 		uh no i'm not
 	
 	
 		okay well i'm married and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s a school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> so i'm on her they have pretty good insurance so i they she carries me on her insurance program which works out real well
 	
 	
 		they really do
 		what uh school district is she in
 	
 	
 		she's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano School District</ENAMEX> in Plano
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's not cheap it's like all insurance insurance just keeps on going up more and more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and course the uh
 		the prices they're charging <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and because of the problems they have
 	
 	
 		exactly and the deductibles are going up and that
 	
 	
 		oh deductibles are high
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's one of the reasons my um the what my product is just getting more and more popular because it's a catastrophic
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> insurance intensive care and a daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> indemnity and so those kinds of things not only help a person
 		um cover um their deductibles
 		it helps you know pay the rent and or the mortgage and they and the car payments when uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has to be off with something like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you bet
 		supplemental anything is important today i'll tell you whether
 	
 	
 		exactly and i'm i real feel real fortunate that i've landed in a with a really good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in a good position
 	
 	
 		well that's great
 	
 	
 		and they're really nice too one of the benefits of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is that they provide me with some stock
 		um they give it to me uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> percent of what i sell
 		and um uh annualized premium and so this is really going to add up through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> i've been doing this over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and have already accumulated quite a bit
 	
 	
 		well that's super
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so
 	
 	
 		we're just uh
 		i carry my own Keogh Plan as far as benefits and i've been doing that since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteen seventy four or seventy five</TIMEX> or whatever and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's more or less my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s and my retirement i'm fifty years old my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty nine</NUMEX> and she didn't start teaching till she was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we raised our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> first and she went back and got her degree and started teaching so it looks like
 		we're gonna retire in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> and she'll uh she'll qualify for a little something after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> of teaching but not a whole lot but it'll be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		certainly be useful and needed
 	
 	
 		right what kind of business are you in
 	
 	
 		i'm in the sporting goods business i'm a own a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s rep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and uh we we represent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen</NUMEX> different hunting and shooting type <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and that's all i've done since
 	
 	
 		i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i graduated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">school years ago</TIMEX> sold a sold
 	
 	
 		is that right well it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i've been in sales in my life uh-huh
 	
 	
 		really oh it's neat isn't it
 	
 	
 		i love it i love it i should've been there a long time ago
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		
 		
 	