
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i would say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Texas</ENAMEX> now because i talked to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> to somebody in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my yeah and well uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano Texas</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano Illinois</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh do they have one
 	
 	
 		yes they do
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't know that well i learned something already
 	
 	
 		yeah well let's see the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> questions are what um
 	
 	
 		how much time do you spend with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		very little because they're grown they're grown and gone
 	
 	
 		oh what
 		oh yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well mine</ENAMEX>'s are down at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT Austin</ENAMEX> in college and the other one's in high school so you do spend less time then because
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah because they don't want to know they almost don't want to know us
 	
 	
 		they wanna be with their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> well how old are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are they married or what
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh yes i have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> married <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> almost and then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> almost married and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the other two</NUMEX> oh i'm not sure <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two single two two</NUMEX>  uh uh for sure single
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> you have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you
 	
 	
 		yeah we have between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> and myself we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's kind of nice though you
 	
 	
 		because i came with a split <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and she had one
 	
 	
 		you shouldn't be lonesome on a holiday huh
 	
 	
 		well no there's so much of them are gone and they're doing their own things and
 	
 	
 		well that's true
 	
 	
 		and a lot of times they they've got you know  uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX> a lot
 	
 	
 		they have to see their other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> i guess too
 	
 	
 		yeah and sometimes they want to do their own thing so sometimes it's just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> and me and and you know what
 	
 	
 		i know
 		right
 	
 	
 		sometimes that's okay
 	
 	
 		i know that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		because you know right because who says that they just must got to come over to see us all the time
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no that's true and if they force them to you know that's not good either
 	
 	
 		yeah that becomes a drudgery and when you
 	
 	
 		well do they all live in the area
 	
 	
 		well let's see i've got
 		of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> around here
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh wow
 	
 	
 		uh you know well we're talking like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Texas</ENAMEX> and then one is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montpelier Montpelier Monteplier Montpelier Vermont</ENAMEX> and the other one's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Everett Washington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		golly
 		how'd they end up so far away
 	
 	
 		well that is  that's the the the my little pair
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> marriage um and uh
 	
 	
 		those are the youngest ones
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah well <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the second the the the the fourth</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the</ENAMEX>  of the uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that are scattered like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that those are a long way how'd
 	
 	
 		and well they wanted to go uh JR my my my least <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> or my middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> excuse me fell in love with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> state and the the the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> fell in love with uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Vermont</ENAMEX> so yeah that's where they've gone to make their homes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vermont</ENAMEX> so they wanted to make their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> there huh
 		my goodness are they are those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> married
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		are they uh just working up there or going to school or what
 	
 	
 		well uh let's see
 		yeah i guess you'd say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JR</ENAMEX> is  working and going to school trying to go to school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i wish to God he would go back
 	
 	
 		oh they do eventually if they have if they're meant to i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i certainly hope so
 	
 	
 		i mean i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that's a sophomore at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX> and i'm i'm going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTA</ENAMEX> right now myself so it's never too late
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well it's oh i agree it's never too late
 	
 	
 		right especially in some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> around here i think they have <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about twenty percent</NUMEX> older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah and when you're saying older we're talking fifty up
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i've seen some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are really really quite up there  you know they look like in their very late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> and i say that's great why not you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh my uh-huh
 		yes why not because that's a a lot of times well it's i i believe that uh
 		we in that category and i'm not in that category quite yet
 	
 	
 		but no
 	
 	
 		but we are seasoned minds
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you're really ready to learn finally finally i mean i don't know why i even went to college when i was seventeen it was a complete waste of money
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 		yeah it was
 		yeah settle down we know what we're wanting to to uh study and uh
 	
 	
 		right right now we're
 	
 	
 		we know our limitations
 	
 	
 		right and uh
 	
 	
 		and we don't try to burn the candle at both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ends</ENAMEX> and then the middle altogether
 	
 	
 		no we don't go out drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> till <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and then you try to go to class in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> we're past yeah we're past that age
 	
 	
 		at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> yeah
 		yes we're we're smarter than that
 	
 	
 		we know what we can do  oh
 	
 	
 		yack right um so let's see so mine and i don't spend a whole lot of time because they're not here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> question  i forgot what the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> question
 	
 	
 		what was it what uh how what do the trends in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and do we approve of what other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		well uh the trends in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> were to spread apart do your own thing but i have seen lately yes i am seeing
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		a change i was gonna say the same thing
 	
 	
 		i'm seeing a change that whoops <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can't do it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are not able to and between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s religion
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh their their faith in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> whether whether you know uh whether you're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian or Jewish</ENAMEX> or whatever  uh and the family
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		those are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that can that that have the wherewithal and of course
 	
 	
 		or gonna have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> on the bone huh
 	
 	
 		Judeo-Christianity uh and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> too believe that the family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> is the one that was given the uh
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> to do this very thing so when another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> step in try to do it they're they're tromping on our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> so to speak so i firmly believe that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		
 		
 	