
 
     		
 	
 		where'd you go on your last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		Hot <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springs Arkansas</ENAMEX> oh and it's beautiful it was great in fact we purchased land up there  uh-huh yeah it's it's well it's not really time share it's just a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey</ENAMEX>
 		did you one of those time share things
 	
 	
 		it's really pretty up there in a place called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hot Springs Village</ENAMEX> it's
 	
 	
 		i've seen the flyers on that that please come up and we'll give you a free <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> or something something
 	
 	
 		it's it's really nice
 		yeah something like that  we got <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three nights</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> up there so we went it was a nice way to get away
 	
 	
 		had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that went and uh
 		some some place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and they gave him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty four</TIMEX> rib eye <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steaks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		what a deal
 	
 	
 		i said well did you buy anything he said no we just went up and got our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steaks</ENAMEX> i said well
 	
 	
 		no  that's the way to do it you know
 	
 	
 		well their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> trip with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and and they said  that was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> they had so they up and they went got <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steaks</ENAMEX> and got out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> for a while
 	
 	
 		might might as well
 		well now we'd we really liked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hot Springs</ENAMEX> just because we neither of us had ever been there and it was it's a pretty town
 	
 	
 		kind of retirement village kind of
 	
 	
 		it's full of i was gonna say it's full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> and full of nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and funeral <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> but it's still a beautiful area
 	
 	
 		yes yes yes
 		yeah
 		well you you know you're a true <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> when you go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> and there's more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickups</ENAMEX> rather than cars
 	
 	
 		well i wasn't born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but i moved here when i was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> so yeah i i consider myself almost a true <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's awful
 		you you can qualify
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> Two but that only because of the they were called up for duty so  well we went to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Estes Park Colorado</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		oh oh now that would be nice
 	
 	
 		which is a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and we rented a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> and uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen cabin</ENAMEX> and and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah that that's that's the kind of vacations i like to do
 	
 	
 		and they got all kinds of activities on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> so you just kind of get on there and let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go run wild
 	
 	
 		what is the what kind of a cost do they have uh with that
 	
 	
 		let's see we had a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> one bath a fully equipped kitchen i mean all you bring is your food they even got coffee grinders and all that stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh what did we pay uh
 		by the time you get everything on there it was about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty eight bucks a night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you're kidding oh that'd be wonderful we got to get there first and
 	
 	
 		no but you well you got to make reservations
 		yeah you got to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> that's seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> bucks for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> first  then you go through the drawing and uh yeah it it it's you got to
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		real expensive here hm
 	
 	
 		there's more to it than that but but it's really nice and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and it's just through the local through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no you can if you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> you don't have to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> up there
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		they they they somehow will accept that but you got to kick into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> system to get out
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well yeah because we're in the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garland Y</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it  it's a lovely place to go if you got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> even if you don't but
 	
 	
 		so that would come in
 		well yeah we have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		well they've got things planned for that age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> but it's all extra everything is extra once you get there
 	
 	
 		well yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Colorado</ENAMEX> being a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> place i can kind of understand that but that's i love mountains when i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> one time and i was just in heaven
 	
 	
 		as i say it
 	
 	
 		we got off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> and i was just  yeah
 	
 	
 		we saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bighorn sheep</ENAMEX> come down
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		well they're <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rocky Estes Park</ENAMEX> is right next to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky Mountain National Park</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we tried <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times and the last time before we came back they were crossing the road and going up the path they're ugly
 	
 	
 		um oh oh
 	
 	
 		we saw also saw a real big moose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> moose came out of the hills into downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Estes Park</ENAMEX> and were eating grass in a vacant lot
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		this isn't little
 	
 	
 		and you're going we're like in civilization here we're not out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>  oh how funny
 	
 	
 		we were on a trolley
 		anyway so you enjoyed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hot Springs</ENAMEX> has gambling casino gambling come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hot Springs</ENAMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		oh
 		um no but they do have <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hay horse</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX>  at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oaklawn</ENAMEX> tracks
 	
 	
 		and bingo i bet you i bet
 	
 	
 		i don't know about that but i'm sure they do with with the age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that's there
 	
 	
 		i'm sure
 	
 	
 		i would imagine they do but i know they have horse <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX> that's why and they weren't running while we were there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> but they were doing simulcasts with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louisiana Downs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so they you can if you want to bet and that did draw a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> you could bet there year around
 	
 	
 		legally oh are where are the are
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah no uh at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX> they they they run
 	
 	
 		i am
 		you can bet in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> around
 	
 	
 		well yeah but legally  they the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> run there from like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February to April</TIMEX>
 		so we're planning to be back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of February</TIMEX>   was like i wanna go back but it's it's in the mountains and i really like mountains i keep my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had never been outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> until he and i got married
 	
 	
 		yeah huh
 	
 	
 		and it was like let's go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> let's you know let's go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and  because we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> over there and that's a pretty area too we've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> a couple of times not to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX> but just to go and do other stuff that's there
 	
 	
 		if you like cabin cooking your own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robber</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cave State Park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> is a neat deal
 	
 	
 		oh i love it
 		what is where is it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robber</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cave State Park</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six hours</TIMEX> from here
 	
 	
 		yeah but see i'm a i i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>  i i have a problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>  well this is true  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robber</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cave State Park</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know i know
 		we don't have mountains in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> though
 		and they got cabins and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen cabins</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah see that's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> go to they have  i guess i got the buying land bug from them they've got a piece of property out on uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake</ENAMEX> of the Pines
 	
 	
 		planned activities
 		
 
 		
 		
 	