
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Scott</ENAMEX> let's uh talk about advice that we can offer a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is going to go to a university and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh-huh do you have any do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		i have some yes some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and they're all quite young and so we want to plan for their education we're we're saving right now and we're getting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		bonds and and uh and hopefully finances set aside so that they can choose a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> that they want to how about yourself do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right no i'm in graduate i'm in graduate school right now
 	
 	
 		so so i imagine you've gone through the experience yourself of selecting your college your own college
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah definitely in fact i'm even going uh  selecting again for for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PhD</ENAMEX> it's it's a closed subject right now
 	
 	
 		very good what uh what do you use as a basis to determine which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> or university you go to
 	
 	
 		um
 		well  i use uh uh
 		uh i have used uh several techniques depending on what for undergraduate i i you know my my criteria were much different than than like for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		when i when i wanted to go to an undergraduate's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> i was looking for something that was you know rather small and easy to get around you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and what i would what i thought would be easy to get through
 	
 	
 		yeah what what you thought huh
 	
 	
 		yeah and and uh yeah my choice of graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> was uh you know it changed a whole lot i i got to where i i wanted to uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> with a little you know with a name behind me rather than uh
 	
 	
 		just the degree itself
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah so
 	
 	
 		well that's a that's that's good because i did quite a bit the same thing in my undergraduate work i wanted to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that was small enough that was personable that you didn't have a lecture with uh hall with about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> competing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>'s attention
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh but you i felt that i got a a pretty good uh undergraduate um
 	
 	
 		where where did you go
 	
 	
 		i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah State University</ENAMEX> which is in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Logan Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the nice thing about it too is i knew that i wanted to get into business
 		and that their business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College of Business</ENAMEX> was accredited and well known at least there in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of Utah</ENAMEX> and around the surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and so forth
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i i felt like number one you need you also need to see what kind of name the like you mentioned before the name the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> can can give you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and another thing that uh another reason why i chose that
 		was the the finances i wanted to make sure that i would be able to afford it that i wouldn't get through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four three years</TIMEX> of of the undergraduate work and and have to leave
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		so i did a lot of talking with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> at high school and also read some
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some books on on the subject at the at the library
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it was kind of unusual because my
 		my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and i all went to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three three</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> depending upon what our choice was so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hopefully we we chose the one that was best for us and i i felt very comfortable and good about that so i
 	
 	
 		um-hum do you do you worry do you worry any about uh uh you
 		being able i mean do you uh obviously you've taken precautions you know or or measures to uh try and pay for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s education but do you think that that's gonna be enough
 	
 	
 		i don't think so  i don't know the the way that tuition is increasing um
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		exponentially it's it's  it's kind of hard to set aside money and have that money grow  same pace that the college tuition is increasing i uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah i all i all i can hope for is that i land a professorship at a at a nice heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		and that the your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can use the benefits of that university <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> that that's an excellent idea that's an excellent idea
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		one thing that uh that we did uh and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is that we weren't able to afford
 		um
 		the kind of education that we all desired so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> stressed that we get excellent grades and that we apply and try for scholarships
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh scholarships were very beneficial in my case to help pay for my education because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> couldn't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and what these scholarship could not supply i was able to to work for and and save and and and get also my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he's a he's a medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> right now he had to you know once he got past his undergraduate and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> degree he had to take out some loans and he's he's working to pay those off
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i i think that the uh
 		you know once you get past uh the initial stages of it that there's different options you can use and and uh the student loans are are a good option and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's what that's  my biggest option right now
 	
 	
 		yeah yes and and as you're well aware that tuition's not cheap
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	