
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		this area <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm born and raised here
 	
 	
 		well great so who you want to talk about baseballwise
 	
 	
 		may
 		may as well talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> all right
 	
 	
 		uh uh
 		might as well
 	
 	
 		well do you think they're going to get anyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i hope i hope they do they've uh i forgot who've they signed already
 	
 	
 		did they sign that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shortstop</ENAMEX> that was
 		they were talking about some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shortstop</ENAMEX> they were going to try to get in the free agency draft
 		or the free agency market
 	
 	
 		i don't know who they uh they they decide sign finally signed up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Downing</ENAMEX> i know
 	
 	
 		for
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		they're they're trying to get uh God what's his name what's that black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s name uh
 	
 	
 		is he with them now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ruben</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Ruben yeah they haven't they still haven't signed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben</ENAMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no i heard that they're not going to talk to him till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s now they talked to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> today and then they're going to talk to them some more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> which i don't know whether that's good bad or indifferent because
 		wish they'd get that out of the way and maybe he could do something else
 	
 	
 		yeah i know well they said they made a mistake they made a mistake by  uh
 		not signing not signing him uh to a longer contract than what they did
 	
 	
 		i know why do you think they did that
 	
 	
 		oh they did did did it for economics but it's coming back and it's going to haunt them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> because he played such good ball the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last couple of years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because now his uh his contracts say they i think they signed him for like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four hundred thousand</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> but now it's going to cost them somewhere about uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred thousand</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million</NUMEX>  is kind of
 	
 	
 		oh
 		you don't think he'll get that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty seven million</NUMEX> like that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> just got
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
 
 		i don't think so i don't he'll he's it's it's going to cost them though
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's going to cost them but he's worth it
 	
 	
 		that's true well do you think they need to fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentine</ENAMEX>'s a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i don't know if he's i don't know he's he's done a lot for the team
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he really has i think he's an excellent i think he's an excellent coach he's probably one of the best ones that they've had just because he's more consistent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he's more consistent than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> that we've had and had there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and i i think he'll do some good he just needs a they just need to put together a good pitching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and i think they'll go pretty good
 	
 	
 		not have so many injuries
 	
 	
 		yeah that was that's what killed them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i went to a few went to a few of their games and it just uh the pitching was okay but it was
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		it was inconsistent
 	
 	
 		are you comfortable that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Witt</ENAMEX> will be back
 		or is he
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		ever going to develop into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super pitcher</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i don't think he is
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't think he is
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Brown</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Brown</ENAMEX> uh he might he might he still he's still got a little learning to do
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought maybe he would but i was kind of disappointed last year
 	
 	
 		yeah i was disappointed the whole season so  they they they started out i mean if they would have continued they went off that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> game losing streak or winning streak then they kind of hit the dumps there for a while
 	
 	
 		well they
 		yeah
 		yeah but then all their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX> were hurt so that that really hurts when you can't
 		when all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX> get hurt like that so
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true you think they're going to do anything this year
 	
 	
 		i don't know i uh
 		uh i think they need a another arm
 		and i'm still not sure that that new <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baseman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Palmer</ENAMEX> is as good as they think he's going to be
 	
 	
 		i think they made a mistake they made a mistake trading Buechele uh
 	
 	
 		but
 		well i don't think they uh think they knew they couldn't afford
 		him and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben</ENAMEX> and they decided to go with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben</ENAMEX> because he
 	
 	
 		yeah that's probably true but uh you know you got to you got to have more not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s going to make the team
 	
 	
 		yeah but they're not willing to pay big bucks it doesn't seem i think they'll have an exciting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last next next year</TIMEX> and i just you know if they don't have any injuries but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Kansas City</ENAMEX> you know just signed a big time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> so they're they're tough at signing all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they got uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joiner Wally Joiner</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		that should help their team
 	
 	
 		yeah it sounds like you keep up on <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> pretty well
 	
 	
 		no i have one of those uh minds that remembers trivia that's of completely useless
 	
 	
 		that what useless trivia
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i mean something important i can't remember but something about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> or football or something that really doesn't mean anything i can remember it's one of those
 		weird things i don't know why you know and i can't find my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> keys then but i can remember
 		you know something that
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> sports that's not even important
 	
 	
 		remember remember who <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX> signed but you can't find your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> keys
 	
 	
 		that's right or my glasses  yeah i know and and why why do i remember sports it's just one of those things i don't know why that if i can hear it on the radio and it just sinks in and
 	
 	
 		that
 		that's great
 		well that's great i've never i've never had a decent conversation with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> about baseball
 	
 	
 		well
 		well that's that's a yeah oh that's that's embarrassing almost but no i could probably name them almost the starting lineup for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		until until now
 		
 
 		
 		
 	