
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		about the weather  uh
 	
 	
 		oh yes uh very appropriate i guess
 		uh you ready for this
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay John</ENAMEX> just a moment
 		
 
 		well guess what we get to talk about the weather  uh
 	
 	
 		the weather is uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of year</TIMEX> has actually been kind of unusual i've expected it to be colder until you know what we've gotten <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last couple days</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know i i fly for a living and i've uh the weather's been terribly unusual every where i've been
 	
 	
 		oh you do so you you you probably go everywhere and have all sorts of weather and imagine it's kind of an experience also trying to land and take off in the weather
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 		that way it was around here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> i'll tell you that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well actually i'm i've i've heard on the news that we uh will be setting a  record here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> for the uh large amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> and moisture we've had this year
 		that it's gonna break all kind of records that were set set set back since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteen thirty two</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no kidding
 	
 	
 		so yeah  if it uh keeps on raining like this and i understand it's supposed to rain until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> they were saying yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yes so we're gonna
 	
 	
 		yeah i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> have been real strong out i went through uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice</NUMEX> on uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh shot approaches to low minimum it was both both times you know and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> never gets that kind of weather
 	
 	
 		wow
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well so are you an airline pilot
 	
 	
 		yes i am with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> yeah yep
 	
 	
 		oh great
 		with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> fantastic i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> also with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		yes and so i imagine you uh
 		oh with all this kind of weather it's uh makes it kind of dangerous for you
 	
 	
 		well now i no i wouldn't call it danger this is uh this really isn't bad stuff to fly around in this is much better than dealing with the thunderstorms in the springtime
 	
 	
 		oh i guess so yeah
 	
 	
 		you know the the the air systems are reasonably calm you don't have uh the turbulence you know you little bit of chop but it's not like it is in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yes well we moved actually down here from another location and it's spectacular the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the thunderstorms</TIMEX> and rain storms you get in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> time the torrents of rain
 	
 	
 		so
 		
 
 		spectacular is the right word for them
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 	
 	
 		spectacular is a good word for them
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i've never seen a thunder show like i've seen down here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">before</TIMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's amazing
 	
 	
 		lights up the whole sky and even on a on a actually i've i've seen it where there's not a cloud in the sky it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a cloudless night</TIMEX>
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> isn't falling but you can see the thunder and lightning excuse me see the lightning going horizontally across the sky and and back and forth and what a light show it's it's fabulous
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 		yeah cloud to cloud it can be real really sensational here
 	
 	
 		yes yes that's true
 	
 	
 		yeah really where you from originally
 	
 	
 		i'm from uh northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and that's a very arid climate from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there's always a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> in fact where i grew up we were <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX>'s drive from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> to uh twelve different major ski resorts
 		and so there was an awful lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> and because it was an arid climate the snow was always a crisp powder light snow
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		which made it fantastic for skiing and
 		and sleigh riding and everything else so we had a great time and
 	
 	
 		oh oh yeah yeah
 		were you near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Park</ENAMEX> they were near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Cities</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's beautiful area
 	
 	
 		in a
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Snowbird</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solitude</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brighton</ENAMEX> and yes all those areas so i imagine have you skied before
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well we've skied i have not skied that area i've driven through it several times uh i've skied we skied <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> a bunch when we lived out there and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh um and of course grew we grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> and we do some skiing there
 	
 	
 		oh yes oh yes
 	
 	
 		lot of cross country skiing there
 	
 	
 		yeah great well do you think this the the weather is typical for this time of the year
 	
 	
 		well not really i you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>'s gotten just hammered with snow um the uh the um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh we've getting a fair amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of year</TIMEX> already i i think and uh i've been surprised that we haven't seen more of the temperatures that we've got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you know that moved in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes yeah
 		yeah it's been it's been cold there was a time though in the uh middle part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> that got really cool really really unseasonably cool
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes it did
 	
 	
 		and then it warmed right back up and i thought great  and that's
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		that's a fun thing yeah uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was just listening here and she said yeah it froze in fact
 	
 	
 		yeah it was it was real cold that was that was very unseasonable for us down here
 	
 	
 		and uh but uh i've really enjoyed the weather down here too because uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> we were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> able to go out in shorts and play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX> in the nice sunny weather weather
 		and it's not as severe i should say as the weather that i've experienced up in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah that's that's real true same with us from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> it's it's uh in fact i've i played golf on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the New Year's Day one year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		down here
 	
 	
 		you know it was yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no no no
 	
 	
 		i have a brother-in-law that lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> and they say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> out of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> it's bitter cold and
 	
 	
 		oh it is it is
 	
 	
 		and the wind and the blowing snow and everything it's
 	
 	
 		well and they've had uh you know usually in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> they get their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> and uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're up over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty five or sixty</TIMEX>
 		
 		
 	