
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay well you you start it
 	
 	
 		well i feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have in the roles that they've played they've uh they used to be at home all the time with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and now most of them work out of the home because it takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> incomes to make it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> and um they just uh they there's more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> now and they've learned that they have to take care of themselves that they can't depend on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to support them now
 		
  
 	
 	
 		sure unfortunately what that's done is it's put everybody in a terrible position because it used to be that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> could work whether it a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> or a woman
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		okay now we're in a situation where uh it or at least it seems that maybe it's the economy or maybe it's just uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> taking advantage of the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> want to work
 		and now that they've made it or at least seems that like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to work in order to uh
 		in order to afford to live you know but uh i think it's it's great i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> works uh
 	
 	
 		makes end meet uh-huh
 		well it's really too bad they and because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are so underpaid and there're so many sole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah it's true it's true what they say like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> get sixty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven cents</NUMEX> to the dollar
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> make doing the same job that's that's terrible
 		but i i think that'll change too
 	
 	
 		well see in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my days</TIMEX> when i was a teenager my i wanted to go to school my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> said well she didn't want to send me to school i was going to get married anyway she said
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that meant that i was going to get married and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was going to work and take care of me but you don't think that way now
 	
 	
 		no that's why now every every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> i know works uh even my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who didn't work for a while is back working now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		except with the few exceptions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are unemployed which is unfortunate lately um every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> i know works my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> took some time off after we had our uh child our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but even that she's planned on getting work which good for her is she works in a  profession that she could get work at home
 		so she's going to
 	
 	
 		oh well that's good that's really good
 	
 	
 		so we don't have to do the
 		yeah she's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> so she gets to do that and my sister
 	
 	
 		she's a what
 	
 	
 		an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like in publishing yeah
 	
 	
 		oh that's really good she can do that at home
 	
 	
 		
 
 		she could do that at home so that's good
 	
 	
 		yeah i wish they could come up with more jobs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to stay home with their younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's the dilemma unfortunately unfortunately unfortunately my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is in a profession that is uh relatively high amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in in publishing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and it just so happens or maybe doesn't so happen that it's not a very high paying field
 		now maybe that's because there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in it like you're saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are underpaid uh the amount of money that she was making didn't didn't make it worth her while to uh you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 		pay a babysitter and
 	
 	
 		not be home pay for a babysitter or day care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know say that and and on top of the fact that
 	
 	
 		um-hum plus the clothing she has to have to wear
 	
 	
 		sure sure that on top of the fact that that uh
 		uh she can do some work at home that that it makes it makes it a perfect fit but
 	
 	
 		well that may be a thing for the future the computers now that they're trying to stress that for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to
 	
 	
 		yeah or to have
 	
 	
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can stay home and work on computers
 	
 	
 		or or have day care at the work place one or the other
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but unfortunate it's like that's not doing too well i know a lot of lot of lot of times it's the opposite though a lot of times
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> stay home and the women <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> go to work
 		which i think is good if you're not breast feeding
 	
 	
 		that's not i haven't found anybody like that i've heard of that but i haven't met anyone like that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		no i i i've known a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i've read uh about others you know just like articles and stuff about other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doing it i certainly would do it uh i have no problem with that unfortunately i'm paid a lot more than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> so it wouldn't be worth it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but i
 	
 	
 		well how do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s roles are going to change in the future
 	
 	
 		um
 		well i think as as time as time goes on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> will um
 		definitely have a better better better role in the work place i think that you know the first wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the work place in any substantial degree was in you know like in the seventies and eighties
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> take on um roles of uh more importance in in jobs and and also again not to sounds
 		i don't want to sound like
 		you know like i like i think it's hard but i mean a lot of times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were given jobs because they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> you know and i think once once it evens out so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> get the jobs that they deserve and get the pay that they deserve which will often be
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		powerful positions where there will be less discrimination in hiring when they hopefully when they hire
 	
 	
 		well see i
 		in the past i could understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> got paid more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> because they were the they called them the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> winners and they'd support the whole family
 	
 	
 		you know
 		yeah but that's
 	
 	
 		but that's not the case now
 	
 	
 		that's why not the case
 	
 	
 		so i that's why i don't think that they should get paid more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> if they're
 	
 	
 		sudden
 	
 	
 		doing the same job
 	
 	
 		why would it be fair earlier i mean you know
 		
 		
 	