
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		in in light the light of what has been happening lately with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> that i know and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and whatnot
 		i think national health insurance is a way to throw a lot of money at a very small problem
 	
 	
 		do you why
 	
 	
 		why well if you took half the money that they would spend in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> for health insurance and gave it to qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to so they could become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> the problem would go away
 	
 	
 		you think the problem is not enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think the problem is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor  doctors</ENAMEX> have conspired to limit the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>
 		and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have conspired to make sure that if you are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> you are going to pay high premiums on your health uh unemployment i mean on your liability
 	
 	
 		gosh i really have a different point of view on this  well because i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> for one thing
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and you think there are plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i don't think there is a shortage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and i do know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OB</ENAMEX> which is my field the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' health insurance the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' malpractice insurance is over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it's astronomical
 	
 	
 		that deliver <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> now they can't doing anything about that i don't think they're in a conspiracy i think it's our fault because we as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just sue them
 	
 	
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't sue
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are very sue sue conscious
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> sue if you put a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten thousand</NUMEX> dollar cap on the amount of money that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> could make from a law suit against a doctor
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they wouldn't sue a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them
 	
 	
 		well that's probably true too
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are very conscious of how much money they can get real fast these days
 	
 	
 		well sure but you know when you think about reasonableness now i believe that a law suit should have some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> in the the tort theory you know what tort theory is
 	
 	
 		and so
 		no
 	
 	
 		well a tort is when you do something wrong
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		well it uh an OBGYN <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> cannot control the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> in the womb <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> is born dead well that happens if if they have complications and
 	
 	
 		well
 		it depends
 	
 	
 		well i know i mean there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that are real slobs but you know there are also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there that are really doing their job
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are really doing their job are paying for everybody else
 	
 	
 		well that's true they are because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> are performing many more tests many of them are unnecessary they are doing so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> sections
 	
 	
 		you know
 		
 
 		just to prevent a a law suit
 	
 	
 		just to prevent because they have all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitors</ENAMEX> now and if anything looks even a little bit funny
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		their only safety precaution is to go in and get that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> and so it's costing more all around in health insurance for tests for surgery for longer hospital stay so it's terrible
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		see i believe that there there is a system already in place
 		for health care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they have indigent health care you show up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parkland</ENAMEX> bleeding and they'll fix you
 	
 	
 		you'll get it that's true
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		in fact you'll get it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presbyterian</ENAMEX> if you show up there too and we have that happen we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> that go through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parkland</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> and at the last minute they come to us well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we can't turn them away
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that if you just wrote the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> out of the equation
 		the problem would pretty much evaporate
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i'm for that i've been through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a two year</TIMEX> divorce where the only one that came out ahead was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> so i'd like to wipe them all out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i i happen to know a few and i even claim one as a friend
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he's a divorce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">attorney</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he better not be mine
 	
 	
 		but
 		
 
 		i think he'll go nameless for the for the purposes of this conversation but i also know an uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OBGYN</ENAMEX> who has stopped practicing
 	
 	
 		yeah some they do
 	
 	
 		uh he just said
 	
 	
 		they stop their OB at least
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean he's not going to deliver any more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> ever his malpractice was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		right right
 		that's incredible
 	
 	
 		and you know he said i had to he had to earn gross <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two million</NUMEX> to take home as much as his malpractice
 	
 	
 		yeah and most of them are very sincere most of them do the best they can they are human occasionally
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 		this this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		something will go wrong
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean you know
 	
 	
 		well you can be human and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i know you can be human and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> but you're not likely to find somebody who is going to you know have a less conscientious effort i mean
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah no most of them do i really believe that from dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> there is no doubt in my mind who is more conscientious
 		but
 	
 	
 		well you know who is getting rich
 		insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah they are
 	
 	
 		you know if you were able to write a malpractice insurance that would
 		negate any financial obligation on the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> over and above the insurance
 		say say you have malpractice insurance and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> dies or is malformed or
 		
 		
 	