
 
     		
 	
 		where you calling from
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		okay well we're pretty close then
 	
 	
 		i've never talked to anyone who's not from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> yet have
 	
 	
 		well you know i've been pretty lucky i've called sometimes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> before i go to my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and i've i've talked to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> i talked to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and i talked to uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> or somewhere
 	
 	
 		obviously i'm not calling often enough
 	
 	
 		so anyway our topic was movies
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i can handle that one
 	
 	
 		yeah i can i'm a movie buff i can too i'm a a junk movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watcher</ENAMEX> so but i see them all i see the junk ones by myself and i see the good ones with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>  i go see all the shoot them up bang bangs
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 	
 	
 		all the uh strong <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> rated and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i go see the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Girls</ENAMEX> and the good ones
 	
 	
 		well i'm ready if you are
 	
 	
 		what kind movies you like
 	
 	
 		um oh you pressed one already i'm sorry okay um
 	
 	
 		yes i'm sorry course
 	
 	
 		i like most everything i'm quite fond of horror movies and science fiction uh-huh
 	
 	
 		oh are you okay so am i
 	
 	
 		um what about you
 	
 	
 		well i sort of well like i like them all but i'm a you know i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> type uh mystery dramatic types
 		we saw did you have you all have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cape</ENAMEX> Fear
 	
 	
 		no but it's on my list of things to see i haven't as a matter of fact i haven't seen whole lot in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last month or so</TIMEX> but did you like it
 	
 	
 		have you okay
 		yes that's tremendous that'll  that'll be equivalent to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Silence of the Lambs</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		oh did you i assume you saw that one yes i really enjoyed it i'd read the book and i thought they stayed very faithful
 	
 	
 		yes that was great
 		they did yes yes it was a great movie
 	
 	
 		did you see the original <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cape Fear</ENAMEX> before you went to see the new version
 	
 	
 		no i didn't no i missed that one
 	
 	
 		i thought i might rent that um
 	
 	
 		that might be a neat idea
 	
 	
 		uh well i'll tell you something that we just saw recently that is old old but i'd never seen was Fantasia
 	
 	
 		yeah bet that was good
 	
 	
 		it was not what i expected it to be
 	
 	
 		oh no it's a tremendous movie
 	
 	
 		it was but i mean i can understand that little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> wouldn't find it um particularly appealing  it'd be way over their heads i think
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i've seen it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times it's such a a great movie
 	
 	
 		and the music is wonderful
 	
 	
 		yes they uh everyone my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and all of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher friends</ENAMEX> are saying we need to go see Beauty and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Beast</ENAMEX> they say that's quite a nice movie
 	
 	
 		i wouldn't mind seeing that well actually we kind of like going to see things like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bambi</ENAMEX> and such too so Beauty and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Beast</ENAMEX> would be okay with me
 	
 	
 		right
 		you bet we seen them all you see i'm such a movie buff i go out i'm self-employed so a lot of times i'll just uh
 		i just have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> office myself and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> and i'll just uh go out for lunch at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> sometimes go to a movie and come back at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that kind of a thing
 	
 	
 		so how often a week do you go
 	
 	
 		oh i probably average at least
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> times a week
 	
 	
 		yeah see you're pretty you're pretty movie buffy i'd do that if i could
 	
 	
 		oh i enjoy it yeah i enjoy it a lot of times uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> will have to stayed after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> till <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and i'll just uh leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and go to a movie and come home at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and i'll be here when she gets here
 	
 	
 		have you seen the new <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i'm a will see that though
 	
 	
 		that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hook</ENAMEX> looks like uh it would be good
 	
 	
 		Hook does look like it'll be good
 	
 	
 		and let's see what else is out new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> that
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Girl</ENAMEX> and that was a good little uh that was a good little movie
 	
 	
 		it's supposed to be cute i heard it got pretty good reviews
 	
 	
 		yeah it was cute
 	
 	
 		um i was  we were a little disappointed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Alone</ENAMEX> which we just saw we kind of catch them sometimes when they come around on videos
 	
 	
 		sure you bet
 	
 	
 		and uh i don't know maybe we just weren't in the mood but
 	
 	
 		yeah that was a little that was a little slapstick you know yes but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Girl</ENAMEX> will sort of it'll bring a little tear to your eyes or something it was cute movie
 	
 	
 		kind of
 		well that's all right a lot of them do
 	
 	
 		oh i understand
 		we uh yeah we see quite a few our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> are moviegoers and
 		future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> they're all moviegoers so we've we just all go to movies
 	
 	
 		it's good entertainment especially if you go you know before the uh when the bargain matinees are
 	
 	
 		oh i think so too
 		absolutely that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i do on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fridays</TIMEX> you know we uh meet at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five thirty</TIMEX> and uh go to the movie and then go out and go to dinner somewhere then come home
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well particularly if you see something that isn't very good you hate having wasted your <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven dollars</NUMEX> each or whatever it's up to
 	
 	
 		you bet well it's expensive to go to a movie i'll tell you
 	
 	
 		well it is particularly when you buy popcorn and everything
 	
 	
 		oh i know because we take uh so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i take my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and her intended to the movie you're talking uh between tickets and popcorn and everything probably forty bucks
 	
 	
 		i'm sure i'm sure
 	
 	
 		because we go we go visit them <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock Texas</ENAMEX> that's where they're at going to school and there's nothing to do in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock Texas</ENAMEX> but go to the movie  and you better do it before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine o'clock</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh that's the last show huh
 	
 	
 		right  but anyway we uh yeah we really enjoy it but trying think of another good movie i've seen lately uh
 		oh
 		i don't know i missed
 		
 		
 	