
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay but you said you saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> did you see it also
 	
 	
 		yeah i sure did of course i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>  as are a lot of women
 	
 	
 		well i
 		i saw i guess i've seen all of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>'s movies so far
 	
 	
 		yeah have you are you planning to see the his new one the JFK
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well probably i want to see what the reviews look like
 	
 	
 		yeah i usually wait for the reviews too although sometimes i've gone and i disagree
 		you know with them not usually the paper as much as the ones on radio and TV i don't always agree with them
 	
 	
 		well sometimes it's a matter of what the movie is about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		even if it doesn't get a good review if it's something i'm interested in i'll probably go see it anyway
 	
 	
 		oh like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on the uh i think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KRLD</ENAMEX> that reviews movies gave uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> the new movie uh like a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four or five</TIMEX>
 		and i was surprised because everyone that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> that i know that has seen it just loved it
 	
 	
 		well i've i've read some reviews  on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> and was planning to see it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> has a review today
 		and it says basically that uh that this is probably just about the best one that they've ever done
 	
 	
 		um-hum so don't you think again it's a matter of opinion
 	
 	
 		sure it finishes by if this is indeed the final voyage of the original crew <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> is a worthy valediction
 	
 	
 		uh i don't like always to listen to what someone else says uh because i think sometimes they just don't happen to or if you know if you're real tired sometimes something doesn't appeal to you
 	
 	
 		well that that can be the case or it can get a great review and be something that i'm not interested in then i'm not going to see it
 	
 	
 		that's right i've seen a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> like that uh you haven't seen <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cape</ENAMEX> Fear yet
 	
 	
 		no i've been reading all the reviews about it but i've never seen it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh it is very very frightening i mean i think it's more so than Silence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lambs</ENAMEX> it's a little bit like that did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silence</ENAMEX> of the Lambs
 	
 	
 		no but i read all about it too
 	
 	
 		yeah well it was pretty gory and so was <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cape Fear</ENAMEX> real kind of gruesome
 		but you know that's kind of like when is he going to die and probably never
 	
 	
 		well
 		this movie Hook is getting interesting reviews some are saying that it too sweet uh  just because they spent so much money on it and it's got such well-known stars i'm thinking about seeing it
 	
 	
 		which one is that
 	
 	
 		it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hook</ENAMEX> it's
 	
 	
 		Hook yes again i've heard mixed reviews on that you know i think this morning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KRLD</ENAMEX> had a gave it a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a six</NUMEX> or something which for him is probably pretty good
 	
 	
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> suggested that it's perhaps too sweet a movie and and that the action sequences might not be as good as other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s movies but it might not be bad overall
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i guess there'll never be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">another ET</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		i know that was a classic and i'm glad they didn't try to follow up with a sequel sometimes it ruins it
 	
 	
 		well no <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET ET ET</TIMEX> is going is is to stood as an instant classic
 	
 	
 		well i think so uh it was on what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and i watched it again have you seen The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butcher</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no that's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Demi Moore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i've been reading about it but i wasn't all that interested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX> well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Daniels</ENAMEX> is in that too isn't he but i i wasn't interested
 	
 	
 		um-hum he does put in a real good the it's a real lighthearted movie if you're uh in the mood to see something just kind of lighthearted you would like it isn't a real thoughtful picture
 		just kind of fun fun you know once in a while it's nice to just go see something that's just lighthearted and fun
 	
 	
 		well sometimes there <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kind of movies i like to see the ones on the big screen like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> where you really have to see them on big screen and then the others like say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Butcher</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wife</ENAMEX> that are interesting but you can rent them later and watch them on TV without any harm
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		by watching on video
 	
 	
 		that's true you know and you have to start thinking about is it is it worth spending the money to go see it or shall i just wait
 	
 	
 		well you know <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Wars Star Trek</ENAMEX> those kind of movies you've got to see them on big screen or else they lose their effect
 	
 	
 		um-hum they really do and i've never been a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> but i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> that wouldn't miss a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> movie
 	
 	
 		well i i've enjoyed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> but i got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fanatics</ENAMEX> i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who took off work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> just to be sure to be in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> group to see it well i'll see i'll see it eventually but i'm not going take the rush
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		well and sometimes you know you miss all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> if you don't have to go <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the very first day</TIMEX> it opens
 	
 	
 		no i i i think it'll still be playing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think so i don't think you need to be one of the first uh do you belong to any of the fan clubs uh you know the
 	
 	
 		oh no no i'm i'm just it's just interesting to watch
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		although there's a big story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> today a debate between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> one saying the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> was best and one saying that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> was best but uh you know the debate goes on i suppose
 	
 	
 		yes well it'd be interesting to hear why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think that
 		
 		
 	