
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucille Hughes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Lucille</ENAMEX> i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Ron Moore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all right and what did
 	
 	
 		and our topic okay our topic was did you hear our topic all right basketball i guess i'm probably a lot like you i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Maverick fan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i certainly am too now tell me what you expect from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavericks</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well unfortunately unfortunately i don't expect a great deal out of them they just have too many problems too many ailments too many hurt bones and maybe too much age at this point
 		you know when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Tarpley</ENAMEX> just now he messed up on them it just hurt them so bad i feel like everyone else i feel sorry for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Carter</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and everyone else it just seems like
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		they were just getting themselves in a position where they could possibly be a a final a final <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> playing for for all of it national championship or the world championship and something like this happens
 	
 	
 		yes yes sir
 		ah well do you think it's time that we go for new uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> is that part of our problem
 	
 	
 		yeah i think at this time we're just in a a rebuilding type of phase you know i think
 		that probably would be evident with the more and more the more and more young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> they draft
 	
 	
 		well it just it's it's it's so discouraging that they can't really i mean they're entitled to more than they've been able to do so far
 		i i'm awfully sorry that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavericks</ENAMEX> can't come on and and do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX> who's your next best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> or who do you like after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavericks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh gosh i'm so much of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magerick Maverick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> i don't know probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Celtics</ENAMEX> i've just always liked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Celtics</ENAMEX> they have a
 		they have a similar situation now that a lot of uh old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and but they're still playing good ball but i'm a i've always been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Celtic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> too but
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		you know i've lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy four so</TIMEX> being a transplanted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area i have to stick with those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Mavericks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we certainly need to support them do we not do you go to the game
 	
 	
 		yes we do you know
 		yes i go to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few</NUMEX> games i haven't been to many i'm not a season ticket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> or anything i was a season ticket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> got to a certain age and went off to school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and doing their own thing sort of gets boring going by yourself
 	
 	
 		yes it does i'm sure it would it's such a monstrous place down there but um maybe next maybe they can do some i don't know who do they need to trade
 	
 	
 		oh you bet
 		well i don't know it seems like  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolando Blackman</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX> sort of carry the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> they just
 		i don't know if i'm afraid to say that's probably who they need to trade to get someone in there good but and that can really help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> but they do that they trade the nucleus of their power right now
 	
 	
 		yes sir it seems that way to me i course i don't know any of the newer ones that they have and i'm not well of versed on their capabilities but we really need to do something
 	
 	
 		well you know i feel like uh the best they can hope for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is probably ah an opportunity to make the play-offs i like their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> i really like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richie</ENAMEX> a lot
 		and i just i think he deserves a good break he deserves a healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> so they can really see what he can do for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Carter</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> i think with all he's invested he deserves a
 		a healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> and a good break also this thing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Tarpley</ENAMEX> it just upset everyone i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans owners management</ENAMEX> everyone
 	
 	
 		i really
 		yes sir
 		and they have just done as much as they can for that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and he apparently can't straighten his act out so we need to to build on something more positive than that
 	
 	
 		you bet i think they're fools if they ever bring him back
 	
 	
 		oh i do too i certainly would agree to that
 	
 	
 		hate to put it that way i just would not believe him anymore
 	
 	
 		well it um i mean you can't give  anyone too many chances  and i think he has gone over the limit
 	
 	
 		no
 		there's an old saying you can lead you can lead a horse to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> but you can't make him drink so and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarpley</ENAMEX>'s just a sad case but to be making ah <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> that's pretty sad
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		well
 		it is tragic i don't um i mean we're gonna have to do something about all of these fabulous salaries they're paying to all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		oh i think you're right everything just been put out of perspective now you know you take a a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Tarpley</ENAMEX>'s age i'd say he was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty one</TIMEX> when he came into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> and and now he's probably an old age of uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five or six</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it
 		yes sir
 	
 	
 		and making all that money well that's uh that's quite a that's a little more of a challenge for a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> than they they need at that point in their life i think
 	
 	
 		i think you're right i believe that one so
 	
 	
 		so
 		so i think you know it's created by
 		
 		
 	