
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh what topic would you like to discuss political topic
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know i guess the thing that's on my mind lately is these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> that have been released  so i can't imagine how it would've been to been incarcerated incarcerated for that length of time
 	
 	
 		well i think it's marvelous they finally figured a way to get them out of there huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm not sure what it ever  what it really accomplished having them uh locked up for that long did the uh did their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captors</ENAMEX> ever really say this is why we're holding them and
 	
 	
 		well what they wanted of course was uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> money and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> the release of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> held by the
 		Israels
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> and uh i guess they're gonna get a lot of those released and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		i understand there's uh what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> or even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		probably a lot i probably a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah  what's uh what's been pressing you lately
 	
 	
 		well i think the developments in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> are rather interesting
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm not real sure how they're gonna all turn out i hope they turn out positively and not turn into chaos but
 	
 	
 		well does it sound like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> definitely out of a job to you
 		
 
 	
 	
 		certainly sounds that way doesn't it
 	
 	
 		looks looks that way uh i'm a little disappointed and i and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		well he's won a peace prize and uh
 	
 	
 		well i think that's one of the
 		problems being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Nice Guy</ENAMEX> and i think that's what he was and is you know i i think he tried to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		accommodate  too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh and in a structure like that apparently it's a difficult if not impossible task i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and whether we like it or not when
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USSR</ENAMEX> was together the peace was kept in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> relatively speaking
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh there might be a big void there and i uh it's certainly a
 	
 	
 		well
 		
 
 	
 	
 		fence sitting situation i i i hope it's not a
 		i hope it gets resolved properly let's put that way
 	
 	
 		yeah  well it's gonna be interesting see what happens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX> there
 	
 	
 		with all those nuclear weapons floating around you get uh
 		get the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> there i think we could have major problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i don't necessarily mean we in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> alone but the world
 	
 	
 		i'm curious what uh what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> think of their neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and uh recent uh gubernatorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> there with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Duke</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how was the what was the press like in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> over that issue
 	
 	
 		well of course there's a number of rednecks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that i'm sure would jump on his band <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i'm sure the vast vast majority would
 		think it of him as he probably is
 	
 	
 		um-hum i it's remarkable that he can uh i think that he can get this far as he's gotten  with uh
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		you know the kind of background he's got and i'm i'm just surprised that he has uh
 		seems like that'd be something that be so controversial that it pretty well exclude himself from any political office
 	
 	
 		well i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> is not the nation
 		certainly still has many racist type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that uh would jump on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> wagon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		being a springer splinter operation i'm sure it wouldn't you know it it raises a lot of noise and everything but i don't think it would probably go very far in a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		overall scope of things
 	
 	
 		well i think we're a little isolated where i live here we just don't have many uh
 		many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> to speak of uh you know probably less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> of the population i would guess
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		we have a fair  a fair amount of uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> and um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX>
 		not too many blacks
 	
 	
 		well well i think it's a i grew up in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think uh you know it's definitely a different philosophy of how you look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> up <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX> as you do in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know it i growing up uh
 		where i grew up in our high school you had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> black that was from out of the area to start with and you know we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in our high school so
 	
 	
 		that was the extent of it huh
 	
 	
 		we weren't really you know even you know when we played football against a couple black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and you know that part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> uh
 		you know they were nothing you know i mean now now it's all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and basketball
 	
 	
 		i'll say there's they sure dominate the pro sports don't they and well and collegiate too so
 	
 	
 		so i
 		i don't i don't know what uh you know times have changed but
 		i i think that's one of the reasons the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Packers</ENAMEX> will always have problems having a
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		getting back to the status they were during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lombardi</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Green Bay</ENAMEX> being an extremely small town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">sixty thousand fifty five thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	