
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Jerry</ENAMEX> the uh topic was favorite TV shows and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what kind are you interested in and how they and do they differ from like mine
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well okay uh most of most of the uh commercial television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> i'm just a little bit sick of
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh in fact i don't watch hardly any uh television at all with uh my other activities uh
 		between my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and my church <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et cetera et</ENAMEX> cetera why i don't have any time uh hardly any time to sit down and watch the news now i do watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discovery Channel</ENAMEX> and some on channel thirteen but aside from
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh do you yeah
 	
 	
 		aside from that i pretty well uh turn it off
 	
 	
 		oh i'm sort of a well i'm different from that i'm sort of a a movie buff i go to a  <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of</TIMEX> movies movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> sometimes quite honestly i'm i'm self-employed and a lot of times i will uh go out and take
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch hour</TIMEX> and go to lunch from like twelve to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and go to a movie and just come back to my office
 	
 	
 		i don't blame you
 	
 	
 		but uh i do it it's like entertainment i'm pretty much of a a junk movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watcher</ENAMEX> by myself if i take my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> then we see something a little nicer you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are all sort of movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> you know we've we've always been to a lot of we've always gone to a lot of movies in our life
 		so but i would just as soon uh be doing something else it's just that
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are gone now and
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s a school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and sometimes  she doesn't get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about seven o'clock so</TIMEX> you know i'll come in like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five thirty or six</TIMEX> and i'll turn on the tube and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		set there and have my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> or whatever and a little TV and sometimes i set there all evening
 	
 	
 		yeah i i well if sometimes if if it's real good like there's more than been there's been more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one evening</TIMEX> that i've uh caught uh every <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> show <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that evening</TIMEX> on uh on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover Channel</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you bet you bet
 	
 	
 		and uh because they're uh
 		they're they're you you know they're documentaries and they're
 	
 	
 		well that's an interesting channel
 	
 	
 		oh you bet in fact i'm glad that it's part of our ah basic cable package
 	
 	
 		well that's great you know i've i've just never spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">any time</TIMEX> watching it and you know
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like my sports and everything but i
 	
 	
 		oh well me too hello with the
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i watched my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX> i watched them to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">halftime</TIMEX> before i left and i left at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">halftime</TIMEX> and started drinking driving
 	
 	
 		well they they whooped
 		they whooped up on them
 	
 	
 		they sure did they just did an excellent job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and they're in the play-offs and uh i'm not sure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> are or not
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> you have to laugh the luck into it now i think but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> they earned it on their own merit
 	
 	
 		i did
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		and you know everybody or not everybody but quite a few of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> were kind of down on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Johnson</ENAMEX> but uh
 		he's uh
 		he's brought the pokes uh from a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a one</NUMEX> and something <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to a play-offs in what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		you you bet as much as everyone you know and use the word love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Landry</ENAMEX> you know i'm glad that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Johnson</ENAMEX>'s there
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well it's uh you know it was a time for the passing of the guard i mean and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> knew it
 	
 	
 		it was
 		i think so too he wanted to go out a winner though i think he would've stayed there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five more years</TIMEX> so he could have gone out a winner
 	
 	
 		so um
 		yeah that's true and i wouldn't i wouldn't have blamed him one bit because
 	
 	
 		no no it's you know he earned those stripes
 	
 	
 		yeah but see nobody remembers him as a loser
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		because he's too he's too far he's far too much of a gentleman and a and a practicing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> to uh to ever be thought of as anything but a loser you know but a winner
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		you bet he's a he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> in anyone's book and i hope he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> in his own book you know because that that's the key there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh he is he is
 		because he has to like himself before he can like other people
 	
 	
 		you bet
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		little things that disturb me and i know he's being a little hard-nosed about it but uh you know this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> of honor thing you know he needs to be there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because he's earned it he deserves it and he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX> and he won't do that yet so i hope he makes up his mind to do it because
 	
 	
 		yes
 		oh he will
 	
 	
 		he needs to be remembered
 	
 	
 		right well nobody's gonna forget <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Landry</ENAMEX> shoot come now i mean i'm not a
 	
 	
 		no no no absolutely absolutely not oh that's true but he needs to be honored put it that way
 	
 	
 		betcha i'm i'm not a native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> by birth but uh i guess by uh length of length of time i've been the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> now is what after you're here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> you're considered a native
 	
 	
 		you bet i've been here since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy four um</TIMEX> and i feel like a native
 	
 	
 		well let's see i came down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March of sixty nine</TIMEX> went to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> and I yeah
 	
 	
 		oh did you yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh i haven't looked back yet either so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and we came we came down from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy four</TIMEX> and uh
 		never had any regrets at all
 	
 	
 		right especially looking at some of the weather <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> has had and then look at the weather we have down here huh
 	
 	
 		you bet it's been
 		it's been a great place to raise our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i've got my last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> graduating from college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this next December</TIMEX> she's getting married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month before</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> so i will have finished be finished  with that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh goodness
 		right well we're well we're finished with all but the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and trying to get him through his technical school
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh we're uh he's over halfway so
 	
 	
 		well good
 	
 	
 		you know we're not staying on the topic of television shows but i really not too very concerned are you
 	
 	
 		no not at all
 	
 	
 		no me neither i i'm i'm enjoying the chat uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well but i enjoy my TV programs i like those i like those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> programs i like everything i can watch watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cosby</ENAMEX> because i think he has a great show
 		
 		
 	