
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um tell me about where you live
 	
 	
 		i live in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just close to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richland College</ENAMEX> do you live in the area too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		although i did live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> for uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> up until uh nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> and then i i moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i uh had lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> before and uh from nineteen eighty to nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> and uh lived worked downtown
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when i was transferred from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> uh to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> i i bought a condo in southwest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no and i clocked it and it was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only nine miles</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and of course didn't think that would be bad uh but the only time i ever drove it was not during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">rush hour</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so so after it was a rude <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">awakening</ENAMEX> to me to find out what i faced every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> and every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> traffic because where i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> was i lived right on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peachtree</ENAMEX> um <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile and a half</NUMEX> from the office
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i wasn't accustomed to commuting and it nearly killed me so whenever i moved back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> i said i i declared that i would not live where i had to drive on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeways</ENAMEX> so now i live
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		in really inner city and uh but it's only it takes me about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> to get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and i love it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well what kind of a a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is it now are you still in a condo
 	
 	
 		well i'm in an apartment
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		but uh  it's just i don't know it's uh
 		i mean
 		most most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i work with you know commute in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">anywhere from</NUMEX>
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">thirty to forty five minutes</TIMEX> some of them an hour or more one way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know  i mean i've i've had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> before and i mean and it's nice but it's just not worth it to me to sit behind the wheel of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for that long
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i just i can't do it so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		anyway i'm very i'm i'm pretty content for the time being where i am
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh we um rent a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">duplex</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and it's only like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple of miles</NUMEX> from where i work it's a little bit further for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> we used to both work at the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and it was only like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two miles</NUMEX> from the uh duplex
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now he's moved but he's going against the flow of the traffic so it's not too bad of a commute it only takes him about fifteen minutes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that isn't that isn't bad really
 	
 	
 		no he can get on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> and  he's going north whereas most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> going south
 		so he's you know in a good situation because the traffic is not as heavy in his direction but we've been looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> but  the first consideration to us is location you know they keep building
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		further and further out and of course you can get more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for the money and stuff but you know to me i'm the same way <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> to day commute i don't like
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh you know it's like i said i i mean i've even had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> ask me they say how do you justify paying the kind of money you pay for rent because i do pay a lot of money <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> for rent i don't deny it
 		but at the same time i said well you know let's think about it  i said i drive um less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> miles a day round-trip
 		and they go you know they're jaws dropped and then and then they go and i spend way less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> a day
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		round-trip commuting and you know that doesn't that's regardless of the weather if it's raining it still doesn't take me any longer i mean sometimes whenever and you know how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> is it's just so flat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we have these torrential downpours sometimes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> literally get you know traffic gets backed up with the wrecks and everything and it'll take them <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half</TIMEX> to get to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're just frayed by the time they get there i think no way so
 	
 	
 		yeah and i think too now we both have little bit older <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> i mean both our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old</TIMEX> now if you get a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> if you buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> more for your money further out you're gonna have to have a pretty decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and put a lot into uh
 		your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> payments and your gas and stuff
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		i mean you know if you've got to drive it <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">sixty miles</NUMEX> a day you're gonna go through that car a heck of a lot faster than what we did i mean that's not something <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think about is the car the car payments and the gas
 	
 	
 		oh i agree with you a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> percent since i'm um  moved got this place i mean i used to i can remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> when i worked especially whenever i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> before i used to put twenty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousand miles</NUMEX> a year on my car
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i put less than twelve on my car
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know and you you can really tell a difference i mean i just don't you know it's just not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't have that expense and by the time i cut down the the cost of my insurance because my car insurance is a little bit less by living so close then the additional automobile expense
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know it's i i thought about it  it's i mean i would like to own again i've owned in the past but i don't know i'm i'm hesitant to give up the convenience
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		plus where i live is so well managed i mean if i have any little thing go wrong i just pick up the phone at the office i call my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> i said we got this problem i come home in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX> there's a note on my dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> table saying we've been in we fixed it let us know if there's a problem
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know i love it i'll be honest with you hey it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	