
 
     		
 	
 		say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Texas</ENAMEX> now since i got somebody from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Virginia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		
  
 		is that right yeah well i never thought about that but there is an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> like i i had a card <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham Michigan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh Birmingham
 	
 	
 		uh you know and i was thinking yeah and i was thinking the only Birmingham i could think of was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right it's funny how many names have been used uh all over the country
 	
 	
 		yeah well tell me what kind of books have you read
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		well to tell you the truth i've been going to college for the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> so mainly text books
 	
 	
 		i was gonna say not fun kind right
 	
 	
 		no um but i i really tend to like biographies a lot not necessarily always heavy ones but you know sometimes biographies i just read one about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grace Kelly</ENAMEX> i i love to read about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to me half the time it's more fascinating than some of these made up stories
 	
 	
 		yeah it is because you know that it's really and truly a the true thing you know i read one about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Hope</ENAMEX> that i liked
 	
 	
 		yeah it happened it happened
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah that was real good i'm like you if it's not a heavy biography you know i enjoy it
 	
 	
 		right
 		i used to like to read about royalty a lot i read when i was younger i read about every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> that lived  i think in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> that was my thing for a while
 	
 	
 		i'm trying to think uh i read a uh a novel  that used the names of like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Di</ENAMEX> and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Phillip</ENAMEX> coming over here to be entertained and all and there was a murder yeah it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sometime ago</TIMEX> seems like it was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Spy Went Dancing</ENAMEX> or something like that uh
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh it sounds like fun
 	
 	
 		it was a lot of fun because they used these real names you know
 	
 	
 		wonder if it was by one of those famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Truman Daniels</ENAMEX> writes a lot those
 	
 	
 		yes in fact i believe it was because uh-huh i believe it
 	
 	
 		really sounds like something she would write
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it was by her that you mention it because uh someone had given it to me and i thought well this will be great and it was
 	
 	
 		yeah i've heard heard that she's done real you know her books are really interesting and they always sell well
 	
 	
 		um-hum well when you use real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that i think you know and royalty especially you know
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		yeah brings it to life
 		i know uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> laugh at us because we're so enthralled with their royalty
 	
 	
 		yeah but you know that's like them being enthralled with our <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and so forth you know
 	
 	
 		i know our movie stars
 	
 	
 		our movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> because it's totally different concept to us
 	
 	
 		oh right
 	
 	
 		but i haven't i haven't had a chance to read a lot lately either i have read uh mostly novels i went to visit my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and i took a novel with me oh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and read it at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving time</TIMEX> and um
 		it was uh one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> novels you know starts out when they're small and continues through <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> and i like that you know
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		oh i always like those
 		have you ever read anything by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Howatch</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i have
 	
 	
 		isn't she fabulous
 	
 	
 		oh she is wonderful
 	
 	
 		oh once you start i don't like to get one of her books because i i just live to read i'll i'll skip everything just to get back to the book
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		i stayed up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> i think till <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two in the morning</TIMEX> finishing one of hers because i start i could not put it down
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		she's just uh i don't know does she how often does she come out with them i probably have missed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few</TIMEX> since i've been back in school
 	
 	
 		well no it seems like she doesn't write as often as oh well like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle Steele</ENAMEX> and those silly things she writes the same thing
 	
 	
 		oh well she can she can turn them out overnight i swear
 	
 	
 		yeah and and they're the same silly things i mean if you've read one there i mean it's you know it's
 	
 	
 		yeah i've never read a whole one of hers i don't think
 	
 	
 		it it's practically the same thing over and over you know
 	
 	
 		and think how rich she is
 	
 	
 		yeah wouldn't i you know i'm criticizing her and wouldn't i like to have her money
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know because they go from hardback to paperback and she has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of them um-hum
 	
 	
 		and then make movies out of some of them or
 	
 	
 		you know miniseries and so forth but i seems to me like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Howatch</ENAMEX> does not write as often i have not seen as many of hers
 	
 	
 		right
 		well hers are so involved and they're and so  such a higher intellectual level because she quotes a lot you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i think she does a lot of research too
 	
 	
 		i do too so she couldn't possibly turn them out like some of these popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> but oh her books are just incredible i don't think they've ever made a movie do you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		no i don't think so and i've often wondered why haven't you you know i
 	
 	
 		yes well no uh i really just thought about it now but there's just maybe it's because they take so much in i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum maybe they're just too involved for the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to go and sit through them you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		they're so big they're such you know it would be like another Gone with the Wind i guess <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a three hour</TIMEX> movie
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah well and maybe that turns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off but look at Gone with the Wind you know
 	
 	
 		oh i know it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> of my favorite movies
 	
 	
 		uh have you uh gotten into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Scarlett</ENAMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		no it had such a bad press i wasn't too intrigued
 	
 	
 		i yeah that's exactly what i was gonna say i was amazed because i in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning</TIMEX> when it was on you know  on route coming out i heard mixed publicity you know kind of good and bad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then when it came out all i heard was just uh how bad it was that i didn't even wanna get it
 	
 	
 		me either do you know anyone that's read it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i haven't heard of anybody that's read it either but it was i think it was on the best-seller list though for a while
 	
 	
 		no
 		well it wouldn't surprise me
 		
 		
 	