
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well what what what do you feel do you feel that that our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uh is it possible to have an honest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or do we have an honest
 	
 	
 		um
 		well i feel that for i feel there's a lot of shenanigans going on i feel there's a lot of crookedness in it but i do feel that for the most part
 		um our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is you know trying trying to make things work the best they can um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		well  uh i'm i'm i'm rather young i'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only twenty two</NUMEX> and so  uh my knowledge is based you know mostly on what i read you know in history
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i do think based on what i read uh what i've read through uh about about our history of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> i think things are getting better
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		uh in the in the last maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten or fifteen years</TIMEX> where
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are becoming a little more aware and uh are forcing our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to be uh on top of
 		integrity you know as an order
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right right i agree but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are demanding that
 		that those that aren't you know that aren't either morally or or politically or
 		going to do a good job that they're they're trying to get them out of it or at least they're taking a stand
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		against it so um
 		i know  a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i feel like they're all all real good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are trying their best to to provide a service to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		when you think that most of the most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
 		i'm i'm not really sure what the pay scales are and and how that that works but
 		um i don't agree with some of the ways that they they earn extra money on the side  you know i feel that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that that that needs to be changed and and they should have more accounting on the different ways that they
 		they earn their money have you ever ran for a public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> probably not yeah probably not being <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty two</TIMEX>  not yet um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> ran <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">time</TIMEX> here in uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		have i
 		no not yet huh-uh
 	
 	
 		our little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and he ran you know for the town <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we felt like it was a a real good experience i think that
 		um
 		you know when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are wanting to get involved to
 		to to make changes for the better in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that it's
 		that's it's a good thing so
 	
 	
 		right does it worry you that um  say someone like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Duke</ENAMEX> got such such publicity during uh during his campaign and that and that now he's running for uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		thinking of running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> does that worry you at all
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that does worry me  especially when with his background you know and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have already voted him down i i don't understand really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		really his reasons for doing that i don't
 	
 	
 		uh i i don't either
 	
 	
 		i don't know what he's
 	
 	
 		i hope he doesn't know something we  or i hope yeah hope he doesn't know something we don't
 	
 	
 		really
 		that's right yeah i was i'm interested in um
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is looking for a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> and we have had oh i think the number is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> already that are running for it and this is not until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> that have put you know their hat in in in the ring to run and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and i was surprised by that because it had seemed to me like there was almost getting to be that it was hard to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to run because of the reason that
 		you know they dredge up every single thing in your past
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean and not very many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to lay their their whole life on the line like that and say hey i you know i've never made any mistakes and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that would be a little bit frightening to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to be put in the public eye like that myself but we've had it here in the state a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are going to run for
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> and it seems like there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are starting to talk about running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know when when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is
 		when he's finished so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um what do you think about the different you know the different formats the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republican</ENAMEX> and democrat
 	
 	
 		well  uh
 	
 	
 		do you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are a good thing or do you think they need to be done away with or
 	
 	
 		i'm kind of disappointed that that uh the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> have such a stronghold in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> because if if if you belong to any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> uh you know any other platform i should say uh you you're not represented
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i don't i don't belong to any particular uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> and and i don't think i ever will but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm afraid that um
 		i think his name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> was the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX> who ran for uh on an independent ticket against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Carter</ENAMEX>  um i was real disappointed that uh uh that he didn't he didn't have a chance uh because he didn't have a platform behind him uh uh you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that's a little bit disconcerting you know where
 	
 	
 		right
 		it is
 	
 	
 		where uh where we really really <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> don't have a voice unless they participate within <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> systems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and especially where if if you don't completely agree with their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> if there's i mean there's not a lot of choice like you say and you have to have the financial support or there's just no hope and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i know that one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	