
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh one of my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> i'm i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so we probably been having relatively similar weather
 	
 	
 		yeah probably although i would imagine that i've had uh  uh
 	
 	
 		yeah uh although recently it's been fairly fairly humid uh
 	
 	
 		some warmer weather and and more humidity than  i think that's typically a little drier out there
 		has it really
 	
 	
 		yeah we
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> is a uh actually i have my uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> and it is one of my favorite locations it's just i i think it's beautiful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it's nice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i i
 	
 	
 		how long have you lived there
 	
 	
 		uh i guess about a little less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah practically a native
 	
 	
 		we have lots of non native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh how hot does it get there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> time
 	
 	
 		oh it it varies i mean occasionally it it it gets up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a hundred</NUMEX> but it's not uh
 		that's not really well i don't know i was going to say it wasn't not typical but i guess there is
 		quite a phase this quite a period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> that is was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> it stayed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a hundred</NUMEX> uh it mid to high nineties it's it's fairly typical uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> doesn't get quite as hot actually because the humidity
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah that's correct i mean being i think being a little closer to the uh  to the gulf we it has a moderating factor but again what we what we lack in the heat we make up for in the humidity i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the ocean
 		the gulf yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		the humidity
 		
 
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		before uh i was transfered  down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> in uh nineteen ninety
 		and uh  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> got hotter i mean temperature wise but i  you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> can get just as uncomfortable
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah well i
 	
 	
 		but
 		for some reason and and i guess it's uh
 		not having just the extreme heat i mean we had uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one one year</TIMEX> we had in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> or more where it never got
 		below of that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two or eighty three</NUMEX> degrees at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and then over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred every day</TIMEX> and that got to be awfully oppressive
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> and and uh south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">west Kansas</ENAMEX> which is extremely dry and it's the opposite but but i mean that real serene heat
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh and and and very cold in the winter uh but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> that i lived there i guess it was the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> yeah i believe so the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> that i lived there
 		it we had a streak of something like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty eight days</TIMEX> in a row <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a hundred</NUMEX> degrees
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh it just absolutely sounds absurd and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> it it it actually hit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred and fifteen</NUMEX> degrees in the shade
 	
 	
 		you know you know it makes you wonder how anyone ever lived before air conditioning
 	
 	
 		oh i know i know
 		well well that's uh
 	
 	
 		uh how much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> did you get in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well well that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">same year</TIMEX> that's when that's when i finally left is that  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that same year</TIMEX> we had this incredible cold spell and and i uh i uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh i mean it was like uh you know thirty degrees <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">below zero</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		yeah and and and i you know i had just bought a little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MGB</ENAMEX> that i was going to fix up and you know sand it down and get it all fixed up and i and i had never bothered to check the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antifreeze</ENAMEX> in it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		and uh you know here is this freezing day and i got my heaters up full blast trying to stay warm and
 		and the uh uh and all of the sudden it dawns me i mean it's like  one <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> clock in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
 		oh i wonder if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>'s got any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antifreeze</ENAMEX> in it  and of course it didn't uh
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		you know and so so i you know i tried to jump start it i couldn't get it in it still i mean had some it was slushing and uh i tried to start it i tried to jump start it i couldn't it didn't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumper</ENAMEX> cable ran to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and by the time i got back it had frozen out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		ran back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> got a can of sterno and you know was doing all kinds of stuff put blankets on the top of it i babied it all night it was fun
 	
 	
 		did you did you uh keep it going
 	
 	
 		it actually i mean the box froze but it didn't it didn't crack anything and i uh i left it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX> and we  called the tow truck and we hauled it over to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> put heaters on it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		warmed it up and i didn't keep it much longer after that but  but it it did uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and after that i decided i was going to go live some place where it was warm
 	
 	
 		well i have never lived anywhere uh  well the farthest north i've ever lived is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh North Carolina</ENAMEX> which is certainly you know not your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and snow country
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and it got you know reasonably cold up there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the in the winter time</TIMEX> but i have never lived anywhere where i really had to battle snow and uh i don't think i want to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well it's kind you know i i finally decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> is kind of a neat thing to visit
 		uh you know when you when you felt some ice cold all white white <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and some things like that it's a nice thing to go visit but it's not something that i want to live in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day in and day</TIMEX> out
 	
 	
 		yeah i had some i had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who lived in uh  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> and then they moved back south because they said you know it just  prospect of every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> having to get out shovel the driveway to get out and then shovel the driveway to get back in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and shovel it again the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">next morning</TIMEX> they said it just got to be too much
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		well you actually get kind of get used to it after a while i mean and and and in the cold really it doesn't get at you that much because you you of course you learn how to dress well and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> are well insulated and stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i actually i i moved from there to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> and and
 		
 		
 	