
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i don't know what kind of music you like but i went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Diamond</ENAMEX> concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i would've liked that
 	
 	
 		oh it was wonderful
 	
 	
 		oh i bet it was huh
 	
 	
 		it was really good really good music and it wasn't too loud and he was on a round stage so every seat in the arena was good
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well um um was it a lot of his old songs
 	
 	
 		yes he did sing some of his old songs and his new songs and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he has a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> he has like a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or twelve piece band sounds like an orchestra
 	
 	
 		oh does he
 		oh huh i would've really liked that yeah
 	
 	
 		it's really good
 		and he had a laser <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam</ENAMEX> show with it you know the the lights shined up to ceiling and like laser beams and
 	
 	
 		oh did he
 	
 	
 		then he had that dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		that makes it look like he's standing in the clouds and
 	
 	
 		oh well i have seen him before but yeah it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh have you oh see i hadn't seen him before
 	
 	
 		it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> i saw him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> once yeah a long long time ago but um yeah we just we went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenny Loggin</ENAMEX>'s concert
 	
 	
 		oh
 		he's a country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		well he's he's rock but um yeah he is really more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that it's
 	
 	
 		oh is he rock
 		i know i've
 		a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> you uh you i hear the songs and i say oh yes i know that song but it's hard to remember their names and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the name sounds familiar i'm sure if i heard some of his music i would know
 	
 	
 		well he he sings <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Footloose</ENAMEX> from the the movie do you you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Footloose</ENAMEX> that song
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh i see okay okay yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah he sang that and yeah but um and that was good it was loud though it was in a real small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> and it was very loud
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 		when i went to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> it with the music was so loud the whole building trembled and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you couldn't talk to the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> sitting next to you you'd yell at them scream at them and they still wouldn't hear you it was that loud
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh i don't enjoy it that loud
 	
 	
 		they put on a good concert but it was just too loud
 	
 	
 		uh-huh huh well do you like the instrumentalists like have you ever ever heard Fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Aire</ENAMEX> or
 		um well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mannheim Steamroller</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i'm just not up on that stuff
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh they're well they're it's all they're instrumental and um
 	
 	
 		i love instrumentals
 	
 	
 		yeah but they're real good they i know they were here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> we didn't make it they they're here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this December</TIMEX> but we didn't make it to that
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i i tend to like the more mellow my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> likes uh harder loud  but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		me too i'm an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>  i like the more toned down things
 	
 	
 		i
 		
 
 		well i'm starting to sound like my mom
 	
 	
 		me too
 	
 	
 		i remember her telling us oh turn that off i can't stand that and i'm kind of i'm like that with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> now turn that down
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah me too my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s uh-huh
 		yeah that's the way my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> she'd say oh that's making me nervous turn that down or turn that off uh-huh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh i don't even know what uh i i have younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and so i don't know they talk about these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> nowadays and i don't even know who they're talking about
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's the way my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> did when they were growing up
 	
 	
 		are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> all grown oh
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh they're grown have their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah and they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> i i didn't know what music music they were talking about the groups
 	
 	
 		yeah well i know they talk about um all these rappers now do you like the rap
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sometimes
 	
 	
 		yeah some of it's kind of fun but well it's just different  oh oh well have you seen any others or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		no i haven't i was just really i felt really lucky to go see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Diamond</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> gave me a free ticket to go as a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> gift so
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		so i felt really lucky to go see him
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh did you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		did you go with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		no she gave me her ticket
 	
 	
 		oh oh
 	
 	
 		she decided not to go so she gave me her ticket and i went with her friend
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> so it was nice i got a T-shirt
 	
 	
 		oh well good oh did you oh
 	
 	
 		i'm not they said they ran small so i bought a large and i i put it on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> and it
 		i wore it to bed like a nightshirt  yes  but i think it'll shrink up because it's cotton
 	
 	
 		oh it's quite quite big huh  quite large huh oh well
 		yeah oh they do usually huh well i'm trying to think what else we've we did go to a current <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> concert um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh did you
 	
 	
 		it's uh he he's uh a local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micheal Ballum</ENAMEX> is his name and and he's kind of almost um sings opera almost and and he
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 		
 	