
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well do you like to sail
 	
 	
 		i used to sail quite a bit when i was younger and i haven't sailed much recently but i do like it i do like it how about yourself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that
 		oh i love to sail i have a i was first introduced to it when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
 		oh gosh in the late seventies i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> who had a little seventeen foot day sailor that we used to go out on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Lanier</ENAMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> just about every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> in the summertime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was just more fun than a barrel of monkeys
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and just loved it and then uh i i don't know it i had never sailed before and i took to it like the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		how old were you at that time
 	
 	
 		um that was um <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five or so</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then i was transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 		and as luck would have it uh one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohorts</ENAMEX> at work uh was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> uh with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who had a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty two</NUMEX> foot uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarten</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact he still has it and so i got to go sailing a lot uh
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		on that we've been down to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corpus</ENAMEX> and over to um i've been on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pensacola</ENAMEX> yacht race and just in a whole little bit of gulf sailing and uh it's spectacular um i just it's one of my favorite very favorite things to do
 	
 	
 		what's it like sailing on the gulf in um Corpus
 	
 	
 		well once you get out
 	
 	
 		is it pretty rough
 	
 	
 		well now sure i've been  whenever it was just horrendous i mean when we went out in storms and then again i've been out there whenever it's just almost
 		you know just real light light waves i mean it's it's varied from one extreme to the other but whenever you get out away from the shoreline out in the blue <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and the you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphin</ENAMEX> start swimming along beside the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and it uh it's wonderful
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		that's something
 	
 	
 		and of course that's the best of all possible worlds because i don't have to pay upkeep on it or any
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because honey you know that that there's a saying what's a sailboat it's a hole in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> that you throw money into
 	
 	
 		i've never heard that one i suppose that's probably true so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who owns the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> that's what he professes that he said yeah then he said
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> foot <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> is probably quite a investment
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 		yeah it really is and uh he also says uh uh sailing is is uh a way to go uh nowhere fast to go to go nowhere at very slow speeds at very great expense
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but then you know there's something so much more magical about sailing as opposed to other kinds of boating i feel like
 		um
 		i don't know if it's a matter of the speed or if it's just the fact that you have a little bit more control
 		at the tiller than you do say if you're in a power boat
 	
 	
 		well oh yeah and i agree with you a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> percent i mean i have after having sailed a little bit i just have no interest at all in a power <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		almost seems like it would be slightly boring
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's just you know the whole idea of getting out there and uh making  you know fine tuning the sails and trimming and and adjusting just to to eke out a little more speed from the wind
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		and uh just have and i don't know just the whole you you you well and you're closer to nature too than having a big throbbing engine behind you
 	
 	
 		more of a challenge
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i i really do love it i've got uh um my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> uh has some a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aruba</ENAMEX> and i'm going down there in uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX> and i hope to get a chance to do a little sailing down there
 	
 	
 		beautiful clear water down there i'm sure
 	
 	
 		exactly yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		so one of the things i think i may even try is uh uh you know the the little sail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> with the what they call it
 	
 	
 		oh where you're standing like a surf <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> only there's a
 	
 	
 		wind sailing yeah whatever but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't you know i'm not quite sure if i'm ready to try that or not i
 	
 	
 		i almost tried that once with a on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club Med</ENAMEX> vacation
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um they had these other flat they weren't flat actually they were
 		um probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> foot little skiffs that were a lot more fun  so i went where my experience was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah and i i have heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk that that uh you know you almost have to have lessons and then it's really you know not easy to master those uh those
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it looks challenging physically challenging
 	
 	
 		it really it really does but again it looks like something that looks how it maybe like roller skating would be it looks like a lot of fun but not that easy to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> have you ever surfed
 	
 	
 		no i never have
 	
 	
 		that might be the same sort of muscles that you'd use but
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		or skied  those are also if your muscles are developed there then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it wouldn't be as difficult as it might be for some other people
 	
 	
 		yeah right right but uh anyway that's uh sort of the the extent of my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> sports but i i do i find sailing just to be uh one of the best ways for me to get out and relax and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		have you ever considered uh either buying in with someone else a partnership in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i have considered it and at the same time it's um
 		where i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> it's in order to to really get the use out of it i would need to move down near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Clear Clear Lake</ENAMEX> closer to the water
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and uh that would mean commuting up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gulf Freeway</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> into downtown and and i'm i live so close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> that i'm just not
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know the idea of having to commute on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeway</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> even as much as i would like to have access to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> you know more often than i do yeah it's it's just not that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's a trade off certainly
 		
 		
 	