
 
     		
 	
 		okay we're ready to begin
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay uh okay one of the things they said about how you feel about putting you an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in a nursing home um
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i'd had that situation presented to me personally <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years ago</TIMEX> when i had to put my place my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> in a nursing home and um
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		he had <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> and he uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wandered</ENAMEX> and i had to put him in there for his own safety because i could not i couldn't care for him here any longer i tried as hard as i could
 	
 	
 		is that pretty much a full time care situation isn't it
 	
 	
 		yes and uh i had to work and he would get up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> and he could get out and wander down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and i was afraid for his safety um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so i had to make that decision um
 	
 	
 		did you did you um check into um a lot of different <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and
 		see what they care they offered
 	
 	
 		yes i did
 		i checked into the facilities uh the other thing that i did and i've recommended other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do the same thing sometimes is to check and with
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> in that nursing facility
 		you know see if you can find out who who has a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> there or if you go and check it stop and ask somebody when you see them you know do you have you know
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX> do you have here um how is the care are you satisfied
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		it took me quite a while to choose
 	
 	
 		did you find there was a large range of costs involved in in nursing homes
 	
 	
 		yes
 		very much so there was a large range of costs uh and the cost didn't necessarily reflect the care
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the cost some of the costs went for other amenities for those that were uh up and ambulatory like really nice dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and you know
 		uh things like that but that was for one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> but then the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> that needed full nursing care i didn't feel i got the benefit of the extra cost
 	
 	
 		is that what that's what i'm i'm thinking uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> right now is is able to care for herself and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i was interested in looking uh for something that would have a a range of care i guess so that you know
 	
 	
 		right and you would want the maybe the uh extra amenities you know like the
 		very nice dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and you know the freedom of the grounds to be nice so they can walk out there and you know activities you'd organized organized activities
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah organized activities
 	
 	
 		and things like that
 	
 	
 		the uh ones that offer more uh
 		uh care i i assumed that they have certain requirements for their uh nursing and medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> uh some sort of requirements state requirements or
 	
 	
 		right
 		right yeah each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is different
 		but uh
 		here here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> there are certain you know requirements
 	
 	
 		yeah is there um uh did you find there was a waiting list for some of them or to get into
 	
 	
 		some of them yes there was a waiting list um
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		in fact i had uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> when my i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> started i went through a series of
 		let's see i had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> started he was in
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that wasn't total total patient care but where he could be watched but he had the freedom to wander around and and help
 		caring caring for himself but he could do you know he could feed himself he could do things for himself um
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and i had him on a waiting list there then he got so that he could they could not handle him at that level and they didn't have a higher level at that facility which i really didn't think of
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		you know when i checked him in uh so then i had to go and search i had to start all over again
 	
 	
 		do you know whether or not uh some of the uh programs such as uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> a uh help fund any of of the costs involved in in elderly care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Medicaid</ENAMEX> will under certain circumstances
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> will again under you know have to be discharged from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many days</TIMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> will like i said under certain circumstances my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> did not was not eligible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> would not cover <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay so there's there's uh some things they'll cover and some they won't
 	
 	
 		so that
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		it almost goes by case by case
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um that's uh that's something i think many people
 		uh have to address at some point or other and and uh it it's a tough decision to make especially depending on your the care that is needed and and uh
 	
 	
 		it is
 	
 	
 		uh in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s life more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> really can't
 		uh with working both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> working it gets almost impossible to do that at home anymore
 	
 	
 		it it does and
 		
 		
 	