
 
     		
 	
 		kind of younger still and we do a lot of activities with them how about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their late twenties</TIMEX> and both are married and we do things as a family all together and when they were younger we were very involved in
 		Little League and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scouts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and
 		things you know i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> things that you do together
 	
 	
 		are are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> still live in the area
 	
 	
 		yes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> and the other lives in Lewisville
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and i think the activities haven't changed because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scouts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ballet</ENAMEX> and church activities and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">uh soccer and basketball and baseball</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is on the swim <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is in ballet
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> takes piano lessons is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> so tends to be very busy
 	
 	
 		right well i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i always felt that if you want to keep them off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> so to speak that if they're involved
 		in a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> type things that um  it really is wonderful as far as socializing and learning and just
 		keeping out of trouble i work at a high school and i see a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who
 		because it's a large school
 		you're just sort are a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">teeny fish</ENAMEX> in a big pond here and if you belong to you know a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> you you
 		just have a better class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and and stuff and i think it's wonderful i i admire you it's a lot of time out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays Sundays</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> but it it definitely is worth
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the time</TIMEX> to
 		get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> involved in in various things
 	
 	
 		well gives gives them the opportunity to uh you know to relate to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and not only to learn a specific skill and how to apply it but but more importantly how to you know work within the uh larger context
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		right the social life  socialization is
 		is worth whatever it is they're learning and it  you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> never were on the championship <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> they were both in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> they happened to have graduated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> where i work and and um
 		all those things were or have served them and still are
 		you know in their adult <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and in college uh you know that they just
 		they remember lots of good times and um we'd still hear frequently from
 		former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band members</ENAMEX> or you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who stop by and say hi to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i and uh
 		so are you active
 		with i mean do you coach any of these things or
 	
 	
 		oh yes i coached <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> i've coached soccer i've coached baseball i'm a uh assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout master</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scouts</ENAMEX> i've actually
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		appeared on stage with them in their ballet performances and then a feel of things so it's a
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it's uh it's it's pretty active and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> teaches piano and she's active with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		well i'd it
 	
 	
 		takes a tremendous amount of time
 	
 	
 		it does and and um but as i say i i really feel
 		to keep them away from the bad element at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or just at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> or wherever uh every
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every hour</TIMEX> pays off in the long run as far as uh
 		keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> from out of trouble and and uh and i see frequently see that here just
 		because it's a high school and and uh you know kids
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get in trouble there's no
 	
 	
 		well the ones in trouble the ones that are bored that's their biggest problem is boredom if they
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right
 		that's right they're also you know have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that
 		either can't or don't care about their activities and don't support them and and uh
 		over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> like in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> that
 		in in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> of high school band their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> never saw a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football game</ENAMEX> to watch them i think i i we never miss a game we still go and the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> graduated in nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX> so but we still
 		you know go to watch these things and and uh
 	
 	
 		well sure
 		like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> we went to hear my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> play in the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orchestra</ENAMEX> then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> we heard him sing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> twice so you know we're
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and uh it's a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> but as they
 	
 	
 		a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> either it be helping to run things or to just sit there and listen to things
 	
 	
 		right right right but it it uh i recall my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> being active in in my endeavors and uh you know i think
 		you you you just can't spend enough time with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in in quality time as i like to call it and and uh
 		you know it's worth every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every hour</TIMEX>
 		every so you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> how old are they
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay well see <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty seven and thirty</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		well i've got i've got a long way to go
 	
 	
 		well start saving your money for college
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	