
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well um i kind of like the 49ers
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right how about you
 	
 	
 		be
 		i'm a i'm a a die hard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		i was born and raised here so i i have to back my team
 	
 	
 		well yes i guess that that's understandable um
 	
 	
 		why are you a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">49ers</NUMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		well they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple players</ENAMEX> they have had and they do now that that um played here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYU</ENAMEX> before they went down there
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Steve Young</ENAMEX> was from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYU</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim McMahon</ENAMEX> was he's not he's not one of my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> personality or otherwise but  he did play here so that you know provides a little bit of interest
 		um how about you what are who are some of your
 		favorite players
 	
 	
 		well there's a lot of them there's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Irwin</ENAMEX> that's uh making making a real real good name for himself this year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troy Aikman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know if you ever heard of him
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		well do you watch football
 	
 	
 		well not too much i i follow mostly you know the college the college ones around here rather than the the professional
 	
 	
 		not too much
 		oh really
 		right
 	
 	
 		so you know you'll  well who do you think's going to go far this year
 	
 	
 		i don't know it's it's it's pretty it's pretty tough i'm i'm i don't follow the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> that that much it's i have a hard enough time just keeping up with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		the uh conference they're in right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> will do pretty good i don't i don't know if they'll go all the way
 	
 	
 		oh good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're probably they they they may be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another year</TIMEX> away from going all the way
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but they'll they'll be in the play-offs and i think they'll do real good
 	
 	
 		well good what do you think about how much the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> make
 	
 	
 		that's a
 	
 	
 		professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well uh that's i wouldn't mind wouldn't mind getting some of their salaries
 	
 	
 		
 
 		all right do you do you think they they should be paid that much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		i think they earn it i think they earn it i mean i i mean i you'd have to pay me that much to get out there on the field to uh
 	
 	
 		you think
 	
 	
 		you know get the crap knocked out of me so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well what about um yeah i guess the risk of injury that they go through i mean they get injured it's pretty much for life in that
 		that kind of a thing do you play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> do you
 	
 	
 		i did i i just i just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach coach</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> right now so
 	
 	
 		oh i that's what i was would do you let your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> play
 	
 	
 		yeah i do i mean i i let them do whatever they want to do i don't i don't hold them back i mean if they want to try it and uh do it that's fine if they don't want to do it that's fine i mean i i leave them leave it up to them
 	
 	
 		as dangerous as it is
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> have
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		because i don't want to hold them back from trying anything i mean they may be may be good at it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right they might be they might be
 		making one of those salaries one of these days  huh okay well um
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		let's see what else do you have any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that you follow at all besides <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		no not really not really
 	
 	
 		that keeps you keeps you going
 	
 	
 		yeah that keeps me busy enough right there do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX> how do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX> how's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> doing this year
 	
 	
 		do you
 		well oh they're doing so-so they
 		they uh their main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> was hurt and so um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Young</ENAMEX>'s been uh you know in there taking his place but i think i think the main one's getting
 		better so he you know they can get back in the
 	
 	
 		is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McMahon</ENAMEX> the head <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> lead quarterback
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		isn't he playing for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah he is i think he is yeah he is and then um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Young</ENAMEX> was and and he hurt his knee <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McMahon</ENAMEX> hurt his knee and so <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first couple of</TIMEX> games
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Young</ENAMEX> went in for him
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought i
 	
 	
 		but i think he's back in there now
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought at first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Young</ENAMEX> started out as a lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> and then he got himself hurt and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McMahon</ENAMEX> came in in one of the games and uh ended up just uh winning the game coming from behind
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i don't
 	
 	
 		and they just let him keep starting because he was doing so good and kept winning
 	
 	
 		well he yeah so he was better because i think he was here at the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> and then yeah that that probably happened so do you watch it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> is that what you do on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> is watch the football games
 	
 	
 		uh sometimes it depends yeah it depends on what it what all's going on sometimes i sometimes i get a chance to sometimes i don't
 	
 	
 		sometimes
 		and who
 		uh-huh oh so well when you coached your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> did you enjoy that
 	
 	
 		yeah enjoyed it a lot i mean this this is my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first first year</TIMEX> as a coach
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> year of playing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my first year</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> so it was a it was a learning experience on both ends
 	
 	
 		oh
 		boy i'll say yeah how old how old do they let them play
 	
 	
 		uh one that's he's just getting ready to turn ten
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		another one's getting ready to turn <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and one that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh are they all boys
 	
 	
 		all boys
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you probably have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> ahead of you  okay well is there any other comments you wanted to make or
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so
 		not that i can think of
 	
 	
 		okay all right well thank you
 	
 	
 		thanks i enjoyed talking with you
 	
 	
 		um-hum bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 		
 		
 	