
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Don't
Give <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me That</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle</ENAMEX> deserves congratulations for her prodigious compendium
of philanthropic donations in the "
                  Slate
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>." But it's simply not
true, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX> asserts in her introduction, that the

                  Slate
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX> is the first list of its kind. I compiled what I believe
is the first list of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Most Generous Living Americans" for Town</ENAMEX> &
Country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1983</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years later</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1986</TIMEX>), I
updated that same list. And in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1989</TIMEX>, for the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, I compiled
a list of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Most Generous Living Americans</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under age 50</TIMEX>. Thanks for setting the
record straight.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rottenberg Philadelphia</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New News</ENAMEX>
Is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good News</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fiddling Around</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Yoffe</ENAMEX>'s assessment of differences between reporting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> and the
'90s, overlooks <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> important issue--media distribution. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, the
national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> was censored by a small handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gatekeepers</ENAMEX>. Any news outside
the established national news held relatively little credibility in comparison,
and therefore held little influence. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, the number of national
news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX> has grown tremendously. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX> print <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, cable and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satellite</ENAMEX> news, and of course Internet distribution put the news into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> too quickly to be entirely monitored by the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>.
There was never a better demonstration of this shift in media distribution than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> story, which would have died in the hands of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> were it not for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> .

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Muscato</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Prejudice at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">160 MPH</ENAMEX>
            

            As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> born and
raised, I must confess to a visceral appreciation for petty jabs at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Southerners</ENAMEX>, "good ol' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>," or other similar cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unknowns</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatch</ENAMEX>" from a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASCAR</ENAMEX> race, however, illustrates how
easily such "harmless" prejudices collapse into crude stereotypes.

            When the crowd rises and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gasps</ENAMEX> after a wreck, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX> notes that they all, including himself, are
"hoping for a violent accident." Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> may harbor such wishes. For all I
know, some hockey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> go for the fights. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race fans</ENAMEX>, though--real ones,
not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s cartoonish inventions--react to the wrecks for different
reasons. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrecks</ENAMEX> usually knock the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> out of the race, itself a
dramatic event. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it is exciting and even encouraging to watch one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>
smack a concrete wall at such high speeds and walk away unscathed. Most fans
prefer that such wrecks not occur, but when they do, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> pay justifiably close
attention to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s fate. The flashy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> apparel, etc., send a relevant
message--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> really care about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>. A lot.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s eagerness for
violence is his own business; he should not presume the same of others. Did
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX> speak with any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> with whose hopes he claimed to be so
familiar? Virtually all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> with whom I have spoken over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> (quite
a friendly bunch, actually) consider the absence of big wrecks,
injuries, etc., a key component of a good <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX> might simply have
trouble believing that mustachioed, tobacco-chewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> wearing big, black
T-shirts can resist the temptation to cry for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. If so, I'd suggest he
attend a future race and talk to some of his section-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>.

            There are
other reasons that wrecks cause fan excitement--e.g., remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> must
continue racing to the start/finish line; it releases tension built up over
long green-flag runs. It is sufficient to note, however, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX> was
content to rely on a mix of his own admitted bloodthirstiness and good
old-fashioned prejudice for his conclusion. I expect better from

                  Slate
               , and hope that it survived editorial pruning only because
you were busy counting your otherwise well-deserved subscription money from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASCAR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> such as myself (look for my 
                  Slate
                umbrella during the
next rain delay!).

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory</ENAMEX>
Vogelsperger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Elmhurst</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
