
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Arguing
With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Argument Culture</ENAMEX>
               
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Do</ENAMEX>
Understand," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> quotes the following sentence from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Tannen</ENAMEX>'s
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argument Culture</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disputation</ENAMEX> was rejected in ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> as
incompatible with the decorum and harmony cultivated by the true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tannen</ENAMEX> might be
surprised to learn that one of the most well-known introductory books on
ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> thought is called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Disputers of the Tao: Philosophical</ENAMEX>
Argument in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient China</ENAMEX> . Indeed, I think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of ancient China
would agree that if there ever was a disputatious intellectual culture, it was
that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warring States</ENAMEX> period (circa <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">479</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">221</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX>). (Note the name
of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tannen</ENAMEX>.)

            In other
words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tannen's</ENAMEX> is pretty much the most egregiously misleading generalization
about ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> that I have ever read.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraser University of Hong Kong</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Librarian</ENAMEX>
Says "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Keep Quiet</ENAMEX>"
            

            I cannot recall a more
gratuitous grouse than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kerr</ENAMEX>'s questioning, in an otherwise estimable
piece, of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>-friendliness" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude Stein</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">volumes</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What We Have Here Is a Failure to Communicate"</ENAMEX>).

            The dimensions of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">library</ENAMEX>'s books are perfect, their typeface is elegant and eminently readable
without being precious, and most refuting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerr</ENAMEX>'s odd complaint, their pages
are of a thickness that affords pliability and easy separation while
maintaining economy in bulk and weight. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the many marvels of the series
is that vast collections of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' works are assembled in volumes so
exquisite yet portable. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin Franklin</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,600</NUMEX> page tome is easily
handled.

            It should
be noted of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>'s treatments of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Twain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry James</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerr</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">covets for Gertrude Stein</ENAMEX>, that their thinnest volumes comprise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,029 and 845</NUMEX>
pages, respectively. If slightness in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of America</ENAMEX> volume is a mark of
esteem, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerr</ENAMEX> can be assured that the two svelte books she reviewed, at under a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> pages each, accord <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude Stein</ENAMEX> a measure of honor beyond mere
inclusion in the series.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Coleman</ENAMEX> ,
university <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">librarianWest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas A&M UniversityCanyon, Texas</ENAMEX>

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Morals of the Story</ENAMEX>
            

            In
"The Theory
of Everything," his review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.O. Wilson</ENAMEX>'s latest book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Pinker</ENAMEX>
writes:

            I was not persuaded that
moral statements can be reduced to psychology, as if the disapproval of murder
were just another human taste like the preference for sweet over bitter <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX>.
(Even a die-hard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ionian</ENAMEX> might think that our moral sense evolved to grasp a
logic of morality that is outside our minds in the same sense that our number
sense evolved to grasp mathematical truths that are outside our minds.)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> difference between
mathematical truths and moral truths is that grasping the former provides an
obvious survival advantage. We should expect an evolved number sense to discern
mathematical truths fairly well; we should not be so optimistic about the
accuracy of an evolved moral sense.

            The
evolutionary process will favor those moral intuitions that best spread the
genes responsible for them--quite independent of whether they induce behavior
that is objectively Good.

            -- Maurile
Tremblay
            

            
               Comic
Relief
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s theory (in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica"</ENAMEX>) that the cartoon he reprinted came from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>'s column
is high flattery for one of us, but it is inaccurate. I usually come up with my
own ideas, but I am, like most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonists</ENAMEX>, very happy that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> can't
draw.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Danzigerwww</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">danzigercartoons</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Insecurity
            

            Like most articles and
studies discussing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> privatization, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Can Newt Gingrich Save Social</ENAMEX>
Security?" takes at face value claims that if retirement insurance funds
are invested in private securities, a continuing rate of return well above that
on federal bonds may be obtained.

            While that has surely been
true in the past, and should continue to be for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years</TIMEX> yet, the argument
almost certainly will break down precisely when the money would be required.
The rise in the stock market in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> has been in no small part due to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX>' accelerating investment of their retirement funds there (see, for
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Surowiecki</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Planet Hollywood</ENAMEX>
Syndrome" on the effects of excess money on Wall Street). However, when
they begin to withdraw from the market en masse, a parallel fall in prices will
occur as the supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who must sell begins to outstrip the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wishing to buy at a historically high cost. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to retire might
enjoy considerable returns on their investments, but those at the trailing end
of the baby boom might see their gains disappear while the market
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overcorrects</ENAMEX>.

            Putting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> funds in the market only makes these effects worse, as that
money must at some point be withdrawn, no matter what, to meet obligations
(similar arguments might be applied to bonds, real estate, or anything else
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> money might be invested in). Some form of privatization might
substantially aid the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to retire, but later <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX>--precisely those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whom the current system is also most likely to shortchange--get left
behind. Any prudent plan to invest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> funds in private markets
must have some way to address these risks; none that I know of do.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newman Oakland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
