
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Rx: Take
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill Pill</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Call Me in the Morning</ENAMEX>
            

            In response to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX>,
Mote, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beam</ENAMEX>": Much of the criticism of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pressgate</ENAMEX>" piece and the
magazine in general has been from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">media</ENAMEX> who were
clearly part of the system I was writing about and, thus, responded
accordingly. Because 
                  Slate
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> don't in any way
fall into that category and deserve to be taken seriously, I thought I should
try to respond seriously to some of the factual stuff. (I'll let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> decide
for themselves if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is "boring," a knock that reminds me of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>'
wishful thinking when I started the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Lawyer</ENAMEX> .)

            First, I didn't "leak" the
piece to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> --a semi-important point for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> like
ours. We blast faxed the piece to every major (and minor, I think) press
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>, after first faxing it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. Everybody got it at the
same time. So, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' decision to put it on the front page was not
based on having any kind of exclusive.

            Now to take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>'s points
in order:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">l</ENAMEX>) Whether I prove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
leaked grand jury information depends on one's definition of grand jury
information. I used the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> used by the relevant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> with jurisdiction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
disagrees with that. No mistakes? How about the stained dress? Or the president
testifying that he never was alone with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>? (I never say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
made mistakes, by the way.)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Schmidt</ENAMEX> disputes
that quote. That happens with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> a lot. But, interestingly, she didn't
dispute it the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time she was asked about the story--by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howie Kurtz</ENAMEX> for his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> story. My notes have her saying exactly that and then saying it again
later on in our interview (at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Hotel</ENAMEX> coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>) in almost the same
language.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) No self-contradiction
here. She volunteered that item about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> and where she had got the story in
the course of narrating that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first weekend</TIMEX> of the "scandal." When I later asked
her directly about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> for her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first-day</TIMEX> story (and stories beyond that)
she declined to comment.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) My point was that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>" answer was the thing that stood out the most to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Isikoff</ENAMEX>
when I talked with him about the tapes. And it's a big part of why
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> held the story. I simply pointed out that this is something
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> might have remembered to put in and quote when it went online
with its first story. In retrospect, though, it would have been fairer and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fuller</ENAMEX> to note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> did, indeed, say the evidence was not at
all clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had instructed her to lie. Nonetheless, I think
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> should have included this important quote if it had wanted to
be fair.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) To take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> example,
let's look at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first-day</TIMEX> reports from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>.

            What did I know? a) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX> had spent "much of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>" briefing these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> told me
that, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> confirmed it but would not tell me specifics. b) The network
reports included material from tapes that could only be the tapes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had made (because these tapes allegedly have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> told her to lie--which was not on the tapes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
heard, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> had supposedly heard the most incriminating tapes).
Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> nor anyone else (even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX>, though she might obviously
remember what was on them--but she was not accessible to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> at this
point) could have heard those tapes or briefed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> about them. So I don't
think it's "intellectually dishonest" to say that this information must have
come from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Remember: He says his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> briefed them for these
reports, and the crux of the reports was what was supposedly on these
tapes.

            By the way, this criticism
is kind of refreshing in the sense that it's so different from the "everyone
knows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> leak" criticism that I've got.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> is just plain
wrong. There are no court decisions in the relevant jurisdiction that support
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> on the notion that leaking what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> before they
testify about what they will testify to is OK. Sure, there are some from other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> elsewhere, but they are few and far between, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> really wouldn't
be able to cite them properly in a brief in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oops</ENAMEX>, forget my last
paragraph under Point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) My point about anonymous
quotes is made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>. I'm against totally blind uses of phrases such as
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>" that don't say how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> or what <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ax</ENAMEX> they might have to grind.
(Example: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Judd</ENAMEX>'s citing of "several sources" to substantiate her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>-interrupted-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> "scoop.") When a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> can't
be named, enough identification should be supplied so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> knows the
source's potential bias. This clearly worked here; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> can see that I'm using
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> and correctly identifies the potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bias</ENAMEX>. Now, go back and read my description of all the truly blind "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>" in
the article, and see if you can tell the difference.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>) Conflict: Yes, I should
have disclosed that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> I gave <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> bucks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>. (I've
also given money to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>.) But how could I prohibit anyone,
even myself, retroactively from making contributions? That was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>; this is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, and since I sent out the initial direct mail for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> (which I
knew would cover political stuff and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>), I haven't made any
contributions to anyone, let alone the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> (to whom, again, I made one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contribution in 1995).</ENAMEX> The only "political" writing or editing I did around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> contribution was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> piece by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Lawyer</ENAMEX> , which I instigated and edited and proudly
published--and which, as you know, made the case against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            I'm proud
of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> and proud of this piece. Prouder, in fact, now than when we
published it, because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly two weeks later</TIMEX> everyone who could take a shot at
it has, and so far I can see that I've misspelled one name, screwed up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequence</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> decided not to wait for comment from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> on its incorrect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">steward-witness</ENAMEX> story after hearing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> wanted a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half-hour</TIMEX> to comment, not before), and included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX>
gratuitous adjectives that I now wouldn't. There may be more, and if there is I
will be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to concede it. But I hope my willingness to admit mistakes
isn't misread as being so much more fallible than others--but only being more
willing to admit it.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve BrillBrill</ENAMEX>'s
Content <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> responds: I appreciate the tone of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s letter, which is nicer
than my piece was. Several of his points, however, demand a reply.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>(a) My criticism stands.
The only thing that's clearly illegal is leaking out of the grand jury <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> doesn't prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has done that.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>(b) I didn't say there
were "no mistakes." I wrote that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> didn't document any significant error of
fact by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . He
doesn't.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> used a tape
recorder, we'd know whether he misquoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Schmidt</ENAMEX> or not. He doesn't
respond to the complaint that he misquoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonah Goldberg</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Still a contradiction
in the article. It would have been consistent if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> had written that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schmidt</ENAMEX>
declined comment on her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> except for the one she revealed.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) This is now a point of
supernuance, not a major criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's journalistic integrity,
which was how it was billed in the story.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) I strongly suspect
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> was the source for stories about what various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> have said.
But there's at least a plausible alternative explanation for where much of this
information could have come from. As I say, it would have been only fair to
mention it.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) This whole argument
about the "relevant jurisdiction" is new since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s article. Eventually the
question of what's illegal is likely to be settled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, which
will consider lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> precedents from various jurisdictions.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> concedes, I
think.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>
concedes.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>) Brill
concedes.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> concedes.
            

            
               Right
Back at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ya</ENAMEX>
            

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 23</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>" claims that "a kind of machinery" is at work on the
right "that doesn't exist on the left <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>." Actually, similar machinery has
existed on the left for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. It runs from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> in the statehouse to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> on the bench to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> on the
nightly news. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> plugged into the machinery the moment he was
elected.

            Examples include the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> use of accepted terms such as "extreme right" to describe any given
idea that emanates from the conservative end of the spectrum. It includes broad
opposition to the slightest bit of reform that might impact the access of trial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to the money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">machine</ENAMEX> of our tort system. It includes attack dog
opposition to any and all school reform that does not result in massive amounts
of additional money for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>. And so on and so on.

            The left
has for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> started opposing things in tandem the moment the handwriting
appeared on the wall. Their opposition has always included near uniformity,
right down to verbiage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sotomayor</ENAMEX> nomination is an isolated example of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> employing this often successful tool perfected by the left.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David C.</ENAMEX>
Klug <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harrisburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>

            
               Remember
Who Lost the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>!
            

            I read with interest
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hegemon and Proud</ENAMEX>
of It," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strobe Talbott</ENAMEX>. However--and you may choose to call me a smug
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigner</ENAMEX> who is also sensitive to "smugness" on the part of the superpower--I
thought it self-congratulatory, ill-considered, and decidedly anecdotal.

            It is certainly true that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is the most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the world. It is also true
that its erstwhile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> has collapsed rather utterly. However, even the merest
glance at the history books will reveal that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talbott</ENAMEX>'s dominate-but-cooperate
scenario has been played out over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>: The wars were always the
exceptions. It is also worth pointing out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has actually
declined in relative economic importance since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
was responsible for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> the gross world product. However, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, even
though the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is far and away the No. 1 economy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>,
with its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, actually has a bigger share of the gross world
product. Never mind <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, who aren't exactly inconsequential. Then
there's the rest of the world.

            It seems
to me that the world as a whole is an awful lot more interdependent than it
ever has been. And I think that's a good thing. So, like, get over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
omnipotence thing.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGinty London</ENAMEX>

            
               Fictional
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Journalism 101</ENAMEX>
            

            Hats off
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fictional Journalism for Dummies</ENAMEX>." Only I would have gone a bit
further. Based on the available evidence so far, this abortion of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN/ Time</ENAMEX> piece was not just overreaching but a shining example of sheer
intellectual dishonesty and reporting at its shabbiest.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Wolf</ENAMEX> National
security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, ReutersWashington

            
               Cheap Is
Good
            

            Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Living</ENAMEX> in a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best World</ENAMEX>": <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years ago</TIMEX>, I paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between 20 cents and 40 cents</NUMEX> a
minute for long-distance service, depending on the time of day. Now I pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.9</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cents</NUMEX> per minute, day or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. In real terms, average airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> fares are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> what they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>, before deregulation.

            I own a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> that spends
several <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> a year on long-distance phone service and airline
travel. Sure, finding the lowest rates/fares is more of a hassle now than it
once was, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> may or may not be better, but to me, this is easily
worth putting up with to get the cost saving.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> may
be in a financial position to pay more to eliminate the hassle, but I'm
not.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Graham Dayton</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wash.</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knifepoint Humor</ENAMEX>
            

            I read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atul Gawande</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Manning the Hospital Barricades</ENAMEX>" with interest. I understand his
premise that we should get along, but my comments as a "meddie" will be much
more parochial.

            I agree that surgeons
generally work very hard. (The question of whether a lot of what they do is
really necessary or appropriate is debatable, as it is for all specialties.)
The "virtue" and responsibility aspect are more problematic. There is the
common ritual of "medical clearance for surgery," where the "meddie" basically
blesses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> and is allowed to share responsibility, despite the fact
that the note is rarely read and the recommendations are often ignored.

            A less than virtuous practice
that is not unheard of is to hustle the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> of a failing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> out of
the OR to avoid "dying on the table."

            I have a couple of additions
for your medical jokes (not original). How do you hide something from an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internist</ENAMEX> (meddie)? Put it under a bandage. How do you hide something from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX>? Put it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s chart.

            Some of my
best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are surgeons.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew W. March</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.D.</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Flying
High
            

            About
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Molina</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary</ENAMEX>": It's great that 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are getting
some exposure to a segment of society of which few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are aware. Across the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> (and, to a lesser extent, around the world) are a handful of people
whose passion for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> in particular, and the magnificence of living things in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>, holds them apart from the rest of society. They surrender to years of
poverty. They don't watch much television. And the study of animals demands
that they go where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> live and put up with what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> put up
with. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">To Molina</ENAMEX>'s list of bugs, sun, and windblown <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX>, I add cold; <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thorns</ENAMEX>; poisonous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> without showers; steep, rugged terrain;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX>; lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>; lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> ...)

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Martin</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
