
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOPE</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sesame</ENAMEX>
            

            I am an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, and my
medium of choice is neon. I just read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dolan</ENAMEX>'s "Sign o' the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>," which
was very informative and accurate.

            As someone working in neon,
I have made a couple of OPEN signs. As an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, though, with a thing for
language and how it is transformed by how it is represented, I had been
thinking about the power that the blazing OPEN sign has in our culture. To that
end, I made an OPEN sign sculpture in which the letter "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>" swings from one end
of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">OPE</ENAMEX>" to the other, alternately spelling OPEN or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">NOPE</ENAMEX>. I only made one
because I had to engineer the mechanical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> to swing that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>"--plus, I had a
small microprocessor designed and programmed to control the swing over when a
gear motor turns on and switches the letter position.

            The whole
idea comes from the OPEN sign phenomenon where one might be rushing to the
store just before closing time, or maybe during imagined weekend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, only to
find, upon arrival, that one is too late or too early. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NOPE</ENAMEX>!

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael R.</ENAMEX>
Flechtner
            

            
               Boogie
Man
            

            For the most part, I have to
agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Ross</ENAMEX>' contention in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bogus Nights</ENAMEX>"
that indie films have been overpraised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deconstructing Harry</ENAMEX>
was one of the most joyless, excruciating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moviegoing</ENAMEX> experiences I've ever had,
and I'm glad to know I'm not the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who thought <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boogie Nights</ENAMEX>
was wildly overhyped (for a movie that was declared "brilliantly original," it
sure looked derivative to me--there was hardly a shot or sequence in the film
that didn't echo a similar, usually superior, shot or sequence in another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>). And while I enjoyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil LaBute</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Company of Men</ENAMEX> for its
amazing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trio</ENAMEX> of performances, it's true that the film itself was little more
than a rigged stunt--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet Lite</ENAMEX>.

            However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atom Egoyan</ENAMEX>'s The
Sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hereafter</ENAMEX> does not, I feel, belong in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Though it has flaws
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egoyan</ENAMEX>'s decision to romanticize the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> incest blunted the force
of the ending), The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sweet Hereafter</ENAMEX> has none of the insufferable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">smugness</ENAMEX> found in so much indie film in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sundance</ENAMEX> era. The ambiguity in
this case is necessary, and the fact that we are never given a final solution
to the mystery of what happened to the bus is central to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Banks</ENAMEX>' and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egoyan</ENAMEX>'s premise that it is the nature of some tragedies to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incomprehensible</ENAMEX>--better to spend our energies fighting the evils we ourselves
make than to rail at the unfeeling universe.

            As for the
Coens: Yes, it's true, their movies have no <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> acts. But I can't help it,
I'm a fan of their hyperliterate, "look what I can do with a movie camera"
show-offiness. They may never be great film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> (but then, how many great
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film artists</ENAMEX> have there been, other than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welles</ENAMEX>?), but
they are reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entertainers</ENAMEX>. Sometimes that's enough.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evansen Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>

            

               Coenhead
            

            In his review of
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Lebowski</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Ross</ENAMEX> shows himself to be a true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the
film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coens</ENAMEX> have "reserved an independence they haven't
earned"? I'm sorry, but the only earnings that count come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. As
long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> continue to please their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, they have earned
the right to be free of the discipline <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> imagines will spring from having
studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> second-guess their every move.

            Instead
of lambasting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> for abandoning artistic principles in favor of the
almighty dollar, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> attacks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coens</ENAMEX> for abandoning film school principles
in favor of their own. He doesn't quite have the courage to say The Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lebowski</ENAMEX> isn't a good film, so he's reduced to saying it could have been a
better film. Please, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>, take a job with a studio so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coens</ENAMEX> and we
don't have to listen to you.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>

            

               Plathos
            

            Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist" on Sylvia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Hughes</ENAMEX>: What hasn't quite been picked up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
is the extent to which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' rewriting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX> in Birthday
Letters --even the less allusive poems--takes on the voice of its subject. A
poetic homage, for sure, since the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> exemplify the stylistic divide
between the confessional poets of the postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> (count <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lowell</ENAMEX>,
Berryman, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarrell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sexton</ENAMEX>, and others) and their more objective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counterparts</ENAMEX> (think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey Hill</ENAMEX>, etc.).

            So, for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>, this volume is a deliberate suppression of his natural voice. Writing
of his dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, he writes under her stylistic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. And that makes
sense.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeney Oxford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>

            
               If It
Doesn't <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fit, You Must Omit</ENAMEX>
            

            Knock off
the cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> jokes ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 6</TIMEX>). It comes across as an attempt to
build camaraderie on the assumption that we're all in the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of white
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> got away with murder, when in fact some of us are in
the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> who believe that reasonable doubt was
established. In any case, why use any divisive devices at all--would the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
use sexist anecdotes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>? Surely you can find alternatives to being too
PC on one hand and going for easy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> laughs on the other.

            -- Hillard
Pouncy
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
