
   
   
      
         
            

            Another
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> of just-short-of-armed-warfare in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> are ...

            
               Hot
Threads
            

            Testifying to just how
moribund the debate over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation has become, the regular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">combatants</ENAMEX> in things political shuffled back to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics '98</ENAMEX>" thread
and ... welfare reform. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fraygrant</ENAMEX>'s observation that "welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> receive
a constellation of benefits" was torn limb from limb--after the gales of
laughter subsided, that is. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX>'s doings provoked some
debate and soon disintegrated into personal attacks among the fraygrants.

            The
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religion</ENAMEX>"
thread showcased the international flavor of the Fray <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. A missionary
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> and a fraygrant from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> argued about the effects of missionary
activity. And a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far East</ENAMEX> weighed in on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confucianism</ENAMEX>: Was
it really a religion, or was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Confucius</ENAMEX> simply to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> morality what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plato</ENAMEX>
was to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> philosophy? The most interesting post of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>, however,
emerged in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">of the Crusades</ENAMEX> that took on a little-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> called the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathars</ENAMEX> and their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inquisition</ENAMEX>.

            
               New
Threads
            

            What is the key to a lasting
marriage? Some choices proffered in the new "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Marriage and Family</ENAMEX>"
thread: friendship, mutual respect, honesty, humor, and variety. Where does
this leave sex and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> long-married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fraygrant</ENAMEX> says, "We are still in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love</ENAMEX>, still fuck our brains out on a fairly frequent basis." Another's "basic
point": "I don't think it's realistic to expect most relationships to be
sexually monogamous and to last a lifetime." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> offered a reason why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> stay together: "Isn't it possible that a lot of long-lasting marriages
are long-lasting because of inertia created by the absence of alternatives to
that arrangement?" Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> agree that sex and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are desirable
but not necessary within the relationship; all agreed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> should be the
primary consideration in cases of divorce.

            Privacy
was the topic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Law</ENAMEX> and Order." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Contributors</ENAMEX>--several of them
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>--discussed an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>'s right to drug test <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and the
government's right to monitor our lives. One particularly invoked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> . Other issues: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> porn on the Net, on-the-scene news on
television, and whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to suffocate in a hot car
should be charged with manslaughter.

            
               Getting
Serious
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Faulkner</ENAMEX>'s The
Sound <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">and the Fury</ENAMEX> remains the focus in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reading</ENAMEX>" thread. This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s subject: the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> of the book's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>, which is written from
the viewpoint of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin</ENAMEX>, a tormented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> who eventually kills
himself. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s burning questions: Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin</ENAMEX> a classic suicide? Who was
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caddy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next week</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray</ENAMEX> will take on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter</ENAMEX>. Jump in, and examine the mind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">misanthrope</ENAMEX>.

            The
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Person</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>" thread hosted a humorous and articulate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> on the importance
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.K. Gandhi</ENAMEX>. Was he a "sheeted ascetic & do-gooder" or a "major
influence" on mass movements everywhere? In addition to this series of posts
('s a sample), the thread also saw a spirited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simone de Beauvoir</ENAMEX>
("the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>") and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt Disney</ENAMEX> (nominated in the culture
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX> of the ballot). Computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Von Neumann</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Turing</ENAMEX> were
also mentioned--big surprise that their names should crop up in an Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forum</ENAMEX>. First-round
voting closes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 6</TIMEX>, and 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> should vote
while they can.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Week</ENAMEX>
            

            An
interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> in the new "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Marriage and Family</ENAMEX>" thread on what a marriage
is all about inspired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> veteran <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fraygrant</ENAMEX> to his thoughts on some of the
unexpected benefits of marriage.

         
      
   
