
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Hot
Threads
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Scene</ENAMEX>" debated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' knowledge of world affairs. :
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> don't care and don't need to know about the rest of the world. The
other: They should care. Other hot stuff <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>: the role of Hinduism
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, democracy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>,
and more reports from our fraygrant in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>.

            

               Godzilla held center stage in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Movies</ENAMEX> and
Television" thread until talk moved to science fiction and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylon</ENAMEX> Five , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Space Nine , and Dune</ENAMEX> . One
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fraygrant</ENAMEX>'s lament, "Why hasn't there been a good movie out in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months of 1998</TIMEX>?" led to a discussion of which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> was the best for film. No
consensus.

            
               New
Threads
            

            Do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really have
an innate ability to generate language? Do or simply recognize patterns? Check
out the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reading</ENAMEX>" thread, which focused <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Pinker</ENAMEX>'s seminal
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Language Instinct</ENAMEX> . To judge from the brouhaha over the early
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chapters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinker</ENAMEX>'s theories are--well--far from popular. Join in to find out
more.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s
tests <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nuclear</ENAMEX>
Arms" thread. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fraygrants</ENAMEX> believe there's nothing to fear--this is
geopolitics as usual; others find the subcontinental tests a frightening
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>. Examining the effectiveness of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> sanctions, fraygrants agreed
that sanctions, if they have any effect at all, will hit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> harder than
they will <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>.

            
               Fray
Feuds
            

            The "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>" thread saw much of the interpersonal squabbling it has become
noted for--especially as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> drags
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">interminably</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> agreed to pity its leading liberal
and her "hatred," but returned to rancorous form when talk turned to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
accomplishments and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s sale of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> technology to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> were thrown to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religion</ENAMEX>" thread. A prominent gay fraygrant denounced <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>'
"hypocrisy," their (large) role in denying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> equal civil and legal rights,
and their "hate the sin but love the sinner" stance. This fraygrant compared
the fight against homophobia to the fights against racism and sexism: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Like</ENAMEX>
those fights, opposition is rooted in bigotry and prejudice and ignorance.
'Religious doctrines' were also invoked to deny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> the right to vote and to
defend slavery. It's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same old</TIMEX> thing this time around." He that anti-gay
political activities, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Measure 2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Measure 9</ENAMEX>, are
almost always organized by conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>. It is a fight for "social
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX>," after all.

         
      
   
