
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must include their address and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gets Smoked</ENAMEX>
            

            I normally find

                  Slate
               's work to be analytically sound and faithful to the facts.
However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High and Mighty</ENAMEX>" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 23</TIMEX> could not be more inaccurate.

            First, to suggest that the
problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> is that it is illegal--forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> into criminality--is
dead wrong. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heroin</ENAMEX> is criminal because it is deadly, not vice versa. The vast
majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>, criminality aside, cannot adequately sustain
themselves in society. For this reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> maintenance programs in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> have been forced to create a government subsidized job category:
"professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> give these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> not just <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> but a
salary, housing, medical care, and in many cases even a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and money to
support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>. Why? Because these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> cannot hold down a job, and for
many <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> is deadly.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> see what heroin
use is really like--not the somewhat benign face <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX> puts on it--they
won't use this deadly <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>. To this end, one of the other ads in the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Youth Anti-Drug Media Campaign</ENAMEX> shows an attractive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who, as the ad rolls,
begins to strip away her makeup. She ages before your eyes, becoming
increasingly haggard and ill looking. Finally, she removes her artificial
teeth--one of the outcomes of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> use is the loss of teeth--and she shows
just how glamorous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> use is not. This is real life.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s repeated
references to marijuana are medically inaccurate. Take a look at recent medical
evidence:

            A PET brain scan of a
regular marijuana <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> shows that marijuana changes the chemistry of the brain
to render vast sections of the brain less active. Moreover, marijuana smoke
contains countless known carcinogens, and the lung smoking of marijuana to
achieve a high adds to the problem--the smoking equivalent of mainlining cancer
into your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. (Smoking just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or more joints a day produces the same lung
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> as smoking a full pack of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> cigarettes a day.)

            However, it doesn't end
there. Babies born to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> who smoke marijuana during pregnancy have an
elevenfold increase in nonlymphoblastic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX>. The most consistent finding
from the literature on employee marijuana use is its association with increased
absenteeism. It is also associated with increased accidents, higher turnover,
low job satisfaction, counterproductive behavior, withdrawal and antagonistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">behaviors</ENAMEX>, and higher use of employee assistance programs and medical
benefits.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX> also
misunderstands the current ad campaign. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> says the campaign targets
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and he is right. However, the campaign is also largely focused on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the core messages of the campaign is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and other
adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentors</ENAMEX> need to talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> about the real dangers of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use.

            The one
area where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX> has it correct is that it is increasingly hard to educate
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about the real dangers of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use. Unfortunately, for all his
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">couching language</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Drugs</ENAMEX> can be awful") and care, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is part of the
problem, not the solution. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inaccuracies</ENAMEX> like those discussed above, which
downplay the dangers in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use, send our young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> mixed messages and
increase distrust. Against this backdrop it is easy for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to not buy
the facts about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. The bottom line is: We can disagree about policies in a
democracy; however, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disagreements</ENAMEX> should be based on facts. This article
largely failed that measure.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housman</ENAMEX> Chief policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Planning Office of National Drug</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control Policy</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX> responds:
            

            
               I applaud <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housman</ENAMEX>'s lust for facts. No one benefits from propaganda based on scare
tactics rather than the truth.
            

            
               But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Housman</ENAMEX>'s facts are
not facts, and his assumptions are misleading. While his claims of increased
child <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> rates have been refuted (see the excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marijuana Myths</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marijuana Facts</ENAMEX> for a debunking of the study that produced this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> and
direct refutations of each of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housman</ENAMEX>'s other factual claims), they are, more
important, irrelevant. Obviously, pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> should not smoke pot--just as
they should not smoke cigarettes or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink alcohol</ENAMEX>. As for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housman</ENAMEX>'s litany on
"employee marijuana use," each of those effects (increased absenteeism,
increased accidents, higher turnover, low job satisfaction, etc.) will show up
tenfold in relation to employee <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use. Without doubt, constant
intoxication of any form will hurt one's work capacity. And then this: "Smoking
just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or more joints a day produces the same lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> as smoking a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> pack of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> cigarettes a day." Funny, I don't see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> arresting
pack-a-day cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> or lobbying to criminalize <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               To be
sure, there are "real dangers" of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use, just as there are real dangers of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> use. Let's be honest with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> about all of them,
instead of terrorizing them with exaggerations and lies.
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Straight Dope</ENAMEX>
            

            While you
write eloquently regarding your controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mighty</ENAMEX>," many other less fortunate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> are either dead or not in a
position within our society to be heard. Your attitude makes me sick!
Publishing that article is like inviting an alcoholic to a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>-tasting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>:
You're within your rights but very wrong.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johnston Louisville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hey,</ENAMEX>
Wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a Minute</TIMEX>, Potheads!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High and Mighty</ENAMEX>"
practically endorses legalization of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> and the free use of marijuana among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>. In the article, you mentioned how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are hypocritical in
their diatribes against illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and their resistance to slamming "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big</ENAMEX>
Tobacco." From a perspective you have a point, but I would rather be busy
keeping an illegal , dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> out of the reach of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> than
jumping on the bandwagon to tax the crap out of my fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> who smoke a
legal substance. I also would rather see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> smoke cigarettes
than use marijuana or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>. Marijuana alters the brain's chemistry to produce
hallucinogenic effects, while nicotine only satisfies the addiction the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">smoker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> feels. Would you want the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> driving behind you to be high on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marijuana</ENAMEX> or on nicotine? The chances of him/her plowing into you while under
the influence of nicotine are far less than being high on marijuana.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heroin</ENAMEX> is
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> that can kill you on the very first try, and most <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> didn't
start out shooting up with needles--they were smoking pot as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Hicks</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Reality
Check
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Re Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High</ENAMEX>
and Mighty": I have one comment in regard to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>--they kill! My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">girlfriend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was found dead <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few weeks ago</TIMEX> of what has since been
determined to have been an overdose of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>. This was someone who no one
would have ever thought to have been a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>. Personally, I don't give a
flip what kind of action anyone takes to warn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> against the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>,
because they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam McGowan</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The
Propaganda OD
            

            Having
just read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High and Mighty</ENAMEX>," I must applaud him vigorously. I'm an
elementary-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>--which is surely the profession most indoctrinated
with anti-drug propaganda--in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. For me, there's an inherent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stupidity</ENAMEX> in the absoluteness of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Say No</ENAMEX>" campaign, which insists that
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> are completely intolerable in a society where both,
especially the latter, are so prevalent. How can we preach such an absolute
message to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> all day at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or on television and expect them to ignore
our social behaviors every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>? It has become uncomfortable for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and dad
to enjoy a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> or cocktail at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX>, lest junior regale them with
the evils of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use. What's wrong with a society where supposedly
rational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> have to "sneak around" to enjoy a drink within the walls of
their own home?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam Ferguson</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Coming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean</ENAMEX>
            

            You will
doubtless get a great deal of trouble about your decision to publish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High</ENAMEX>
and Mighty" on the current <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> ad campaign. There is no topic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that
is so steeped in cant and posturing. Thanks for pointing out the obvious--that
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use, while dicey, is an established and unavoidable part of human culture
and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dishonesty</ENAMEX> on this point does no one any good.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frodeman Department</ENAMEX> of philosophy and religion, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Tennessee</ENAMEX>

            
               Gag
Yourself With a Sex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dress</ENAMEX>
            

            In its promotional letter of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31</TIMEX>, 
                  Slate
                wrote, "Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s sex dress has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">resurfaced</ENAMEX>, and 
                  Slate
                can't stop talking about it."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLEASE</ENAMEX>
DO! As a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, I have to tell you that I was disappointed in this opener.
You seemed, at first blush, to be above all the crap/sensationalist headlines
the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> use to sell their stuff. But for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> now, all you can talk
about is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal. Could you possibly tear yourself away and find
something more interesting to discuss? This can't be the only story.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire</ENAMEX>
Wynters
            

            
               Secret
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Service</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> is absolutely right in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 23</TIMEX> piece, "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Real Secret</ENAMEX>," about the extent to which presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX> has become absurd, but even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX> fails to ask outright the most
important question: What makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s life so valuable? In a
democracy, after all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>' lives are supposed to be equally valuable.
During the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, it was feared that a presidential assassination might set
off a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>, so by protecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> was,
at least arguably, protecting us all. But nobody worries about that sort of
thing nowadays, and yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is more tightly protected than at the
height of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. Perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> is really protecting its own
bureaucratic rear.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn H.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reynolds</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> of law, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Tennessee</ENAMEX>

            
               I-Rate
About the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E-Rate</ENAMEX>
            

            Trying to be charitable, the
best I can muster about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Quigley</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 23</TIMEX> article, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Server Time Out</ENAMEX>," is
that he is simply ignorant of the facts of rural life.

            In conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, we
have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecommunications Infrastructure Fund</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and libraries
(dreamed up by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, among others) that antedates the
e-rate and is far more generous with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">telcos</ENAMEX>' money.

            I work for a public library
system in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> (not even the most rural part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>) with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. My system and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas State Library</ENAMEX> provide access to a number of
rather expensive databases that few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> can afford to purchase on their
own. The smaller, poorer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> benefit most, as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> would
otherwise not have access to such resources. The most cost-effective way to
deliver this service to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> is via the Internet.

            I have spent a good part of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several weeks</TIMEX> trying to get any kind of non-800 Internet access
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> that have the misfortune of not having an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISP</ENAMEX> in their
local calling area. (Ironically, thanks to the heavy hand of big bad state
government, they can get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an affordable</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ISDN</ENAMEX> line, but as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISPs</ENAMEX> are not
regulated, there are no ISPs where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISDN</ENAMEX> lines terminate.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quigley</ENAMEX> should try getting
DirecPC out in the boonies. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, getting service at the rate he
quotes requires a dial-up phone line connection to an ISP for the upstream link
(there is a much-higher-priced two-way service). <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, while, in theory,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> provides a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DirecPC LAN</ENAMEX> service (TIF generously provided <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> computers
for these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>), I asked several times for pricing and conditions back in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, and I still haven't heard anything more than that it would "probably" be
several <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX>.

            In short, while the market
probably will work quite well in providing good telecommunications in dense
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> areas, very little has changed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX> in the rural areas
I work with. I stopped believing the hype about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX>, cable, or xDSL
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rollouts</ENAMEX> in rural areas some time back.

            I can't
resist saying it: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quigley</ENAMEX> is an armchair <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> spouting snide opinions about
circumstances of which he obviously has little firsthand knowledge. His "let
them eat cake" attitude is insulting and offensive.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Gaines</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Texas Library System</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quigley</ENAMEX> responds:
            

            
               I find
it upsetting that someone could so quickly lose faith in the possibility of
technological innovation in an industry that has been around for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">less than six</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. While it seems as if all our technological problems would be solved if
we simply regulated the industry, let me remind you that it took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least six</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> for even the VHS-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Betamax</ENAMEX> argument to be solved. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> everywhere
would frown on the idea of ghettoizing an industry that is only in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infancy</ENAMEX>--to do so would irrevocably cripple its progress and make the
possibility of lower costs almost nonexistent. Your complaints (e.g., no local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISPs</ENAMEX>, lack of choice in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> technology) are exactly the reasons that the
e-rate would not work. Without these innovations, which only the market can
produce, the Internet connection cost will remain exorbitant, even with the
e-rate discounts! <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the assumption that the Internet industry will all
but ignore the needs of the rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is absurd. The latest census
figures show that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24.8 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> lives in rural areas--to
suggest that the industry will ignore <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost one quarter</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> market is
inane at best.
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must include their address and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
