
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must include their address and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kenya</ENAMEX>
Watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Headlines ...</ENAMEX>
            

            The
flippant headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kenya Catch Them</ENAMEX>" in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" is way out of bounds. Show some judgment.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McMahon Baltimore</ENAMEX>

            
               ... And
Shut Your Trap
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> is obviously
not the only one obsessed with presidential sex. In its latest edition,

                  Slate
                speculates in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 2</TIMEX> "Flytrap
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>" and beyond on whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will issue a mea
culpa for his still-alleged transgression, debates the value of any
physical evidence that may confirm he had consensual sex with former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, and reports how "weird, inexplicably weird" it is
to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in the flesh before her grand jury testimony. Like others in
the national press, you seek to elevate what you call this "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flytrap</ENAMEX>" flap to
the level of scandals such as <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX>. At the same time, you
lower the level of political discourse in 
                  Slate
                to that of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> , building on harmful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hearsay</ENAMEX> while generally ignoring
questions about the partisan motives and support behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s seemingly
interminable investigations.

            Gimme a break. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> is
nothing but a flyspeck when compared with presidential scandals of the past.
Yet thanks to the efforts of conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-haters and a scandal-hungry
press, it has become a "major story" that threatens to undermine the valuable
work <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has done in boosting our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s economy, cleaning up our
environment, advancing the needs of the poor and middle-class, supporting a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX>'s right to choose, making improvements in our education system a top
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">priority</ENAMEX>, and asserting both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> might and values abroad. All that is real
news. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> imbroglio is nothing but an opportunity for the media to
dabble in salaciousness. That 
                  Slate
                is following suit makes me
question my subscription.

            Rather
than cancel yet, I'll first try ignoring 
                  Slate
                for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>.
By then, maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> will have had time for a few cold showers, and
rather than dwelling on sex you'll be ready again to write about national and
international political issues of greater significance.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Kingston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pierce Seattle</ENAMEX>

            
               Monicaed
Out
            

            Your
relentless preoccupation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica in Flytrap Today</ENAMEX> and elsewhere
has finally pissed me off. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>, this clearly is not a matter of my
political affiliation but, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>, it is also clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of

                  Slate
                have very little appeal outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thom Ottawa</ENAMEX>

            
               Give It
Up, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s Flytrap
dispatches are just great. However, his suggestion in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Give It Away</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 4</TIMEX>) that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> should save <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> because it would
be too awful if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> should lie again is absurd.

            Come on,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, you know better than that. Nevertheless, everyone, even

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, is allowed a brain seizure now and again.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bossingham Tokyo</ENAMEX>

            

               Publishme
            

            About the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 8</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Readme":</ENAMEX>
You can justify withholding the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>'s article in a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozen</NUMEX> different ways, but the fact remains that because of the financial
liability to your parent company you decided not to publish a story that your
training and experience as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> indicated was important and ought to be
told.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
Lipsey <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  Commentary Comments
            

            Though I have some
disagreements with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 5</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>," and though I believe she has been less than fair in
several of her comments about my work, I am nevertheless indebted to her for
taking up some of the questions I raised about <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> scholarship in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commentary</ENAMEX> .

            To begin with, though I
consider some of the things being written about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> by feminist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> to be offensive, even shocking, I have never suggested answering them
with censorship or anything of the sort. I am only in favor of subjecting them
to criticism, which is what I have done in the pages of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commentary</ENAMEX> , and
which I was heartened to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shulevitz</ENAMEX> has herself now done in

                  Slate
               .

            Nor do I believe that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extermination of Europe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> is a "religious topic" that is or should be
beyond discussion. I made it quite clear in Commentary that I favor
serious research and teaching about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> in a university setting, and
I have never suggested otherwise. I do, however, oppose the propagation of
nonsense--a word that applies with precision to many things being written these
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ofer-Weitzman</ENAMEX> book, Women in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> , rightly held up
for disapproval by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shulevitz</ENAMEX>, is by no means the worst of its kind. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> who
want to see how memory of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> is being twisted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of a
contemporary political cause should turn to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> issue of
Commentary and examine some of the passages I quote from the writings of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Ringelheim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of education at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Holocaust Memorial Museum</ENAMEX>.
She is hardly a marginal academic in a fringe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>; in fact, she
occupies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most important positions in the field.

            Finally, I was more than a
little troubled and perplexed by the charge that I engage in distortion. In the
only instance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shulevitz</ENAMEX> provides, I stand accused of taking a word from an
obscure feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> and repeating it "throughout" my piece for rhetorical
effect. She also suggests, without elaborating, that I have committed other
even more serious distortions.

            Yet the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> example Shulevitz
puts forward is about as thin as the paper 
                  Slate
                is not printed
on. Far from incessantly repeating the word "malestream," I use it only twice.
And I hardly drew it from a hard to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. I was citing a basic text, a
special issue of the journal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contemporary Jewry</ENAMEX> devoted to "gender" and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referenced</ENAMEX> in virtually every book on this subject. I hope I am
not being "shrill" in pointing out that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> is readily available in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Public Library</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shulevitz</ENAMEX> claims to have combed.

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>," we are told, "intends to make a habit of ruling on disputes" of
the sort I provoked in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Commentary</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shulevitz</ENAMEX> would help it acquire some
welcome credibility in its rulings if she were also to make a habit of being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schoenfeld</ENAMEX> Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Commentary New York City</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shulevitz</ENAMEX> replies:
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel Schoenfeld</ENAMEX> has a
point, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>--who sometimes writes too much, too fast--must concede
it. The word "censorship" was ill-chosen. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schoenfeld</ENAMEX> doesn't have the authority
to censor anybody and was only exercising his right as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> to damn entire
fields of endeavor. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> ought to have said is that, as a
responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> at a publication as serious as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Commentary</ENAMEX> , Schoenfeld
should think about the language he uses when he does damn entire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX> of
endeavor. Is everything that comes out of the latter-day study of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> says latter-day because he exempts chroniclers of the
ghetto from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX>) "execrable," "one of the worst excesses" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holocaust</ENAMEX> studies, and "nakedly ideological"? It is true that he only uses
"malestream" twice, but he quotes it in order to imply that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>
everywhere are using it at every turn. ("Mainstream scholarship on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genocide</ENAMEX>, we are being told on every side, is not so much mainstream as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'malestream</ENAMEX>.' ") There isn't a field of study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> couldn't make
ridiculous simply by quoting its more unappealing jargon. Does Schoenfeld
really mean to compare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> writing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who died in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> with "a
narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> living somewhere on a commune and insisting on a macabre sisterhood
with the dead <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>"?
            

            
               Strange
as it may seem to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> writing outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX>, attacks as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mean-spirited</ENAMEX> as his have real consequences inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX>--particularly on
the funding, tenuring, and acceptance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> under attack. Just ask any
literature <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> how quickly <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> departments
flushed out their theory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mavens</ENAMEX> once deconstruction became a dirty word. Or try
to find a job for a Ph.D. specializing in cultural studies now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Sokal</ENAMEX>
has made a laughingstock of the field. Not that these particular movements
didn't deserve ridicule, mind you. But it behooves both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schoenfeld</ENAMEX> and
Culturebox, with the prestige and reach of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> such as Commentary
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> behind them, to pause for a deep breath before we relegate
entire categories of scholarship to the dustbin of intellectual
history.
            

            

               Snakepit
            

            Thanks so
much, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>, for planning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my weekend</TIMEX> for me. Make that canceling my
weekend because, prior to reading your review of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Snake Eyes</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trigonometry</ENAMEX>,"
I had planned to see the actual movie version, and now I needn't bother. Your
review not only told me I would hate the ending but gave such detailed
descriptions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> the shots in the film that I was left with the feeling I
had already seen the entire thing. All I need now is a CD of the music and a
bag of popcorn. Your writing has the power to evoke strong visual images in the
mind's eye and for that very reason I feel you should show restraint when
reviewing a film early in its release. I found myself thanking the celluloid
gods I had missed your review of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Crying Game</ENAMEX> .

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer Fort Worth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX> replies:
            

            
               The
sequence I detailed was from the middle of the picture, occupied <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> of screen time, and was evoked because it illustrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Palma</ENAMEX>'s film
syntax better than the usual dumb <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">adjectives</ENAMEX>. I didn't give away any plot
surprises; read the review in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> if you want to know
them. (I didn't even say who the villain was, although it's so obvious--and is
even in the coming attractions!--as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have.) And if I think that the
ending is a major dud and DON'T say so in print, then as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> I've been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">derelict</ENAMEX> in my duties--especially if said (undescribed) ending left an
otherwise friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> pissed off. See <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Snake Eyes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next weekend</TIMEX> and
let me know if I really spoiled it for you.
            

            
               Why Guilt
May <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Set You Free</ENAMEX>
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Everyday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E. Landsburg</ENAMEX> misses the point when he compares the
damage done by letting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> guilty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go free with the damage done by
convicting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. He is right to try to quantify the costs, but
he should include all the costs.

            The trouble with a legal
system that allows a significant probability of convicting innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is
that it allows unscrupulous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> to become petty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tyrants</ENAMEX>. Will you stand
up to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who can put you at significant risk of conviction with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trumped-up</ENAMEX> case? Private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> could also tyrannize each other: What will you
do if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> threatens to frame you for some crime, and you know the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> might convict you on borderline evidence? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landsburg</ENAMEX> should count not
only the cost to innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of going to jail but also the cost in liberty
when they must cave in to threats of slander or malicious prosecution.

            We see this now in our tort
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, where innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> routinely cave in to threats of lawsuits.

            Of course
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackstone</ENAMEX> knew that it would be better to convict one innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> than let
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> go free if the effects were limited to those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> cases. He was
concerned with the effect on everyone else.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stromquist Berwyn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must include their address and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
