
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Ad
Nauseam
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Surowiecki</ENAMEX> ("Buy This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX>!") would like us to believe that the reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are jettisoning
their advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> is because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> don't know how to market
themselves. In fact, much more has changed than meets the eye.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Ogilvy</ENAMEX> started
his ad agency, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> looked at ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> as marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>.
They would approach an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and basically say: "Here's our product. How do we
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> it?" Consequently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> were able to attract the top marketing talent
around. On the research and account <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> side, this meant the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MBAs</ENAMEX>.
And, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> expected elite services from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, they were
willing to pay the high salaries such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> demand.

            That's changed. Management
consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> realized that ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> had tapped a lucrative market in
selling marketing services. And they already had a cadre of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MBAs</ENAMEX> from the top
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. Suddenly, ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> were faced with substantial competition for one
of their basic services. Eventually, they were no longer able to compete for
the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MBAs</ENAMEX>, because these weren't the services their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> were
demanding.

            I don't really think it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> to characterize this shift as a "marketing problem." I think it was a
fundamental shift in thinking on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> side. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agencies</ENAMEX> had been seen as
marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>. Now they're seen as service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX>, not unlike any other
outsourced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX>.

            Today, we
have the sad situation where most marketing decisions are made long before ad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> get involved. Typically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> calls an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and says: "Here's
the strategy. Execute it as cheaply as possible." That's a big change.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feldman</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX>
Brides for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven Geeks</ENAMEX>
            

            What
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New Organization Marriage"</ENAMEX>) doesn't mention is that these
so-called power marriages are ever the same. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restoration</ENAMEX> comedy, the
normative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>--he the rake and she the one who will never, ever agree to
marry anyone--find themselves in society (read: office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>) at the
highest levels and must prove themselves to one another by being bright,
competent, and able to handle lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in their circle. Having done so,
they finally agree to marry but with stipulations: She has privacy, freedom to
pursue her own life and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, control over money, etc. The deal is struck
and creates a new kind of marriage--or so they hope. She wins the admiration of
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> for landing the rake and he wins by landing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">filly</ENAMEX> who was known
as impossible to break. Status achieved.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Geldard
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disheartened</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
            

            I thought
you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> would be quicker off the mark. It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pea</ENAMEX>-soupy spring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, and I was looking forward to a cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> and dose of

                  Slate
                to sort out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s beating the Jones rap. Instead,
you're still leading with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> apology
("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sorry Excuse"</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cullen Murphy</ENAMEX>'s discourse on lying ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lie of the</ENAMEX>
Land"). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX>'s OK ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>")
but kinda warmed over and unsatisfying. I count on you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> for instant
analysis, not the play-by-play. I don't know if it's connected, but you were
quicker when you were free. After anteing up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> to subscribe I still
love you, but this morning I'm disappointed.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferziger Hong Kong</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
