
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Papist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defines Papal Bull</ENAMEX>
            

            I note the headline in
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s
Papers" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 17</TIMEX>), by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papal Bull</ENAMEX>." Clearly, this refers to
the important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> document "We Remember," a reflection on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shoah</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">document</ENAMEX> expresses repentance for actions of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shoah</ENAMEX>. Of
course, this document is historic and groundbreaking, but it is not a bull.

            I quote
from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Church Visible: The Ceremonial Life</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Protocol</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James-Charles Noonan Jr.</ENAMEX>, Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">395</NUMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Apostolic bull</ENAMEX>: A document
that derives its name from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> bulla , meaning "leaden seal," which
is used to imprint the reigning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s insignia, or seal, on the document. The
most solemn of the papal documents, the bull creates a prelate a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cardinal</ENAMEX>
(although the biglietto announces it). Bishops are officially appointed
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">papal bull</ENAMEX>, as are other high-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. It is also the document
that announces beatifications and canonizations.

            (I recommend this book for

                  Slate
               's reference <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>--it has all manner of interesting facts
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> and is quite authoritative.)

            I know
that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> commonly use the term papal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bull</ENAMEX> to describe almost any
document coming from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy See</ENAMEX>, but you are 
                  Slate
               , and thus
seek the highest standards. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> is a helpful service--I'm just
trying to make it more helpful.

            -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent J.</ENAMEX>
Rigdon, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C.L.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of the MissionsArchdiocese</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>

            
               Lawyer
Says <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lawyer Lied About Lying Lawyers</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Feige</ENAMEX>'s comments about
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lying Lawyers</ENAMEX>" were
not far off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>--if the target was set up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 1975</TIMEX>.
But since he appears to be talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> functioning in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> generally, and he appears to be talking about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997 and 1998</TIMEX>, he's not
even close.

            As many of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> may
know--but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyer Feige</ENAMEX> apparently does not--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX>
adopted a new code in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Model Rules of Professional Conduct</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> rules have been adopted (usually with amendments) in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 40</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> jurisdictions (not including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> rules explicitly
reject virtually everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feige</ENAMEX> said in his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist</ENAMEX>" piece.

            I'm the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the leading treatises on legal ethics--and it's updated
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. But don't take my word for it. Ask any current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> of legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ethics</ENAMEX> in any law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> ( including a law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>).

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hodes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> of lawIndiana <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University School of LawIndianapolis</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feige</ENAMEX> replies: The point of my piece was not to examine the minor
differences between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Model Rules of Professional Conduct</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Model Code</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professional Responsibility</ENAMEX> --a subject that I am sure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hodes</ENAMEX> has examined in a more lengthy tome--but rather to discuss the
application of the code (or rules) in the real world.
            

            
               It is
surprising to me that someone as well known and erudite as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hodes</ENAMEX> can fail to
grasp the simple thesis of my piece--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> apply their analytical skills
to the rules of professional responsibility much as they do to any other text.
That <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want zealous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> to defend their interests, and as a
consequence, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">zealousness</ENAMEX> tends to gain the upper hand in the battle between
aggressive advocacy and restrained, dignified legal conduct. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> will
interpret the rules to maximize their ability to do what they believe is in the
best interests of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, and this is made easier by the porous
construction of both the Rules and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Code</ENAMEX> . Whether this is a
good thing is a subject worth discussing; whether it happens is obvious. And
not just in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Bronx</ENAMEX>, where I practice, but in every jurisdiction from
municipal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Code</ENAMEX> states and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rule</ENAMEX> states
alike.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Weisberg</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Watcher</ENAMEX>
            

            I'm going to break with
tradition and write about something I've enjoyed recently about

                  Slate
                rather than something about which I have <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ants</ENAMEX> in the pants.
Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year and a half</TIMEX> that I've been reading his column in

                  Slate
               , the tone of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s columns has consistently been
somewhat cynical and worldly about the political process he covers. In recent
columns, however, I have greatly enjoyed seeing his intelligent skepticism
pointed as much toward the media as toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. What's most
noticeable about his columns on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal is that his viewpoint is
unique among all those emanating from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. It's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carville</ENAMEX>-style partisan critique (one could hardly peg <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>), and it's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Ivins</ENAMEX>-style "quit drooling over inconsequential sex"
critique. It's a critique that takes on the cultural attitude and assumptions
of the press and how those assumptions slant their journalism, and it's
refreshing.

            The most
recent column ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica"</ENAMEX>) makes a much-needed point about the
subtly condescending nature of traditional journalism's attitude toward
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> (a column in the future might explore the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>' similar
attitude toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>). From the article about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>'s distaste for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> through the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatch</ENAMEX>"
entries and the column about why the press feels the need to take
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> down, I have greatly enjoyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s writings. More
importantly--and much rarer--I have learned a lot. Keep up the good work.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
Colon <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>

            
               I'm King
of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-Year-Old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Imagination</ENAMEX>!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> does a lovely, lovely job on the absolutely deserving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Eszterhas</ENAMEX>
("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>"). I've followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eszterhas</ENAMEX>' leaden touch since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F.I.S.T.</ENAMEX> , and for my diligence, got written into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burn Hollywood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burn</ENAMEX> , complete with an invitation to play "myself," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Benson</ENAMEX>. When
calm legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">acquaintance</ENAMEX> advised him that neither I nor my name were
available, he changed it, I see, to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Maslin</ENAMEX>." Still and all, I have to
say that the title of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> imagination still unequivocally
rests with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Cameron</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> be damned.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Benson</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
