
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Hot
Threads
            

            For obvious reasons,
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Scene</ENAMEX>" was the hottest thread in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>" this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> nuclear detonations on the effectiveness of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> sanctions.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> crisis figured prominently <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all week</TIMEX>, with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>-based
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fraygrant</ENAMEX> filing regular . By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week's end</TIMEX>, the focus had shifted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>'s
role in the unrest: Does the fund and its "economic groupies have something big
to answer for"? Or, as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> hand maintains, is "the cause of the
present problem in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> or the
cupidity of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX>, the living incarnation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
Family Values"?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s statements
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> situation also sparked discussion: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">She "</ENAMEX>never, ever had any
business making policy statements, let alone take part in policy-making" vs.
"She certainly has a right to speak without being accused of wearing the pants
in the presidency."

            A clear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal is atrophying: The "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'98</NUMEX>" threads all but mirrored each other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. Politics <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'98</NUMEX> featured
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX> and tax reform, missile-guidance <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems</ENAMEX>, school
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vouchers</ENAMEX>, and inherited wealth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> thread, meanwhile, began to feature
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> and tax reform and missile-guidance <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems</ENAMEX>. Noting the similarities, one
astute fraygrant suggested restricting more civilized, high-minded debate to
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics</ENAMEX>" and reserving "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>" for equally important venal, mean-spirited
exchanges.

            
               New
Threads
            

            Did you know that the average
sexual encounter for a bonobo a) occurs with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the same sex and b)
lasts <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a mere 13 seconds</TIMEX>? This is just one of many interesting facts that
surfaced in the new "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay</ENAMEX>
Life" thread, which has discussed everything from genetics to friendships
to prejudice. Is homophobia innate or a repressive cultural construct? Should
gays be accorded equal rights by law in all respects, including social
practices such as marriage? (According to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX>,"All biological,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sociobiological</ENAMEX> and historical realities are irrelevant to gay rights.") Should
the sexual orientation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Bloom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kauffmann</ENAMEX>, or Proust be factored
into of their writing? Is it reasonable to assume a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is straight until
proven otherwise? Are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ménages à</ENAMEX> trois relatively rare?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conspiracies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>" in 
                  Slate
                inspired a new "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Conspiracies</ENAMEX>" thread, with testimonials from "basement wackos"
interested in the connections between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientology</ENAMEX> and even
the nebulous "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">America Mystica</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> have kept things real thus far,
questioning why secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX> remain secret, what constitutes conspiratorial
thought, and what differentiates the aforementioned wackos from legitimate
psychodrama connoisseurs.

            
               Art
Smart
            

            

               
                  Slate
               's review of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Rothko</ENAMEX> exhibit at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery of Art</ENAMEX>
raised questions on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abstract Expressionism</ENAMEX> and nonrepresentational art in
general in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX>" thread. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> art and art history to be able to
appreciate a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothko</ENAMEX>? Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fraygrants</ENAMEX> find his colorfield paintings
peaceful, others find them oppressive. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> fraygrant commented on the nature of
art criticism, saying, "I'm not saying that non-representational painting is
bad; just that there is more bullshit attached to such paintings than others."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mondrian</ENAMEX>'s later offerings came in for a drubbing, though his early
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">representational</ENAMEX> work appears popular.

         
      
   
