
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NewsHour</ENAMEX> Takes Umbrage
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>"
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 15</TIMEX> alleges <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> was not truthful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> when he explained
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor</ENAMEX> was dropped as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. The 
                  Slate
                column alleges the reason was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> had
had conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> about a job with the independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. That is absolutely wrong. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> appeared on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NewsHour</ENAMEX> during the period when we knew he was talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lester M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal</ENAMEX> , executive producer <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s note: As we
read that column, we find no allegation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> was not truthful. Any
such implication was certainly unintentional. 
            

            
               Defending
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dad</ENAMEX>
            

            This e-mail is in regard to
the unfair, as well as poorly researched, article about my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis Gates Jr.</ENAMEX> It is very seldom that I take notice of any
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> that even mentions my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. This one caught my eye, not only because
of the ridiculous picture of him on the front, but also the numerous pages of
incompetent work.

            I have
grown to know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s faults over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, and yes, in many cases people
are blind to them. I, for one, think they should be. Never in my life have I
seen a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> so dedicated. I do not mention only one thing he is particularly
dedicated to, because I see him on a day-to-day basis, going to work and doing
a job that only he could ever do. He never ever leaves the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> before
completing a daily routine that he has done <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> for as long as I've known
him. Part of the routine includes bringing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every morning</TIMEX> to
start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">her day</TIMEX>, making sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is in order, kissing us all goodbye, and
then taking care of himself. Although I don't think any of our
home life is even any of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, I had to comment on the fact that you
quoted him as saying he was a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>. If in fact he said that,
I am sorry. He is a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and I would be the only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to ever know if that is true. Printing it in your little article
was, for lack of better words, stupid. I also know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> loves to do a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> things at once. That fact holds true wherever we go. Even on slow,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laid-back</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> getaways, where no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who is trying to get some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> can follow us. When he reaches the last thing on the list, it may
not be done to the best of his unsurpassable ability, but it wasn't due to any
fault of his own. He is an amazing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, it is true, but he gets tired like the
best of them do. You can understand that, can't you? You seem to have slept a
little bit while you were writing this article. And you can quote me when I say
that this article was an insult to your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Helen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Gates</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Interesting Conflict Over Conflict of Interest</ENAMEX>
            

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ethics Upside Down</ENAMEX>," he notes that there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> possible reasons
why conflict of interest is a bad thing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The conflict causes
some kind of personal advantage to distort either your perception of the truth
or your willingness to honestly state what you perceive. In other words, it
amounts to a bribe. Or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) the conflict reveals a previously hidden incentive or
tendency to misperceive or misstate the truth.

            But I
think he misses an important reason: Though the conflict may not reveal a
previously hidden incentive (as in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>), it may create one. That is, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>'s aim before the conflict may have been to present the truth as
accurately as he could--whether additionally inserting his own opinion or
not--without any hidden incentive or tendency to misstate the truth present.
But the conflict itself might create such a tendency or incentive. I
cannot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor</ENAMEX> fell prey to this possibility. But he
certainly could have been instilled with a tendency to misrepresent in order to
please a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>. Lastly, his incentive need not be financial (a
"bribe"). It could be any one or combination of a number of things, including
power, prestige, or even misplaced ethical values (values that he thought were
right, even if they were, in fact, not). Again, all this is not to say that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> is guilty of such an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>. But it should not be so quickly ruled
out.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Silver Spring</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>

            
               Country
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Road, Take Me Home</ENAMEX>
            

            It may be the last publicly
acceptable stereotype in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> journalism: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appalachian</ENAMEX>. "Dear
Prudence" disparaged this ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> with a statement that would be
regarded as reckless racism if written about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> or some other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ethnic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is not the only or the last to do this but only the
latest. I have observed these slurs on television, radio, and print <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. I
marvel at how supposedly sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> can speak, write, or edit
such transparently untrue and vicious statements.

            You can
and should do better than this.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Booth</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butterfield Morgantown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.Va.</ENAMEX>

            
               How Much
Is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That Hund in the Window</ENAMEX>?
            

            
Apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Steyn</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Worst Songwriter of All Time</ENAMEX>") has never heard the truly worst
of all time. I have. While stationed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954 and '55</TIMEX>, I heard
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> radio play "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wieviel kostet der Hund im Fenster?</ENAMEX> " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wow</ENAMEX>!

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mort</ENAMEX>
Weintraub
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
