
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s
Willing Historiographers
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s Willing
Executioners," his review of my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Nation on Trial</ENAMEX> [hereafter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANOT</ENAMEX> ], <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Shatz</ENAMEX> suggests that I am a mirror image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Goldhagen</ENAMEX>.
My essay is "equally biased and inflammatory," he writes, and whereas Goldhagen
delivered a fierce attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>, my own essay is effectively an
"apologia" for them.

            Before turning to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shatz</ENAMEX>'s
specific criticisms, I want to remind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of the approach I adopted in my
analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s book. Throughout, I simply juxtapose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s claims
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> he cites or compare his claims to the standard, mainstream
scholarly findings. Until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shatz</ENAMEX>'s review, no one disputed my account of the
scholarly record. Indeed, his vehement criticisms of my essay notwithstanding,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> himself does not accuse me of misrepresenting current scholarly
wisdom. Thus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shatz</ENAMEX>'s altogether novel critique merits close scrutiny.

            Shatz reports that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> acknowledges the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> was a brutal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>, but he
glosses over its disturbingly popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>."

            What can
Shatz possibly mean? Goldhagen claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> "was, on the whole
consensual," and that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> generally "accepted the system and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> as desirable and legitimate." I report that, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s
own main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Gellately</ENAMEX>, fear was "prevalent among the German
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," and that to pretend otherwise is "foolish" ( ANOT : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX>). Clearly
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> question, however, is how central was anti-Semitism to what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shatz</ENAMEX>
calls the "disturbingly popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>? I quote this
typical passage from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s main source, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Kershaw</ENAMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anti-Semitism</ENAMEX>, despite its
pivotal place in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s "world view," was of only secondary importance in
cementing the bonds between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fuhrer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> which provided the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Reich</ENAMEX>
with its popular legitimation and basis of plebiscitary acclamation. At the
same time, the principle of excluding the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> society was itself
widely and increasingly popular, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s hatred of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>--baleful in
its threats but linked to the condoning of lawful, "rational" action, not the
unpopular crude violence and brutality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>'s "gutter" elements--was
certainly an acceptable component of his popular image, even if it was an
element "taken on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>" rather than forming a centrally motivating factor for
most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>.

            I add that, according to
Kershaw, "during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> ... when his popularity was soaring to dizzy
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">heights</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> "was extremely careful to avoid public association with the
generally unpopular pogrom-type <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> outrages" ( ANOT : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shatz</ENAMEX> is surely within his
right to question these findings. But he ought to have directed his ire not at
me but at the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> on the subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gellately</ENAMEX>, who was just
appointed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> chair at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clark University</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kershaw</ENAMEX>, author of
the forthcoming <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-volume biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shatz</ENAMEX> alleges that
"anti-Semitism permeated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> ideology, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> is deaf to its
nuances." Thus he proposes that anti-Semitism was crucial to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s rise to
power. Citing a raft of scholarly studies, I report the consensus that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-Semitism</ENAMEX> did not figure centrally in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s electoral successes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX>
and thereafter ( ANOT : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31-2</NUMEX>). I also note the scholarly consensus that,
beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>--to quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Friedlander</ENAMEX> in his authoritative
study , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazi Germany</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> --"the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> theme did become less
frequent in [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s] rhetoric." Finally, I report that a careful review of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Domarus</ENAMEX>' standard collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s public pronouncements and speeches
shows that, during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these years</TIMEX>, the main negative theme was anti-Marxism and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anti-Social Democracy</ENAMEX> ( ANOT : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shatz</ENAMEX> seems to believe that he has
"scooped" all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> in the field with his clever insight that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perceived Social Democracy</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and Marxism as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> creed."
The scholarly question, however, is why did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> tone down the explicitly
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> theme," if not because it didn't resonate well with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shatz</ENAMEX> doesn't answer this question; indeed, he can't even comprehend it. To
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s credit, he never gainsays this commonplace of the scholarly
literature. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shatz</ENAMEX>, he is familiar enough with the discipline to know
that it would be preposterous to do so.

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shatz</ENAMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> deduces from some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>' disgust at the destruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
lives and property during <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>-sponsored pogroms such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kristallnacht</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Germans</ENAMEX> overwhelmingly condemned the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> atrocities.' If they
did, they gave new meaning to the term 'silent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>.' "

            Of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shatz</ENAMEX>'s distortions,
this is the most outrageous. Where does he get his reading of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kristallnacht</ENAMEX>?
Here's where mine comes from. In assessing the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> reaction to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
violence generally and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kristallnacht</ENAMEX> in particular, I quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s
authoritative scholarly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bankier</ENAMEX>, as well as
Kershaw:

            During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first years</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> incitement [says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bankier</ENAMEX>], most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> ("large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX>,"
"the bulk," "sizable parts") found "the form of persecution abhorrent,"
expressed "misgivings about the brutal methods employed," "remained on the
sidelines," "severely condemned the persecution," etc. With the revival of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
anti-Semitic terror in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>, "large sections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> were repelled by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sturmer</ENAMEX> methods and refused to comply with demands to take action against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>." Indeed, the "vast majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> approved the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nuremberg</ENAMEX>
laws" not only because they "identified with the racialist policy" but
"especially" because "a permanent framework of discrimination had been created
that would end the reign of terror and set precise limits to antisemitic
activities." "Sturmer methods and the violence" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years 1936-37</TIMEX> "met with
the same disapproval as in the past." "The overwhelming majority approved
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> segregation and economic destruction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>" on the eve of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kristallnacht</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX> "but not the outbursts of brute force. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]t was not
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>-hatred in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> sense." "All sections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>," Bankier
further reports, "reacted with shock" to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kristallnacht</ENAMEX>. "There were few
occasions, if any, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Reich</ENAMEX>," Kershaw similarly recalls, "which
produced such a widespread wave of revulsion," reaching "deep into the ranks"
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> itself. The motives behind these outpourings of popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disgust</ENAMEX>, to be sure, were not unalloyed. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> evinced moral outrage.
Some recoiled from the sheer brutality of the violence (which also defaced
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s image). Some opposed the destruction only because it squandered
material resources ( ANOT : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX>).

            The opinions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shatz</ENAMEX> ascribes
to me are simply the scholarly consensus. Significantly, he adduces not a jot
of counterevidence for his novel claim that only "some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>" opposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kristallnacht</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, there is none. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shatz</ENAMEX> also violently dissents from the
scholarly consensus on civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> attitudes toward <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>
II. Yet again, however, he cites precisely zero evidence to support his
objections.

            To
sustain his claim that my essay is effectively an "apologia," Shatz substitutes
appeals to popular prejudice for scholarship. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shatz</ENAMEX> calls me <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s
"doppelganger." It would seem that this honorific more properly belongs to
him.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman G.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finkelstein Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Adam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shatz</ENAMEX> replies:
            

            In his reply, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s modus operandi is to cite authority, and where he cannot hide
behind authority, he distorts the points I made in my review. He insinuates
that I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Goldhagen</ENAMEX>, even though I made my hostility to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s views amply clear elsewhere in the review. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s
attempt to tar me with the brush of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagenism</ENAMEX> is telling. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>,
anyone who views <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> anti-Semitism as in any way significant to the history
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Socialism</ENAMEX> is an accomplice of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Nowhere in my review do I argue that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-Semitism</ENAMEX> was "crucial to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s rise to power." Rather, I argue that it
cannot be blithely discounted, as is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s wont. In wooing German
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> did tone down their anti-Semitism, emphasizing instead their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist</ENAMEX> and anti-Bolshevik credentials. But unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>, I see a
change in degree, not in kind. Anti-Semitism remained a constant theme of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ideology</ENAMEX>, which associated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> with the ills of modern capitalism,
internationalism, socialism, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Versailles Treaty</ENAMEX>. While it's true that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> were often alienated by violent expressions of anti-Semitism, enough of
them were willing to look past <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> rhetoric about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> problem to make
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazis Germany</ENAMEX>'s most significant mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Kershaw</ENAMEX> writes in the
passage cited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>, anti-Semitism was "an acceptable component of
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s] popular image." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, a similar development has occurred
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Marie Le Pen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Front</ENAMEX> has softened his
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> racism in order to attract more votes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Employing Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s logic,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> would have to argue racism hasn't really figured in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Pen</ENAMEX>'s surge in
popularity. But it's a distinction without a difference--more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
are backing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> known for its racist program. It's a wonder that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> doesn't see how damning this is. But then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> finds
reassurance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s observation that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> ideologues
advocated the annihilation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> would perhaps also want to note
that an overwhelming majority did not," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> writes.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s
interpretation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kristallnacht</ENAMEX> is not "simply the scholarly consensus." While
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">evoking German</ENAMEX> outrage at such state-sponsored pogroms, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bankier</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kershaw</ENAMEX> do not conclude that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> overwhelmingly condemned
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> atrocities." Where does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> find evidence of such
condemnation? Were there such protests as later surrounded the euthanasia
programs for the retarded? Were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> moved to speak out against the popular
legal restrictions on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> rights? In a study much cited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> and the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Question</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Gordon</ENAMEX> writes
that "Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> were apathetic to the persecution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and no study,
past or future, can ever change that fact." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> does not have to accept
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s views to see that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>' disgust at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kristallnacht</ENAMEX> seldom
resulted in action on behalf of their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
Finally, does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> suppose that a brutal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX> cannot also be a
popular one? As most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> have recognized, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s triumphs in foreign
policy and the economy earned him the admiration of many, if not most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>.
If the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> had rested only on coercion, it's doubtful that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> could
have persuaded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> to remain loyal to him, and to fight
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heroically</ENAMEX> to the end of the war. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kershaw</ENAMEX> writes in the passage quoted by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> state enjoyed a certain "popular legitimation and basis
of plebiscitary acclamation." Although anti-Semitism was less significant than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nationalism</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Bolshevism</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>' mass appeal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> and his peers
were able to execute the Final Solution because they could count on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">allegiance</ENAMEX>, and sometimes even the love, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. To be sure,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s vision of a "consensual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>" glosses over the repression
of the labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>, the killing and imprisonment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s view of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> terror state forcing its programs on a helpless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is equally one-sided. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> were homegrown populists, even if their
wish to murder <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> was not widely shared by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> must, in
turn, bear some of the responsibility for the horrors the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> inflicted.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s note:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s
Willing Executioners" incorrectly stated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian Jewish Congress</ENAMEX>
is trying to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Bettina Birn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Nation on Trial: The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Goldhagen Thesis and Historical Truth</ENAMEX> , removed from her job at the war
crimes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian Department of Justice</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> did contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> with its concerns about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birn</ENAMEX>'s involvement
in the book. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CJC</ENAMEX> has lodged no formal complaint against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birn</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Gross
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Product</ENAMEX>
            

            In
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX> wrote:

            I wonder if the work of
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> [watching for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>] is in the GDP. Of course, it
wouldn't be. They are an input. The output will be a shot on television of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, and the value of that will be in the GDP.

            No, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>. The shot on
television of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> will not be in the GDP--at least, it will not be
in the GDP if the shot is on network television. You see, no one pays
for network television: No one spends money to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> coming out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watergate</ENAMEX>.

            Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> spend
money to show commercials on network television: The picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is
just an input into the provision of advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are
willing to pay for.

            But wait! Advertising
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> are not an output, but an input. Businesses pay for advertising
services as a way of moving their products. Advertising services are an input
to the cost of production of whatever is being advertised.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">photographer</ENAMEX>'s work will make it into the GDP only when someone buys a bottle
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tylenol</ENAMEX>, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick</ENAMEX>, or whatever is advertised on the news show in which the
picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is shown.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad DeLong</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX> replies:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLong</ENAMEX> is right and I thank him for the correction. I also thank him
for leaving me a tiny out in those cases where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> is seen on cable.
            

            
               Not Hip
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skip</ENAMEX>
            

            Thanks
for your article on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis Gates Jr.</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>," by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>). It was appreciated, although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' brazen efforts at
self-promotion on the basis of increasingly poor scholarship have been the talk
among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> for some time. My only regret is that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> wasn't even more hard-hitting.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monroe H. Little</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr</ENAMEX> .

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Completely Dead</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partially White Men</ENAMEX>
            

            The
list
(footnoted to the piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis Gates Jr.</ENAMEX>) of dead white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> excluded from
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary of Global Culture</ENAMEX> includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexandre Dumas</ENAMEX>, who was,
in fact, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-quarter</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX>, which makes this snub of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most
productive and popular novelists of all time all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>. (Did that other
mixed-race <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pushkin</ENAMEX>, make the cut?) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dumas</ENAMEX> received the same sort of
accusation that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> makes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, of overusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of uncredited
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">collaborators</ENAMEX> and thus diluting the value of his name. His work appears to have
survived, despite his exclusion from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary</ENAMEX> .

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles R.L.</ENAMEX>
Power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
