
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Chasing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Damon</ENAMEX>
            

            In your
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 18</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinstein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, you state that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miramax</ENAMEX> was
"the driving force" between various independent movies, among them
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clerks</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trainspotting</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Il Postino</ENAMEX> . The wording of your
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> partook in the creation of those movies, when in
fact they were funded and filmed without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax's</ENAMEX> assistance, and then Miramax
bought and distributed them. Similarly, your suggestion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> "eschews
expensive stars" and "uses novices" such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Damon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Will</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunting</ENAMEX> suggests that the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX> in the lead role was the result of
an aesthetic, or perhaps moral, decision on the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinstein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>.
In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>, who was one of the movie's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, attached himself to the
project as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> as a condition of its purchase. True, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> were not
fond of "using novices," they might have rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>'s condition. But it's
also worth mentioning that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey Weinstein</ENAMEX>'s interest in funding <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Will</ENAMEX>
Hunting was not spurred by his own finely tuned aesthetic sensibilities but
rather by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Smith</ENAMEX>, a golden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> after the profitable release of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chasing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX> , who delivered the script for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good Will Hunting to Weinstein</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and insisted that it be made. The moral here is to remember the
difference between the ability to recognize quality and the ability to create
it out of whole cloth.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Bennett</ENAMEX>
Cohn
            

            

               Chatterbox, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eat Your Hat</ENAMEX>!
            

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 6</TIMEX>
"Chatterbox" accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fob James</ENAMEX> of
"down-and-dirty," "soulless," and "win-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-cost" politics because they called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Arrington</ENAMEX> a "liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>" and printed his picture when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arrington</ENAMEX> endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>' primary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>. My, my, aren't we sensitive. What part isn't true? And what is wrong
with reminding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arrington</ENAMEX> is black? Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> claiming that race
is politically irrelevant? And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arrington</ENAMEX> isn't being made into a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Horton</ENAMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>"? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is equating the pairing of one's political opponent
with a violent criminal to the pairing of one's political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>? I hope he will be similarly concerned the next time a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> is
roughed up a little.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Welte</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The
Strong, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Silent Type</ENAMEX>
            

            About the following item in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 16</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>": "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs a completely positive account of
the productive and powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> that has developed between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>, especially regarding international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s
issues such as the handling of rape charges at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rwanda War Crimes Tribunal</ENAMEX>,
and clamping down on the international prostitution trade. So what does it say
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Lady</ENAMEX> that for this article she not only declined to be
interviewed but even declined to answer written questions?"

            Perhaps
it says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> feels that she can accomplish more in the real
world by doing rather than talking, or perhaps she feels that the public has
had its fill of interviews and answers to written questions from such female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">luminaries</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. Get real!!!

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
Tartow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SenateNew Hampshire</ENAMEX>

            
               All
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
            

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 16</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> asks what it says about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> that she
refused to comment for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> story on her partnership with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>.

            My
response: It says that she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> have been under such a barrage of
unfair criticism for so long that she is keeping her head down. A low profile
is not always such a bad thing, especially when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> is all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Barnhill</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Down
With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX>'s assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> editorship in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Club</ENAMEX>" was brilliantly on the money. She replaced fine,
intelligent journalism with warmed-over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> pap and chased a lot of solid literary and artistic talent
out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and kept the door locked lest taste, God forbid, get
in.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weber Guilford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>

            
               Too Much
Sex ...
            

            Someday, I
am going to enter into 
                  Slate
               's online world and find nothing
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>, or anything involving the words "sex
scandal." Someday ...

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kiffin Smith</ENAMEX>
            

            
               ... And
Too Much Breakfast
            

            I love
the zine, and don't get me wrong about this, but go easy on "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>," OK? This "easy aces" number takes up way too much space.
A lot of us read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, too (I do as part of my job), but why let
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marjorie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX> hog so much of the book? If I want to have conversation about
the trivia of urban life, I can talk with my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>; and you can fill the
otherwise entertaining, informative, urbane, and whimsical pages of

                  Slate
                with things that I can't get at home.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Gray</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
