
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Hot
Threads
            

            In "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Scene" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>-based fraygrant kept the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fray</ENAMEX> informed of
breaking news in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. Following the announcement that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.J. Habibie</ENAMEX> would
be the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, was offered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> based there. Fraygrants
analyzed the Western media's take on events in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>; the consensus: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> deserve a failing grade.

            Even when something new
breaks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-scandal front, it takes on a familiar sound in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>." The regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-bashers the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s imminent downfall now
that he has been revealed as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitor</ENAMEX>" by selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> technology to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> suggested that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> hold off on the hanging
party until all the facts are in--and predicted that this scandal, too, would
soon blow over.

            
               New
Threads
            

            The 
                  Slate
               
dialogue on "McCarthyism" inspired a new thread, which this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> drew parallels with multiculturalism and . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> fraygrant recounted the
case of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canwell Committee</ENAMEX> red hunt and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melvin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rader</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Canwell</ENAMEX>'s later attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Goldmark</ENAMEX>, which
eventually led to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> murders of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldmarks</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthyism</ENAMEX> was seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. A fraygrant
even quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yogi Berra</ENAMEX>'s "It's déjà vu all over again." But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fraygrants</ENAMEX> maintained that it is the charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> that smack of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthyism</ENAMEX>: "You don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is being smeared. Many disagree."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX>'s

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article on Aldous Huxley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave New World</ENAMEX> led to
discussion in the corresponding thread. While most fraygrants felt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s conclusions left
something to be desired, the specific points were debated. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> fraygrant
wondered what was so wrong with the society in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave New World</ENAMEX> and
materialism, but others took exception to such a pessimistic view of life: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>
needn't assume the worst."

            The recent death of Frank
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> and 
                  Slate
               's article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz Democracy</ENAMEX>" prompted the
return of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music</ENAMEX>" thread. It began with a request for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> to list
their favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> or world music albums of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX>. Discussions
covered the merits of dance as a social and recreational activity ("facile" or
"spiritual"?), and of rhythm in music ("fascist"?), as well as commentary on
pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tori Amos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde composer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mauricio Kagel</ENAMEX>.

            
               Fray
Feuds
            

            The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bubble Economy</ENAMEX>" thread
began with a discussion of IQ and merit, which set the tone for the remainder
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>. From challenges to just how meritocratic the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy is to
rewarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for ability and outcomes, fraygrants laid out the various
economic and philosophical arguments supporting rewards for results vs. rewards
for hard work and effort. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> fraygrant fought against the tide and argued that
innate ability and inherited wealth should not be determinants of future
economic opportunity. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The week</TIMEX> ended with a discussion of the economic
rationale for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for both effort and performance
(outcomes) in an environment of imperfect information and joint production.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray</ENAMEX>'s reputation as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> for hostile, rude, and mean-spirited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> suffered a severe beating
at the hands of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reading</ENAMEX>" thread, which was so civilized that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
suggested taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> shots afterward. The discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>'s The
Sound <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">and the Fury</ENAMEX> wrapped up with a lively <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>'s
continuing relevance--particularly regarding race. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, the introduction
of a new Reading topic: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Pinker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Language Instinct</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
