
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hole in Your Logic</ENAMEX>
            

            In
"Big-Bang
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theology</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Holt</ENAMEX> writes:

            
               Maybe the universe had
a natural cause. But the big bang could not have been caused by prior
physical processes. That is because it began with pointlike singularity ,
which, according to relativity theory, is not a "thing" but a boundary or an
edge in time. Since no causal lines can be extended through it, the cause of
the big bang must transcend the physical world.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">black hole</ENAMEX>, according to modern physics, is also a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">singularity</ENAMEX>. So, does each and every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">black hole</ENAMEX> in the universe also
prove the existence of God, since, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holt</ENAMEX>'s argument as I understand
it, "prior physical processes" could not have created them either?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erich Schwarz</ENAMEX> New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX>
of Finiteness
            

            

               
                  Slate
                should probably know better than to publish an essay aimed
at deducing the existence of God. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Holt</ENAMEX>'s piece "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Bang Theology</ENAMEX>"
starts out that way, though he ultimately contents himself with the existence
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Cause</ENAMEX>. But he too quickly dismisses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hawking</ENAMEX>'s argument that
the finite age of the earth does not imply a beginning. To be sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawking</ENAMEX>'s
explanation is rather convoluted. Let me see if I can find a simpler way to
present his view. Suppose that our position in time is represented by a
positive (that is, non-negative and nonzero) number. Then at each moment we
know that only a finite amount of time has elapsed (if we're at time <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, then we
know that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no more than 5</NUMEX> units of time have passed). But note that there is no
first moment: if we're at time t, then time t<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2</NUMEX>, which is unequal to t, lies in
our past. There you go: a universe with no beginning but a finite age.

            -- Joydip
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kundu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>

            

               Winnie-the-Canuck
            

            Contrary to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>," Winnie-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooh</ENAMEX> is neither <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>. He
is, in fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>. The original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winnie</ENAMEX>-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooh</ENAMEX> was the mascot of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regiment</ENAMEX>, an actual living bear named for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winnipeg</ENAMEX>. Winnie
found himself in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> when the regiment was transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great War</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>). He was placed in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> for safekeeping when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">regiment</ENAMEX> went on to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and in this period <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winnie</ENAMEX> became a great favorite
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX>-going public.

            And the fictional
Winnie-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooh</ENAMEX> was named for the real <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bear</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bear</ENAMEX> born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> who never
relinquished his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>.

            So, if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bear</ENAMEX> is going anywhere, send him back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>. However, we put no claim
on the other, lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyrrell Medicine Hat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alberta</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bother,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eh</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s polemic as to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winnie</ENAMEX>-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pooh</ENAMEX> serves only to stoke the fires of
controversy swirling around the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> unfortunate dolls. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX> is not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>,
but neither is he <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> or a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> of the world." He is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>. Pooh
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scholars</ENAMEX> (there are such things) know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.A. Milne</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great White North</ENAMEX> and bought his son's teddy bear in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winnipeg</ENAMEX>, hence the
name.

            Besides,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paddington Bear</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yanks</ENAMEX> created the stern <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smokey</ENAMEX> (a
suitable symbol of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> authoritarianism). In the interests of justice,
Winnie must be ours!

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Robertson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham Vancouver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Columbia</ENAMEX>

            
               Boop
Boop a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Doop</ENAMEX>, Indeed
            

            Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redux</ENAMEX>"--of course all refined <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostesses</ENAMEX> know that mint
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jelly</ENAMEX> is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> but a jelly. You spread jelly on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, like that piece of
bread the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> call by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">misnomer Yorkshire pudding</ENAMEX>. But they serve that
with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> and put gravy on it, so I don't know what <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> you spread your mint
jelly on when it is served with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX>.

            I for one
am more than a bit tired of the arrogant, ignoramus, false-elegant
pretentiousness of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. All these refined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> should learn to keep their mouths shut so as not to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incriminate</ENAMEX> themselves. Boop boop a doop, dearie.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Nelson</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
