
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dentists</ENAMEX>
Don't Need <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welfare</ENAMEX>
            

            Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Chapman</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geeks</ENAMEX> Don't Need
Welfare":

            The same
thing happened in dentistry in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1960s and 1970s</TIMEX>. With increased
government funding for training <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> got more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX> just in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for the full effect of fluoridated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to kick in. The result: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>
of unemployed or underemployed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX> and early
1980s.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Rethman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.D.S.</ENAMEX>,
M.S.
            

            
               Words,
Words, Words
            

            I just had to comment on the
commentary in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 13</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> ) on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> word." I am an
African-American with many black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. No one I associate
with uses the term "nigger" to describe each other or any other black person
for that matter. I question what research and/or actual experience was used to
determine that "since it has become a common phrase of salutation and even
endearment among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, a high proportion of its current usage is in fact as a
synonym for 'black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.' "

            While that
comment sounds like amusing irony, it is in reality a dangerous assumption
based on very little (if any) actual experience with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have had the
offensive term used to describe them. It is a propagation of the myth that if
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would just respect themselves, they would receive respect from
other races in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. You may never understand how offensive that word is to
a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>--but trust me , as a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, it in no way
meets my approval as an appropriate word to use to describe a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richards</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
