
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must include their address and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Multiple
Thumbs Down
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> further
damages his case in his
reply to my recent letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. Responding to my suggestions that
he uses selective quotation and inadequate research, he writes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siskel</ENAMEX> gave
Armageddon a 'thumbs up' and named it his 'flick of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>' on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sneak Previews</ENAMEX> ."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siskel</ENAMEX> did indeed give the
film a "marginal thumbs up"--hardly "cringe-making praise." Otherwise,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s sloppy homework is again on display. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siskel</ENAMEX> named it his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flick of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week</ENAMEX>" not on television but in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> , where he reviews
one film <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> at length. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siskel</ENAMEX>'s review is here.) If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> had clicked on a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX>, he
would have learned that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flick of the Week</ENAMEX>" is not an endorsement and can
be a positive or a negative review; the current "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flick of the Week</ENAMEX>" gets only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. We have not appeared on a program named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sneak Previews</ENAMEX> since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, which may offer a clue as to how carefully <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> watches Siskel
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& Ebert</ENAMEX> while forming his opinions.

            I note he
does not reply to my observation that most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> he mentions have
given negative reviews to most of the films he says we praised.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger EbertChicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times Chicago</ENAMEX>

            
               Awww,
Shucks
            

            In
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trashy Books</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX> is guilty
of false modesty. This called to mind a remark of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> (no relation, I think): "All modesty is false. Otherwise it's not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modesty</ENAMEX>."

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Liptak</ENAMEX> New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>

            
               A Job
Well <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Done Is Its Own Reward</ENAMEX>
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Privatize the</ENAMEX>
Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX>!" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E. Landsburg</ENAMEX> suggests, somewhat tongue in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cheek</ENAMEX>, that we allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, after he leaves
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, "to sell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> citizenships to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidders</ENAMEX> of his choice. ... If
he does a better job, those citizenships will become more valuable, and he'll
get a better price for them."

            This, he contends, will
encourage the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to do a good job.

            Earlier in the column,
however, he exposes the flaw in this idea. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landsburg</ENAMEX> notes, "What if he [the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>] keeps us out of war through policies that make the world more
dangerous for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?"

            Indeed, what if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> makes the world (including the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) a more dangerous place,
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> remains a safer place relative to the rest of the
world? Even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would be safer than other places, and thus
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> would be more valuable, it would still be, in absolute terms,
more dangerous than it was.

            Really,
we already reward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for doing a good job--we reserve a place for
him in history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presidents</ENAMEX> who do a good job are remembered favorably; those
who do not are not. This is not always true, of course. Sometimes when a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> does a terrible job we just name an airport after him.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Silver Spring</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Landsburg</ENAMEX> responds:
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Touché</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>.
The plan I proposed not only gives the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> an incentive to make the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> better, it also gives him an incentive to make the rest of the
world worse. So I should not have proposed it. After all, we wouldn't want to
deter future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> from emulating great achievements like, say, freeing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> from Communism.
            

            
               Flytrap
Claptrap
            

            After a promising beginning,

                  Slate
                has degenerated into a ridiculous mess of sixthhand
rehashing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal. It has been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> since I've seen a
substantive and interesting article posted. How about stopping publishing so
much of this drivel and hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to write intelligent, interesting work on
some (any!) other topic?

            If

                  Slate
                continues in anything like its present form, I certainly
won't be renewing my subscription. You'll continue to have an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-hating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junkies</ENAMEX>, but as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> go on I don't think this is a
viable business model.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Woit</ENAMEX> New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must include their address and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
