
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Lighten
Up on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
            

            In her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 6</TIMEX> entry in the
dialogue "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Victimized or Vicious</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> writes,
concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>, "I have to stick by my observation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, for
better or for worse, grow into their appearance, coming to look on the outside
as they feel on the inside."

            Imagine
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Limbaugh</ENAMEX> said something like that regarding, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Howard</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Tripp
Trapped
            

            It seems
that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> view <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Victimized or Vicious</ENAMEX>) as some kind of wicked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stepmother</ENAMEX>, and that is unfortunate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> is justified in worrying that her
job and reputation were being threatened after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> identified her
as someone who is "not to be believed." It would be very easy for me to say,
piously, that I would have sacrificed my job rather than make the recordings,
but I am a single <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-year-old</TIMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and I can afford to take a more
principled stance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> has not only herself to think about when it comes to
protecting her job and reputation, but also the well-being of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
her ability to support them. What would <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who sacrificed
her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in order to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damian M.</ENAMEX>
Schloming
            

            
               Taping
for Trouble
            

            Please ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonah Goldberg</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victimized or Vicious</ENAMEX>) to explain why he thinks, if all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tripp</ENAMEX> wanted to do
was to protect her good name, she continued to tape <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> long after she
would have had enough "evidence" for this purpose. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> says, "A 'seeker
of the truth,' as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> refers to herself, might at best need to tape one
conversation and hold it in reserve for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that dark moment</TIMEX> when her veracity was
challenged. Instead, she taped <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 hours</TIMEX>' worth and offered them up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gratuitously</ENAMEX>, to get the ball, which wasn't moving much, rolling."

            Why,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonah</ENAMEX>?

            -- Angus
Maitland
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX>?
Yikes!
            

            As one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Yates</ENAMEX>, the topic of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange</ENAMEX>
Bedfellow," I can tell you that he has been a distant and ineffective
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. I say this despite the fact that I agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> on
most political issues. Not surprisingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> admits his personal
relationships with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> has done little for the
economic development of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX>. While I admire his championship of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arts</ENAMEX> and the environment, these do little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concrete</ENAMEX> for the vast majority of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> who
refuses to set up an e-mail link for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>. How does this sit with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> enterprise? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> refused to step aside when he became obviously
physically infirm. He misses more votes than all but a handful of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> maintains little
contact with his district and made only token campaign appearances. He refused
to debate his campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emperor Sid</ENAMEX> treated those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> who dared
to oppose him as traitors and thought of himself as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> by divine
right.

            Our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> will now be
vastly better off by his replacement by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> 45 years his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> has
personally enriched himself at the expense of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> and his
retirement is welcome to many.

            
Ironically, one of the biggest news splashes made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX>
was when one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> invoked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sid</ENAMEX>'s clout and attempted to set up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>-walking runs in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock Creek Park</ENAMEX>. When this hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, out-of-touch
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sid</ENAMEX> denied any knowledge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>'s activities. What an embarrassment.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Phenomenology of Spirits
            

            As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clandestine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> wine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fareed Zakaria</ENAMEX> describes in his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>," I feel obliged to clarify the place in the pantheon
of winedom of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the figures mentioned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zakaria</ENAMEX>'s hymn.

            I speak, of course, of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hegel</ENAMEX>. Whatever the merits of the rather severe idiom in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hegel</ENAMEX> chose to
couch his ideas, he was nonetheless a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> in good standing in the wine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>' circle. He grew up in a wine drinking area (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Württemberg</ENAMEX>), and he did a
stint as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> tutor at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frankfurt</ENAMEX>'s most distinguished wine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX>. In
fact, in an effort to lure him into taking the job, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hölderlin</ENAMEX> even
promised him, "you will drink very good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Rhine wine</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> at the
table." When he was writing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Phenomenology</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spirit</ENAMEX>, despite his very
meager income at the time, he was ordering shipments of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Médoc</ENAMEX> and Pontak
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Haut-Brion</ENAMEX>). (See where his priorities lay.) When he became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>,
his tastes shifted slightly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mosels</ENAMEX> (loved them), <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rhine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>, and Cahors
(lots of it). He especially loved the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1811</TIMEX> vintage of "comet" <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>, and he and
Schleiermacher even stopped quarreling for a while after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schleiermacher</ENAMEX> gave
Hegel the address of a good <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX> merchant!

            Worldly
in his heart, he was also not averse to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX>, drinking and praising
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lacrima Christi</ENAMEX>" (red) as he was writing a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> oration on the Augsburg
Confession. When he was visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saxon Dresden</ENAMEX> at the height of the Prussian
reaction in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1820s</TIMEX>, he surprised his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> sitting at the table with him
by ordering the most expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Château Sillery</ENAMEX>. With none
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> quite understanding just what called for such a lavish outlay
on the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>'s part, he astonished them even more by raising his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and
toasting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 14</TIMEX> and the storming of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bastille</ENAMEX>. So on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 14</TIMEX>, instead of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX>, a crisp <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riesling</ENAMEX> might be the way for us German wine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> to toast
that venerated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> holiday. We can celebrate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hegel</ENAMEX> and the revolution at the
same time. And indulge our secret taste.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinkard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> of philosophyGeorgetown UniversityWashington

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bedrock</ENAMEX>
Blues
            

            As much as I enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuger</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> analysis of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>," from time to time he gets the
facts just plain wrong. Usually it's in the last paragraph, and it's usually
some flippant remark that would be witty if it were only true.

            In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuger</ENAMEX> wrote:
            

            [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>] told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
there that home ownership is an investment in society, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX> of
middle-class life. Wonder if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> had trouble resisting the
observation that it's an investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s never made, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX> he's never
stood on.

            I quote
from Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">151</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meredith Oakley</ENAMEX>'s biography <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On the Make: The Rise</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> :

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> shy
of her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> birthday, returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fayetteville</ENAMEX> ... inclined to accept
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty-nine-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s marriage proposal. Any remaining reluctance
was dashed when he greeted her return with the news that he had purchased a
small brick and stonework <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> she had admired.

            This
oft-reported account of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s marriage proposal is well known. Too bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuger</ENAMEX> felt the need to be witty--but wrong. Guess he was just following
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth Law</ENAMEX> of Politics (Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">146</NUMEX>)--"Under enough pressure, most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--but not everybody--will stretch the truth on you."

            -- Kari
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chisholm Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ore.</ENAMEX>

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delicate Art</ENAMEX> of Profanity
            

            I was just reading this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fascinating</ENAMEX> and well-written article ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flame Posies</ENAMEX>,"
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3</TIMEX>) about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and
admiring the balls of a publication that ran the headline "Who gives a f***
about the yen?" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> and had already used the phrase "holy shit" upward of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times in the opening paragraphs, when I happened upon this sentence:
"Later <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX>, the paper spread its legs for the theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> Flight 800
was downed by foul play, based on the discovery of 'PETN' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> in the
wreckage."

            I am, personally, a big fan
of the well-chosen off-color remark. "Screw you," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"kiss my ass</ENAMEX>," "fuck
me"--these are all phrases that have levels of meaning that have nothing to do
with the physical acts they describe. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donnie Brasco</ENAMEX> and
"fuggedaboudit.") I have recently deliberately begun to use variations of "kick
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ass</ENAMEX>" and "bites <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> in the ass" because they are colorful, evocative phrases;
because, thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> , ass references are newly familiar and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hilarious</ENAMEX> and because they don't evoke particularly vivid mental images of
asses any longer. Or at least, less than they used to.

            What I am very gently trying
to get at is: I don't think the phrase "spread its legs" has quite entered the
off-color oversoul. I think, like "up the ass," it is just a smidgen too vivid
for the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>. (Then again, we have seen the rise of "suck" in its
many forms, so perhaps I'll be proved wrong.) So when you write "spreads its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">legs</ENAMEX>," that's exactly what I think of, and for me, there is something
inherently unpleasant in having my gender's chief sexual activity thrown up on
the electronic page as an analogy for submissiveness. Human reproduction pretty
much hinges on leg-spreading and, hence, one would think this act would be
synonymous with ... well, something better than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> being
sluttishly seduced into an ill-supported <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> theory.

            Bottom
line: You don't have so much as a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> sketch to point to
as an example of how the phrase "spread its legs" has become so prevalent as to
have mostly lost its primary meaning; I think sex deserves better than to be
compared to bad reporting and I'm not especially keen on seeing my gender's
role during sex interpreted as one of whorish submission.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Powers</ENAMEX>
            

            
               School
Principles
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brooks</ENAMEX> chides Bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKibben</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>" for having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, arguing that it is "symbolic
politics taken to an extreme." If only one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> does it, it will have little
effect on the situation. "Maybe if everybody followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKibben</ENAMEX>'s lead it would
[make a difference]." In the next paragraph, he says it's OK for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> to send their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> to a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> while opposing school
choice because you should be able to rise above principle to send your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.

            Am I the only one who notices
the faulty logic? The problem is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> aren't an isolated example.
Many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of school choice send their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, even
while professing steadfast belief in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. This is like McKibben
having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, making his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>/significant other take fertility <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, and
then telling everyone we are running out of resources and everyone
else should have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.

            If there
were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> white, affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> sending its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> while
decrying school choice for others, that would be one thing. For an entire
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> to engage in this behavior is a national disaster. Perhaps that
is why (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooks</ENAMEX> says) public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are crappy in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-fourths</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones Pasadena</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               The AFI
Cannon
            

            I followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freund</ENAMEX>'s argument in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High Concept</ENAMEX>" about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">AFI 100</ENAMEX> greatest films list and the
decline of cultural gatekeeping right up to the point when he began discussing
the actual movies on the list. But his offhand comment that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde</ENAMEX> "presents criminality in soft focus" is so off-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam</ENAMEX> it taints his
entire analysis. Exactly what is "soft focus" about the bank teller who gets
shot full in the face or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Hackman</ENAMEX>'s agonizing death throes or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde</ENAMEX> 's final, staccato "dance of death"?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freund</ENAMEX>'s take on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> pictures as a "daydream of limitless wealth and power" is even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">loonier</ENAMEX>. Has he even seen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Godfather Part II</ENAMEX> , which charts the
complete moral decay of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacino</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> in minute psychological detail? <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Freund</ENAMEX>
is right that in many ways the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> pictures (especially Part
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> ) are the opposite of the traditional gangster movie, but he's precisely
wrong in his reasons why. In fact, it's the older gangster pictures that
romanticize the charismatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crooks</ENAMEX> portrayed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney, Robinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX>
al. There's nothing romantic about the criminal violence depicted in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> movies or the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> seems to drain out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacino</ENAMEX>'s
character over the course of the epic.

            Given the
volumes that have been written about these movies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freund</ENAMEX>'s blatant misreadings
are stupefying. Maybe a little more cultural gatekeeping on the part of

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> is in order.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
Warrick <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pleasant Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dirt</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Boards</ENAMEX>
            

            Regarding the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29</TIMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millionerds"</ENAMEX> column on white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> writes,
"But I have now seen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many hundreds</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>, bearing the remnants of
some recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> meeting, and I cannot recall ever seeing anything on them
remotely resembling a thought."

            Have you now? Have you ever
been part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> developing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OO</ENAMEX> plan for a software project? Have you ever
diagramed a relational database for a critique from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>? Most of
the white boards you've seen were spied while you were escorted about by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flacks</ENAMEX> or techs and suits on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> mission. They were all sort of nervous
because you're a celebrity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. They gave you free meals. Am I right so
far?

            You've
never seen a white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> used in real technical development, have you? You
don't really know what you're talking about, do you? The fact that what you've
just written--and much of what you've written before--is untrue doesn't bother
you because it's all in fun, right? And not really important, true? Just to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">amuse</ENAMEX>, you see. You're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stylist</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX>
Coffey
            

            
               So ...
What?
            

            Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>'
comments in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millionerds</ENAMEX>" about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX>' use of "so": It's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> thing, not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> thing. I work in
Champaign-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Urbana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 150 miles</NUMEX> south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">120 miles</NUMEX> west of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, home of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Illinois</ENAMEX>) and no professional
programmer I know has this verbal mannerism.

            My
personal opinion would be that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> give so many technical presentations in
formal and informal settings, where every other sentence or clause starts with
"so"--"so then the frob bit is set, so this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">path</ENAMEX> is followed, so no data hits
the wire"--that they just "get in the habit" of prefacing everything with
"so."

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carroll Cisco Systems</ENAMEX>

            
               Working
Words
            

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Turner</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">remark</ENAMEX>, discussed in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>," may have been unintentional in its reference to the
"welcome sign" over <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Auschwitz</ENAMEX>'s main gate, his attitude remains the same:
forced labor without hope for education, decent child care, or a better future.
I'm not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, but I immediately recognized the infamous quote.

            I believe a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haitian</ENAMEX> proverb
properly sums up the entire work/welfare debate: "If work were good for you,
the rich would leave none for the poor."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amen</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Max E. Hughey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jr. San Diego</ENAMEX>

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
