
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must include their address and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               A Few
More <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Minutes of Depression</ENAMEX>
            

            Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s
"Readme" about
the Internet and its links to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>: Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who use the Internet a
lot get depressed because the Internet is just more interesting than their
regular lives. They meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who share their preoccupations, quirks, sense
of humor, and sexual fantasies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who like to argue about politics and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX> (still taboo subjects in much of real-life <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>), who are experts
in fascinating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>, and who like to explain them. They can take on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pseudonym</ENAMEX> and express parts of themselves that they have to repress in their
ordinary lives. They can play bridge and chess and mental footsie with people
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. Then they come back to real life, and the contrast makes
them feel bad. Same old, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">same old</TIMEX>.

            Don't
forget--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of the Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> study lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>. They
may already have been anxious, bored, dissatisfied with their lives. But they
thought that was just the way life was, so when social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> asked if they
were happy, they said, "Sure." After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> on the Net, they know it doesn't
have to be that way--but they're still living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>.

            
               --Katha Pollitt New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>
Has Been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Berry Good to Me</ENAMEX>
            

            In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 9</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX> had this little tidbit:

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> problem with all
this: Despite the apparent oddity of the home run ball case, not one of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">horrified</ENAMEX> public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> has shown why it isn't a perfectly straightforward
application of the gift tax. So shouldn't they rethink the whole idea?

            Actually, I think it
is a straightforward application of the tax code not to tax the gift of
the ball, since there is no income to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> giving the ball away. Since
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who caught the ball gave nothing to receive the ball and received
nothing in return, even if the ball has some inherent value of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000,000</NUMEX>,
there is no "realizing event" that would trigger taxation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are only
taxed on income that is actually received, otherwise you would pay income tax
on the increased value of your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> (you only pay when you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX>).

            A rough analogy: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suppose Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX> threw a blank check for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000,000</NUMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>. If I caught it,
returned it, and received nothing in return, I have nothing to tax. If I fill
in my name and cash it, I pay tax. If I fill in the name of my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and
he cashes it, he pays income tax, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who signed the check (not me,
since I am simply the conduit and never received any benefit) pays gift
tax.

            In short,
this should not lead us to revisit the idea of a gift tax. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>"
quoted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story simply misstated the law. There is no reason to change
the law, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuger</ENAMEX>'s evident wish to do so aside.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carr Washington</ENAMEX>

            
               Plugging
Leaks
            

            I enjoy

                  Slate
               's humor, but I just finished reading the "leaked" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lush</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Levine</ENAMEX>) and found it amazingly stupid and insulting. Yes, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair deserves ridicule in many ways, but I can get lurid guesses
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> relationship anywhere. From 
                  Slate
                I
expect and am paying for serious attempts to assess what happened and what the
consequences might be. Leave the idiotic romance novel accounts to others.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weeks Carrboro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must include their address and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
