
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grill Brill</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brill's Con Game</ENAMEX>" raises
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> interesting question: Why is the press so afraid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Brill</ENAMEX>?
Short of cases of outright lying (à la <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Cooke</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Glass</ENAMEX>), I cannot
recall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> so viciously going after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of their own. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> answer is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> has gone a long way toward turning off the golden spigot of leaks from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. The broader reason is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> has had the temerity
to breach the inky wall of silence that largely protects <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> from being
subject to the same rules of exposure they expect everyone else to live by.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saletan</ENAMEX>'s points are especially absurd. One is that it now apparently is not
enough to disclose the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of the information in a story; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> also should
have disclosed "[h]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ow</ENAMEX>, and with whose input, [he chose] to focus his
investigation on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s manipulation of the press rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" If
that is the new rule, why didn't Saletan disclose in his article how, and with
whose input, he chose to focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>. What are his hidden motives? The other
bit of nonsense is the complaint that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> relied on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
Circuit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> about the scope of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Rule of Criminal</ENAMEX> Procedure
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>(e) but didn't cite supposed conflicting authority. The problem for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circuit</ENAMEX> and, unless and until the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> takes up this issue, it is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s rulings that bind him,
regardless what the rulings may be in other circuits. Brill, who trained as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, understands that. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saletan</ENAMEX> does not.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summergrad Washington</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate 's Fragile Egos</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mote</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beam</ENAMEX>" and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brill's Con Game</ENAMEX>" both
display clear outrage at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's</ENAMEX> magazine piece. Their outrage was also shared
by the talking heads on all the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> shows. What comes across to an objective
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">viewer</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saletan</ENAMEX>, and the press in general feel emotionally
that they are collectively above criticism and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> has violated a taboo.
I am surprised. I had thought better of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saletan</ENAMEX>. That they feel
their egos were punctured by even an intimation that the press was in the wrong
in its <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> coverage tells something about them.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed O'Connell</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Overkill
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX>
            

            Little hard on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> here,
aren't we? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> separate, exhaustive shots posted simultaneously?

            When it comes to
accountability, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment media</ENAMEX> have the biggest glass jaw in the
world, and its pre-emptive atomic carpet bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s Content only
proves it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX>) tootles along and everyone in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLean/Russert/West</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Street</ENAMEX> axis whines and moans about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">professionalism</ENAMEX> and standards. Then comes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN/ Time</ENAMEX> sarin story to
prove the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>" deserve all the scrutiny anyone else can muster.

            Give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> a shot. I'd
leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangulation</ENAMEX>-in-cradle attempts to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS News</ENAMEX>. 
                  Slate
                is
part of the revolution, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>. If you join the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Old Guard</ENAMEX> aboard
the "torpedo Content before anyone's even read the piece in question"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bandwagon</ENAMEX>, it's less salutary for you.

            On the
other hand, you did manage to use the great word "rebarbative" in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 17</TIMEX>
"Culturebox" ... so I'm not altogether unhappy.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmer Seattle</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brillos the Press</ENAMEX>
            

            Thou dost
protest too much! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> has accomplished with its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue what
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of public criticism of the press could not. Now someone has done unto you
what you have been doing to others. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Unbiased press</ENAMEX> ... hogwash!!!

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwendolyn M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>
            

            
               We're
Not Boring! Honest!
            

            Next time you describe the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Journalism Review</ENAMEX> in an article, it would be better if your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> took a look at a few recent issues before typing. We call this
reporting. The soporific thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> so offhandedly invents in
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mote</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beam</ENAMEX>" bears no resemblance to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CJR</ENAMEX> , and
we're surprised the false description got past your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>.

            We invite

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to come to their own conclusions. Check out the
contents page of our strong current (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July-August</TIMEX>) issue, or read some back
issues (including our own look at coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> saga, which
ran <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months ago</TIMEX>)--via our Web
site.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Hoyt</ENAMEX> Senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Journalism Review</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Bugs in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
            

            Permit me
to congratulate you on your fine sense of humor. In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Getting Buggy Wit It</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Shuman</ENAMEX> wrote an excellent article on the joys of bug-finding and
bug-squashing, and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that same day</TIMEX> you published the 
                  Slate
                table
of contents with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bugs</ENAMEX>. Very droll! I had to chuckle when I used Netscape <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.04</NUMEX>
on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Solaris 2.5.1 Sparc-5</ENAMEX> and had the pleasure of seeing such things as "_<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>._
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newrecycled FreeGlobal/Images/ClearDot</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gif</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WIDTH</ENAMEX>=<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 HEIGHT=1</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VSPACE</ENAMEX>=<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>>." It is sad that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>
do not have the opportunity to view the joke.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Heath</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Nobler
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>
            

            In
"Moneybox" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 19</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Surowiecki</ENAMEX> noted that the market
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cap</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> was
larger than that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX>, leading him to conclude that the Street
values the offline <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> at next to nothing. There's an alternative
explanation. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I have been regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>, but we
recently tried barnesandnoble.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Without revisiting the multiple e-mails and
telephone calls that we had to exchange before finally obtaining a book, the
experience left us more determined to shop with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX> More importantly, my
desire to walk into a physical <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> has diminished. At least
for us, the online version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX> has reduced the value of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">offline</ENAMEX> version, thereby rationalizing the Street's valuation.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
Philbrick
            

            
               Rumors
for <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Breakfast</ENAMEX>
            

            Regarding the dialogue
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Estrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brooks</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Breakfast Table"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 22</TIMEX>): Now I know that I can't have a beer
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in a public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> without being accused of
impropriety by one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s ever-watchful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partisans</ENAMEX>. So be it.
I'll make some concessions to the need to avoid imagined appearances of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impropriety</ENAMEX>. But I'll have a beer with anyone I damned well please.

            To put in perspective the
conspiratorial inferences that <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Estrich strains</ENAMEX> to draw from seeing me with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Bennett</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson Hotel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>--a block or so from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , where I always go when I'm looking for a secure locale
in which to do furtive things--perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Estrich</ENAMEX> should know that I also had some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beers</ENAMEX> recently with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. We were at his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>,
where no peeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partisans intruded</ENAMEX>.

            To be clear: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Bennett</ENAMEX>
was not leaking to me; he was not telling me what to write or say on
television; it was not a business appointment at all. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, evidently
troubled and hurt by my former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Brill</ENAMEX>'s ugly portrayal of him,
had asked if we could get together for a private and personal conversation to
help him understand why a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose fairness I had mistakenly touted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>
would write a catalog of falsehoods and distortions about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>,
painting them both as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. I had readily agreed, because I like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>
and I felt I owed him the best perspective I could give on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s article, the
extreme tendentiousness of which had surprised me. I had asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> whether
we should find a spot where he would run no risk of catching flak by being seen
with me; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> had indicated that he was not going to let the risk of
encountering malicious gossipmongers dictate which bars he could frequent.

            Our
conversation moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s article to other nonconfidential matters, such
as the legal rules curbing what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> can say to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, to matters
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>, mutual acquaintances, and other matters that
even so creative a mind as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's</ENAMEX> might have trouble painting as grand jury
secrets. After the arrival of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Estrich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> and I also wondered idly whether
she would seize the chance to misrepresent our conversation as something
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unseemly</ENAMEX>, about which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> should be embarrassed. This she has now done.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> was not embarrassed. I am not embarrassed. It is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Estrich</ENAMEX> who should be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">embarrassed</ENAMEX>, for having concocted a fantasy to serve her partisan agenda.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
