
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               The Old
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
            

            I very
much miss the quirkiness you speak of regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX>
("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>") . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX> has turned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> into just
another pandering, up<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-to-the-minute</TIMEX> glossy ... sort of like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
without the big perfume ads and photo layouts. It's too bad. Now where do I go
for quirk?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Paigel</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Chainsaw
Let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loose</ENAMEX>
            

            About your
comment in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 16</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s
Papers" about the "inordinate" amount of coverage that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Dunlap</ENAMEX>'s firing
got: This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> has become a corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX>--arrogant, cocky, boasting he can
turn a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> around in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX> when others need <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, eschewing
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> for coach seats. In other words, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Iacocca</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>,
only instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, he's been selling his own qualifications in his
never-ending quest to land other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> jobs. As a business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, I can tell
you how hard it can be to write about business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, who are generally
careful, scripted, and pretty dull. Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> isn't much in revenues, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chainsaw Al</ENAMEX> is good copy--anytime. But I personally hope the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times is right: that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> have grown tired of "slash and burn" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>'s eagerness to get rid of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chainsaw Al</ENAMEX> is a marked contrast to the
story I've been working; namely, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Auto Workers</ENAMEX> strikes against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flint</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX> There are no clear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> in this one and no
sign when this might end. Even if it ends, it doesn't end, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>'s
problems are far from over.

            -- Micki MaynardUSA
Today <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> chief

            
               Of
Wealth and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Men</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
Surowiecki needs to read more carefully. In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Real Things</ENAMEX>"
he criticizes a piece I wrote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX>
for assuming that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> manufacturing is all but dead and gone. Then he goes
on to describe "the resurrection of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>." But I would
never have made such an ignorant statement. What I did say is that "the glitter
of instant wealth" being made on Wall Street is overshadowing the steadier
achievements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, wage-earners and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> alike, who used to
call themselves "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>." That's a cultural critique, not an economic
report.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Kazin <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Surowiecki</ENAMEX>
replies: Actually, I was responding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kazin</ENAMEX>'s cultural critique and not
whatever economic report he did or did not make. In pointing to the way Wall
Street now values industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and other traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, I was
trying to show that in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, at least, have a great deal of respect
for "the manufacture of useful goods and vital services" and not the "glitter
of instant wealth" (Internet fever aside). Unlike <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, when the economy's
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> often seemed to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Milken</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boone</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pickens</ENAMEX>, who were "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX>" in that classic populist sense of the word, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who get the most attention and respect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are almost all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX>
who spend their time making things, not playing with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s money: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dell</ENAMEX>, or whoever. In that sense, the stock market boom is
founded firmly on the "steadier achievements" to which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kazin</ENAMEX> refers.
            

            
               Marrying
for (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Less</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McIntyre</ENAMEX> compares <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oranges</ENAMEX> in his article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Marriage Penalty?</ENAMEX>" Of course it is true that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given</TIMEX> level of spending,
lowering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> tax will require raising another. And if many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> are
married, any new tax will be levied in part on them. However, the real question
is whether under the current tax code, all other things being equal, you are
better off living together unmarried than tying the knot. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McIntyre</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">un</ENAMEX>-PC example regarding blindness, marriage is a choice; for some, taxes will
feature in a decision to get married. And for two-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>, getting
married nearly always results in a higher tax bill. You can consider that a
penalty or their just reward, but that's a different debate.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Nord</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Hard
Labor
            

            I am writing to compliment
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Surowiecki</ENAMEX> on his simultaneously rigorous and humanistic analysis of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> strike ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moneybox</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 10</TIMEX>). He has pegged the contradictions facing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> labor with a precision sorely lacking in the mainstream coverage of
this episode. The negative stereotypes defining labor in the mainstream press
are easily invoked, but rarely is the positive rationale behind organization
defined beyond "worker dissatisfaction." Labor in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is by no
means perfect, and dealing with intransigent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> can be a byzantine,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">harrowing</ENAMEX>, and expensive process. In many ways labor can be characterized as
decadent in its victory over the truly horrible conditions of the early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>, and many of us wish to believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worker</ENAMEX> has been given too much and should be slapped back into line with the
realities of the global marketplace.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Surowiecki</NUMEX> points out the shaky rationale for this particular strike but does
not end there, reminding us that the control we have over our workplaces and
the responsive nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> (in abiding by the bulk of these
rules or by factoring labor unrest into their long-term calculations) can be
directly attributed to the efforts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> (regardless
of whether or not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-trick pony <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Radosh</ENAMEX> wishes to brand them all as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subversives</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Compliments</ENAMEX> also for his reminder that those efforts are personal
and carry consequences for those who are willing to take the risk of
confrontation.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Man</ENAMEX>
Behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Firing Range</ENAMEX>
            

            In his
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz characterizes Charlton Heston</ENAMEX>'s life, both
on-screen and off, as unremarkable. The anecdotal evidence for this spurious
conclusion? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX>'s prolific on-screen career is marked by an assiduous
research of his roles, a consistent and committed work ethic, politeness to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">co-workers</ENAMEX>, respect to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>, and a humble self-effacement--all of which
have resulted in a prolific string of performances and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> popularity.
His private life is characterized by an enduring, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54 year</TIMEX> relationship with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, an extremely close relationship to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and a preference for
studying history and writing (which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX> admits he does very well). Ho hum.
One wonders what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX> considers remarkable. That a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> could have such a long
acting career in and around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, display none of his profession's
characteristic egotism and self-absorption, and maintain close, intimate family
relationships, including a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54 year</TIMEX> marriage, strikes me as remarkable, indeed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX>'s political involvement is summed up as the dabblings of a dilettante.
The examples of his rhetoric provided are labeled as "nasty," while
many--myself included--find them insightful as (only slightly) hyperbolic
illustrations of the absurdity to be found in modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. One
can't help wondering if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> would have found more remarkable signs of genius
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX>'s life if only he had obliged with more egotistical displays, a
family life in shambles, and political and social views to the left of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark D.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caudle Beavercreek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>

            
               Making
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letters Better</ENAMEX>
            

            About the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12</TIMEX> edition of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s
Papers": at the risk that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> was "just kidding," I can't believe
that a serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> would think factual mistakes in a publication's
articles are comparable to factual mistakes in letters to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. Regular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> tend to be the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of the factual mistakes in letters.
However, those same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> need to be confident that a publication's own staff
are held to a higher standard of accuracy. If not, we can rely on the
publication about as much as we can rely on the accuracy of news in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Usenet</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alt</ENAMEX>.conspiracy newsgroup.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clarke Seattle</ENAMEX>

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
