
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               The Fact
Check Is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX>
            

            I disagree with my friend
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glass Houses</ENAMEX>") that fact checking doesn't protect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> from
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> who make things up. It does, just as it protects <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> from
old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> who get things wrong, no matter how many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> they've been at it.
When someone reports a complicated story for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many weeks</TIMEX> or even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, stuff
happens--notes get confused, memories fail. Once the story is turned in, it's
the job of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> to try to separate what is clearly not true from what may
or may not be. Beyond that, the fact checker is a safety net. Anything the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> doesn't catch, the checker does, from misspelled names to lapses in
logic that only a fresh set of eyes can recognize.

            When I was deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> during a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-month</TIMEX> period of apostasy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, there
were no fact checkers; it was before the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Shalit</ENAMEX> business, so the
fact checking "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> describes did not exist. In fact, having
come from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that rigorously fact checks every word of every story, I
had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> conversations with fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> about why such a system wasn't in
place at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> . No one could tell me, but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> mentioned
an article called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Are You Completely Bald?</ENAMEX>" It had run in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '80s</TIMEX>, and it mocked the very notion of fact checking as unnecessary and
stupid. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX> of that piece was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich Blow</ENAMEX>, then a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> intern,
now an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX> dumped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Glass</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s revelations. It's a small, small world.)

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lane</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> now routinely fact checks stories, I take him at his
word--but it seems inconceivable to me that someone fact checked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Hack</ENAMEX>
Heaven" story if the subject of the story wasn't called and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> he
worked for wasn't contacted. Simply consulting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s notes ain't fact
checking.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Smith</ENAMEX> Deputy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Monthly</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Ahead of
the Curve
            

            In a profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Loury</ENAMEX>
("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Loury</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Round</ENAMEX>
Trip"), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> writes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Since The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> was published, it
has become clear that almost everything about it was inexcusably wrong: suspect
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>, mistakes in statistical procedures that would have flunked a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sophomore</ENAMEX>."

            While this
is true, it misses the most interesting aspect of that very bad book: Viewed
solely on the technical merits, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> is no worse than many
more reputable examples of social science research. Many of the mistakes made
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> are made routinely by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> across the political
spectrum. The public policy literature is filled with confused causal modeling
and the use of flimsy, though grandly named, variables such as "socioeconomic
status" that don't mean what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> think they do. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> and Herrnstein
are hardly alone in presenting sweeping policy conclusions based on the narrow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">correlations</ENAMEX> found in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> limited data set. It is only the largeness of the
topics explored that exposes the smallness of method <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> and Herrnstein
employed. This book masquerades as reputable social science, which it is not.
However, the ease with which <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> assumes this guise may be as
sobering as the book itself.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pollack</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bait</ENAMEX> and
Switch
            

            Your "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist</ENAMEX>" on alleged payments to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hale</ENAMEX> is so sloppy that one is tempted to assume some bias on the part of
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>.

            The statement that Caryn
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX> "recovered her memory" and estimated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker Dozhier</ENAMEX>'s payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> at
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX> is contradicted by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the very</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> article <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foer</ENAMEX> cites to support
it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX> said that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dozhier</ENAMEX> who received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $200,000</NUMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s claim that she "backed down" from that number in later interviews
(not cited) is thus groundless.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> also neglected to
mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX>'s credibility is bolstered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s decision, after a
preliminary investigation of her charges, to refer them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>.

            The
theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> was just "hanging around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dozhier</ENAMEX>'s bait <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, looking for ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">handouts</ENAMEX>" is contradicted by another allegation that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> failed to mention:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dozhier</ENAMEX> met on several occasions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Spectator</ENAMEX> board
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Boynton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Henderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> 's funding foundation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> who escorted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> on each
of his visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dozhier</ENAMEX>'s bait <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> should be able to testify as to whether
those meetings took place; if they did not, it seems unlikely the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> would

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
Lauriston
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foer</ENAMEX> responds: Let me answer your criticisms in order.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> article, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caryn Mann</ENAMEX> makes no specific estimate
of how much money <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dozhier</ENAMEX> received. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> article, which came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days later</TIMEX>, she gives
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX> estimate for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX> admitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post that the estimates she gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> were imprecise and
inconsistent. She told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , "I'm not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>. I spent more than
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> trying to forget this, and now I'm trying to remember it."
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) My piece specifically
mentions the letter written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Holder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>, in which
he called for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX>'s charges.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hale</ENAMEX>
was simply "hanging around" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dozhier</ENAMEX>'s bait <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> isn't mine. I credit it to
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who investigated the allegations.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) One
last point: My brief piece made it amply clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> was thick with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Spectator</ENAMEX> crowd.
            

            
               The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX> Letter <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Printed This Week</ENAMEX>
            

            Why do you
print so few e-mails to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>? Is it that you actually get such a small
amount of e-mail? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> Slate printed one letter! As someone who
enjoys reading this stuff, I would like to see an expansion of this area. I
know you have "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>,"
which is sort of similar, but couldn't you have both?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX>
Kaften
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
