
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Cocktail
Catholicism
            

            In
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Toward the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wet Martini</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fareed Zakaria</ENAMEX> writes:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buñuel</ENAMEX> makes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> common
errors. First, he gets the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immaculate Conception</ENAMEX> wrong, which refers to the
conception not of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> but of his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>--it's the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Anne</ENAMEX>, whose hymen is invisibly pierced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Ghost</ENAMEX>.

            I imagine
(indeed, I hope) that I am one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> who point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zakaria</ENAMEX> is also
wrong. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buñuel</ENAMEX>--born <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>, even if he opted out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>--confused the
Incarnation, in which the Holy Ghost caused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> to conceive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Immaculate Conception</ENAMEX>, which refers to the fact (or belief, if you will) that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> was born without original sin, although otherwise by the normal biological
process.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>
            

            
               
                  Note from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fareed Zakaria</ENAMEX> is indeed wrong; he's even willing to admit it. If
only we here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> would let him! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zakaria</ENAMEX> realized his error before
publication and tried to amend his copy, but his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> failed to make the
change in time (though we have now rectified our slip). Slate thanks the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> (yes, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who pointed out the mistake, as well
as the nuns, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>, and lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologians</ENAMEX> who gave them such excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">educations</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Brandy,</ENAMEX>
Capitalist
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s
Papers," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX> points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moesha</ENAMEX> ranked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">124</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">139</NUMEX> shows but was nonetheless renewed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another season</TIMEX>--yet another
instance of the relentless creep of affirmative action. Might I suggest another
explanation?

            In a 
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal</ENAMEX>
Opportunism") just before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moesha</ENAMEX> 's premiere, I reported that
African-American viewing patterns bear almost no resemblance to those of other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 1</NUMEX> for nonblacks, No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Undercover</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 1</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> but not even in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> for nonblacks.
Only <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monday Night Football</ENAMEX> was in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>' top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist</ENAMEX>, of
whom there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> among us, I hear tell, might bear this in mind when
targeting malt <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX>, fast food, and sneaker commercials.

            I have yet
to obtain viewership figures for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moesha</ENAMEX> , but I suspect the show will be
in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Brandy</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sweetheart</ENAMEX> of black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--she's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Houston</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Brown</ENAMEX>. Isn't it a little self-pitying to ascribe
misplaced guilty liberalism and soggy altruism to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who bring us
season after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> of formulaic sitcoms, spandexed soap operas, and
disease-of-the<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-week</TIMEX> movies? Where's the social purpose in that--affirmative
action for lousy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and worse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> (most of whom, it must be noted, are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">white</ENAMEX>)? It might just be that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moesha</ENAMEX> is about advertising dollars and
not about oppressing the beleaguered white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Just a thought.

            -- Debra
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickerson Washington</ENAMEX>

            
               The
Future of Futurology
            

            Thank you
for such a perceptive essay ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Road</ENAMEX>
Behind,") by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>. It astonishes me that so many of the bright
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> are capable of understanding things like quantum
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tunneling</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boolean</ENAMEX> algebra but are incapable of understanding history or the
future. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur C. Clarke</ENAMEX> wrote a book imagining the future. His
specific predictions were pretty good, but his most insightful observation was
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of futurology and the reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> usually can't see the
future clearly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> pointed out that we usually overestimate the amount of
change that will happen in the short term and underestimate how much change
will happen in the long term. Our own achievements seem to loom so large that
we can't imagine what our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> might achieve. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> is the
clearest possible demonstration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>'s theorem. It sometimes seems that
working at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> megahertz precludes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from having much long-term memory.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Quinn North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
