
   
   
      
         
            

            Here is a
sampler from 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>," where the market of ideas has
been deregulated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Subscribers</ENAMEX> engage one another in debate, discussing news and
cultural happenings and even trading gardening tips. To wit, a selection of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s hottest topics. And of course, you can always jump right into the
action. Click here to
join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray</ENAMEX>.

            
               Hot
Threads
            

            What did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> know,
and when did he know it? Inquiring minds in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>" thread
focused <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> on the question of key <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whitewater</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hale</ENAMEX>'s
possibly tainted testimony. The possibility that outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> (notably
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-hater <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Mellon Scaife</ENAMEX>) might have tampered with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star witness</ENAMEX> stoked the debate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>,
naturally, chafed at the notion that they might be sidetracked in their dogged
pursuit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal critics</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
no-win dilemma: He must investigate his own chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>--a course that would
invite all kinds of political fusillades--or turn the process over to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s internal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. Oh, and that gal back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>?
Her planned appeal raised scarcely a blip.

            A by an
unassuming fraygrant caused the venerable "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Language</ENAMEX>" thread to erupt into its
most intense debate ever. The topic: Does language influence culture? By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s
end, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lines</ENAMEX> had been drawn, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> opposing camps staking out their turf
and even coming up with labels for their positions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bi</ENAMEX>-Directionalists
believe that language influences culture even as culture influences language;
the other side avers it doesn't. The debate should segue nicely into next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>'s discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Pinker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Language Instinct in the</ENAMEX>
"Reading" thread.

            
               New
Threads
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black in America</ENAMEX>" erupted
when an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fraygrant</ENAMEX> asked which white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fraygrant</ENAMEX> would be the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to apologize to him for slavery. Affirmative action was debated, as was
the question of privatizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>: Would it collapse <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s class
divisions or just lead to even more problems? But the biggest firestorm erupted
over test scores: How are they used? Are they obsolete? Do test-result
disparities reflect just cultural-knowledge disparities?

            After a
slow start, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Education</ENAMEX>" thread got a shot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> when one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fraygrant</ENAMEX> posed a . A lengthy debate ensued on vocational education programs in
high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>: Are high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> the best place for them? Should some programs be
moved to the post-secondary level? Should the whole lot be moved? Another topic
emerged: the issue of exit exams in higher education. Which states use them,
and in what fields are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> tested? The focus has now shifted to The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Curve</ENAMEX> and its discussion of the needs of gifted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.

            
               Fray
Feud
            

            In the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religion</ENAMEX>" thread, one irreverent poster asked, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Gandhi burning in hell?</ENAMEX>"
Another on why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> never became a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> despite having been possibly the
best <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christian</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>. This question tapped an ongoing battle between
staunch conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> and liberal-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX> on topics ranging
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frontline</ENAMEX> special "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Jesus to Christ</ENAMEX>" to the interplay of
politics, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>. Not much common ground here; the battle
continues.

            
               A Feast
for the Eyes
            

            The "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX>" thread was all
about the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clement Greenberg</ENAMEX>. The debate was inspired by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Gopnik</ENAMEX>'s recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florence Rubenfeld</ENAMEX>'s
new biography, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clement Greenberg</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Finch</ENAMEX> review
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ArtNet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> really have a great eye, or was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson Pollock</ENAMEX> just a lucky loser foisted on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gullible public</ENAMEX> by a bull in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">china</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>?

            
               
                  Slate
               's
"Movies
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>" dialogue between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Ross</ENAMEX> has inspired some
interesting posts in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Movies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Television</ENAMEX>" thread. To illustrate their
views, fraygrants posted lists of their favorite films in different genres,
from the familiar to the obscure. This led to some on just what belongs on a
list of favorite films. Other topics <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>: What makes a sex symbol sexy,
commentary on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Jordan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Butcher Boy , Werner Herzog</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dieter Needs</ENAMEX> to Fly , and the (apparently) implicit homoeroticism in
Grease .

         
      
   
