
   
   
      
         
            

            Things
have heated up in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>," where 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> do battle over
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s big issues. To wit, a selection of some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>'s liveliest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">threads</ENAMEX>. Click here to
join in.

            
               Hot
Threads
            

            "Scumbag"? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Whitewater
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX> provided grist for the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>"
thread. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> defended <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s name-calling in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning</ENAMEX>
News interview as essentially truthful; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> wondered if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> was
merely projecting. Meanwhile, the discussion over who's really in
trouble--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>--has grown more polarized
and personal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have turned up the rhetoric, even referring to
him as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapist</ENAMEX>"--while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are accusing him of being party to a
witness-tampering scheme. It's getting ugly.

            In the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big</ENAMEX>
Questions" thread, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fraygrants</ENAMEX> argued about interpretations of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX> and definitions of personal and religious freedom. Also debated:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.O. Wilson</ENAMEX>'s new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Consilience</ENAMEX> . The former <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ant</ENAMEX>-nut has written what
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> fraygrant called "a historical polemic--that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enlightenment</ENAMEX> thinkers
were right, after all." Will the social sciences fall under the combined weight
of the humanities and natural sciences? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Pinker</ENAMEX>'s review in

                  Slate
                and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX> 's interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilson</ENAMEX> have stoked the flames.

            
               New
Threads
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Faulkner</ENAMEX>'s The
Sound <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">and the Fury</ENAMEX> was the subject of the new "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reading</ENAMEX>" thread this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 1</ENAMEX>, a k a the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Benjy</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, was deemed "a tour de force ranking
with anything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> wrote" by the thread's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>. Who
and what influenced <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sound</ENAMEX> ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Joyce</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulysses</ENAMEX> ? Can only
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southerner</ENAMEX> truly appreciate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>'s settings? Contributors to the
discussion ranged from novices to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>; they included a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> who shared
her experience of introducing the novel to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> who has
written on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Stone</ENAMEX> (the model for several <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Faulkner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>) for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mississippi Lawyer</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist" and Sarah Kerr</ENAMEX>'s review of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Walking Out on the Boys</ENAMEX> kicked off debate in the new "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sexual Harassment</ENAMEX>"
thread: Is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a single</NUMEX> pass by a superior sexual harassment, or is a pattern of
repeated abuse necessary? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fraygrant</ENAMEX>'s perspective: "I'd much rather work
with someone who was honestly attracted to me and took 'no' for an answer than
someone who may or may not be honestly attracted to me but wants to cow me in
any case." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Packwood</ENAMEX> were compared, with
the consensus ruling that only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Packwood</ENAMEX> may have been guilty of real sexual
harassment. Also examined: the lasting effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>' hearings on his
performance in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>.

            
               Fray
Feuds
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> as last, the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Language</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thread</ENAMEX> was on a roll. The discussion on language and culture moved to the need
for self-appointed "language <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mavens</ENAMEX>" such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>. Some fraygrants
took the prescriptivist position: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> must be told how to use the language
if it isn't to succumb to its natural tendency to go "all higgledy piggledy."
Tosh, said the opposition. All language needs to do is communicate one's
meaning clearly. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mavens</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX> to fight the "tide of language
change."

            Voting is
underway in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Person</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>" thread, which, created before the recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> survey, aims to identify, once and for all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who
has most influenced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>. Visit the voting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> to register
your vote--it is open to all 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>. No ballots will
be accepted after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 6, 1998</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Week</ENAMEX>
            

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sexual Harassment</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thread</ENAMEX>, the debate over an acceptable definition of the term led <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> fraygrant
to post a statement on what is appropriate in the workplace. inspired reactions
from both sides of the table, ranging from "Yes, that's exactly it" to
"Call me a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cynic</ENAMEX>, but I ain't quitting a job for a f--k unless I'm SURE it's
love and even then, dammit, HE can quit."

         
      
   
