
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must include their address and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Authorized Freud</ENAMEX>
            

            Some notes regarding the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt-Andrew Sullivan</ENAMEX> dialogue in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Book Club</ENAMEX>" about my new anthology <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unauthorized Freud:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doubters Confront a Legend :</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the few points on
which these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> fully agree is that I am a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> atheist. They are,
however, sadly mistaken. I was born and raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. It is true, alas, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX> observes, that I am not "in command of my senses" and that, in fact, I
am an outright "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maniac</ENAMEX>." I must also concede that my articles on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freud</ENAMEX> and the
recovered memory movement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> --articles that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX> hasn't read--were, as he <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, "tirades." But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from now</TIMEX> on, by virtue
of studying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX>'s own understated prose, I hope to cultivate a more
rational and deliberate manner.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Crews</ENAMEX> need to see a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">shrink?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX> is not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to have posed this profound
diagnostic question. Indeed, it has been the standard retort--pioneered by no
less an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX> himself--that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freudians</ENAMEX> throw back at those who
challenge the empirical credentials of psychoanalysis. See the concluding
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter</ENAMEX> of my book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Memory Wars</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>).

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. It is less than cogent to
view the historical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freud</ENAMEX> through the lens of one's own contemporary
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">psychotherapeutic</ENAMEX> involvement. Nor it is helpful to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lump psychoanalysis</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">psychotherapy</ENAMEX> together, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> does. I have never attacked psychotherapy,
by which I mean the general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> of helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk through their
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxieties</ENAMEX> and face the difficulties in their immediate circumstances. The
target of my skepticism has been psychodynamic therapy, whereby the
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">patient's manifestly</ENAMEX> perceived problems, beliefs, and feelings are treated as
mere "compromise formations" tossed to the surface by deep turmoil that can
only be resolved by dredging for repressed memories, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oedipal</ENAMEX> cravings, and the
like. If I am to be deemed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maniac</ENAMEX>, let's at least try to state correctly what
it is I've been raving about.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Nearly everyone who is
ignorant of the critical literature assumes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX> made some genuine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">discoveries</ENAMEX>, but the list varies according to taste. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX>, for example, is
quite sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX> was right about repression, resistance, transference, the
Oedipus <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, dream interpretation, and (God help us!) "the probable origins
of homosexuality." Thus, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> found me asserting what nearly any
research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of psychology could have told him--that not one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distinctively Freudian</ENAMEX> concept or hypothesis has survived independent
scrutiny--he gave a horrified glance at my chapter titles, abandoned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unauthorized Freud</ENAMEX> , and pronounced me insane. If he had kept on reading,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollitt</ENAMEX> did, he would have encountered reasoned arguments by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> challenging each and every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Freudian</ENAMEX> notion that he considers
self-evident.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollitt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX>
alike deem me insensitive to the depth and complexity of the psyche, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX> warmly endorses <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychoanalyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Lear</ENAMEX>'s admonition that we dare
not reject <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX> lest those qualities drop out of sight. But neither Pollitt
nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lear</ENAMEX> understands that psychoanalysis has been a means of
simplifying the mind by presuming sexual and aggressive motives to be
invariably primary and by invoking deterministic "mechanisms" that always lead
to a few banal and arbitrary causative factors. As my introduction points out,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">psychoanalysis</ENAMEX> would be helpless to address the intricacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freud</ENAMEX>'s own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">devious</ENAMEX> and supersubtle mind. Only when we have grasped the full extent of the
Freudian intellectual fiasco--it is adumbrated in my book but exhaustively
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">explored</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Macmillan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Freud Evaluated: The Completed Arc</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>)--will we be able to talk about motives with an adequate respect for
their actual variety and volatility.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>.
Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollitt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> are disappointed that Unauthorized

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX> doesn't pay homage to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freud</ENAMEX>'s cultural importance in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our century</TIMEX>.
True--but I fully grant that importance. Quite simply, my book asks whether it
was attained with or without the benefit of accurate clinical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observation</ENAMEX>, defensible drawing of inferences, and encouraging therapeutic
results. The answer is: without them. Once that fact has sunk in, a cultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> can assess the true magnitude of the problem that Unauthorized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX> only glancingly treats: how <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> secular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>, not excepting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> in therapy, could have been so
thoroughly bamboozled.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crews Berkeley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High</ENAMEX> and
Mighty"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: A Low Blow</ENAMEX>
            

            About <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mighty": The Partnership</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug-Free America</ENAMEX> has never claimed that
"all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use leads to disaster." Our advertising is based on a breadth of
research from which we develop specific campaigns depending on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and the
demographic we're targeting. There's a huge difference, for example, between
smoking marijuana and smoking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> and between communicating to an 8-year-old
or a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX>. Take a look: Our advertising does not--and never has--treated
all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> equally.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s article shows a
fundamental lack of understanding about what our campaign entails. Had he
contacted us, we would have been happy to discuss our advertising as well as
our research. We would still be open to such a discussion.

            We welcome
scrutiny into our advertising campaign and our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, but here's one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suggestion</ENAMEX>: How about waiting for some results before deciding this can't
possibly work, and how about reading the existing research that shows it can
("The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Impact of Anti-Drug Advertising</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins University</ENAMEX>; "Does
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anti-Drug Advertising Work</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stern School of Business</ENAMEX>)?
Advertising will not solve the drug problem, but done right it can vastly
improve the chances for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> to stay off <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leigh</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leventhal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant director</ENAMEX>, public affairsPartnership for a Drug-Free
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AmericaNew York City</ENAMEX>

            
               Culture
Wars
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 20</TIMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Browser</ENAMEX>"
on uncritical movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> is wrong, I think, to suggest that mainstream
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> should ignore blockbusters or dismiss them in a paragraph. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
of mass circulation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> are intensely interested in such
titles, and I find my reviews of movies such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Godzilla</ENAMEX> ,
Armageddon , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lost World , Starship Troopers , Lost in</ENAMEX>
Space , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween H20</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BASEketball</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force One</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>, to be invaluable opportunities to help open their eyes to the clichés and
stupidities being retailed by the filmmakers. He is wrong, too, to say of my
favorable review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Negotiator</ENAMEX> that I overpraised it in a
"cringe-making way." I did indeed say it "really hums along," in the second
sentence of an opening paragraph which, if he had quoted it all, would have
destroyed his point. I invite any 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> to examine my
entire review and
decide if it supports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s generalizations.

            The technique of
generalizing from an exception to the rule is an effective but not honorable
journalistic practice. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> will take a closer look he will find I have
given negative reviews to most of the big-budget blockbusters of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>,
and that I review more foreign, art, documentary, and indeed films (like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pi</ENAMEX> and Taste of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cherry</ENAMEX> ) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> than 
                  Slate
                does
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s technique is to selectively choose those titles from each critic
that illustrate his point, while remaining deliberately oblivious to reviews by
the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> that would weaken it. The article works only if

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> take him at his word, for example, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Siskel</ENAMEX>
gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX> a "rave" (he did not). And it is not fair to criticize
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> for praising <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lethal Weapon 4</ENAMEX> while suppressing the
information that I, for example, disliked it, because that would not help his
case--just as the information that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX> disliked many of the other films he
mentions would also not serve his thesis. If you are going to criticize
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, you have to be a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> than he is in this essentially
unresearched piece, which is excellent only as an example of the off the top of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> thumb-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> genre.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger EbertChicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times Chicago</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> replies:
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> can decide for themselves whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebert</ENAMEX> overpraises The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Negotiator</ENAMEX> by clicking here to read his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and a half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> review. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siskel</ENAMEX> gave
Armageddon a "thumbs up" and named it his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">flick of the week" on Sneak</ENAMEX>
Previews .
            

            
               Gender
Impolitics
            

            About
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 19</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Earthling</ENAMEX>": Watching feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> wriggle, squirm, and
say nothing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s violation of everything they are supposed to stand
for undermines any theory that female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>--elected or otherwise--are
any more principled than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> are another, lesser, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>--and
their differences from everyone else transcend gender.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn H.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reynolds Knoxville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>

            
               Easy on
Breakfast
            

            Lucianne
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> at "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> was too much. Did you forget to send
me the e-mail about your buyout by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> ? Is name recognition now
the primary requirement for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berman Seattle</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must include their address and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
