
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must include their address and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               No, It
Wasn't an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Innocent Romance</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>, the writer
of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An Innocent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romance</ENAMEX>," should get a grip. Adultery by one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, even
über <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, is harmful to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. It's not
necessarily the public disclosure of the adultery, it is the fact of the
adultery itself.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>, adultery is
generally a good sign that all is not well in the homestead; ergo, the fact of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adultery</ENAMEX> tells us the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is suffering. Therefore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is probably
suffering (yes, even <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one 3,500 miles</NUMEX> away at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>).

            Your
value-free ramblings, unconnected as they are to any sense of morality or
healthy shame, sound a lot like the greatest hits from a sophomore philosophy
seminar. Clever? Sure. But of any real value or connection to real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
the world? Definitely not.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dillon Houston</ENAMEX>

            
               Yes, It
Was an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Innocent Romance</ENAMEX>
            

            Well done!
A hearty thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX> for his piece "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An Innocent Romance</ENAMEX>," which is
another blow struck for sanity in this war against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s sinister attempt to
manipulate our emotions. These are potentially dangerous times. This country
needs all the sanity it can get.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie Bryan Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles</ENAMEX>

            
               To Bonk
or To Boink: That Is the Question
            

            Recently,
in a few articles (such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An Innocent Romance"</ENAMEX>) I have noticed the use of the
term "bonk" to refer to the act of sexual intercourse, especially in reference
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. I am impressed by 
                  Slate
               's attempt to use hip
language, but I'm afraid someone has been lax in his cataloging of the latest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">terminology</ENAMEX>. As a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> familiar with all the latest urban lingo, I
believe the proper term to be used in these contexts is "boink." Not only does
the word itself sound more fluid, but I also think the connotation it has is
more appropriate to the meaning 
                  Slate
                intends.

            
               --Theo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LeCompte Philadelphia</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Trash</ENAMEX>, Nostalgically
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s reviews of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paperback</ENAMEX> versions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trashy Books</ENAMEX>") brought back fond memories of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Report</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential Commission on Pornography</ENAMEX> , a peculiar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> that is now
likely to be emulated.

            Back during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nixon</ENAMEX>
administration, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decisions permitted some "obscene" materials to
be distributed only if they were combined with other matters that had
"redeeming social value." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> of a government document called
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential Commission on Pornography</ENAMEX> , or something
like that, presented an opportunity to sell the smut under an appropriate
cover. The illustrated edition included the full government report and garden
variety beaver shots, etc. It came out around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>, I believe, and I may not
have the precisely correct title.

            I recall that its technical
quality was poor, with a mimeographed text and low quality photographic
reproductions as well, which didn't match the text very closely. With modern
technology, so much more can be done. The video of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s testimony
will also lend itself to interstitial illustration.

            Sadly, my
copy of the "illustrated edition" was lost in a college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">dorm long ago</TIMEX> and far
away. Perhaps one could be found at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur</ENAMEX>
Stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarksboro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>

            
               Roll
With the Polls
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snowball</ENAMEX>'s Chance" ignores the obvious countereffects of polling. It is a
well-established fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will tend to slant their views and responses
to questions so as to better agree with what they perceive to be the majority
opinion. The perpetual quoting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s high job approval ratings helps
ensure that his job approval remains high. This phenomenon could unravel in a
similar way to that described in the article: As the polls drop a little, the
pressure to agree with the majority decreases, and the numbers have the
potential to drop precipitously. It would be difficult to determine which of
these phenomena is at work without careful study (i.e., without doing more than
just watching the polls and guessing).

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harkavy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            

               Government Gaming
            

            I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Chapman</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> "Vice
Is Nice" misses the point. Legal gambling is a good idea, since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will gamble in any case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> should regulate gambling as it
regulates other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, seeing that the odds are posted, that the games
aren't rigged, and that the promised jackpots are paid--and then leaving those
who want to do so free to waste their money gambling if they please. But
"legal" gambling is not what we have.

            What we have is
state-sponsored gambling. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> either runs the games, as in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lotteries</ENAMEX>, or sponsors them and takes a large cut of the take, as in casino
gambling. By running the games, the state endorses the dubious value of
"something for nothing." Worse still, it deceives the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>: Instead of
emphasizing the truth of the business--the long, long odds--it emphasizes the
unrealistic chance of winning big. (The ads for every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> lottery prove that
point.) The state treats <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> not as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> it serves and protects but as
suckers it will swindle.

            If the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> were not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> of the gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX>, they would apply the same consumer
protection standards to legal gambling that they do to other businesses. As it
is, they connive in the deception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, because they share the
take.

            I would
like to know if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX> would favor privatizing gambling, so that anyone
who put up proof of the ability to pay off the pot could run a lottery, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX>,
or whatever. That would take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> out of the gambling business
both ways. And I am sure that in that case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would make
sure not only that the games are honest but also that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> knew how long
the odds are.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Abel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ragen St. Louis</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX> replies:
            

            
               I don't
disagree with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ragen</ENAMEX> on the wisdom of getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> out of the
lottery business, repealing special gambling taxes, and leaving the whole
business to the free market. But I would not let the best be the enemy of the
good. I think "state-sponsored" gambling is preferable to none at all--just as
state-owned liquor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> are a lot better than <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traveler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Clothes</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Hollander</ENAMEX>--who wrote
"Travel
Without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clothes</ENAMEX>!"--might be interested to know that traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inns</ENAMEX> today provide clothes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX> are offered light cotton
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">robes</ENAMEX>, which can be worn around the hotel and in the surrounding neighborhood.
Heavier robes are provided in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>. Traditionally, the wearer would wear his
own traveling clothes to the inn. The clothes would be given over to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cleaned</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> would use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inn</ENAMEX>'s clothes during his stay. When the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">traveler</ENAMEX> left, he would again wear his own traveling clothes, which have been
cleaned. In this way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could make weekslong journeys on muddy footpaths
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> set of clothes, which would be washed regularly.

            I doubt
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> are interested in having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> walk off with their clothes, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollander</ENAMEX> suggests. However, it's conceivable that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> could provide the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> with a set of clothes while he's staying at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>. For example, a
business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> could arrive at the hotel wearing a suit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> would
provide casual clothes, and also underwear, socks, dress shirts, undershirts,
ties, etc. The business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> would wear his own suit to business events,
perhaps paired with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>'s shirts, socks, and ties. At the end of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trip</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> would receive his own clothes back, now laundered, for the
trip <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or to the next destination. Admittedly, providing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s clothes,
which are more complex, presents a slightly greater challenge. But this method
would make it possible to travel indefinitely carrying nothing more than a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paperback</ENAMEX> and a credit card. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, which is assured of getting its own
clothes back, can offer more than just jeans and T-shirts from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX>.
Wouldn't it be nice to have a closet full of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armani</ENAMEX> to go with your
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400-</NUMEX>a<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-night</TIMEX> hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> Tokyo

            
               A Pubic
Mistake
            

            Despite

                  Slate
               's status as an online zine and all that that implies,
(erratic spelling, shaky grammar, much exposure of genitalia), I feel strongly
that you should probably aspire to at least adequate copy editing. I'm
referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX>'s assertion in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 17</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s
Papers" that "pubic radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> have tripled." Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuger</ENAMEX> is simply
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obsessed</ENAMEX>, like the rest of you media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX>, with pubic matters, or perhaps we
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> have finally entered adolescence, with a concomitant increase in
all things pubic. But please consult the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Manual of Style</ENAMEX> : Any
sentence that contains the word "pubic" must also contain either the word
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>," the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>," or the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>." I'm shocked to see such a
lapse in a zine of 
                  Slate
               's quality, and was considering canceling
my subscription until I realized that to do so would mean that I would not have
access to the upcoming "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Explainer" on "What Is Oral Sex?</ENAMEX>"--and that I simply
could not swallow.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elliot Chicago</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must include their address and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
