
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Veiled
Threats
            

            I linked to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Veil of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tears</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Hollander</ENAMEX>, because it is always entertaining to read the
latest misconceptions from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> issues. While I was waiting for
the browser to log me on, I thought maybe, this once, from a publication like

                  Slate
               , I would be not amused but happily impressed by a thorough
report. Silly me.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bemused</ENAMEX>, I went through the
illogical conclusions plus the tired rhetoric of veil equals oppression, blah,
blah, blah. I laughed out loud when I got to the part where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> insisted
that although the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>" (uh, we're known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> world,
too) "claimed" they weren't oppressed by the veil, they, like, really were.
Question: Did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> actually interview any of these "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>"?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, maybe minor, point that
I feel compelled to clarify has to do with this statement: "It seems suitable
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, for example, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can't vote." A little research here
would show that no one votes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, be they <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, because
it's a monarchy, and voting's not really in.

            Oh, by
the way, I happily and quite comfortably wear my veil when I go shopping
downtown. I tie it tight around my
electrical/biomedical-engineering-from-USC-filled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, over my
up<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-to-the-minute</TIMEX>, very fashionable, mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> designer clothes (sorry,
don't mean to brag, just trying to break that ridiculous stereotype). And my
curvaceous legs certainly don't show.

            -- H.A. Dialdin
            

            
               Tabs of
Steele
            

            Perhaps all the tabloid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reading Emily Yoffe</ENAMEX> has been doing on behalf of 
                  Slate
                has taken a
toll on her logical capacities (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Pay for Say"</ENAMEX>).

            There is a very simple reason
why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>' book contract is less tainting (or less obviously
so, anyway) than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>' or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troopers</ENAMEX>' lining up for
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">tabloid/</ENAMEX>right-wing payouts. For the latter, the only value in their story is in
its salaciousness: If they had told their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">benefactors</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> was an
upright <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who never told a lie or looked twice at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, they wouldn't have
got a dime.

            As senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> during a tempestuous <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> term, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> can provide
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insights</ENAMEX> and behind-the-scenes anecdotes that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will find
interesting, even if he didn't see naked interns running up and down the West
Wing. As a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX> and the troopers (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zercher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGrath</ENAMEX>) have a
much greater incentive to spice up the truth or to invent a story out of whole
cloth.

            Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoffe</ENAMEX>'s example of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX>
Steele backfires on her. After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> wasn't paid for what she
said, but for a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> together. That photo was worth
money to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> claimed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> was secretly the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> probably could have earned more money if she had
volunteered some scandalous yarn.

            If your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> had been really incisive, she might have raised questions in the
opposite direction: Do big advances like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> received
increase the pressure on him to include some--perhaps false--"revelation" that
can be used in promoting the book? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoffe</ENAMEX> suggests that truth can be found just
as easily in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> as in traditional publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>; a less determinedly
shallow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> might wonder if the dominant role of money is suffocating the
truth in both venues.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Economics</ENAMEX>
            

            In his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Soft Microeconomics</ENAMEX>"
piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> tells us he uses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> browser. This
may well be, but Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> is very likely on his computer, and he
certainly paid for it even if he subsequently removed it. The idea that
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> is free is silly. It cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> to develop, and that cost
is amortized in the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows</ENAMEX>.

            This is one way the browser
really is part of the operating system.

            I doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> cares
all that much which browser <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use as long as they have to pay for Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>. In the fullness of time, there will be enough sites only viewable
with Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> and others will switch. Their personal
preferences for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> won't be worth the inconvenience.

            The same is true for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word</ENAMEX>. I wouldn't be surprised if Word is already on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s
computer, so he can read all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word 8.0</ENAMEX> documents produced by
others, which are unreadable with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WordPerfect</ENAMEX>. Eventually, he will use Word,
even if he doesn't like its equation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>--it will be just too inconvenient
to indulge his personal preferences. Perhaps he'll utter a little grumble of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dissatisfaction</ENAMEX>, like all those grumbles coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> being forced to
switch to Windows to be compatible. In the meantime, he has probably paid for
Word, so why should <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> care?

            There is absolutely no need
for this, of course. Software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> could make their file formats <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>,
enabling easy exchange of documents. The computer security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> Simson
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garfinkel</ENAMEX> has provided a thoughtful discussion and interesting recommendations
for government action in his column "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Let My Data Go</ENAMEX>!"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the biggest myths
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> computer software is that it leads to "natural monopolies." In fact, the
software incompatibilities that tend to create <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX> are carefully
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nurtured</ENAMEX>, precisely because they do create <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX>.

            It may be natural for
businesses to create and exploit monopolies whenever they have the opportunity,
but that is why we have, and need to enforce, antitrust legislation. The
software industry, if anything, has a greater need for protection of market
competition.

            
Incidentally, as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> might be interested in a series of
articles from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Education</ENAMEX> on how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is
reducing software competition in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Franks
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evanston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
