
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Mad
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>
            

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Goldberg</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My</ENAMEX> Nanny
Problem," he notes: "By contrast, the image of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> has undergone a
renovation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebbishness</ENAMEX> has alchemized into sensitivity. Take
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Reiser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad About You</ENAMEX> . He's whiny and feminized,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> tell me they find him doting and caring (me, I just see the whiny,
feminized part)."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reiser</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">character on Mad About You</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Buchman</ENAMEX>, is supposed to be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie</ENAMEX> get married, it's a nondenominational ceremony. Is he
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>? That's left up in the air. You might say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, he sounds <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>," or
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>," or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Brooks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sid Caesar</ENAMEX> played his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX>," but
that skirts the issue, which is how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are portrayed on television. To that
end, you might say that the conspicuous absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> issues is the
problem. But the complaint in the article is not that TV shows feature too few
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">male Jews</ENAMEX>. If it were, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad About You</ENAMEX> would just be one more in a line of
shows presenting evidence of that. Your complaint is about how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are
portrayed on television. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad About You</ENAMEX> is not all that useful as
evidence precisely because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> issues are absent from the show.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Silver Spring</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>

            
               My Klanny
Problem
            

            I would
rather not sound like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the PC <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Goldberg</ENAMEX> talking
about his opposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> marrying gentiles in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Nanny Problem</ENAMEX>"
strikes me as almost racist, and definitely xenophobic. Although he did not
offer any reasons for his stance, the only plausible ones would run along the
same lines as those offered for white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> not marrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>,
etc. It is patently offensive on almost all levels. I cannot imagine anything
of this sort being allowed in any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> of decent stature if it were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke or Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX> upset about an interracial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> on television. I have
been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> of 
                  Slate
                almost from the inaugural issue, and while
I am rarely disappointed with what I read, any more of this sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BS</ENAMEX> may cost
you a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX>. And even if that were not an issue, I am still
disappointed with the editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> for allowing this sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">manure</ENAMEX> to
published!

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Christopher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appling Irvington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>

            

               Loser
            

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>' "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Losers</ENAMEX>," about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>'s culture of forgiving failures, he
makes reference to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine:

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks ago</TIMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> business-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> wrote a gently mocking article in the school
newspaper about his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> job on Wall Street and then found himself instantly
blackballed from job interviews by every Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.

            While I hope many of your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> have had the opportunity to read the e-mail version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>'s (the
student's) article, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> is completely wrong about the blackballing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX> has
not only been invited to interview at several bulge-bracket <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, he has been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">warmly</ENAMEX> received, even by those he lampooned.

            Our
lesson for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brand</ENAMEX> is everything--go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> if you can.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel</ENAMEX>
Yarbrough
            

            
               Car
Berater
            

            I have followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Q.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Howard Kunstler</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> with interest. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> certainly seems to
have both the better case and the more reasonable tone. Nonetheless, there is
some merit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kunstler</ENAMEX>'s complaints about the ills of sprawl.

            May I
point out that sprawl is to a large extent the fault of our current local tax
system? If we replaced the current property tax on land and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> with a
tax falling solely on the value of land, vacant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and along the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> leading out of them would be built upon, instead of held for speculation.
Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could live closer to where they work and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, burn less gasoline
when they commute by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, and more often be able to walk. A denser population
would also make mass transit more feasible.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosen</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The
Talking Cure
            

            I was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">irritated at Christopher Benfey</ENAMEX>'s criticism, in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">True</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Confessions"</ENAMEX> (his review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Hughes</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Birthday Letters</ENAMEX> ), of the
idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sylvia Plath</ENAMEX> might have been helped by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX>. Is it really
such a strange idea that a suicidally depressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> might benefit from
treatment of some kind? I suspect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benfey</ENAMEX> feels that her early death by suicide
was somehow ordained, and has something to do with her status as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>. This
is the kind of sentiment that contributed to her death, and to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' many
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of silence.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
Krashin <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu</ENAMEX>

            

               Imprudent
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> received several letters mourning the retirement of "Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>," a weekly advice column.
            

            I am
dismayed to hear of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>'s return to her needlework. It is not that I am
against needlework. I frequently engage in it myself when stumped by the
complexity of an algorithm. It is just that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>'s advice is

                  Slate
               's best--some might say only good--facet. Please don't let
her leave.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dismayed</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa Iowa City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
