
 
     		
 	
 		i was trying to think about some of my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i liked in music and they're none of them are recent right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Lightfoot</ENAMEX> do you know who he is  and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moody Blues</ENAMEX> and i like to listen to piano music a whole lot and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Nelson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> so you like  a a variety sort of easy listening because you you like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but not all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i don't like that when they start i don't know i just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Nelson</ENAMEX> i guess because he's such a character
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh uh-huh yeah i i like some of his songs though they're they're not so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they're not so sad country all the time they're just kind of sweet sometimes you know i mean they're not the the typical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where they're just you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> left me my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> left me you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> is broken down
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>'s broken down and my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> just burned down you know but
 	
 	
 		yeah and there there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> have you ever heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Winston</ENAMEX> he plays piano i think he's dead now  but he plays wonderfully
 	
 	
 		no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like that
 	
 	
 		are do you do you play the piano is or you just like it
 	
 	
 		very badly i've got a piano  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> got a piano and uh vowed that someone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was going to learn so we all had to take lessons
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i was  the one that did the least poorly so she gave it to me and it's sitting here mostly taking up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> but sometimes it makes you feel good to sit down and play it it is real relaxing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it must be fun to be able to play it and you know if you can play tunes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can sing along to it'd be
 		that'd be kind of fun i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because i mean i play the flute and
 		not many things you can play that'll you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will sit there and sing along to and you can't sing along either so
 		but um i like a lot uh i like classical music just because of the when when i i don't play i like jazz music but
 	
 	
 		oh so do i forgot about that i said so do i i forgot about jazz
 	
 	
 		what's that
 		what's that
 		yeah i like a lot like i like uh the the New Age music like with um uh the um um i don't know if you've heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Neurotic Collection</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX> of those i love them
 	
 	
 		yeah i love those too they're just so relaxing
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i'd never heard them before until i went in a music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and you know how you put the headphones on and listen to it and i just i heard a piece and it was just so wonderful and then even my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> loves to listen to it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		isn't that nice i mean it's nice when you have a piece that that is so so peaceful that everybody likes you know and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it it it it you know it has pieces that are uplifting but it uh it's mostly relaxing and you don't uh because it doesn't have words you know you don't feel like
 		there's anything you have to remember you know as far as singing a song or something like that or interpreting what they mean or but uh
 	
 	
 		i mean you can just sit you know those little booklets that come along with it and you can just see the things that they're trying to show with music my my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> has gotten so into it that he's identified the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have written certain songs and he buys the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> that have that person
 	
 	
 		yeah oh okay i see what you're saying yeah
 	
 	
 		you know on it huh i mean i don't even know who did which ones but he does
 	
 	
 		i i can't identify them either i just like them i couldn't i know which ones come next but i don't even know their names most of them i don't know their names of the song but i i can identify them but i like that and i like um
 		course i i like classical music and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		were you in the band
 	
 	
 		i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> yeah so and i was in like chamber music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and stuff so
 	
 	
 		so was i
 	
 	
 		i'm used to pieces i and and i played classical flute i didn't play play jazz flute or anything like that so i can i can relate to it i suppose but uh
 		and i like i'm like you  i like the older stuff too because i like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and i like i like um uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		let me think who
 		um i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hebert</ENAMEX> um oh you don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hebert Laws</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hebert Laws</ENAMEX> is a flute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> he's a jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flute player</ENAMEX> and i like um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Chuck Mangione</ENAMEX> do you know who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Mangione</ENAMEX> is yeah i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Mangione</ENAMEX> i'm trying to think of all um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh what's his name plays the trumpet
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moody Blues</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moody Blues</ENAMEX> i i like mostly the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		did you like them
 	
 	
 		oh  but we do have i like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Simply Red</ENAMEX> we got Simply Red i thinking of all our CD's that we have what i really like and uh
 		i like Breeze i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> i think just because they all sort of sound they sound like a lot like red <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Simply Red</ENAMEX> if i'm going to listen to that kind of music nowadays that's it's easy in listening
 	
 	
 		so what type  Simply Red i've never heard of that
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		is it just instrumental
 	
 	
 		no it's it's got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> singing but  it's it is instrumental but it's it's got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> singing but it's got a like a whole bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> singing you know um   how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		on he can't hear me i i don't remember how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but it's it's got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and it's not
 		it's it's nice i mean it's pleasant you know music it's not what's it hurts your ears to hear it but it's not as it's not like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> where it's got that much instrument to it
 		you know it doesn't have like all the brass and everything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is telling me we have to hit the road we're going to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> and see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and then i'm going to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sulphur Springs</ENAMEX> yeah where are you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh you must live in this area
 		we're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay so we're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay you're going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Texas</ENAMEX> or something oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah just because there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> up there not because there's much else
 	
 	
 		oh okay well they're having a lot of recruiting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> in all the different areas that's why i was just wondering yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Texas</ENAMEX> is recruiting for you know their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall semester</TIMEX> and they're they've been doing a lot of that in the area
 	
 	
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>
 		well they're not colleges
 		they're not going to recruit me anymore i'm through  no more for me what what do you do
 	
 	
 		no more huh
 		well right now i'm just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homemaker</ENAMEX> but i'm going to school uh for legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> and that's why i know so and uh just nothing basically
 	
 	
 		are you going to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Texas</ENAMEX> for that
 	
 	
 		no no it uh no i don't go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Texas</ENAMEX> uh i got a degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWU</ENAMEX> but i'm really interested in legal  you know in the legal environment but i don't want to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> so i said well i think i'll go back to school and
 		see about being a legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>  so
 	
 	
 		that'd probably be pretty interesting i was summoned down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> they had summoned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four hundred</NUMEX> showed up and it was for a murder trial
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> had supposedly uh strangled this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and stuffed cotton toweling down her throat and up her nose anyway this is happened in nineteen eighty three
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they had us fill out a long questionnaire we stayed till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about one thirty</TIMEX> and they're going to call the ones that they're interested in from the questionnaire <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two to three</NUMEX> at a time and the trial won't take place until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's how it works
 	
 	
 		and they say it's going to last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two to three weeks</TIMEX> and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in front of me said i can't believe i was summoned i was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> and i was tailing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that was killed
 		well then i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and he said that this woman
 		this socialite in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> had hired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> to kill her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and the one that's accused was the one that actually did it and she has since taken off with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who had been uh
 		getting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> and then selling it and he had skipped bail and they finally extradited him and he's going to testify for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> against her so he'll have his sentence reduced
 	
 	
 		and this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that was in front of you oh well they'll weed him out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> yeah he he got off right away and i wrote that down on my questionnaire that he'd told me that so i figure that that will make me biased and i won't be chosen
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hopefully
 	
 	
 		well not necessarily but there's probably something else that might make you because you could know about you could know about the crime but not necessarily be taken off the jury you know not be accepted for jury the jury
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you i mean pretty much a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would know about it you know and and know some of the different things about it but um
 		they they might weed you out some other way you know if you if you don't believe like if this was a capital crime and and you don't believe in if you don't believe in death penalty you're not going to be picked at all so but
 	
 	
 		the death  penalty
 		no i said that i could i could believe in it in certain instances but i would be i'd find it hard to levy that against somebody
 	
 	
 		yeah so see there there they would have a doubt about you that you know because if that's what if that's what the punishment is in that in that instance then you're always going to say
 	
 	
 		you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know not guilty you're you're not going to want to have them have that crime uh that punishment so
 	
 	
 		yeah but then when you're uh when you're picked see i was picked for another murder trial before oh gosh and it's so hard because you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		everybody is wanting to go on and and get the sentence done and if you're trying to hold out you know there's so much pressure on you and you've got to come up with a decision
 	
 	
 		well especially with something where you have to find you have to find it beyond a reasonable doubt you have to find whether they're guilty beyond a reasonable doubt and it's like do you really feel that sure about
 		
 		
 	