
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hi Kay</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		i uh was thinking about salaries and benefits and uh was wondering what's the most important thing to you besides a salary in a job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well um i we just recently graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice University</ENAMEX> and uh we were going through a lot of job interviews and things and some of the things that were important to me
 		my uh when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was looking for his job was um
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> you know we he had been in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so i was used to his not being home at all  so i was you know didn't want him to have a job that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		would make him kind of be on call all the time and have to go in at any time and you know even on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and and um and things so that was important to me and also insurance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for the family our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> because we'd like to be able to take care of our medical needs and not be thinking so much about whether or not you can afford it
 	
 	
 		sure
 		yeah i don't ever want to have to worry about that that's real important to me um you know we have that that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um that's what we the insurance that we have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> when we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> they had um a different type of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> there that i really liked a lot
 	
 	
 		um-hum us too
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was um not that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>'s where you have to go to their they're sort of like clinics you know uh but this was just an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> where you could go to private practice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and to the regular
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and all that but it was with a certain list of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> that you know participated in the HMO
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um you know then you only had to pay the it for us it was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> dollar copayment every time you went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three dollars</NUMEX> for the prescriptions
 	
 	
 		well that's nice
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's good
 	
 	
 		and uh i especially liked the prescription especially since my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> tend to have ear infections all the time  that those prescriptions can be very expensive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i know we just went through that ourselves
 		we just you know were like fifty dollars for this series of antibiotics and things
 	
 	
 		oh i know especially if you get what is it Seclor i think that that just about breaks the bank right there
 	
 	
 		um-hum the
 		yes
 		yes it's pretty bad well yeah and we um we were interested in having dental dental insurance too because um well having been in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> we kind of put things off and only went in when we knew there was a problem somewhere and stuff and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do you
 	
 	
 		we wanted to be able to go in and have our teeth cleaned and just checked all over and
 	
 	
 		do you have the basic plan or do you have the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other one</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		we have um you know we're at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX> with uh an  we have like the
 		medical the dental insurance is separate is that what you mean and i don't think it's the basic i think it's the other one
 	
 	
 		right
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that's like you get additional they'll pay a little bit more i think for the different procedures we just have the basic right now and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for most things it tends to cover it we don't have too many major um expenses at this point but we have been able to find
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors dentists</ENAMEX> that will accept  pretty much whatever the basic plan pays a couple of times we've had to pay oh i don't know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> but that's not that bad
 	
 	
 		uh-huh no that's great yeah we need to go shopping for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX> and things like that too
 		yes and let's see besides insurance other things that we looked at um
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> does not like to commute very far and and we don't like him to be you know having to drive an hour to work or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no we don't like that either
 	
 	
 		so we kind of looked for where where the uh his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> would be located and how far well he's uh you know he's at the one that's at um
 	
 	
 		is his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in Plano
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy five</TIMEX> at uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six thirty five</TIMEX> and so well by living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> we're just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about fifteen minutes</TIMEX> away and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's not bad
 	
 	
 		especially especially when they finish all the construction out here and we didn't want him to let you know to like we had some job offers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> area and we thought well you know he would be really commuting
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh yes you're not kidding
 	
 	
 		and not only is it you know trouble to have to drive but it takes time away from your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> when you're out driving
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and um so that was something that was important to us and because like like i say i we kind of felt deprived that he had been in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and been away from us for so long that we were anxious to do everything we could to have you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		made us be more together and and what other can you think of another thing that you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> looked at and
 	
 	
 		well that those are some of the things that are very important to us too um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we we'd like you know other benefits that are provided um the athletic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> that that you can sometimes take advantage of um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that's that's pretty nice but i have to say that since we've come here we haven't done it too much though we haven't enrolled in too many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> or or any of that but that's a that's a nice benefit to have
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's true that's really important um also what um opportunities there would be for advancement
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think we looked at besides just you know what salary you would be having having now but when
 		when could uh your salary increase and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		is there was there somewhere to go
 	
 	
 		yeah that that's one of the i think the hard things right now i mean they're going through some some tough times  to say the least uh i know many of us are thankful that he still has a job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes that that we can make our mortgage payments and
 		yeah that's really true
 	
 	
 		uh uh one of the drawbacks i think of working for a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is often times you do have to follow pretty rigid um  guidelines um if if an employee is especially exemplary i think it's often
 		in a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> it's a little bit easier for them to say hey you know this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> did a wonderful job give him a big bonus kind of thing a lot of times
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have bonus plans where i think in a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> it's hard to do that because there're just so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to deal with and you have to have guidelines if you know for salary increases and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things that that happens when someone when you're dealing with a large company
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		but well we also were interested in um you know being sure that he
 		felt like he liked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that he would be working with and that there would be some uh opportunity for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for friendships that way so that you would feel happy going to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday</TIMEX> and rather than thinking oh i really i can't stand these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i but uh so that's something that was important to him and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		thinking he could um work under those
 	
 	
 		how long has he been in his present position
 	
 	
 		oh just since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last last summer</TIMEX> it's only been not even a year yet so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i was going to say  it sounds like you you picked out a lot of good things you know for him to to have to uh to choose in a position that has a lot of thought put into it
 		in a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> though you also get moved around a lot he may be having to drive over here to Lewisville some time or or we may be having to drive to Plano you never know
 	
 	
 		yes we're
 		oh yeah
 		you never know we're hoping that that won't be the case we
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think one of the most one of the most deciding factors of why we chose um this area is that um
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irving</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so he we have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> here his side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and being when we were down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> we were isolated i mean it's not that far but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would have we didn't have anyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that was our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and although we had really good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and and we had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and school support and things um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		we were anxious to move close to family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> just because we wanted our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to know their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah we're very
 	
 	
 		so that really made a big difference i think in why we chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and chose to move this way
 	
 	
 		we're very far from our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and it's really hard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and um they were the only grandchildren
 		and so our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are are are really far away in fact this is a little off the topic but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> happened to be on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> going from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> to back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and it stopped in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half an hour so</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i loaded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and we went downtown and  met her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX> and brought her a little snack and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> basket and  i think it it made her trip a little bit nicer
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		oh that's nice
 		yeah and it is i think it is important to you know want to be close to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean it's it's hard i mean to to just for us to snatch <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half hour</TIMEX> like that is is a special occasion for us so um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's definitely the way we feel
 	
 	
 		it's nice
 		it's nice that you can have your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> close like that
 	
 	
 		we're really enjoying it i wonder what it would be like i mean i i wanted to be close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but i also thought that it would be harder to be close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>  but it's turned out really good and i think that you know we're really satisfied with that choice and
 	
 	
 		yeah sometimes it can be
 	
 	
 		we you know kind of felt like um it was worth it to us
 	
 	
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		but anyway  well i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> just ran out the door so i need to go check on them but i've really enjoyed this conversation conversation and and uh nice to have met you and you have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay
 		well i have too
 		okay you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	