
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Jim um</ENAMEX> can you tell me a little bit about your opinions on capital punishment
 	
 	
 		uh the bottom line that i after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> of working with the state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> system i've come to the conclusion if you're going to give the man the death sentence
 		go ahead and fulfill the sentence understandably the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> says any time you hand down a death sentence to somebody they get a one appeal once that appeal fails within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty days</TIMEX> execute sentence
 		if you're going to give the man the death sentence don't keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on death row for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight nine ten years</TIMEX> and make him worry about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		plus costing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> twenty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five thousand dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> just to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> locked up
 	
 	
 		well you've you've got a point there but um do you think one appeal is is too stringent
 	
 	
 		no
 		i do not think one appeal is everybody's entitled to one appeal
 	
 	
 		okay
 		now um what do you think about about the death penalty itself do you think that we should have a death penalty
 	
 	
 		absolutely and i wish they would exercise it more thoroughly let the punishment fit the crime in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> we've got a very weird situation going on we're under federal supervision
 		and i agree to a point i agree with how the system works in some respects in other ways i don't for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time offenders everybody's entitled to screw up once we'll give them the early release credits we'll give them the good time credits we'll give them the early parole
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> trip down whether it's for the same crime or totally separate one you serve your sentence day for day
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> trip down this is where
 		my views on it goes way far beyond what the law states
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> trip down if it's for the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> or for a totally different one this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> has proven that he does not want to conform to the rules of society so you kill him period end of story
 	
 	
 		yeah well i kind of think we're too lenient number one
 		now i work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> but i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> so the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> just come out and said that because of what with
 		treating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> so-called brutally because uh the state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>'s overcrowded we have to release them
 		so they took the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> with the the minor crimes and they let them go they didn't have to serve the rest of their term and which is absolutely incredible
 		um
 		i think number one my opinion is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> are too lenient
 		but yet you get some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> trials and and it comes down to the nitty gritty when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are ready to condemn a person
 		they always kind of forgive him a little bit nobody wants to put the finger on somebody and say well that's it you know we're going to kill you
 		so it's got to be up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> i think we need we have to put into place <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> that are stricter than the ones that are in there now
 		and the other thing is i'm not sure about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> if someone breaks into your home
 		you have to do your utmost to leave so you can't cause a confrontation with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you can't shoot him you can't do anything with him i'm not sure what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Texas</ENAMEX> has got it rigged to where i can't shoot the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> can enter my property and i can't shoot him but once he's physically inside my house
 		uh the law reads to where you can defend yourself if you feel your life is being threatened yeah at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> if somebody's in my living room i feel real threatened so i'm going to come out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> blazing
 	
 	
 		yeah it's
 		yeah and ours
 		yeah and see in our case it's you have to you have to exit you have to leave and if you have to leave your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to get away from this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> that's what you should do
 		so
 		what choice have you got
 		you know <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as far as as far as</NUMEX>
 		our laws go up here
 	
 	
 		well the the legal system in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has gone to such extreme measures they've swung so far away from
 	
 	
 		yeah you're fading
 	
 	
 		there there is no such thing as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> in this
 	
 	
 		you're fading away <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		country anymore we only have situation ethics
 		i said yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> robs the liquor store and yeah he shot the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> but he was under the influence of narcotics
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		that that should make absolute <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> difference you shot the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you get the death penalty period
 	
 	
 		that doesn't make any
 		right
 		right
 		and so he was under the influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX> at that time when when the act was was performed but he knows he's going to go back and do the same thing over again
 		you know when he's straight so so-called
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that any one i believe you if you murder someone i believe in an eye for an eye
 		and i think probably uh
 		uh maybe the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that uh that i talk to
 		you go out there and you kill somebody you rob a gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> or a drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and you shoot somebody
 		you deserve to be killed also
 	
 	
 		that should be automatic death penalty no if ands or buts
 	
 	
 		right
 		right um you're subject to one appeal i i kind of don't agree with you on that i think probably you should have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> appeals
 	
 	
 		but that's what's got our system bogged down so bad now they've appealed everything to where if they've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> typographical error where in their
 		in one line instead of spelling
 		they've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> word misspelled i mean it's a very minor clerical error they couldn't tell they they'll appeal the hell out of that and that just throws another wrench and it takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> to work an appeal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's yeah right common sense has to has to set in some place it's just like uh  uh organized crime now they know all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they know that the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of organized crime and all that sort of stuff why can't they do something about it
 		because they can't if they if they tape something they can't they can't bring it into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> as as evidence
 		and they know
 		they just had this uh i don't know if it's been in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> but um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that got out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> here to go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> um swearing in ceremony
 		and they got uh
 		uh somebody and i'm not sure who who it was what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> what law enforcement agency
 		they got a movable bug a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a court order for a movable bug which means that you can take it any place and put it any where
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now they're contesting that movable bug because they didn't state that they were going to put it in this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> where this meeting took place so there's a technicality there but they know outright
 		that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> and whatever else you got and yet they're not going to let that evidence in you know as admissible evidence in court
 		so that has to be looked at too um i don't know who they're protecting they're not protecting the innocent that's for sure
 	
 	
 		since so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that came up with the laws that made all these loopholes and technicalities take a look at your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> you'll find that the vast majority of them are practicing lawyers
 	
 	
 		that's true that's true um self-preservation of the species i guess right
 	
 	
 		that's it what they don't realize the time is coming and i see it coming over the horizon that the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people people</ENAMEX> are getting fed up with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BS</ENAMEX> and are demanding are going to demand real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> instead of this
 	
 	
 		well the
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we're getting to a point where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> gets a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen year</TIMEX> sentence he's going to serve fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> and he's out
 	
 	
 		you're kidding
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> actually assigned
 	
 	
 		because of because of what because of overcrowding or
 	
 	
 		overcrowding
 		overcrowding
 	
 	
 		huh
 		now the pendulum's going to swing
 		more and more people
 	
 	
 		we've gone too far to the left it's fixing to come back hard right
 	
 	
 		yeah because you look at the statistics now and i'm sure it's in your your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> just like it is in ours that
 		every major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> now the increase of crime is is escalating i mean there are more look at the look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there are being shot now
 		i mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> there's there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> they just get blown away for no reason you know stray <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> or
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> they were going out there and they were shooting and they get these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and they don't do anything with them so i kind of i kind of agree with you i'm kind of you still in the in the uh prison system
 	
 	
 		yeah i've been with them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		how do you like it
 		well
 	
 	
 		all things considered i'd rather be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> because once i walk inside the gates the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> have more rights than i do
 		say an inmate swings at me or he's raised his fist threateningly toward me i've got to let him hit me before i can hit him bac k to be justified have it called what they call a justified use of force
 	
 	
 		that's incredible
 	
 	
 		thank uh federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Wayne Justice</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you uh you carry a firearm in when you're in there
 	
 	
 		no in inside the gate i do not carry any weapon at all
 	
 	
 		nothing
 	
 	
 		nothing
 	
 	
 		not even a uh uh billy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> or
 		huh
 		what's the purpose of that so they can't take it
 	
 	
 		so they can't take it away from you
 	
 	
 		yeah well i don't know so you going to make a career out of it
 	
 	
 		i seriously doubt it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh it it it all boiled down to when the opening for this came up it was the best deal going it was paying so much more money than what i was making before i couldn't turn it down
 	
 	
 		oh okay is it uh was it uh civil service
 	
 	
 		uh actually really really
 		
 		
 	