
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hi Chris</ENAMEX> this is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carol</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		this is interesting uh question come up here uh proposal for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> um or something like that doing public service i
 	
 	
 		or doing or doing public service
 	
 	
 		suppose the idea is to um
 		i don't know
 		but but the point be to that get
 	
 	
 		well
 		in order to go in order to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> you have to have a college degree
 		and so that eliminates a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from that and doing public service how are they supposed to support themselves
 	
 	
 		it sure does
 		yeah i i i suppose the idea the idea would be to get um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> interested in public service
 		and to um i don't know maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> give give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> give young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> an appreciation for maybe what they have and what other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't have
 	
 	
 		well yeah i think that's a good idea although i don't i think if it's something that's forced on you
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		um i think that the attitude
 		is not going to be quite the same
 	
 	
 		well i tend to agree and um uh in that we do live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and i think one of our uh one of the
 		things that our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is based on is freedom of choice
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um forcing someone to give up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> of their life uh doing something that may not be or
 		the timing that they want to do it or uh perhaps even you know
 		maybe they would have something something else just just the idea of forcing someone to do something i i'm pretty much against that
 	
 	
 		yeah from what i've read most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> do do some type of volunteer work at some time in their lives
 	
 	
 		just on their own um-hum
 	
 	
 		but i right but i agree it has to be at their choice and it needs to be a time when they're ready to do it
 		um i don't think you can just snatch somebody away from
 		you know you don't know what their circumstances are or what's going on in their life you can't just snatch them away and make them go do something they don't want to do
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		sort of like the draft
 	
 	
 		i think there would be an awful lot of resentment and um i i really don't think it would be feasible on our country
 	
 	
 		then that raises a question of how you know are you going to pay them or are you going to provide them with you know
 		place to live and food to eat and whether they have a family you know
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah some young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do some young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> start <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> young and or maybe are responsible for their parents
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> things like that
 		i suppose they may have exceptions but um
 		i guess it all it would all boil down to
 		i mainly i i guess my question would be what what's the purpose what's what's trying to be accomplished by
 		by that proposal
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure i'm not sure if it's a way to cut down government expenses or it's like you said that's something more you know to to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aware
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		more esoteric
 	
 	
 		yeah what's going on and what needs to be done but i really do think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are pretty well aware i think more so now than ever before
 	
 	
 		you know i think that's true and i i tend to think that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are also growing up with a bit more awareness of that at least i mean i i feel i try to as an individual my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are very young but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		i i think they're being taught a lot
 		maybe to be more responsible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		hopefully to understand that everyone is not as in as fortunate
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		as as perhaps they are
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and i think that that's the trend now i think that's the trend now and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are a lot more willing to give of their time
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 	
 	
 		and help out
 	
 	
 		you know its also seems to me if someone does it on a volunteer basis then they will probably put a lot more into it than if they were forced um
 	
 	
 		yeah and get and get more out of it
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so i think we or  sounds like we pretty much agree
 	
 	
 		yeah it's an interesting idea but i think we do agree and
 		at least i'm i'm i don't think i would vote for it if it came down to that
 	
 	
 		no i don't think i would either
 	
 	
 		maybe just do our best to
 		to do our own fair share and
 	
 	
 		do what you can when you can right then as long as you feel good about yourself and what you're doing to help i think that's more important than
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well it's been nice talking to you about it i have to admit it's something i hadn't thought of before it it is interesting to think about it
 	
 	
 		nice talking
 		yeah really
 		well it does kind of catch you by surprise
 	
 	
 		yes
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay well thanks
 	
 	
 		okay we'll talk to you later bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	