
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay pro football i like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Giants</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pro football
 		okay
 	
 	
 		that's right across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i don't think i could  i don't think i could
 	
 	
 		yes
 		that's one end to the other that's true
 	
 	
 		i don't think i could spread my patriotism any more than well actually i like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">49ers</ENAMEX> too but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> i go with so
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i'm surprised being that being from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i thought you'd be a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		well i'm not originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> so uh i kind of i moved around a lot when i was well up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and uh so i've i've kind of picked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> all over the country
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i liked uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> i lived in in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Texas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abilene i</ENAMEX> worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abilene</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> and i really enjoyed watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> play and they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they went through a rebuilding thing down there and and and uh i watched them go downhill like all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> do you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> did like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Giants</ENAMEX> did like like i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">49ers</ENAMEX> are about to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i think that's true
 	
 	
 		i think the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> get a little old and get a little tired and uh
 	
 	
 		well the only thing that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> may have done differently is that they've done a good job in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> of of getting rid of their older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and and bringing up new a bunch of new people
 	
 	
 		sure
 		you're exactly right and and this the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> failed to do <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> failed to do that they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bum Phillips</ENAMEX> in there and a and a good running back i forget to uh i forget that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>'s name uh
 	
 	
 		you know
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell Earl Campbell</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Earl</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campbell</ENAMEX> and they run that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to death
 	
 	
 		um-hum but it it worked for them but uh you're right they they kind of
 	
 	
 		and
 		yep but
 		they had nothing to back it up and
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and uh you see that so much in pro sports we we go through this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this rebuilding cycle without a without a backup <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bench</ENAMEX> and
 		it's it's happened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> here with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtics</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> they finally gotten some backup support so you don't have to keep <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> out there for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		but i like uh i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> i i kind of think they snuck into the championship <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year this past year</TIMEX> and and i'm not so sure  they'll get away with it again but
 	
 	
 		well i think i got to agree with you there
 	
 	
 		they they kind of pulled it off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> but i like
 	
 	
 		they did a they had a excellent game in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> uh i was real impressed but uh because
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes
 		i think the whole thing of how they got there was to me i i kind of well i i guess that's the rules and
 		and the way the and the way the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the play-offs</TIMEX> are run but i
 		i don't know i just think there was probably some other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that they only missed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">couple of</NUMEX> points and they really should have been in there but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> because of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Parcells</ENAMEX> and i like him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> and he's he's been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> a a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> i i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure that they can repeat okay
 	
 	
 		well as hard as it is to repeat anyway uh and as as close as i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Giants</ENAMEX> were to the rest i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		there really wasn't a a dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> this year
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		and uh you know if if if like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> was dominant for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> uh they had a you know they had a chance to but uh i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s going to be able to do that
 	
 	
 		no i don't think they'll be able to carry it that far uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		they've got i mean they've got some excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		who who would you if you had your pick out of anyone of the league <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> who would you say is going to be the new new uh <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">champions</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety one</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum uh i might go with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		that kind of that kind of put you out on a limb a little bit i guess
 	
 	
 		you know this may be really out on a limb but i might go with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> as as good as they were toward <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> got into the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> and just just missed
 		think they'll be hungry next year
 	
 	
 		i thought i thought for sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> was going to be in there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX> i really did and i would that would be my choice that would be my choice again this year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> when he went down hurt they brought another young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> in there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich uh Reich</ENAMEX> or yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reicher</ENAMEX> or whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reicher</ENAMEX> whatever his name is and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> he they never even missed a beat i mean they just kept right on pouncing
 	
 	
 		i think it was
 		no
 	
 	
 		and if it weren't for the tumble of the ball <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> would have been there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and and to me that's another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super team</ENAMEX> course
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm being up here in the northeast corner i kind of like these northeast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i can believe that
 	
 	
 		course i used to like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriots</ENAMEX> too they were just down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from here but boy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriots</ENAMEX> are kind of sad they're now they're talking of moving out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and they ought to all get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and take <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kiam</ENAMEX> with them
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 		
 
 		yeah i think that's probably would be best for the area
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah they they really
 		i think they hurt the sport <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> with all that controversy over that locker room incident with uh with uh all that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> and stuff and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think they just could have handled it more professionally i i i believe that they they hurt themselves i guess
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		they've had a lot of trouble with uh with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sullivan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiam</ENAMEX> they didn't really see eye to eye and of course the the big political football up here you know now they're now they're trying to move the team somewhere else the last i heard
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> just kind of
 		i've been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patriot fan</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and you know when you when they're only like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> miles from where you live you can get to see the games once in a while and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's just a shame you keep going there and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">like week after week</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> you come away a loser i mean you after a while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> get tired and we just didn't go anymore so
 	
 	
 		yeah well losing is i mean i'm i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis and Saint Louis Cardinals</ENAMEX> when they were there were uh a mostly a losing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah sure
 		but they played like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> exactly right
 	
 	
 		they exactly and and yeah they never they never did things to embarrass the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and that's what i think would be would be bad about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah they they really didn't do good at all for us up here and that's that's too bad because they were they were some good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> they are some good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriots</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> you know and
 	
 	
 		um-hum well that's true
 	
 	
 		i think they need to get rid of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grogan</ENAMEX> he's been around too long they need to put him in the front <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> doing management or something but they need to get him off the field and and get the manager
 	
 	
 		well he's going to he's going to kill himself
 	
 	
 		he is eventually
 	
 	
 		he's going to end up paralyzing himself or something i mean i worry about that guy
 	
 	
 		because he's been
 		he's been hurt so many times and he's not as agile these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX> they just take advantage of that and and and though they don't show it and say it and do it intentionally
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		it's just their strength will beat him you know sometimes
 	
 	
 		yeah well the only thing that might save him is that in the backs of their minds they may think that they don't want to hurt him permanently
 	
 	
 		sure of course no one does i'm sure they don't you know it was
 	
 	
 		and so they may let up on him so i don't know
 	
 	
 		that that would be and the other thing is they're going to be there in that same position one of these days you know and hopefully they like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bo Jackson</ENAMEX> now as i understand has hurt himself in both baseball and football he he's there's question as to whether he's going to come back i haven't read <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s paper
 	
 	
 		right right
 		well the last i heard i didn't read it in the paper but i heard it on TV was that they were still saying that he's out permanently you know yeah
 	
 	
 		is that right there's a there's a fabulous career
 	
 	
 		yeah well they were they were talking i think i was watching uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAAs</ENAMEX> and they were talking about uh you know this is one reason they say that
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> get the money as quickly as they can you know get all the money that you know
 	
 	
 		oh sure because they're they're tenure is real short
 	
 	
 		right and it could end at anytime
 	
 	
 		anytime at all yeah but yeah yeah he may come back into <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> but i doubt if he'll ever come back and play
 	
 	
 		you know it was weird when i what i read in the paper was
 		uh the
 		uh
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the baseball</TIMEX> career was over permanently the football career might not be and i don't understand that i would have thought it was the other way around
 	
 	
 		well i would have too i that's the same that's that's i don't understand that obvious i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> is much more strenuous than baseball
 	
 	
 		especially yeah i mean
 	
 	
 		you get a chance to sit down in baseball every once in a while you know if you're not up for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> innings or whatever but
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 		and you don't get hit
 	
 	
 		yeah the key right there yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		or you're not supposed to anyway
 	
 	
 		some some big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX> not out there trying to stomp you into the ground you know i mean but uh i that that's surprising i i was i had not heard that in the in the
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		it it may have been a misquote but that's sure what i got
 	
 	
 		yeah they
 		no i'm i'm sure they probably well it all depends i guess on on what they feel is you know what he can do because <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> is not a light an easy sport either that's a very very athletic sport lot of running and stuff like that and the hip
 		may be a real problem but i i would think that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> would have been more of a detriment to him than than baseball would
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah i was i i was kind of surprised that uh that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royals</ENAMEX> let him go with a football career as long as they did you know
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> i'll tell you i think i still think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Montana</ENAMEX>'s the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> that ever handled a ball
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Bradshaw</ENAMEX> i think is probably even better than he is or better or was was better than than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Montana</ENAMEX> is now
 		because i of course  another another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steeler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> showing up here you know another black and yellow surfacing up here you know  this is the black and blue league up here in the corner
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradshaw</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> and i think uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Montana</ENAMEX>'s probably one of the finest and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Elway</ENAMEX> i believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> if he had some different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in front of him
 		he would be on par with
 		with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Montana</ENAMEX>
 		because i really think that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> did not do much for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elway</ENAMEX> and his career except make him look bad on times when he really should not have looked that bad
 	
 	
 		well that's uh i agree with you there i mean he didn't have the surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> had there's no doubt about that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a fact i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Elway</ENAMEX> i think he was a fabulous he he still is he's got a he's got a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> left in him
 	
 	
 		i don't think he'll do it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		no i don't believe so i don't believe he's going to be able to get the job done in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> he's going to run up some big numbers and stuff but i don't believe he's going to get the job done there because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> simply because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> is not not the
 	
 	
 		i'm not even yeah
 	
 	
 		doesn't have enough depth i don't think to support him like like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Montana</ENAMEX> got supported with the 49ers
 	
 	
 		well i think it's it's not only depth i don't think that they've got the spirit or whatever to go out and get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to support him i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that could be true too
 	
 	
 		yeah the coaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> seems i mean they were they were fighting each other coaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elway</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that in-fighting can really destroy a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and its ability to win
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that did it to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> didn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah pardon me
 	
 	
 		didn't it do that to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh it certainly did it most certainly did yeah we as i say we went through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivans</ENAMEX> that that owned the team you know and and owned the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's unreal the in-fighting it was it was just it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> in the paper was like you know it was like saga like a like a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like a soap opera it you know who's fighting with who who doesn't want to go out on the field who doesn't want to catch it's unreal i mean you know that that's really detrimental to the team
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve it</ENAMEX>'s been nice talking with you
 	
 	
 		yeah it has
 	
 	
 		it sure has and i i'd like to try this thing every once in a while i thought i'd give it a try <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX> being so rainy i'm locked in up here anyway so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well like i say i i guess i'll root for any <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football game</ENAMEX> because i really like the sport and i'm glad that was my topic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah it worked out real good
 	
 	
 		you uh you uh take care of yourself and if you're ever up this way to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Attleboro</ENAMEX> look me up my name's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Smith</ENAMEX> and i work in building twelve
 	
 	
 		you too
 		all right i will
 		all right
 	
 	
 		okay come on up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">bye</NUMEX>-bye
 	
 	
 		you you take care bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	