
 
     		
 	
 		okay capital punishment oh i honestly don't feel like it's strict enough in my opinion
 	
 	
 		in the way that it's applied or that it's applied at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		so i how do you feel that it should be applied
 	
 	
 		well i just i just feel like
 		there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapists</ENAMEX> and everything else just walking the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		and that that the penalty ought to be out there and be enforced
 	
 	
 		yes yes not
 		getting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paroled</ENAMEX> lets say in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX> i mean if your going to sentence somebody lets say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> let them stay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		that's i agree with that completely i know we don't have enough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> but there has got to be some kind of punishment for these people
 	
 	
 		there has that's right
 	
 	
 		because if they turn around they can get away they get away with it and they get away with it and they get away with it and then they do something worse and they get a slap on the wrist they get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty days</TIMEX> in jail and they finally get up to where they kill somebody else and they go through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen</TIMEX> appeals and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how many <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> dollars
 	
 	
 		that's right that's honestly right
 	
 	
 		and it's
 	
 	
 		they have really got it better than we do in a lot of ways
 		you know
 	
 	
 		well they certainly are living off our expense at our expense
 	
 	
 		but they sure are just
 		because some innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can really it seems like really serve a rough time you know i'm not saying innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> let's say someone wrote a hot check for instance
 	
 	
 		i didn't
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know it seems like when they go to prison it they really seem like it's a rough time for them and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> well go to prison oh he's just there to serve his time and get back out on the street
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and and be paroled and and have served the sentence that's what that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> face with that choice one thing i really hate is they don't explain to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> in a in a trial on a capital murder trial or in
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		cases of rape or in different things that are so horrible what it means when they sentence them to
 		you know they'll sentence them to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and say that it's you know that it's going to you know that should be life but instead in in given the choice of either sentencing to death or sentencing to life they'll give them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then turn around in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX> that you know and less they're out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		even if if they're even in that long or they appeal and then they get an appeal that says it was you know an unjust amount of time it was an extraordinary long length or something
 	
 	
 		time uh-huh
 		yes i just i would just be i would love to see them just really get real strict on parole
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		i'd like to see the death penalty more as a deterrent i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know that nobody that it doesn't
 		you know it it's not a deterrent right now because it's not really effective
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's  should be you know this for this crime this is the penalty you killed someone you know in cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> or whatever this is what's going to happen
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah you get it back yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i mean it sounds horrible it i i hear myself saying this and
 		but i don't know what else to do with some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are because they let them back out again and they do the same thing over and over again then they put them back in jail and they get out and and more and more innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are hurt or killed
 	
 	
 		but it's
 		i i know yeah
 		same thing yes
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> just are on the endless merry-go-round in the legal system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's like i said at our expense
 	
 	
 		uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really doesn't think that much about it because it hasn't happened to them which it hasn't to me either you know thank goodness but still it it could
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i know i you read about it in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> somebody who's done this or that
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		something
 		really horrible and they just get away with it and nothing happens
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and as far as the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> i honestly don't know what their capital punishment is you know i i haven't kept up you know anything like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> the southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> seem to be
 		somewhat more conservative and still have the death penalty and i think i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> had it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and then they um took it off the books they repealed it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Manson</ENAMEX> and and some of these other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were sentenced to death at the time they repealed the death penalty were sentenced to life in prison
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and are now now that even though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> has reinstated the death penalty
 		for whatever various crimes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were there originally when they when they changed the laws to revoke the death penalty are still in there for are in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> in quote for life and and are now coming up for parole some of them like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> who's come up
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's been denied fortunately but
 	
 	
 		but yes but still it came up though didn't it i mean you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that originally sentenced him sentenced him to death
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then while he was on appeal on his thousandth and one appeal the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> reverked revoked the law in the early seventies and then they reinstated it later but the penalty didn't go back you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it seems like a lot of times the law is is totally on the criminal side and and isn't protecting the rest of the people
 	
 	
 		yes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> is really
 		seems like left out in the cold more or less doesn't it in a lot of well especially in things you pick up the paper and you read you know you think oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		and the the laws are all the rules some of the things that would make sense to to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that this this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> has a a prior  criminal history you know where he's raped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> women
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then he gets up for this one trial and they don't find anything out about the facts that he's done this over and over and over again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so they say well this is you know i i don't know if they say it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> or whatever but they give him a lighter sentence thinking he's not a habitual criminal
 	
 	
 		or you know plead insanity
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		you know  and a lots of things
 	
 	
 		to some extent if they would do something with some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but that seems to be a good way to get off for a lot of them too
 	
 	
 		oh yes i think yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		they plead <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX> and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years later</TIMEX> they're cured and let loose on society again
 	
 	
 		yes i
 		it just just doesn't make sense i just
 	
 	
 		i mean it's a it's a scary world out there anymore where your afraid to go out i know in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> metroplex area i don't go out hardly if i don't have to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at night</TIMEX> by myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i certainly i i grew up in a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and it wasn't that way when i was younger
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well like i said i live in a small place you know
 	
 	
 		we could go around and boy
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		even the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> now though has really changed from when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> but now i'm raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		it just it really is
 	
 	
 		yes ever you can't even
 		when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> i would run between my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and four</NUMEX> blocks sometimes and as long as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> had a general idea where i was and i was back on the time and now i don't let my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out of the front yard that i can't see them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		see them yep
 		yeah  it really is well we're probably fixing to run out of time pretty soon but i've enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well good talking to you too bye bye
 	
 	
 		bye okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	