
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh books
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		mainly i read the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> these days
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's very good i do too
 	
 	
 		good that's great to hear uh and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> literature uh i've kind of i used to read a lot of uh novels
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it seems as though if you really want to set a time side time to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> and you work and and whatever uh that pretty well takes up your time for reading
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it does it
 	
 	
 		and i i been praying that God would put a desire to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> in my heart and he really has it's getting to where a just really want to read it
 	
 	
 		that's good
 		that's good it it  it's uh it's hard for me to find time also to read uh a lot of times i do just read magazines and stuff like that for
 		for you know because i don't have a lot of time but when i do get to sit down and and read i like to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> and i like to read i read to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> a lot too
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		and uh i like to read you know <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible i have Bible</ENAMEX> storybooks so i like reading those to her and she really enjoys those
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's good and it and it's kind of short because we don't woe don't have a lot of time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to read so
 		it's real enjoyable
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		for both of us
 	
 	
 		have you ever read any of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank E Peretti</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frank E</ENAMEX> no i guess i haven't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh This Present Darkness</ENAMEX> and uh
 		uh i forget the title the other well he uh he's also written a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> how old is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> okay he's written some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s books as well and they're all spiritually uh oriented yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		what's his name again Peretti
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frank E Peretti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P E R E T T I</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank E Peretti</ENAMEX>
 		i have to look for those
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah do because uh i love to read his his uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s  books just
 	
 	
 		just to read them well that's good
 	
 	
 		yeah oh they're good they're great and it's uh like uh uh usually about a family of um
 	
 	
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archeologists</ENAMEX> and the spiritual fights that they get into like uh uh digging in old ruins and running across like uh the old gods
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		yeah
 		oh that sounds pretty neat
 	
 	
 		yeah it is it's real exciting
 	
 	
 		oh i'll have to look for those
 	
 	
 		and it also teaches them spiritual warfare you know so
 	
 	
 		right
 		well that's neat well i  i have a my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Precious Moments</ENAMEX> collection and i like that because it's a it's real easy to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh follow for her you know uh gosh if if i read straight out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> to her she'd  never understand any of it
 	
 	
 		well it's hard for me
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it is it is real hard to to follow and understand and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> that uh has a little bit of a uh a glossary in the back and it helps explain who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are that's that's about the hardest thing is who's related to who
 	
 	
 		i know it and especially it's hard to keep your interest in those begats
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes yes it sure is but but it is good reading and it's good for us and and everything i really do enjoy it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's right
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		i also but then on the other extreme i like to read uh
 		i guess horror i don't know horror <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven King</ENAMEX> type books
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i've read a lot of his too
 	
 	
 		the and i i like that that's good fun reading
 	
 	
 		yeah can't put them down
 	
 	
 		no you can't you really can't they are good and ooh they just they're just so suspenseful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really do enjoy his
 	
 	
 		uh there's another guy
 		oh what can what is his name
 		oh durn  you would well you know when you're recording you can't remember remember
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh oh Dean uh Kratz</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kranz</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Krantz</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah who
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Krantz</ENAMEX> i know her
 	
 	
 		uh no it's a guy
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and he he writes the same thing though it's that real gruesome  horror stories yeah
 	
 	
 		oh
 		ooh yeah yeah that's good
 	
 	
 		Koontz uh his last name ends in a Z i know that
 	
 	
 		yeah oh i think i know who you're talking about uh i've seen i don't think i can pronounce it either but
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm in a book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> and i think i've seen his books
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in there  i've never read any of his
 	
 	
 		i kind of got burnt out on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven King</ENAMEX> though it seems like
 	
 	
 		but they're real
 	
 	
 		it's all the did you ever read the uh uh
 		oh it's one of his first books
 		The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stand</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes that oh that long thing
 	
 	
 		i know it and that seems like all of his books have kind of come from that i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah they do kind of follow or
 	
 	
 		you know that
 	
 	
 		are similar
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i love that book though i thought it was great
 	
 	
 		yeah it really was and i loved <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Shining</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh yes
 	
 	
 		that was that was my favorite
 	
 	
 		oh those <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hedges</ENAMEX> when they started moving whenever they  they made that into a movie i was thinking oh my gosh if they show that i'll just die for some reason that scared me more than anything
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah that is he just brings stuff alive you know you could just visualize everything that's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and that was a pretty scary movie too
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they did a pretty good job but  they didn't follow it exactly but they did give it you know do it justice
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's right
 	
 	
 		but uh most of the time they don't with when follow books very well when they ma ke them into movies
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true i liked it as well
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah uh i did too
 	
 	
 		that's
 		another big fat one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah that was good i liked uh i also liked uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cujo</ENAMEX> did you read that one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		except it broke my heart  i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog lover</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah  me too and then uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Night Stand</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Night</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no it was uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead Dead</ENAMEX> Zone that's one i liked
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		Dead Zone
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i've read that one too
 	
 	
 		that was a that was a real good one
 	
 	
 		he's written a lot of books <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> he just sits down <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours a day</TIMEX> just like any other job
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i know it
 		right and then he has some under uh another name
 	
 	
 		that's right that one about the gypsies or that hunger or something uh
 	
 	
 		that he's written
 		yeah
 		yeah uh i think his name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bachman</ENAMEX> he wrote under the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bachman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bachman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah he is really interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah he's so prolific
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah ooh i wish i could do that
 	
 	
 		oh i know it and i have gone back and after i i graduated i read some of the old classics that i just bluffed my way through and have found that i enjoy them quite a bit too uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i do too i love old
 		good old
 	
 	
 		once you can get into the language you know the language uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it's like it's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> but it's not the same <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> they speak today
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so it's kind of hard to keep you know at it but their worthwhile
 	
 	
 		that's true but i
 		that's that was one of my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was uh
 	
 	
 		literature
 	
 	
 		literature
 	
 	
 		yeah me too
 	
 	
 		i used to love those old good good old books
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i didn't mind doing that at all
 	
 	
 		Nathaniel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawthorne</ENAMEX> is pretty scary himself
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i liked uh
 		oh gosh why can't i think of their names uh
 		
 
 		shoot the one that wrote uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wuthering Heights</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> wasn't that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Eyre</ENAMEX>
 		no he wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Eyre</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		no that was another one
 		yeah yeah uh well you know who i'm talking about
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah those are good old
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		good old books and
 		good old books and classics that's right
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		sure is neat
 	
 	
 		that's why i like to watch that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Masterpiece Theatre</ENAMEX> on channel thirteen because they'll take a classic and and uh televise it you know put it into a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		a viewing format more or less
 	
 	
 		right
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just don't have time to read nowadays
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know it's it's really hard for me i work <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> jobs and
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		uh have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and teach <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and go to school myself so it's it's hard for me to
 	
 	
 		well i can imagine
 	
 	
 		
  
 		sit down and read but when i do i just
 		just love it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah me too
 		well i think we've accomplished <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> so  it's good talking to you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think we have too thank you very much you too bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	