
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay i guess that's it uh
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		i was just thinking about what movies i've seen lately mostly uh  we go to uh the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> run movies i guess what the ones that we call the dollar used to call the dollar movies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh so we see uh the ones that have been out for a while i was trying to think what the last movie that we went to see was probably <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia House</ENAMEX> with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah sure
 	
 	
 		found it quite enjoyable myself uh uh had also seen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunt For Red</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> you know with him in that and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		God i don't have to say kind of caught me off i'm more of a
 		
 
 		looks good in the paper commercials look great on TV um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh i did see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red October</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh this is going to be i've seen a lot of video lot of lot of video VCR stuff um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man oh man</ENAMEX> i have to say uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chevy Chase</ENAMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vacation Christmas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		thing was one here recently we saw at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> time um
 		God i haven't been in a movie since
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Superman Batman maybe Batman</ENAMEX> might have been one yeah
 	
 	
 		well that's
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well well i didn't even see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> so that's uh that's pretty good so
 	
 	
 		it's been
 	
 	
 		or no let's see uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Tracy</ENAMEX> i did we did see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Tracy</ENAMEX> so that's
 	
 	
 		i haven't seen any of that stuff really
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 		uh so you so then you're not a uh uh not a frequent movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goer</ENAMEX> either
 	
 	
 		well i love it we uh got a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and and and she just turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year old</TIMEX> so it just kind of put the clamp on things um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah so
 		so you watch a lot of videos
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then uh
 	
 	
 		stop by and get them at you know for ninety <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine cents</NUMEX> and bring them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right what uh what do you find uh that you're looking at most in those uh the i mean are they are they the comedies and uh that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		comedies and the PG's and the no skin uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we're uh know like we saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally</ENAMEX> and uh well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Crystals</ENAMEX> in it we saw that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and which was video that's that's probably the last movie i went to see yeah that's probably the last one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		uh-huh yeah we we saw that one uh we find that uh that uh if you can get into those dollar movies you know they're uh they're a dollar and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> what is it dollar and a quarter dollar and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half now</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> Promenade yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promenade</ENAMEX> yeah and uh you know we we find those pretty good they're not uh it's not so far you know from when they were <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> run that you don't enjoy them
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		occasionally you'll find one that's you know some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> will be talking about them that you wished that you'd seen them  so you could talk about them sooner but uh
 	
 	
 		i mean fifteen bucks to go see a movie with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s a little ridiculous
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 		that's a little bit too much so
 	
 	
 		yeah and some of them that turned to flops we saw other other <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">other night</TIMEX> we saw um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Red</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay which is not that old but you know it was bounced around the VCR <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX> there and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but yeah we i used to really
 		you know i'd just pick up the paper and we'd go see a couple you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> but no we haven't i haven't been to a movie in it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah but uh
 		yeah we we find even uh you know even looking at the dollar movies which are you'd think those are the ones that uh are coming back around because they were good the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we don't find a lot of those uh you know they'll be running uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four to six</NUMEX> of those on a weekend
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weekends three weekends</TIMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three two</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or three</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> there won't be anything that we want to go see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so then when something comes up they'll usually stay on a while so we we still get a chance to see you know one of them that we want to see
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh we saw <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avalon</ENAMEX> and uh i think we went in to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avalon</ENAMEX> because we couldn't get in to maybe we wanted to go see Ghost and couldn't get into Ghost because the line you know they sold out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we went to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avalon</ENAMEX> and uh i really was not that impressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avalon</ENAMEX> it uh
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		you know it's uh it's one of these uh more i don't know melodramatic and and
 		i don't know uh not satirical wasn't funny at all but it was
 	
 	
 		kind of drab
 	
 	
 		i don't know had a had a lot of hidden meanings in it i suppose but uh you know
 	
 	
 		ooh my it's got to be something fun yeah you don't have to think yeah sure
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh right
 		but uh i really enjoy uh the espionage type of movies the the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunt For Red</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia House</ENAMEX> i had read uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia House</ENAMEX> book before so i i i thought it was a real good movie um
 	
 	
 		is it a good movie
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i enjoyed the book quite a bit too so that's that made it made it more interesting to me
 	
 	
 		let's see
 	
 	
 		uh a lot of it the dialogue was uh a little difficult to understand because
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Michelle Pfeiffer</ENAMEX> had a was speaking with her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> accent you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russian</ENAMEX> accent so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was part of that was a little hard to understand
 	
 	
 		probably overcompensated a little bit
 	
 	
 		right and uh
 		so you if you knew what was going on you could kind of anticipate what was going to be said so i i had a little bit advantage there over my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> she had not read the book
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		and well i think the now it's all coming back to me what was the one not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Deep but The Abyss</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um yeah
 	
 	
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		yeah we didn't see that one i'm not uh i don't see don't go see too many in well i would but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> doesn't like the the uh the science fiction semi horror type stuff you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		things that uh get you on the edge of your seat a little too much for her
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm not much of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rotocop</ENAMEX> man <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robocop</ENAMEX> you know myself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		this one it wasn't heavy hi-sci you know hi-fi because it was a lot of it was actual stuff that takes place and they had of course the breathing apparatus which was liquid and and then all a sudden
 		you know when you actually met this thing and and that that was you know towards like the last <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the movie only really got strange but it was uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it was cold in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> and it's wet in the movie and they kind of just it was it was comfortable it was easy to go in you didn't have to think a lot and and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and there is nothing worse than going to see a movie where you have to follow a hidden plot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it  and then you leave the movie like with your brain you got a headache  trying to follow this damn movie
 	
 	
 		right
 		well it's it's bad enough that you know if you got a little back problem or something have to sit in those seats and wiggle and squirm around and usually come out with your back hurting anyway so
 	
 	
 		yep
 		specially those intermission movies yep
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and course those those dollar dollar and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">quarter</TIMEX> movies you might catch a spring too so
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		got to be careful
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well anyway uh i guess  if uh if you're don't have anything else to talk about i guess i we can hang up on this one
 	
 	
 		they're great
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay i appreciate it thanks uh-huh
 	
 	
 		thank you sir
 		bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	