
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay so what do you think about us getting involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't think we have any choice
 	
 	
 		oh i don't think we did really either
 	
 	
 		as long as we do it in a logical manner rather than what we did in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> except jack around with it
 	
 	
 		well that's that's true yeah
 		the uh the the biggest difference i got to agree was the idea that we were allowed to go and get it done rather than than set up a a line and say we're not going to let you cross this this point anymore and
 		that really hurt the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> experience uh i got to admit that one
 	
 	
 		i think uh basically what we're going to have to do is now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has made the made the stand is what we'll have to continue to uh stick up for our foreign policy if we don't then what's going to happen is that everybody well it's just a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time shot they're not going to do anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well do you think that um by uh going over there and doing what we did that uh it's going to give us a chance for peace over there
 	
 	
 		i don't think there's ever going to be peace in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that kind of
 	
 	
 		mostly it it just that that region never had peace even as far back in biblical times it's never been peaceful
 	
 	
 		well that's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> just don't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> don't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> and then half the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> don't like the other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but is i mean is that any different than uh the way it is in even our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i mean uh back in the fifties and forties the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> didn't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> didn't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> but we're getting to the point where we get along pretty good i mean
 		isn't it logical that just any of the that you can solve differences like that
 	
 	
 		no because you i i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX> has the educational background i i i don't think they're later they're rate of literacy is so low that they're still they still have a trouble mentality
 	
 	
 		so you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so you think it comes down to education or or something like that
 	
 	
 		well well you don't find many intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> starting wars you know
 	
 	
 		i suppose that's probably true
 	
 	
 		you know uh basically the more intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do not want to fight one uh because they've already been there all you have to do is go fight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and find out it's not much fun i've spent uh over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty eight months</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> so and i mean it's not it's not a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as years</TIMEX> go by it becomes more fun now than it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty eight years ago</TIMEX> you know but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah because yeah i guess the uh you kind of think about the good things and not about the bad
 	
 	
 		and you forget some of the smells and stuff like that but i think you know probably the probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> is if you have too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> mixed up with troubled mentality not only the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX> but also in in the what they call the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> world
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX>  as soon as one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> gets the power they just knock off they're old ancestral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> and it's pretty you know
 		it's pretty much that way over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX>
 		and you have the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> question and there hasn't been a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> over there for God since you know
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two hundred years three hundred years</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> was born and but but you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are suddenly coming out of the woodwork going oh yes we want a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> but there hasn't been one for you know well over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two thousand years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you have this troubled mentality they all you know like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shiite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> or whatever but it's basically all all based on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a tribal network
 	
 	
 		right
 		well isn't it also though based on religion i mean isn't that a a real powerful
 	
 	
 		out of some degree yeah to some degree but uh religion is a factor over there but uh i think the strongest factor is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> of the family
 	
 	
 		um-hum well don't don't you think though that uh because of religion it just enhances the differences uh of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> and makes it so that it's that much harder to get along
 	
 	
 		well they have the same problem we do yeah i mean you know everybody there's Christianity and then you then we have subdivided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baptists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutherans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> and stuff it's basically all the same
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> are not as liberal in their interpretation of of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuran</ENAMEX> as we are in our interpretation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		you get the more the more i guess you call the more militant sect of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shiites</ENAMEX> who you know if you're not a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> and and you don't adhere adhere strictly to it
 		then you're nothing and you're just you're you're just getting lip service much like uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayatollah Khomeini</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he's a he's a prime example
 		oh i'd i i will but seriously doubt that that you will have peace in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX> as long as you have so many war infections that are they can't even agree on which facet of of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> they want to follow
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's true
 		well since there's not going to be peace over there don't you think like getting involved as we have
 		that that's going to mean that we're going to be involved from now on and so any war that breaks out we're going to have to be in the middle of it
 	
 	
 		well we only we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> choices we can be involved or not involved if we're not involved then we're going to be sitting over here freezing in the dark
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we probably could with ultimate fuel supplies and uh some relaxation of our old uh policies here survive but we're not going to do that
 	
 	
 		it doesn't seem that way does it
 	
 	
 		no there's there hasn't been any real you know alternating energy situations situations or or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> played out nobody wants to do it somebody has to make the hard decision and whoever does that will be a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> term president
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's kind of like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> income tax whoever you know whoever puts that up is going to serve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> term that's going to be it because your going to be gone they may pass the uh state income taxes but that'll be the last thing they pass
 	
 	
 		yeah that's probably true
 	
 	
 		nobody actually wants to make the hard decisions  have to do is basically what we're doing now is pick some of the moderate uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> as  and uh support them because they're because they will have more uh encounter with us as far as the educational and sociological economic background goes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you look over there you're not going to you don't see any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> driving uh
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		racing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 		they want <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cadillacs</ENAMEX> or Lincolns
 	
 	
 		true they want the the gas guzzlers yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah so you know who's who produces those the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> produces those and i think after the war no that we're not going to see a bunch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> buying <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">equipment</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">equipment</ENAMEX> has gotten blown out of the sky or off the ground
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		didn't it though
 		yeah i i got to agree with you there i think that does get a lot a lot of good there
 	
 	
 		you know and uh we we pretty much proved our worth in combat as it were and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where did they get the uh where where does the expertise come for for bringing a whole lot of ground and it doesn't doesn't come from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and it doesn't come from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> it comes comes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		who's going to put out their oil fires the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">hum United States</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		we have the technology when we have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and we go do it and i think we're going to i think we're going to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in a a presence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX> from now on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		let's say i'd have to say overall that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the war</TIMEX> was was beneficia l to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> with with the change in attitudes and all that you know all that stuff i mean it's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think better about uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> now
 		and that's really going to i think eventually come back and and help with overall business standards i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going um take more pride in their work and things like that i think it's going to really help out overall
 	
 	
 		i i i agree <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent on that after after after all you know i mean everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> put down a deadline if if it wasn't meant to be one he'd attacked
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's the way you're supposed to do it instead of doing like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> did you know say well you know uh um i'm getting out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">olympics</ENAMEX> and i'm going to give you back <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know i mean you either make your stand or you don't if you can't back it up just don't say anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> said he backed up of course he course he had some real good help
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah he had some excellent military people
 	
 	
 		yeah it's like  and like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collin Powell</ENAMEX> and the rest and uh yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Cheney</ENAMEX> those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were real smart they're a lot smarter that any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> gives credit for
 	
 	
 		i i was
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i was impressed with most i mean i i really you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Schwartzkopf</ENAMEX> they're military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but i really didn't know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> was as military minded as he is i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX>'s hard core you don't get to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of Defense by being a wimp
 	
 	
 		that's right i well he was what uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> or something like that i can't remember where
 	
 	
 		but he'd served in the military
 	
 	
 		yeah and see i don't know that and it well you know i was real impressed with his handling of this i know that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah the whole i mean the whole thing was done well it was just you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		it was uh of course he had to fight that to beat microscope anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i hesitate to call it a war since i mean it was
 		i guess it was i'm not used to having them over in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days</TIMEX> you know just kind of gosh we just got started good i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> might be over it you know uh you know because they had a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven day</TIMEX> war at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time but uh
 	
 	
 		i don't think very many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		although i i wish instead of turning south you know and taking a right turn and going down <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait City</ENAMEX> i wished we'd just turned left and gone toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah there was uh there was a lot of talk about the idea that the even the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> themselves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wished we would have done that uh
 	
 	
 		i think we should have because because we're going if we don't do it now we're going to have to do it shortly
 	
 	
 		yeah well unless they finally do take care of it themselves but you know you kind of have to wonder whether it's going to be any better with uh you know depending on whether it <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shiite Muslim</ENAMEX> or uh or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> in power but uh you know
 	
 	
 		but the only thing that'll save that is we won't get the credit for or the blame for the massacre and and then if we do have to to go back in it will be because you know someone asked us to
 	
 	
 		well that's true too yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and of course <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>'s the time to do it because since we have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> over there i'd sure hate to you know spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX> pulling them out and then turn right around send them back over again
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah that's true
 		yeah especially the cost of that and and uh uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> i mean they're there they i think they could handle it better but if they came back and then had to turn around and go the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX> would be just horrible
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they shouldn't leave anything in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bagdad</ENAMEX> taller than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> feet
 	
 	
 		yeah that's probably true
 	
 	
 		they just you know just just level the whole place and let it go but we're going to have to be over there and we're and our presence is going to have to be felt and they've got to be strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> or presence uh if we don't then i think that we're going to be back there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> era you know wringing your hands and going trust me trust me
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so do you think it's you do think it's a good idea for us to have uh
 		
 		
 	