
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay what
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		opinion do you have about what was what happened
 	
 	
 		well it's it's a real mixed um
 		feeling about it uh
 		it's really good that we did well and that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we we went in and did what we set out to do i i have there's there's been like a lot of things said about if it was a political
 		well if it was a war for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a war for ideals and seems to be real mixed between those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		i don't know i think the
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> should have been ousted out of there and now we don't seem to be as interested in in doing what's right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as we were when we started the whole thing
 	
 	
 		yeah see i feel like i don't know i feel like the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motivation Bush</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trilateral Commission</ENAMEX> and he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skull and Bones</ENAMEX> at i think at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> i'm not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh his motivations are i don't feel like he was absolutely on the up and up with us on you know the motivation the true motivation he talks a lot about the new world order
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> probably don't really know what that would mean and i maybe i'm being maybe i'm assuming too much no i don't think most would i really don't and so i feel like the real motivation was something that
 		uh most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would have absolutely no idea and that that motivation is to um you know to establish a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> world order and to break up the monopoly power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> will
 		so that they will submit under the uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> world order  i mean that's what i felt so i'm like going hum am i glad we went over there and did that um i think God's ultimately in charge and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know i'm not afraid of what they've done i'm not afraid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> i feel he's lost and you know he needs to get saved just like the everybody else but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know i just i guess i have kind of like hum kind of real cautious in the whole thing because i know that there's a motive that hasn't been openly discussed or revealed to anybody and uh that's where that's why i really don't have a real
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		set opinion because i don't know everything i don't much you could watch news all the time but you don't know anything hardly and he did talk about that though he did uh at least he did mention it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know what i'm saying i don't think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> understand what he's talking about when he talks about that new world order
 		so i don't know what do you think of that
 	
 	
 		it's
 		it's
 		it's a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> that needs to be broken up that's for sure
 		it doesn't it's they have far too much influence over there and they're so unstable that it makes it hard for um
 		it
 		it makes it hard for us to deal with them
 		i have that same problem at work
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		our our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> is so unstable it makes it very difficult to laughter to plan ahead or or do anything that that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		productive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		
 
 		i can understand why he he felt he needed to go over there on the other hand it's too bad that he couldn't use this i i i know that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>'s real important to our life style but it's too bad he couldn't use this as
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a launch to say let's conserve more because he never said that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		during the whole war he never put out like a conservation a conservation effort for oil
 	
 	
 		um-hum but the motivation though see wasn't didn't have anything i don't believe it had anything to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> because
 		i think i i feel like the real the real motivation of the war was to break up that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> power not
 		to disperse the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> but to they were a big problem for the the unifying of the EEC the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Economic Community</ENAMEX> which are gonna become i i i mean they're gonna be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're gonna put us under if we don't become part of the new world order <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> if we don't
 		i mean we're going to be in big trouble because when <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> unites unites that's why <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building plants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> because they're going to have power like we can't imagine
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so the i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> wanted to break up this other power thing
 		and it looks real good but in the end
 		i just see that ultimately who's going to be in charge of this one world order you know what i mean is is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> really any better than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> or does he just look better do you know what i'm saying i mean i think one person
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		in power that's not really seeking God and wanting to do good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and not deal for selfish motives is very dangerous and i don't see that this one world this new world order that him and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> keep talking about i just don't see that um
 		that's just a real good thing but i think it's something that's going to happen but i guess that's what i feel happen with the war and that was the motive of the war was to try and break that up and so that they could be you know
 		get more power over that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
 		lands when they try and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> really start pushing this new world order well he talks about it all the time i mean
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean that's all he talks about but anyway there's a good book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Abraham</ENAMEX> um you probably have heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">None Dare Call It Treason and Call it Conspiracy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		well anyway Call it Conspiracy is a real good book and he talks a lot about this i've heard him interviewed some so i think it's kind of interesting but anyway he probably has a new book out that i don't know about yet because i haven't heard him in a while but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know so that's kind of my thing on the war i'm kind of like nah  it's all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">power</ENAMEX> plays you know there's so much stuff going on we don't know about
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah it's
 	
 	
 		you know i'm like going hey <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX> you know he knows a little bit but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he doesn't even
 		i mean we would all die if we knew what was really going on i mean all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> would probably go into coronary attack  well they would
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		i know i agree
 	
 	
 		oh my money's in the stock market oh i can't believe they're doing this but it doesn't change anything so i'm just like
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know just i mean i would probably most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> probably think i don't even have a high school education you know because of my attitude about it but i just feel like there's so much going on
 		that you know hey i'm going to pray about it and  if i feel led to vote for a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i'm going to do it but i'm not going to get all up tight about all this
 		and stuff you know hum-um because i know at first we were watching the news a lot and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> it was like gosh we were like  all the time and i thought gee you know God's going to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> i mean he starts
 	
 	
 		well you can't yeah
 	
 	
 		he starts nuking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> he's in big trouble i mean we'll just we'll hear about it you know what i mean  if anything major happens we're going to find out so let's chill out and just do what we need to do so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		that's where i got to too the first i got chills up and down when i heard the on the radio and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time they started doing the bombing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i know it was kind of exciting at first but and then i know the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> of the bombing we had it was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> and we had home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and we had a surprise birthday party planned for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen year</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		and so when we  you know we're on the way to home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and the bombing's just begun you know and we go into this birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> for a surprise party
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and so it was you know we just went from one extreme to the other you know and it was like kind of sad it was like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> this is really hard you know i want to watch the war and so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and so imagine the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen year old</TIMEX> yep boy i had a surprise birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and a war started in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that'll be a good story when she's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> won't it
 	
 	
 		right it will be
 	
 	
 		well well anyway well i guess do you think we're finished
 	
 	
 		i guess so
 	
 	
 		i think so too i don't know if we did what we were supposed to but  yeah we did they can do a lot of research we get along good too some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> you don't along with that good you know you have you know what i'm saying
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah we talked
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		isn't that funny i bet they're going to do a lot of research on that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well yeah <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i talked to about about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> he was very opinionated and
 	
 	
 		i know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was difficult
 	
 	
 		really he probably had those glasses on like you know those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annie Hall</ENAMEX> kind of glasses i don't know what you call it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX> glasses that's what they are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> i call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annie Hall</ENAMEX> glasses but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah real thick
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is i don't know if they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annie Hall</ENAMEX> glasses or not i just i don't know i always think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annie Hall</ENAMEX> when i see them but
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they're versions of that
 	
 	
 		really i know the female version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX>'s but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i know i talked to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who was i talked to some of the yuppie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> you know and they're pretty interesting but yeah they're real opinionated but i guess that's better than nothing you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but anyway yeah it's been interesting though all these different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and some of them are real friendly you know and it's like yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> when i come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i'll call you you know and then others of them are like they just wanna go but then some of them have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> crying in the background too so
 		there may be other reason than you know that but well anyway are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i didn't know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> were doing this
 	
 	
 		yeah i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> that we talked about fishing so and uh oh i had some i've had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> they work at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> up there do you work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> does
 	
 	
 		see mine does too in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and um yeah but no there's there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> and stuff and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> talked about fishing and i asked him if he took his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then he didn't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i felt bad but well i'm sorry and he goes we're divorced well i'm sorry it was real sad but he was pretty nice and stuff and then him and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> started talking salary
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh no
 		
 
 	
 	
 		how much do you make up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> so i was just going wait a minute we're supposed to be talking about fishing now stop but yep anyway is that funny but we did talk about fishing though so but i guess i'll let you go i'm going to finish my dishes and
 		if anything happens interesting in the war maybe they'll have another thing and we'll get you again all right bye
 	
 	
 		okay all right thanks bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	