
 
     		
 	
 		well what's your favorite shows
 	
 	
 		oh gosh that's hard to say  it's um used to be a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twin Peaks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> but they've made me mad so i haven't watched them in a while in a while
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh  i watch a lot of uh public we watch public television a lot Mystery and
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		oh  oh i oh i really like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mysteries</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's one of my favorite
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mystery and uh Masterpiece Theater</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i watch that occasionally when
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there's something really interesting on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		oh  out out outside of that i it's hard to have a
 		i don't really watch a whole lot
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't not anymore i don't there's just nothing on it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i got i got sort of hooked on that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Dark Shadows</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have you
 	
 	
 		yeah i when i watched it originally i didn't know it was a i don't know it was going to be a series i thought it was just a movie
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and so i started watching it and all of a sudden stay tuned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> and i went what
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and then it blows into this whole series thing so i sort of had to stay with it
 	
 	
 		yeah is is it good is it
 	
 	
 		not really it it it's it's gotten to the point it's getting ridiculous now and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they they just had the uh season finale and i don't i don't know what they accomplished but i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> just
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		figure well let's just do anything and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we'll we'll have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of months</TIMEX> to come up with some new ideas
 	
 	
 		yeah that that's that's kind of what happened on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Twin Peaks</ENAMEX> they did all this big building up building up building up and then the
 		the solution was ridiculous i had it figured out by the third
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i thought i already had it figured out and i did and that made me mad
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't like programs that i can figure it out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um the only one that i watch religiously is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Law</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really like that
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> really like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Law</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's my favorite
 	
 	
 		
 
 		is it good i've i've always heard it was really good
 	
 	
 		well i'm i'm a struggling law student
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and
 		i the reason i like it is because they give you good law in there
 	
 	
 		do they
 	
 	
 		yeah it's not like these other programs where they just make up anything they want
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and they they throw little tidbits out that are really good
 	
 	
 		you know like they they at least you know they've been in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> before
 	
 	
 		um-hum of course i mean it's got its bad side so it's limited by the format and obviously you don't get into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> as quickly as they seem to make it out that you do
 	
 	
 		oh of course
 		yeah
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		they're they're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and they're they're waiting list is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years four or five years</TIMEX> for a civil case
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ooh</ENAMEX> Lord
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean you know it's very difficult to
 	
 	
 		it'd be nice if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> traveled that quickly but but it sure it it sure doesn't
 	
 	
 		yeah it would yeah
 		no not at all you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> of justice grind slowly
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well it's not really justice's fault but that's on a another whole subject altogether
 	
 	
 		yeah i'll agree with you there
 		i'll agree with you
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i know i know the shortcomings too
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah
 		oh let's see what oh i guess i've got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> so we do <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX> everyday
 	
 	
 		uh well not it's not on my that's not on my list of
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no
 		not it not no it's a it's not something
 	
 	
 		now there was some of the some of the classes i'm in i think i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> i think imitate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bird</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh oh yeah  have an intellectual role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bird</ENAMEX> that's pretty good
 	
 	
 		that's it i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bird</ENAMEX> would make a good judge
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		better than some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> i've seen
 	
 	
 		oh that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		yeah i've got my own pet peeve about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> but uh
 		oh well we're stuck with them
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that we're kind of stuck with them
 	
 	
 		sort of like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um let's see what else is oh i like A&E
 	
 	
 		i wish i wish we got i wish we got that on our cable system we don't there's always good stuff on A&E
 	
 	
 		they don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A&E</ENAMEX> on cable in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well not where i am not we're we're in far north we're i mean we're
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm thirty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five miles</NUMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> it's a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> here and i've called griped about them not having A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E A&E</ENAMEX> but they don't have it i mean in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> they do
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 		yeah i'll tell you
 		the um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh A&E</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Discovery</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> i couldn't i couldn't live without those
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i watch oh i like C i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s new uh news coverage better than anybody's
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i i just leave it when i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> i just leave it on just to listen to it
 	
 	
 		yeah during during when the war was real hot and heavy we just had it on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all day</TIMEX> long
 	
 	
 		yeah best coverage
 	
 	
 		yeah oh the oh much better than anybody else's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> got sort of ridiculous with they they they felt like they had to interrupt normal programming for all this but they didn't have anything to say
 	
 	
 		now they're plus they had all the inaccuracies were ridiculous then they'd come back <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> later and contradict themselves to oh it was just get it was ridiculous so i just
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well the coverage was a little bit ridiculous anyway i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it it it got far more coverage than it should have i it was it was beautifully played out thing i mean
 	
 	
 		yea h oh yeah
 	
 	
 		it it roused the patriotism of the of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and all that sort of stuff and
 	
 	
 		but uh they they interrupted for no good reason a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly i mean and sometimes they they would now i like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jeopardy and Jeopardy</ENAMEX> comes on here at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven o'clock</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and for i don't know it must have been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three weeks</TIMEX> there they were doing this expanded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nightly</TIMEX> news
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and i'm going i will never get to see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jeopardy again</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		rehash it was just rehash rehash total oh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i'm saying what are you telling me that you didn't tell me in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your first half</TIMEX> hour
 	
 	
 		nothing  and i i know i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">scud attack scud attacks</ENAMEX> are some are exciting to somebody but after you've seen them seen them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> in a row
 	
 	
 		nothing
 		yeah
 		oh well there goes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriot</ENAMEX> missile oh well that's good that's good
 	
 	
 		
 
 		across the black sky a white streak
 	
 	
 		yeah oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> golly gee
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well maybe maybe we're a bit uh uh
 		oh
 		jaded
 	
 	
 		yeah we are
 	
 	
 		and and  because television's brought everything into your living room
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well i it was interesting it was interesting
 	
 	
 		but it wasn't an exciting war it really wasn't
 	
 	
 		no i mean there there
 		there was nothing to it
 		i mean
 	
 	
 		which is that's good that's good but
 	
 	
 		i mean yeah i'm happy for that
 	
 	
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX> coverage it's pitiful
 	
 	
 		i'm happy for that but but unfortunately i sort of had the inside track because i'd been in the i'd been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen years</TIMEX> and i worked and i worked in intelligence
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and and there was no
 	
 	
 		contradiction in turn
 	
 	
 		yes another one of those  military intelligence <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha ha</NUMEX> that's what that's just like justice for all
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i mean my goodness there's they're sitting here making all this big deal out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		and i'm sitting there thinking to myself uh-huh sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean they've poured <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> into this stuff but those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid people</ENAMEX> can't read comic strips i mean how do you expect them to operate tanks
 	
 	
 		no they can't
 		it's put it in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i mean
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they can't even read their own language
 	
 	
 		yeah it it
 		it was just it was the coverage just went way too far
 	
 	
 		yeah i it just totally ridiculous i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>'s could have fixed the whole problem <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> if they just sent sent their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in there and killed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> says he says just send the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>'s in to to pick off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> they'll they'd love it i mean
 	
 	
 		that's right i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>'s aren't
 		they're not afraid of anything
 	
 	
 		huh-uh no
 	
 	
 		see what happens when they when they take a plane load of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> down in
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		that doesn't uh that doesn't that situation doesn't sit around and develop very long
 	
 	
 		no
 		i just wonder what's going to happen to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostage</ENAMEX> to the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> that's over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> now that you hear all kinds of things
 	
 	
 		all right i i i think everybody's jumping to conclusions i don't think anything's going to change
 	
 	
 		you don't think so i just
 	
 	
 		no <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> off i don't think the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> situation's going to change i don't think that
 	
 	
 		oh that's true oh are you kidding but they all hate each other
 	
 	
 		they're not
 		yeah they're not going to come up with
 		they're not going to come up with a peace plan or any of this kind of crap
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		you know you you see them on interview they interview everybody and everybody says the same things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that they always have
 	
 	
 		well they they get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oshmid Yakomo</ENAMEX> you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Embassy</ENAMEX> and you know
 	
 	
 		oh yes i know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yes i keep saying when are they going to knock on my door and interview me they've talked to everybody else in the world
 	
 	
 		yeah really and it was it was real it was even worse here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> because because a lot of the
 	
 	
 		was it
 	
 	
 		matter of fact all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> and and uh the F the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-16</ENAMEX> squadrons came out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		did they
 	
 	
 		so every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> on the local news they were down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fayetteville</ENAMEX> or they were down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Goldsboro</ENAMEX> and they were talking to the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and and
 		i and i understand the way they feel about their
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> being over there and all that but to get on camera and just oh  this is so terrible i just i don't what we're going to do well i'm thinking to myself
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know what do these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think they were getting into when they joined the military
 	
 	
 		they're they're voluntary army
 	
 	
 		you know i'm going it what did you think it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a paycheck
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah they do they think it's a paycheck
 	
 	
 		you know run around and and play soldier
 		well the reservists sure do we had a reservist here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> who who
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		who's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> was ordered up and he refused to go
 	
 	
 		we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> that did t hat here
 	
 	
 		i hope he got busted
 	
 	
 		oh yeah she did
 	
 	
 		yeah the uh this this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> did too he ended up going to Leavenworth
 		which is good i'm glad
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean just when uh the they military paid for her education
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they kept having her on the news <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then and then she
 		that's right then she didn't want to do her obligation yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> ooh she's she's
 		in hot water
 	
 	
 		well i you know i'm not i'm not racist or anything but one of my one another one of my pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">peeves</ENAMEX> is they had a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> on the news talking about how unfair it is because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX> are poor and therefore they don't have a choice but go in the military
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so there's more of them getting killed than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whites</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		now to me that doesn't make any damn sense
 	
 	
 		it nobody forced
 		
 		
 	