
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		um
 		i think uh
 		i like to listen to a program called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Focus on the Family</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doctor James Dodson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and from what i understand it's it's a new thing good about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> um
 		especially spending time with one another i know if if i were to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i would have trouble
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because i work and uh i have my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and i have a hard enough time spending time with them you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i i'm i'm pretty busy myself i'm in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> at  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> and i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i can't see even having time for a pet let alone children
 	
 	
 		yeah really
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		there's a lot of single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> too that are trying
 	
 	
 		yeah i think day care seems to be uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a real big issue
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and uh i'm not sure or i just wonder when we'll know what the effects of day care
 	
 	
 		yeah well actually there's been some studies that say it has some positive effects that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get you know exposure to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> their age at an earlier time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so they tend to be more cooperative with their peer group although they don't have real good uh role models
 	
 	
 		yeah i've heard that they they call them uh that they say that they're more um
 		creative that they're really just more rebellious
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from the day</TIMEX> care
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't have the time to give that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> attention
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and i just wonder if maybe day uh the home schooling is going to come
 		into more and more
 		uh homes
 	
 	
 		i can i can see that happening
 	
 	
 		yeah because
 		really if you have a good curriculum
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		do you really need to have that certification
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> i taught i taught <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and it was like
 		whoops you know it's not for me
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		because i i just don't have that discipline with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that uh you need for them to learn
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> i was i like found myself
 		uh telling them to write their spelling words <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> times each and i just heard this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> say that  you know something that that's how you know you're a bad teacher
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and i was doing it just keep them occupied
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think another problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> uh
 		is is the role of television
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i don't know it seems they're using it as a babysitter instead of a learning tool
 		that really that really annoys me because i think i don't know i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> probably did that to me a little bit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		using it as a baby a babysitter
 	
 	
 		yeah it's just
 		go watch TV you know
 		leave us alone
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		will numb you out
 	
 	
 		which
 	
 	
 		well i've i've heard some uh there's a book out now called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Saturday Morning Mind Control</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh he raises some serious questions about why do they have these really a lot of money goes into the advertising for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s programs
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and yet uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can't buy uh what's the deal
 	
 	
 		yeah but they can they can whine and squeal and complain
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i'm watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ninja Turtles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i know it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> the price of toys <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> is ridiculous
 	
 	
 		yeah i could be
 	
 	
 		and they all have to have the same one you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		i can see having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and not letting them watch TV and making them toys out of wood
 	
 	
 		say
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		here <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> this is this is all you're getting
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i wonder how long that last
 	
 	
 		well i i used to babysit for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that didn't have a TV and their their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> turned out fine
 	
 	
 		they didn't have a TV at all
 	
 	
 		they they had no TV
 	
 	
 		were they Pentecostal
 		
 
 	
 	
 		no
 		i mean they had a nice stereo
 		they listen to stereo they were into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah they just
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they just didn't watch him on TV
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which i thought was pretty neat
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 		it's very good i think TV has really had some bad effects on all of us
 	
 	
 		especially the the violence on it
 	
 	
 		i've
 		yeah yeah
 		and you can't control it you you know it's the cable channels sometimes you can but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		boy the cable TV they'll just show anything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's coming right into your homes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		i think TV can be good if if the family watches it together on they're watching good shows
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> or whatever i mean even some regular network TV is okay
 		if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> there and you know helps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> or help the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> understand
 		that yeah this that happened in the TV show but probably doesn't happen in real life
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		and there's a lot greater instance of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> committing murders too isn't there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		killing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and so forth they don't they see these things happening with no consequences
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		yeah you see it on TV The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> gets up and lives afterwards
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Double O Seven</ENAMEX> he's supposed to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's okay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i
 	
 	
 		you going to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the future
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		you going to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the future
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh because i'm like forty three
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and so it's uh it's too late
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i wonder sometimes wonder if i'll ever
 		if i will regret it when i'm old but uh i just can't see myself as a parent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it's
 	
 	
 		i'm still pretty young i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five</TIMEX> but
 		i don't know i don't see it for for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a few years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		really are you married
 	
 	
 		no i'm single right now and i'm you know sorting things out which way i'm going to go with my life before i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know career to to much into my career you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i wish you the best
 	
 	
 		okay well it's good talking to you
 	
 	
 		it's good talking to you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		all right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	