
 
     		
 	
 		all right now we used to be big time <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">campers</ENAMEX> but now we're not quite so much since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are involved so much in sports
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh-huh what type of camping did you do
 	
 	
 		well  when we before we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we was in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle group</ENAMEX> you know we we went like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty or thirty</TIMEX> at a time we took uh just our little tents
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we did it that way then when we started having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> we bought a camper you know and we did it that way
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		oh how neat
 	
 	
 		so we've always enjoyed camping
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i know i have um i just have a tent and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i like to go out and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> in the tent and then i bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> and that way i can sleep in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> and be more comfortable
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes yes now we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> and when they go on vacation a lot of times they'll just sleep in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> and the next night they'll stay at the motel you know or something like that and they enjoy it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes i don't i don't think i'm a real true trooper you know when it comes to camping all the bugs and stuff  but i i try
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh me either  i hate to be on any that stuff
 	
 	
 		but but i try you know to uh to get out there and enjoy everything but what was so fun though is that i had to take my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> because he went out camping with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and he got poison ivy
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it's all over him the poor thing you know so there's definitely hazards to going camping if you don't know what you're looking at
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		oh shoot
 	
 	
 		oh but now i enjoy it every once in a while i mean it's not something i'd want to do real often i'm a sissy i either want to do it in the fall or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		right right definitely when it's cool well have you done much camping around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well not really because usually it's when we go off you know like for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple weeks</TIMEX> or so it's usually like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well have you camped all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just about
 	
 	
 		wow see now i haven't so that i bet you that's an experience there
 	
 	
 		just about
 		oh it really is it really is also i said we mostly did ours before we started a family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 	
 	
 		it's a lot easier then
 	
 	
 		well i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> like to camp a lot and they uh they've been going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf Shores Alabama</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh which is really really neat they said they've got the white beaches and the sand and it's not real populated so they can they feel like they're in the outdoors and still close to the ocean and uh from what i understand from them it's really really pretty there
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i'd like to go anywhere you know i just like to go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really do
 	
 	
 		well have you done much camping up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> and and those parts in the mountains
 	
 	
 		no not really not that much um we've been well
 		we've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> you know and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> and you know places like that but usually if we're with a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we really don't stay any one place very long
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know like if we're just going through and they camp <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but now that we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and we go every blue moon i'd rather just go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galveston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah yeah yeah rent a beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or something yeah that's that's my idea of camping
 	
 	
 		you know
 		yes yes
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but we're uh we're getting more into it and we've done uh we've done quite a bit and uh uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like to go out you know as often as they can um so that's good you know they're they're becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> then of camping
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> really enjoys it they really do but by the time we really get a chance to it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> you know and it's so hot
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and our camper does doesn't have an air conditioner
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it's one of those pop-ups i'm sure you could put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in probably but we hadn't did that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh yeah well that's really neat
 	
 	
 		yes we all enjoy camping and they're you know they're in like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> As and scouts and stuff like that you know so they get to go camping in those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at least their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> goes with them i don't when they do that but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah oh that's neat that's really neat
 	
 	
 		that really is
 		well how old is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i well i have um a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that's uh going to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> here pretty soon and then a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that's thirteen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they're they're getting old enough to where they can help out with a campfire and cooking and and all that kind of stuff too
 	
 	
 		oh yes yeah yes
 	
 	
 		and that's that's really neat
 	
 	
 		it really is mine's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they really enjoy it too
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah i i agree with you they like to get out there and but this wasn't so fun this last time for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan</ENAMEX> to to get out there and he didn't realize he was touching poison ivy and it got all into his eye and it was really swollen and uh so they had to give him shots and everything so
 		oh well maybe next time he'll stay away from those particular
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah yes yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> or what <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bushes</ENAMEX> whatever they are
 	
 	
 		oh but i have uh brother-in-law and a sister you know that just really just camp
 		you know they love to go camping they could they would all the time they wanted you know wanted to because there's nothing holding them back but i'm just not that involved in it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no now i like to go out like several times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> but not on a on the regular basis i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who go out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every single weekend</TIMEX> when you know in the season uh and and i just couldn't do that you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		me i haven't really as far as entertainment i don't know what you would do if
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know but i guess
 		my entertainment's television i guess
 	
 	
 		just getting away
 		yeah right right see i see they just want to get away
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> they'll go home you know straight from work and they'll pack up and you know and then they'll leave and i'm just going you know by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> i just want to crash you know and i want to go home and you know do all that and then uh get out on the road to boot so
 	
 	
 		oh i don't either
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but anyway that's their life
 	
 	
 		yes but they probably live in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> also don't they
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		well see we're in a real small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> area and you know that makes a big difference
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		now that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		because if we want to go camping we can just go <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just a few miles</NUMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah  that's true
 	
 	
 		that makes a difference
 	
 	
 		well it was nice talking with you okay
 	
 	
 		it was nice talking to you too and we'll probably be talking to you again okay okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay well take care bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	