
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so what's your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> or do you have a favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		well i uh i'd have to say my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> would be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX> Bengals
 	
 	
 		Bengals
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh i was uh i was pulling for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengals</ENAMEX> when they uh lost the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that was sad wasn't it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> was it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah that was just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i i pulled for them for the sole reason because i didn't want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49ers</NUMEX> to win
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		anybody who plays the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">49ers</NUMEX> really
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh it's kind of hard to uh to know what to do with some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and they're either extremely strong or very very weak and uh nothing much in between
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's true uh my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is are is are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean i've liked them ever since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> that they won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> last i think it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> i think it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i pretty much like them ever since that
 		and they haven't they haven't produced since then but
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		least i've stuck with them i'm loyal
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well that that and that's the important thing i mean whether they win or lose why the fun is is in the supporting them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and staying with it and hoping that uh you know the next time is a better time around
 	
 	
 		yeah what other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> uh do you like up there
 	
 	
 		well um
 	
 	
 		or do you not watch much football
 	
 	
 		oh i love football
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		oh watch it uh every every game that's on i watch
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Sunday</TIMEX> and Monday
 	
 	
 		yeah and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no there uh
 		well let's see i never use thought about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> too much yet
 	
 	
 		yeah me either it's kind of like they they gave me the topic and i'm like football jeez it's been a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah right uh uh
 	
 	
 		did you know that they're playing a game today
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World League</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah what time is that supposed to be
 	
 	
 		they're playing it right now
 	
 	
 		oh are they
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> that's carrying it it's either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> one or the other i think i'm not too sure one of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> it's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barcelona</ENAMEX> versus <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		hum well uh
 		i haven't for some reason have never really gotten enthused about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> from from the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World League</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah the temperature's just not right
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and uh it just seems like it should only be done in cold weather
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		rather than just be played at anytime anytime during the year
 	
 	
 		we usually don't uh we usually don't have very cold weather down here you know during uh during football season it it gets colder later on in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it takes a good while for it to get cold
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple couple Christmases ago</TIMEX> we had a a freak storm
 		and i live near the coast actually i live like right on the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		and uh what they they called it like a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> hurricane and so instead of bringing high winds and destruction and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> it just brought a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> and basically it rain it it snowed only on the coast but not inland
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so the coast was completely we had like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> foot snow drifts which in the coast we barely get an inch of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah and so we you know because being near the water we get less <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> than anybody else
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and this time we had a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> we we i had fun playing in in the snow playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> in the snow
 		and so i mean i i had never done that before and it's it's so much fun because you can hit harder and land harder and it doesn't matter because it's snow and yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		is that right
 		huh
 		i would think uh that if you were real cold and you hit uh hit the ground that it would seem to hurt more
 	
 	
 		yeah well we had like layers of clothing to keep away the snow
 	
 	
 		well that helps doesn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but the snow also helps you know and it it we had like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> foot deep snow in this in this open field and so it was a little hard to run but when you got hit and you fell you didn't really feel it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you just felt the hit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but when you hit the ground it was you know just snow it was it was pretty fun but it's it's a lot better to play it in the cold weather that's true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah right right
 		
 
 		what kind of weather you having right now
 	
 	
 		well right now we're having nice weather i i probably say in in the upper sixties maybe lower seventies right now
 	
 	
 		oh my well our weather's suddenly turned cold again uh our weather is so unstable
 		you never know
 	
 	
 		yeah especially at this time
 	
 	
 		yes and uh this morning why it was raining and it was quite cold and then it seemed to warm up somewhat and then before uh before i got out of church it cooled off again
 		so much so that i uh stopped at home to change coats because i had to go down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and uh the coat i had on was just too light in weight
 	
 	
 		yeah is it very windy up there now
 	
 	
 		yes very strong winds
 	
 	
 		yeah we had some pretty strong winds pick up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> and they've been up been with us all day
 		well
 	
 	
 		well been awfully nice talking with you
 	
 	
 		yeah this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i've talked with someone up north really mostly i've been talking with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah right right most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seem to be there out there
 	
 	
 		seems like they have <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> calling from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		okay well good talking to you
 	
 	
 		yeah nice talking to you too bye
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh bye-bye</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	