
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		where do you get most of your current events
 	
 	
 		oh  well when the war was on i was watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T V</ENAMEX> a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 		
 
 		i haven't been doing it so much now that it's calmed down
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i was i was uh we don't have cable so we were watching C <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N N</ENAMEX> a lot and then trying to switch thank goodness for remote control
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we were switching from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> to another and in between keeping the radio on
 	
 	
 		yeah C <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N N</ENAMEX> coverage was really good
 	
 	
 		it was extraordinary yeah we um um and then you know couldn't wait for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> reminded me of when i was younger the uh the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> and just couldn't get enough of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		it kind of get wrapped up in it
 	
 	
 		yeah um i it was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first couple of nights</TIMEX> sitting up and watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T V</ENAMEX> late into <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> and you just wanted to get the latest news what was happening
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		kind of like watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		kind of like watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you just couldn't you couldn't put it down you couldn't put it down
 	
 	
 		yeah after a while though it started getting a little repetitive it ran out of news
 	
 	
 		it did yeah it was like you know that what was it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> steps forward <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step back
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh but occasionally you know you'd stay in tune just long enough to get the latest different tidbit or a different angle and uh you really became addicted to it for a while
 	
 	
 		right right
 		do you uh normally read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i try to um  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> comes uh in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and i leave for work at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> huh yeah yeah and i usually don't get a chance to sit down until after work
 	
 	
 		the what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		pretty good newspaper
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and at that point i try at least try to get through most most the front section and maybe you know one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other sections
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't i don't regularly watch
 		news or uh
 		newspaper i would say i get probably most of it from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> you know they finally told me hey there's a war  going on oh okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		where do what what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> do you get uh there
 	
 	
 		uh just the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX> local paper
 	
 	
 		how does it how does compare have you can you compare like how does it compare to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh it's it's it's not even a comparison
 	
 	
 		yeah that's funny because every once in a while if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i have traveled or something um and we pick up a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> we're really shocked even in a major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> at how local it is it's really provincial
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah the news is the same way the news local news here is kind of lousy
 	
 	
 		is it really i mean
 	
 	
 		it's not much different than when i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Roanoke Virginia</ENAMEX> which is really small town
 	
 	
 		that's that's maybe because we get so you know we're so jaded with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which is really international and and it keeps reminding me you know that this we're we're really in an in an isolated different situation here and i keep saying no wonder the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the world vote for in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> vote the way they do i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		that explains it
 	
 	
 		but uh i probably do watch more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T V</ENAMEX> because i get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and in between say cooking dinner or something if i can catch a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock</TIMEX> news
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		i watch that usually uh before we settle down uh depending what time we get to bed we'll usually watch the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the eleven o'clock</TIMEX> news we have a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten o'clock</TIMEX> news here at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and that's ideal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because because by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten thirty</TIMEX> i start to fade
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		i'm in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so i have a really weird schedule and i don't know i really don't have time for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T V</ENAMEX> and newspaper just i wouldn't  i wouldn't have time to read it so i'm
 	
 	
 		what are you studying
 		like yeah i remember when i was in school
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		finding the latest thing out from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> is usually the most uh time effective
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah no i can remember way back back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> when i was in school the i think the only time we only really watched the news and this tells you how old i was was during the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> missile crisis
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i we could just we were all centered around that television yep
 	
 	
 		what's neat is seeing history happen you know
 	
 	
 		that's exactly right and i'd
 	
 	
 		i guess that's it
 	
 	
 		yeah although i do worry that how easy this one was might be a bad lesson
 		uh to the to the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> um you know than there is the other generation
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um  in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> there was a lot lot of service  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> from here you know and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really saw that
 	
 	
 		oh that's true yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		saw it first hand
 	
 	
 		that was probably the best part of the news was the uh some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> human interest stories
 	
 	
 		yeah some of it got a little i i don't know i thought it was a little too personal that they were digging each other life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		little too much maybe
 	
 	
 		does it does it bother you that uh at this point in your life that you're not getting more direct news or
 	
 	
 		uh no not really
 	
 	
 		what are you studying
 	
 	
 		i'm in computer science
 	
 	
 		okay yeah um i guess
 	
 	
 		i see it as information age
 	
 	
 		yeah how old are you
 	
 	
 		i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay then i'm see i'm about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> older
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i really do i do rely i do miss it i do rely on the news and uh i i guess i regret i don't get enough local really local we get some local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> but i guess i'm more interested in the national or international news
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it's almost getting to the point where there is there's too much that
 	
 	
 		overload news overload
 	
 	
 		yeah you shouldn't even worry about most of the stuff i mean i don't know it's a little near sighted but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but
 		well it's hard i'll i'll tell you though it is hard when you go to vote i mean there are so many issues and there're so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> running that you know unless you have some way of evaluating it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i guess the news does help well it was really nice talking talking to you okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> did it work out your <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time all right
 	
 	
 		i hope so
 	
 	
 		okay alright bye-bye
 	
 	
 		take care bye-bye
 		
 
 		
 		
 	