
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay camping my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camping</ENAMEX> experiences are
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> using a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry eighteen</ENAMEX> foot uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mobile trailer</ENAMEX> and and that's you know like going to lakes and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		i see
 		sure
 	
 	
 		setting up the trailer for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or ten days</TIMEX> or whatever uh what's what's your thoughts on camping
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well for me camping i've never owned a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> so for me camping is more more more has a lot more to do with backpacks and tents
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i guess that this camping <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds of camping that um i've done one is to throw <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a</NUMEX> a tent and food <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and the like in the back of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and drive to a campsise and setup the tent and have the the car right next to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the other is to actually you know carry everything on your back i've done camping out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Aspen Mountains</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> where
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> that's we call that backpacking which is the same thing which is you're you've got everything on your back you know an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> frame uh
 	
 	
 		right right
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		uh uh yeah that well
 		um the older you get the more convenience you try to bring with you i guess so i'm up to dragging the trailer around which is my next step is going to be probably <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winnebago</ENAMEX> i hope if i only can afford one but that
 	
 	
 		i understand
 		oh yeah oh
 	
 	
 		of course camping again is is is like you say that that your your backpacking is i guess what i would call true camping i'm not
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure that the other camping type of camping is nothing more than a leisure or
 	
 	
 		well either way it's get i guess maybe we can define it as living away from the home
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right we have we have uh around the lakes and ponds up here and stuff we have uh campsites that are uh barriers set aside for each like the each individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> and you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sewer hookup</ENAMEX> and water and electricity
 	
 	
 		but
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and you back in you know and or just pull into your spot and
 		uh some you can rent by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> some you can rent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nightly</TIMEX> or by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah when when i mentioned i've done this camping out of the car i've actually done of the situation just like that but what's interesting is it's through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> has a little uh owns a piece of land on the edge of a lake that borders that the lake is on the border of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lake</ENAMEX> Texoma
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah they what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Texoma</ENAMEX> they've got a big uh  big rec <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> up there right
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right so that's where i've done most of that actually
 	
 	
 		
 
 		is that a pretty nice place
 	
 	
 		it is it's really beautiful the the lake is is outstanding it's a huge huge huge lake
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i spent about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abilene</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> i i worked out there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abilene</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">west Texas</ENAMEX> and i never did get a chance to get over to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Texoma</ENAMEX> i i wished i had uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh yeah i think you
 		well if you every get to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> you can probably you know borrow you can go up there and get a space for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bucks
 	
 	
 		that's unreal yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah so it's easy to do i'm actually interested in getting one of those kind of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has been talking about this in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of years</TIMEX> one of those kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">campers</ENAMEX> that pop-up
 		so it's about uh maybe <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eight foot square</NUMEX> and but only <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about two feet</NUMEX> tall and when you get to where you're going it raises up and there's tenting material
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that folds out from it it's like a crank up top thing you yeah it's you're talking of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> type that you pull huh yeah okay
 	
 	
 		yes exactly
 		exactly exactly my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has a lot of interest in those and i've actually been keeping my eye on the paper and they seem to be running <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between one and two thousand dollars</NUMEX> which
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you can that's about the price of them up here they're they're uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> sells them <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX> sells them
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		they have some some good buys on them and those are pretty nice i they're they're have a little galley a little uh sink that's got some compressed air and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in it and uh and a little stove that's like a propane stove
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of little cabinets and and uh sleeping  on either end of the the canvas when you open it up it's just all screened in so it's pretty neat uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah that
 	
 	
 		the nice thing about dragging that is that it's very very convenient to travel on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> with because it's very low
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		mine is like pulling a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> behind you you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you said yours is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eighteen feet</NUMEX> long what
 	
 	
 		yeah an eighteen foot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry</ENAMEX> uh it's completely self-contained i mean i have everything a shower a TV everything in it you know but
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you you the brand is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T E R R Y Terry</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i never heard of it
 	
 	
 		well they're i guess
 		they're pretty popular up this way yeah it's a pretty rugged trailer it's a tandem wheel even though it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only eighteen foot</NUMEX> long so there's it drags pretty good you know with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i've got a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsmobile</ENAMEX> that i pull it with when i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh if i get rid of that i'll have to get rid of the trailer because i don't i'm not sure what else will be able to lug it around the hills up here
 	
 	
 		well that's neat
 		
 
 		oh yeah that's something
 	
 	
 		kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hilly country</ENAMEX> up through this way but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's great
 	
 	
 		well uh i i like camping i i did a lot of it i when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were small of course they're all grown now and gone i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and they've kind of all gone and
 		we don't really do that together much anymore as they've out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are still in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so we kind of don't get together but maybe once a year and then we just do a little fishing but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i wished i had the opportunity to do camping because i used to love to live at the lake <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all summer</TIMEX> and into the fall and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh it was kind of pretty nice but uh i just wish that i had an opportunity to do a little more
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		the thing that i i then again i i tried pulling the trailer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> and i went everywhere with the trailer like to beaches and to stuff but that got to be a hassle you know breaking down and setting up and breaking down so i decided that
 	
 	
 		and and
 		right
 	
 	
 		i would lease a spot a spot on this particular lake here in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> and go there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every every spring</TIMEX> and stay there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all summer</TIMEX> and it really worked out good for me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and and you can and you still do that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and so you drive to work from there or you just take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> off
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no i d rive from the campground
 	
 	
 		oh wow that's nice
 	
 	
 		which uh it adds maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> miles uh you know uh each way but it's not all that much uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty</NUMEX> miles is going is just going a little different way it's probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> miles longer than my normal way to work i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		it's uh it just adds <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about twenty miles</NUMEX> to it but it's worth it to get to the campground and be just be out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and the woods all by yourself or you know with just a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> around or so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that's that's pretty nice because you can fish and just
 	
 	
 		well i envy that what a great life
 	
 	
 		yeah well  like i say it just uh
 		i i enjoy doing it i wished i had more time to do it but hopefully i can get up a retirement here before too much longer and then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i'll be looking forward to to like i say with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winnebago</ENAMEX> because as the older you get the less things you want to do
 	
 	
 		i understand and
 	
 	
 		i don't want to let the i don't want to let the canopy down i don't want to jack it up i don't want to do all that stuff anymore  and just turn the key off and get in the back and do whatever you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right
 		just want to get in and
 		yeah yeah that's funny well
 	
 	
 		but uh it's been nice uh like i really appreciate talking with you and i thought i'd uh give you a call on my <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch time</TIMEX> here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and worked out good
 	
 	
 		nice talking to you too
 		well i appreciate it and
 		and good luck with your uh your future your hopes of buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winnebago</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh i thank you very much you're ever up this way look me up here at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in Attleboro
 	
 	
 		i'll do it nice talking to you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> bye-bye
 	
 	
 		thanks sir
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	