
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		hi
 		okay you wanna start
 	
 	
 		hi
 		um yeah sure um i think i think we should have a balanced budget even if it means that services are dramatically cut back
 		if you can't pay for it you shouldn't have it period
 	
 	
 		that is very true however our whole economy is based on loans
 	
 	
 		and
 		that's just
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh uh but but right this moment you probably have several loans out or you have borrowed money against your credit card or something
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		master charge
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i don't have a master charge thank you
 	
 	
 		but uh see that our whole system is built on on owing on borrowing
 	
 	
 		right but that's the problem see as our system shouldn't be based on owing and borrowing and all that
 	
 	
 		uh true but uh uh uh without it <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wouldn't be able to own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> or they wouldn't be able to own a house
 	
 	
 		yes they would they just wouldn't be able to own the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> that they think they deserve to own
 		or the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> that we think we deserve to own we might have to you know just be able to i think if we a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> went without debt
 		then the next generation like if if our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i we're <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty eight</TIMEX>
 		if we lived our lives and didn't become you know indebted like you know our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> before us
 		that um the budget would balance and that we became accustomed to living with what we could afford
 		which we wouldn't be destitute i mean we wouldn't be living on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> by any means but just compared to how spoiled we are we would be in our own minds
 		but i feel like the generation after us would oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> it it would be so good
 		it would be so much better it wouldn't be perfect but then they could learn to live with what what they could afford to save to buy
 		and if you want a nicer car than that well you save a little longer
 	
 	
 		well now i agree uh i agree with you <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> percent i'm just taking the other side just so we'll have a discussion
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		here
 		uh but i still go right back to what i said when is the last time you had uh fifteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> all at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time to go out and buy an automobile
 	
 	
 		but see i we made poor choices in college we took out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> both of us had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> in loans for student loans
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i look back on that and i bought shoes i went shopping i did not need that money i did not need it
 		i didn't need it i shouldn't have even qualified to get it i didn't need it and it would have been a little rough i might have eaten some bologna instead of roast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">deli</ENAMEX> but i did not need it
 		and as i look back now now we're paying that back i told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> if you have to live in the ghetto to go to college do it but don't take out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> in loans
 		don't do it and i don't i hope don't think he'll have to do that but i just
 		so like we might if we didn't have those loans we could have saved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five years</TIMEX> the money for that and i believe we would have because God's really put it in our heart not to get in debt you know
 		but we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> that do this on a constant basis that are totally debt free and they pay cash for everything they buy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		including new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vans</ENAMEX> and so
 		so i guess i've seen it done and i know you can do it you know
 		but you have to drive that old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> until you get that money saved up for that new van
 		and that's where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> don't like to do it and so and we don't want to cut back our services from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> because we're spoiled
 	
 	
 		well i have one way to suggest reducing the budget
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		very simple
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		just take all these civil service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and and uh uh take some of those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX> away from them like <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Columbus Day</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Day</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean they get they get all these days off now give them
 	
 	
 		i know
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> i think we here at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> get a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		i know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's about uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> less than civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> get
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now just look at that money the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> could save if they didn't have all of those days off all those holidays
 	
 	
 		yeah that is true
 		because i always think the mail never comes on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> and you're like well what is it
 		you don't even know it's a holiday
 	
 	
 		well now don't forget the mail is something else again that has nothing they're not civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX> people
 	
 	
 		but isn't that federal in the federal budget
 	
 	
 		no no they have their own budget they go by
 	
 	
 		but isn't it part of our income it's not part of our taxes
 	
 	
 		no you know that's why the price price of mailing a letter keeps going up
 	
 	
 		it's not
 		that's why it keeps going up  huh that's another topic
 	
 	
 		you know i could
 		i can remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when it only cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three cents</NUMEX> to mail uh uh uh a letter
 	
 	
 		
 
 		those stamps are valuable now
 	
 	
 		yeah  they probably hey i ought to go looking through some of my old mail
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's funny yeah and that is a good short term thing though that little things like that
 		that overall though i just think we're just going to i don't know see i know i guess i'm kind of leery of this topic because
 		i know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is real for the new world order the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> world <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and alleviating all you know national debt between all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> but i see that to
 		be a potential power problem later with um who's going to be in charge with this new world order
 		and i you know i'm uncomfortable with that much power being in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place but i know we already have a new money system we already have new bills printed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Treasury</ENAMEX> already has our new bills printed for new currency and i mean i've seen them
 		and so i know that the long-term vision for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is to alleviate all national debts and to start over afresh
 		but i'm concerned with whose going to have the power over this new world order that they keep talking about you know
 		that's a lot of power for one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to have
 		and so um i guess because i i guess i feel like i know what their long-term vision is i'm kind of like
 		you know yeah the only answer is to start over or to totally change our lifestyles and i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are willing to do it
 	
 	
 		well what about uh uh sending all this money overseas supporting other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> third world governments
 		how do you feel about that
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't feel we should loan them money if i i wish our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> were really seeking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> on these things
 		and if we feel led to give a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> money to help them fine but i don't feel we should be loaning money like that i mean it doesn't work are they gonna
 	
 	
 		well in so many cases it's not a loan it's just a give a giveaway
 	
 	
 		but it's not but it's not set up as a giveaway if it were set up as giveaway and it was something that
 		i mean our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> could be seeking God saying God is it your will for us to bless this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> with this money is it your will this money and your will for us to give to them
 		and i believe if we gave it no strings attached that God would bless our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> but because we're our motive is interest our motive is not pure it just backfires i mean none of these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> have paid us back
 		it be do you understand it's i guess it's a principle of giving and receiving you give it no strings attached and they may never give you anything back but
 		because there's no strings attached it like gives them a freedom to give us something back and it might not be money it might be um no taxes on our things
 		our computers going into their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> it might come back in another way but it would be come back bu t because we're loaning it i think that's the problem and i don't mean give it to everybody that asks
 		use a lot of discernment don't give money to every nation
 		you know what i'm saying i think we're loaning money to too many nations
 		but i think if we gave to a few select ones that really needed it that it would work out better for us and for them
 		and so now we have all these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> that owe us all this money and so i just think we're never going to get that back you know
 		do you understand
 	
 	
 		no that that's true i i understand that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> still owes us money from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> debts have never been repaid i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> just wrote them all off
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and said well we'll cancel it just like they did to the that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> debt here uh last week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh uh half the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the world simply canceled the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> debts
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
  
 		
  
 	
 	
 		to help them
 	
 	
 		right long what long term though do you think it would be best to see an a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> world you know you can't alleviate all national debts or do you think it would be better for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to just start seeking God on how to turn our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> around financially
 		that's my opinion my opinion's the latter
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well uh i've got to respect your opinion you have some uh solid ideas
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i know but what's yours do you agree or do you disagree or i mean what do you think long term
 	
 	
 		well i don't believe in a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or a single control for the world
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that's
 		asking for trouble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are too different
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean you could travel from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> coast to the other here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and find tremendous differences between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> they have their own ideas how things should be run
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so therefore i don't believe there could be a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for the whole world there's too many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX> involved uh the language barriers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh oh sure they somebody said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> well let's make it <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> uh an international
 		uh language
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's a big laugh we can't even make <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> a a national language here in our country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we've got too many uh uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh immigrants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah um
 	
 	
 		they don't call them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> anymore that was back during my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">granddaddy</ENAMEX>'s day
 	
 	
 		yeah different
 		ethnic groups
 	
 	
 		a well yes yeah but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i know what you're saying
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> came over from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lithuania</ENAMEX> back uh just before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh as a matter of fact he's a draft dodger
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he uh was supposed to serve some time well he did serve his time in in the uh the militia
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he came back he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> again and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> said well if you
 		
 		
 	