
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay the topic that we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria</ENAMEX> again as I mentioned was
 		what do you feel is wrong with our public school system and i guess
 		if i were to look at with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> grown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and having been through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> of them through public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>
 		i guess the public school system i would have to say is that
 		we probably need to pay our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> a little bit more
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		we need to we need to probably
 		try to get more <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and the and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> if we could
 	
 	
 		smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX> possibly
 	
 	
 		and the other thing was we need to really really to tighten up our discipline in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> because they run here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> i'm not sure about the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are almost running rampant up here
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and it's too bad because there are you know serious drinking problems with with real
 		um you know young young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i'm talking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine ten eleven</NUMEX> twelve years old
 		drug problems
 		go ahead i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		i would  when i was in school um i was supposedly in one of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax county</ENAMEX>
 		and i'm i think back and i i don't feel like i i could have learned a lot more and don't feel like i learned as much
 		i've only been out of school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> but i think i could have learned a lot more and i've i worry about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that are in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> that aren't as good um i don't know any particular ones but you know when  when they say one of the where i went to school was one of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> then i think
 	
 	
 		yeah i lived i lived that's just outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax county</ENAMEX> that was really really a nice nice area down there and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my i had the same situation here my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were we bought them up and put them in the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> and
 		they were not not too too bad and this was going back like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> i guess
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> they were not too too bad at that time
 		and i was fortunate enough to have the opportunity to move from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> with my job
 		and i worked there in the southwest for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten almost ten</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> got a my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> got a much better education education in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> simply because they had the opportunity to have more <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh relationships with the with the uh the facility okay and and that helped like especially one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> he was he could learn but he really had to work at learning if if that makes sense to you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and uh again like you say there was and you are still a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and there's so much more you could have learned and
 		but i i i don't know i think discipline i guess if i were to look at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing we've lost
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> used to have a respect for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> i guess at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time but i think we've kind of lost that in out school system and i'm not really sure how to get it back i say discipline and that might be the wrong choice of words but it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i know um i know with um i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> need to be paid more i have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who and myself who've thought about
 		going into elementary education and to teaching and then they looked and saw how much money they got and said well there's a lot of other things I can do and get a lot more money
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's so it it's so hard and and it's so hard to compete and and that's not one of the things that's gonna make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like yourself who are just graduating from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> you know or out across the country
 		wanna go jumping into a an education field when the when there's you can almost double your pay in almost any other field you know for as a as a entry level
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and i am not saying that we should give them the world either but I think we should pay them a little more money
 		um they say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and eighty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days a year</TIMEX> is all they work and i don't really believe that i think it's a lot more than that
 		when you figure the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and time they put into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and stuff alright and even if is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only a hundred and eighty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days a year</TIMEX> lets pay them for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred and eighty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days a year</TIMEX> i mean
 	
 	
 		and and i mean their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their day</TIMEX> doesn't end you know when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> out
 	
 	
 		no no they  that's what i mean at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time we we used to able to carry that over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> of course i
 		i can see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>'s point too where at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at three o'clock or four o'clock</TIMEX> they want to go home and not worry about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so but if they had probably some renumeration to help them say you know maybe i'll give this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> a little extra help or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in the long run i think it would really be worth while
 	
 	
 		i mean they they uh go home and grade papers lesson plans prepare for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		what what is your major in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that your ah super that sounds good and you're finishing up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		i'm an interior design major
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> so
 		exactly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's great i i wish you all the best in in your future in your endeavors out there in what ever you are doing and it's good to talk to a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> rather than
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		most of the folk i've talked to are are industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that like my self that have been in the work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> and and it's ah it's refreshing to talk to ah to some of you younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> and get your ideas and thing you know and see how you feel about things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i don't know what else we can do about this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> situation <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX> and if there's anything else you'd like to add
 	
 	
 		i think that's about it you too
 	
 	
 		you have a nice day and i'm going to say good bye for now and if you're ever up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> way around <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> look me up it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Smith</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albrough Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		alrighty you too thank you bye bye
 	
 	
 		have a nice one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX> and good luck in your future bye bye
 		
 
 		
 		
 	