
 
     		
 	
 		yeah the question was uh what kind of books do you read for entertainment uh
 		uh  i guess
 	
 	
 		oh i just read for escape  well i mean it's
 	
 	
 		okay  with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i can understand that
 	
 	
 		yes it's that's simple i read to escape and i don't read any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parents</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> either  so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		what uh what kind of
 	
 	
 		well i just finished just i just finished <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> a great book
 		it it's very a typical for my reading though but a great book one called The Things They Carried by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim O'Brien</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and it's uh God i don't know if i would call it
 		a collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam war</ENAMEX> stories or if i'd call it a collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> love stories
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		strange book beautifully written
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just beautifully written
 	
 	
 		by uh somebody who was there or
 	
 	
 		yeah a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who was there as a uh foot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> so he considered himself to be you know a a true <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that were ground  yes yeah i can imagine
 	
 	
 		yeah so what's the latest one you've read
 	
 	
 		yeah well i tell you what i'm a kind of uh a history
 		nut i'm trying to think back now i read an awful lot of uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">periodicals</ENAMEX> and uh you know almost what you call reference book and uh the last uh  i'm embarrassed to say the last you know honest to gosh cover to cover book that i read i cannot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right offhand i tried to read uh one of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Michener uh Lone Star</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Texas History Book</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have never been able to make it through any of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michener</ENAMEX>'s work
 	
 	
 		oh well i've had similar problems it does tend to to
 	
 	
 		have you are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> buff at all
 	
 	
 		yeah as a matter of fact yeah
 	
 	
 		because i finished one
 		i think this is like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>
 		and somebody had given me one of these dinky do crappy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s novels set in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Jakes</ENAMEX> one and the novel didn't  do that much for me but boy the period of time was fascinating
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i then read
 		was it <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Battle Cry of Freedom</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom</ENAMEX> it's kind of like a historical compendium
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> and it's not a story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> it's a story of all the politics and uh lobbying and just basically state by state events that led
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to of the events that brought about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> and it's fascinating because i had always you know have been raised on this you know <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Emancimation Proclamation</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh there was a lot more to it than that weren't there
 	
 	
 		there was a lot more to it than that as a matter of fact that was a very minor part that kind of become like an afterthought
 	
 	
 		yeah well it was a political move it was made to placate some of the northern support but not completely alienate all the southern
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		support because you know it was uh if you read it it only emancipated those who were in
 		areas uh in rebellion against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> all the other areas which would i think at that time would have included <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> and
 		oh may have been <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> a few <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> you know that were not part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> but still had slaves they didn't emancipate them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well you know what else really surprised me now i'm married to a native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> and i'm not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i've got the same problem
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm glad you put it that way and i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native Texan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> too my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is always you know talked about  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> being a uh rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and oh my God all this <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> pride
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i kept waiting for where's some reference to this God damn <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">State of Texas</ENAMEX> and the role that they played either leading up to or in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> they might as well have not even
 	
 	
 		isn't isn't much there is there
 	
 	
 		been there you know they weren't a state and the only the only way that they had any part in it was after worth as to you know who's going to be going there and i keep telling my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> that and he keeps saying oh no i thought okay
 	
 	
 		they supplied some uh you know they were some groups
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vicksburg</ENAMEX> if you ever get a chance to go over to Vicksburg the battleground at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vicksburg</ENAMEX>
 		uh there's an area there where there was uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX> and they had an interesting time there
 	
 	
 		oh i'll bet they did
 	
 	
 		and down there at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabine Pass</ENAMEX> uh i can't think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s name but he held off the
 		you know just he and a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> managed to hold off the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">navy</ENAMEX> for a while from coming up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabine River</ENAMEX> which was of no consequence but still is an interesting story
 	
 	
 		well you know why they actually held them off
 		none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> wanted to listen to their kind of luted grammar
 	
 	
 		that could be it  could be it
 	
 	
 		now you didn't hear me say that outside of um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and then the last <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> battle was fought at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Val Verde</ENAMEX> you know over there on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> border you had a lot of
 		of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> heading for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and they were cut off at the pass more or less at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle Pass</ENAMEX>
 		and they didn't get across the river there so they're the last and that was actually after the war was over but it was the last
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		organized battle between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX> participation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> was uh minor at uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> don't tell that to a native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> though i mean my God they fought and won the whole thing
 	
 	
 		at best yeah
 		yeah well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galveston</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		yeah Well i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> so you know i was
 	
 	
 		that's a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that's a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> see i was raised in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> which you know hell we didn't even you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we didn't even know where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mason Dixon Line</ENAMEX> was and besides you know if <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> didn't grow there it didn't matter
 	
 	
 		it sounds like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> and then i had probably lived the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> so you know what does that make me an honorary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yeah on yeah
 	
 	
 		God knows what
 	
 	
 		oh well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> right now so
 	
 	
 		well then she's going to come out well rounded but outside of those kind of things you know the other thing that i've really gotten into reading
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think this is because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are getting to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is science fiction
 	
 	
 		i've always kind of enjoyed it i i used to read a lot more than i do now
 	
 	
 		well i've gone to the point where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> travels i get out like you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> books
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i'm trying to think of
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Asimov Robot</ENAMEX> series
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean i think i've read all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of them and i understand that there's a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last six weeks</TIMEX> he's been on the road a lot
 	
 	
 		um
 		i just turned around and looked at my brief at my briefcase my uh bookcase up here and i see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX> up there
 		and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shadow</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Blooming Grove</ENAMEX>
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thousand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grant Takes Command</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">The War</ENAMEX> in the Year oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gee</ENAMEX> that was the one i was trying to wade through was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Michener</ENAMEX>
 		didn't get very far on that
 	
 	
 		you know i think i read <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> when i was about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old</TIMEX> or so which is about the developmental level that you know you need to be at to read those things and i still even then i was so so disgusted with it i i tried to read
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't remember which other one it was whatever one it was it was such a blockbuster seller
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i just i got about like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> pages through it and realized i had like a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> more i thought i can't do this
 	
 	
 		yeah it really the the books are kind of uh imposing to say the least
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		no let's see here's one called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ghost Towns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mining Camps of New Mexico</ENAMEX> now not too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have read that one i don't think
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		and there's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The History</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yoakum County Texas</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		is that a big thick book
 	
 	
 		i've got uh
 		yeah and i've got yeah and i've got a History of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kingsley Iowa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what the what the hell for why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingsley Iowa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well because that's where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> all came from  and they had a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centennial</TIMEX> here awhile back
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grant Takes Command</ENAMEX> that was pretty good
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		that was part of that trilogy that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Canton</ENAMEX> did
 	
 	
 		now that's one
 		that's one i don't know see i had never really been into science fiction that much until uh
 		somebody gave me <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mist</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avalon</ENAMEX> probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five or six years ago</TIMEX> i don't know if i'd call it science fiction or fantasy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		sometimes it's awful hard some of those get very philosophical they can be in any setting
 		they just happen to put them in a futuristic setting you know the
 	
 	
 		well i loved that novel and then somebody said oh God this would have been even long ago because i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and it was raining <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> and i had a hole in my roof and i was waiting for the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to collapse and uh i was reading Dune
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		which seeming rather ironic
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i read the whole damn book while i was home hauling out you know like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> gallon buckets of of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and waiting for the roof to collapse and reading about these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> wearing their little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeman</ENAMEX> Steel suits and
 	
 	
 		uh-huh you're reading Dune
 	
 	
 		i think that's probably my favorite of of any piece of science fiction that i've ever read and the movie was awful oh yes it was just terrible
 	
 	
 		that was a movie too wasn't it
 		was it
 		yeah i'd i didn't see it but uh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it was it was beyond
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Stewart</ENAMEX> was in that i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that's on the new <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> series was in that thing uh
 	
 	
 		i don't know i just remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sting</ENAMEX> was in it
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and if you were trying to follow any type of uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		plot it it total even having read the book and i've read that book probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times watching that movie i couldn't figure out what they were talking about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		couldn't
 	
 	
 		at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i was real disappointed in that well i'll tell you another good book do you like scary  things
 	
 	
 		um well well some history books are pretty scary but yeah
 	
 	
 		have you
 		that's true have you read <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Silence of the Lambs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no somebody who saw the movie here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> told me it was the most terrifying thing they'd ever seen they didn't sleep <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		well see i'm i'm debating whether i  want to go see the movie after having read the book i mean the book is is chilling just chilling
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i have no idea i don't have the foggiest notion what it is about
 	
 	
 		then i won't tell you
 	
 	
 		okay yeah  but
 	
 	
 		it's just that if you're ever ever really want to just be scared out of your wits
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's the one
 	
 	
 		that's the one yes
 	
 	
 		even better than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaws</ENAMEX> and some of that
 	
 	
 		yes because the character the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> that is so horrible is another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> And you're just drawn into his
 		his horror of him that you begin to kind of like him
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that  i mean
 	
 	
 		a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freddy Kruger</ENAMEX> type huh
 	
 	
 		no no This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s smart and he's suave and he's all the characteristics all the characteristics yeah all the characteristics
 	
 	
 		oh the worst kind yeah yeah
 		
 		
 	