
 
     		
 	
 		well i really enjoy reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> we get the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX>
 		and i try to look at it if i get busy  i don't get a chance to pick it up like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> i noticed several copies have been untouched haven't been touched but uh
 	
 	
 		well do you have time to read the paper in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well not in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> but um if the well i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son children</ENAMEX> and if they uh go out to play or something i like to keep my eye on them so i'll
 		you know maybe go outside and read the paper while they're playing or  sit in a chair by the window or something
 	
 	
 		you know a lot a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> at all we we took the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning News</ENAMEX> for a while and then uh well we've been taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Herald</ENAMEX> for ages and then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">uh dog</ENAMEX> just ran off with my shoe that's off the subject
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		went outside picked it up and ran off anyway um and then we switched the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning News</ENAMEX> but we found we couldn't read enough of it and by the time i got home and had time to
 		to read some but but i guess the the issue is uh beside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> do you take any news magazines
 	
 	
 		well we i don't take like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> or anything like that but i do like to watch um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> i have several chores and things to do so it comes on at
 		like the  <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine o'clock PM</TIMEX> and so i will turn that on while i'm doing some work and i can hear the news not have to sit right down and listen to it
 	
 	
 		did did you did you hear what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartzkopf</ENAMEX> had to say about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Arnett</ENAMEX> and uh the the news coverage
 	
 	
 		well  he didn't have too good of opinion of it no i mean yes i did hear that and so um i do try to keep that in mind that whenever you're reading a paper it usually has a particular flavor
 	
 	
 		well any you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> and even the news that sometimes that that's why i like some diversity the idea that i we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> which which we we take from time to time
 		and we the problem is they call up and make this deal you know and well we're taking that and and we also hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garland Daily News</ENAMEX> i guess it's it comes out sporadically like twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> or something but i think what's interesting is that if you're that there uh this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as difficult as he is or as as much as they try they put some bias i had the chance to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Rowlett</ENAMEX> speak to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and it was interesting that they think that they're basically impartial
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and that but and and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> accuse them of controlling the news he says you know we don't control the news we just report it the way we the way it is and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i wouldn't think that i would really say that that's not true because um it seems like certain newspapers always espouse certain candidates
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and so um news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> always tell the story from a certain angle and that's why it's a good idea to get a wide variety of coverage so that you get a lot of different opinions you may never get the truth but you'll have a variety to choose from
 	
 	
 		yes and i i thought that was particularly interesting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Gulf War</ENAMEX> that there were pieces of information that that were apparently uh leaked just as a as as uh a
 		a ploy which was um i i find that fascinating that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i do too do you ever listen to the radio or any
 	
 	
 		i listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KRLD</ENAMEX> and uh KLIF the news talk radio and i actually listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> radio do you know it was on radio now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no i don't
 	
 	
 		it's on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven ninety</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum i really um have gotten out of the habit of listening to the radio from any kind of even music and um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well when i go to work i listen
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> does and it's how come he usually calls me sometimes and says oh i just heard on the news that such and such happened you know if it's something really interesting and and then i'll know to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to keep an eye out for it but i've got out of the habit of listening to the radio
 	
 	
 		well with with your you know if you're around the home though and and and can watch TV and read the paper the problem is is that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about twenty minutes</TIMEX> of news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">radio</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> is and then they start repeating everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and so it's kind of a oh that's what's interesting is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> uh i don't think i'm trying to think if it's much local i listen to a little of that and i listen to a little of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> point one i i'm i'm inveterate switcher
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety eight</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> i'm i'm eclectic approach
 	
 	
 		do you have a particular local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> that you watch on television
 	
 	
 		well i watch channel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> but that has to be that's another bias that has to do with the weather reporting i'm not sure that actually i think channel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> is probably but i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fox</ENAMEX> he goes to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um well i am we're fairly new to the area and so we're still shopping for a favorite channel
 	
 	
 		well the channel <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight</TIMEX> when they came here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">thirteen</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen years ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Rowlett</ENAMEX> came together uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> and apparently channel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> was way down and now they have turned it all around and done a pretty remarkable job and then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they've been some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> move around and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Chriswell</ENAMEX> is anyway the i i don't know do you do you do you seem to can you tell much difference between the local radio TV stations
 	
 	
 		well i really think so i noticed on channel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> that there's all of the um anchors
 		are seem to be like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">White Anglo Saxon Protestant</ENAMEX> type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and they all seem to be you know fairly similar and i kind of prefer
 		a you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> i don't recall that they have any female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX> and i like different i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX> to be different kinds of people
 	
 	
 		i think that adds to the diversity i think that uh i like that uh there i know you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wylie Price</ENAMEX> i don't know if you kept up but he's been protesting that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes i have and um i prefer you know to have a little bit of variety like that because i think you're more more likely to get
 	
 	
 		yeah and i think he has legitimate argument i mean you can uh i i i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> and so i i have some prejudices
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i think that i think that that from a a justice standpoint because we have the option of not watching that station uh i'm not sure i i'm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		totally in favor of affirmative action in some of the programs but i think that uh in some cases there there should be some real opportunity and and some diversity and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and this kind of thing and i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it turns out though from what i understand has quite good i occasionally go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> and uh there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> and watch the news and and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> really does have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have quite good news i think channel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> is the number one uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliate</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Rowlett</ENAMEX> was saying that he course he pumping his own
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		well we you know like  all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> seem to be pretty good it's just we haven't found one that we've snuggled into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> so we had a
 	
 	
 		where'd you move from
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> or i did have a favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> that i usually tuned into for local news i guess because you get use to you like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX> and you feel comfortable with them and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it is interesting though it becomes a little of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> in fact the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that was on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weatherman</ENAMEX> on channel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> worked for me oh long time ago <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> or so even <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">longer than that twenty one twenty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> or so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty four</NUMEX> anyway long time ago and and shortly after i got we got here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen years ago</TIMEX>
 		and uh they had they had fired him uh because he was too  anyway didn't he didn't have the personality and wasn't drawing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> and that's interesting is that's that's what the TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> do they're trying to get ratings
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's true their job
 	
 	
 		and i think if we remember that that they're out after the ratings
 	
 	
 		that's true so that really effects how they report the news
 	
 	
 		and some well it's like the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Hansen</ENAMEX> on channel <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight little</TIMEX> is a sometimes a little too cutesy but i wonder if we're coming up on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> have you talked have you been on the conversation when they beeped you at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		with is he the sports
 		yes i guess it is time to close now so i can run go help put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to bed but i have yes it's nice bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay well good talking to you good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	