
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		okay well like i was saying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burlington</ENAMEX>'s crime it doesn't involve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and what you see on the TV's from you know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 		so what i believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want the subject is is big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> crime which is something
 		that i don't have any first hand experiences about but i have you know concerns and i have a few ideas of um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how to combat it i mean i don't i don't think uh ideally you know you need money to do everything so that's one thing that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's one thing that that's that's crime that you can't fight it if you need that money so
 	
 	
 		right yeah well when uh we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> i grew up around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> and it's always been a very large uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and increasingly growing
 		it's has kind of the split population um there's a lot of retired military uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> that live there and then there's a very large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> there
 		and the one thing that we noticed that over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> has gotten worse and worse is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> crime in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and that is uh been the worse thing that we've seen happening uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		does it spread out of the neighborhoods into the more the uh retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> or does it stay in the bad neighborhood
 	
 	
 		um the majority of the actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> crimes like the  the drive by shootings and stuff stays in the neighborhoods but the crime spreads out into the more affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> through robberies rape
 		and uh car crime there's a very large uh or very high percentage of car theft
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio San Antonio</ENAMEX>'s not far from the border to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> so a a lot of the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> go to uh you know hack <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and they take them apart and a lot of them go over the border especially like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX>
 		a lot of those those in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Z uh the Z</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Datsun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> end up over the border and uh
 	
 	
 		so that's a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> if you live there is to really lock your car up
 	
 	
 		very much so very much so in fact um for a while there uh they had
 		downtown if you were to come come to a stop light they had a a rash of where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were uh when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were stopped at stop signs that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would get in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and hold a knife and hold them up
 		so now ever since then when you drive into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> keep their doors locked while they're in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> until they get down there and once you've reached the
 		the river walk area which is the tourist area it's usually pretty safe during the during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> if you're just kind of cautious and don't go down the back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> and um
 		you know or or alone if you stay with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and along the area where they have the the river patrol cops it's very nice
 		but at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at evening</TIMEX> um again you they have the high tourist area the river walk area which is nice but you don't want to get off the beaten track um
 		there's a lot of parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garages</ENAMEX> there because parking is very tight and so you don't want to get caught in the parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage um</ENAMEX> alone
 	
 	
 		oh my it sounds like um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Juan Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> we were there
 		just well for a lay over and um well it wasn't a lay over we were we had
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we were we had we were staying at the other end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> and we drove into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Juan</ENAMEX> to catch our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> it was at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> really wanted to go on the beach and they look at you crazy you don't go on the beach well it's a big tourist town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know don't they don't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go for a walk on the beach at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and they said no it's very safe in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> but at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> they even have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> come around at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dusk</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and sound their sirens pretty much telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> be wary you know and get off the beach
 	
 	
 		it's just so sad you know it is just really so sad you know it is just really so sad because you can't enjoy anything any more um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> i don't know what the answer is uh
 		education i think is a lot of it um so many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are are drop outs um uh
 		there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that go on and that they just have hopeless lives they they lead themselves down hopeless <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnels</ENAMEX> i think education helps a little bit there um
 		they again i don't know really what steps there are that they
 	
 	
 		well what they what they say they try to do is to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> um early and young and what we have here in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burlington</ENAMEX> which
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it doesn't cost a lot of money but they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		council that they have all these after school activities for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they set up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> in the winter time they shovel their snow they have a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> big sister <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> they have bottle drives they have cleanup outings
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and they have also organized fun activities like gyms going to the beach and playing volleyball at the beach in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and they have gyms open
 		and it seems that the younger you can get them and get them involved with programs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		after school you might keep them but you again you need that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> trying to keep the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> you know tell him hey stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> it'll get better you know so that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> doesn't have a job and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she doesn't work you don't know you can be better than that You don't have to live on the you know for a street life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's good that sounds like they've got a lot going on there
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah but it's so cheap they don't have a problem here i mean um they can deal with that scale
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they might have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX> when you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five thousand</NUMEX> troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX> plus when you're getting into the well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> now it's twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> and they're
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and they've got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen year old</TIMEX> that's their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> that is carrying a gun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's just it's the morals of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> which i mean i guess we everybody's responsible for the society but
 		if i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that that did things so bad it's not they don't care about anybody these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they're stealing from they're just the big bad rich guy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we don't have it so we deserve it and we should take it
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i don't know how you combat that i i don't know where you start or with a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> um
 		so many of them all they see is just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> and unless you can take them out of the environment enough to where they don't have the peer pressure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> as soon as they come home from school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think a lot of it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are totally irresponsible too we're talking these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen years old</TIMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> might be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years old</TIMEX> and i'm kind of irresponsible but i have the morals that keep me from
 		you know if i was going to go out and drink or do something i wouldn't do it in front of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know they bring their their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns</ENAMEX> home and they bring their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> home and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are just sitting there in the same room
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's just that they have absolutely no no morals and it's really sad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and i don't know how you combat that i really i don't know what the answer is to that problem you know
 	
 	
 		but i like your idea of education  i mean if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> aren't supplying it they've got to get it from someone else from the schools
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		and what do those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do they get it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and come home what do they do then i i feel i feel for them i don't know how to make it better for them or
 		you know unless  because it they can't remove themselves they can't just leave and say okay well it's not acceptable i'm leaving the big city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and i'm i'm going off you know when they're ten they have to live in it and
 	
 	
 		yeah it's really sad like if they did have a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> program those those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> might have hostilities towards them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right i think so and uh
 	
 	
 		you know like you're judging us and i'm not good enough to raise my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> which basically is true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it it it's i'm glad i don't live in a big city
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just because i mean not just because i wouldn't feel safe it's just because that i would be reminded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> of something that i don't see and i might see it on a you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sixty Minute</ENAMEX> special
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh-huh no in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> it was like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> it was just a matter of who was shot <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know it but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> is considered a nice clean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> believe it or not  i mean they have all kinds of nice write ups about it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh-huh oh yeah but
 	
 	
 		but any big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has a bad section
 	
 	
 		but there's a lot of them it's very prevalent a lot of the crime is very prevalent
 	
 	
 		yes they're very bold it seems
 	
 	
 		uh-huh very much When we moved here to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monterrey</ENAMEX> it was a big change because it's such a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> we're just above <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carmel</ENAMEX> and um there's hardly most everybody seems pretty well employed
 		around here and um those that aren't there's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celinas</ENAMEX> which is about a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifteen minute</TIMEX> drive which is mostly migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and there's a lot of crime there
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">um</ENAMEX> migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers people</ENAMEX> that are down and out and uh they all seem to congregate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celinas</ENAMEX> not so much here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monterrey</ENAMEX>
 		so it's it's pretty quiet you know we walk the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> run in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and you know you're just have your normal smarts about you then you really don't have to worry or
 	
 	
 		really even uh even in the worst crime areas in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burlington</ENAMEX> i i can walk the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> i wouldn't i if i did it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think there would be trouble in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so you wouldn't get confronted or anything
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i don't think you would uh
 		someone might grab you mess around with you but they're not going to grab you steal your your money and slit your throat which in a lot of big cities
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean that's what you your going to have to expect that to happen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just totally unfeeling like uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh  oh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh uh i didn't know that about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burlington</ENAMEX> i'll have to keep that in mind
 		
 		
 	