
 
     		
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight years ago</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was raised here but i i have never lived here so um
 		when when we came back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i i was really kind of excited there wasn't a state income tax and there wasn't a tax on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> that we purchased at the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and things and all of that was new to me so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm sort of feeling like we're getting a better deal here than what i was accustomed to
 	
 	
 		yeah well did you move from the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> and then in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and then um and both places had pretty good state income tax
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um we've always paid tax um you know on everything we purchased you know even food at the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> so
 		i thought it was really you know kind of a pretty good deal not to have to pay tax on your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries groceries</ENAMEX> and
 		but i think i mean i i don't enjoy paying taxes and it's hard but um
 		i think that's what we have to have to you know have our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and and have our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and  excuse me and have
 		and have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> that we need and we have to pay for them and pay for the employment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that run them and and things like that and i think i guess
 		what i feel is that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> um they don't like to pay taxes because they feel like well there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who aren't paying their fair share
 	
 	
 		yeah i think yeah it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that can really influence the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and have all the money to
 	
 	
 		and um that makes you feel bad
 		right and you know when um when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> the the elections were going on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> election and state and you know i i didn't have anything against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clayton Williams</ENAMEX> personally or anything but um
 		it was kind of hard for me to think here's someone who as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wealthy</ENAMEX> as he is didn't have to pay any income tax that he said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX> he claimed  he had didn't have to pay income tax and he thought well you know there's some people
 		are living pretty pretty good life styles but they're not paying income tax and that's not fair to me and there's you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who uh are abusing
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		the systems that we pay taxes to support and all of that makes us feel bad but i think you know all in all how i feel is that um i'm willing to pay the taxes because
 		i think i like our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> compared to the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i've studied and visited and um i'm willing to pay extra to live here and to enjoy the services i enjoy how do you feel
 	
 	
 		well yeah i agree that you have to pay taxes for the services you get and i think that you know i don't think there's probably any really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		put that system that everybody would think is fair as far as being taxed you know i guess in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> with uh we live here also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that it's mostly sales tax so it's really the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have the money to buy things that are paying the more because they're paying the sales tax on the larger items that they buy and stuff i've lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> most of my life we um lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we were kind of in for a rude awakening they had personal property taxes on like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> we're there it was like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight hundred dollars</NUMEX> and we're like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		you know what happened is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> said i used to complain to pay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> dollars to get licensed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and now  you know so i mean that was kind of different and then to file a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a state income tax was also kind of tough too um i guess since we've been married we've moved a lot and so it always seems like
 		you know we're always paying in taxes for something and so the it was kind of nice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> to finally be able to get a little bit of money back but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i um have accounting background so then i also have done tax returns in the past and for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when i worked  for accounting firm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know it is kind of sad to see all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know have the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> to hire somebody and have the money to spend to put their money in places  they don't have to pay taxes or to buy something that loses money so that they can
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know offset the income that they get or whatever so but you know i think if
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i can understand maybe why the rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't want to pay you know a large large percent because it you know that's not really fair either if they've earned their money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		by themselves well you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>  just kind of given the money it's kind of depressing sometimes i think
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well it is and um and sometimes i think um
 		well for myself that the income that we have we're paid a certain salary but i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> keeps in mind
 		this'll be deducted you know some so many taxes will be deducted from it and so i think we're you know our salaries are a little bit higher because we have to pay taxes on it and so i think you know in that way we're compensated
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um just by our society yet you know they don't pay you um
 		what just what it would take and then if if you pay taxes on it you wouldn't have any money left over and  and um but some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that make
 		a great deal of money and everything um i wish that they would i guess because i'm not one of them  i wish that they would um you know realize that they
 	
 	
 		well yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		they couldn't make this kind of money they couldn't live that kind of life style anywhere else
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in that even if they made that kind of money there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that have like fifty percent income tax you know that have socialized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX> and things and that they um they wouldn't be able to enjoy the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uproots that and that so that you know they need to be willing to pay a little bit more for it yes they've earned it and yes they've that's great they've you know had such great fortune here
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		but they need to pay for it too because they couldn't do that somewhere else
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um um i like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> um not having the state income tax and i hope that
 		because um you know that we've had enough industry here that i guess it is that why we don't  the industry here is able to to um fund
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> because we have oil here and things i mean that's what i've always heard is that um
 	
 	
 		but they must have enough other stuff because the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> has been the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few years</TIMEX> that that really hasn't been the industry that is bringing in the money for the taxes i wouldn't think
 	
 	
 		big boom
 		yeah there's something about um the industry in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that um there's enough i know we moved here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and um the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> had it's enough money it was really nice that they had uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but they began to cut back because of the oil problems but um you know they would have have um so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> outdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> and and like uh community
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> type things that the it was such nice services to offer the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and i really liked that
 	
 	
 		don't you have to why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just kind of debate expect certain services then then they don't really think they should pay for them or something maybe i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it's true and i'm you know like the the property tax that we pay and everything is so much higher than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> pay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> but um i'm
 		i'm comfortable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least this year</TIMEX> with we pay we have some good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> thing might be changing but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm willing to pay for that for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i'm willing to sacrifice i guess i mean i'm not going to be the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that's going to grumble about the taxes even though we're paying pretty high percentage um
 		i feel like you get what you pay for and i want to be here and i i enjoy i enjoy living here in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and having seen other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i'd much rather live here and pay taxes than live somewhere else and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and not anyway well  i guess i better let you go
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it was nice talking to you i haven't ever i need to i've never initiated one of these phone calls do you call in do you get to pick the subject or do they kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah it was nice talking
 		no no they just define it to you and so so you get what get uh luck of the draw but  yeah  anyway well good luck to you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		yeah
 		okay you too bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	