
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay the topic said to discuss the weather what is it like where you are and how's that different from normal and
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i tell you what it is it's warm where i'm at
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well let's see if you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> and i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> are you in east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> or west Plano
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh west</ENAMEX> Plano
 	
 	
 		okay well i'm in east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> i'm out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Rios</ENAMEX> so it's bound to be different over here but yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		good deal well i tell you what uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> i went out and played a little golf and uh i paid the price my neck got got burned to a crisp
 	
 	
 		oh
 		got a little sunburn yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but uh it was it was beautiful out
 	
 	
 		wow
 		i worked around in the yard a little bit and
 		i've got sunburned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> and you know got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those what <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> degree burns and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> looked at it and said don't ever
 	
 	
 		oh Lord
 		
 
 	
 	
 		don't ever let that area get sunburned again
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh it's got the you know the kind of the black freckled things on it that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> looks at every once in a while for that what melanoma business
 	
 	
 		right
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		so i am super whenever we go down to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galveston</ENAMEX> to the beach or something like that you know i look kind of stupid i'm out there in a T-shirt and everything else
 	
 	
 		all covered up
 	
 	
 		pretty much covered up but uh you know i'm never going to let my shoulders and back get sunburned again
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i tell you i'm the same way i tell you i i knew better i should have put some sunscreen on uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> but i don't know it felt so nice out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> after all you know you're not supposed to worry about sunburn in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's right that's right they shouldn't even be selling suntan lotion yet
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		but uh hopefully uh you know it's going to stay warm for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		well yeah i hope so yeah we're going to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> they'll probably have another sandstorm out there you know
 	
 	
 		so you're going to go to the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> huh yeah
 	
 	
 		big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> yeah are are you a native type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Planoite</ENAMEX> or you been here a while or
 	
 	
 		no i just been uh up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> for about uh i guess close to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> now and uh
 	
 	
 		okay well well where did you come from originally
 	
 	
 		i grew up in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> right outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amarillo</ENAMEX> and uh then when i went to school at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay well i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		are you okay
 	
 	
 		yeah i grew up over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roswell</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Plains</ENAMEX> if you know where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plains</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		i've heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plains</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		it's on the it's on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> where do you know where well you go south out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> down to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brownfield</ENAMEX> and then you like you're headed over toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Roswell Plains</ENAMEX> is right there
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about fifteen miles</NUMEX> in from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> line
 	
 	
 		i see okay
 	
 	
 		so so yeah you talk of little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">west Texas</ENAMEX> yeah i'm
 	
 	
 		well no see i'm from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panhandle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay yeah i know where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panhandle</ENAMEX> is that's north up there isn't it yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		right right right up there by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amarillo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who lived in Dumas
 	
 	
 		okay yeah on the other side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amarillo</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah so anyway yeah we're kind of familiar with that part of the world now there's where the weather's interesting i think it's kind of dull around here compared to
 	
 	
 		well that's right because uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> it'll be eighty and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> it'll be about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> below i tell you what and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> still lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> and we talked to her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and they said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> they had or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> they had a you know one of the world class sandstorms out there that happens every once in a while hadn't had one like that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh Lord
 		that's one thing i do not miss about uh being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> i tell you
 		because one i i'll never forget uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one spring</TIMEX> we had a real big dust storm come in and it started raining and uh it was like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">raining mud</ENAMEX> out there you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i recall a snirtstorm out there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> where about this time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> that there was a big cold front coming in and they got the dirt up in the air and then it snowed a little bit
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		
 
 		oh Lord
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i can imagine that happening more in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amarillo</ENAMEX> than i could in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> but still anywhere out there it could happen
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's exactly right i tell you
 	
 	
 		yeah i we like i said i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albuquerque Karen</ENAMEX> and i both lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albuquerque</ENAMEX> for quite a long time and then i went to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i came here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty nine and then seventy two</TIMEX> they opened or seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> they opened up that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> out there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that was like going home and uh so we went out there were there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about ten years</TIMEX> until that all folded up out there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i see
 	
 	
 		ended up coming back but uh
 		yeah the weather out there was uh-huh it it could get a little bit a little bit interesting now and again
 	
 	
 		oh it sure can because uh the you never just you just can never tell what it's going to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's just hard to plan anything
 	
 	
 		well if you've been here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> you didn't get here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> they had the big freeze and stuff here did you what was that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eighty four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that i did
 		this
 		okay
 	
 	
 		oh wow that would have been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six or seven years ago</TIMEX> then
 	
 	
 		yeah uh my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first year</TIMEX> down here uh uh that first winter i remembered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> was closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one one day</TIMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		that yeah with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> but that uh that's about the worst worst winter i've been been through down here
 	
 	
 		well the uh
 		was it i guess it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> that they had the real right before was it right before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> or
 		where
 	
 	
 		yeah where it got just real real cold
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah got down to around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> somewhere and then warmed back up and killed everything off
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah that was that was bad news we're still try i set out a whole bunch of crepe myrtles and stuff and of course it killed th em
 	
 	
 		oh Lord
 	
 	
 		well they all come back from from the bottom
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i'm getting kind of convinced that if something doesn't grow naturally here there's no sense in planting it because eventually you're going to lose it
 	
 	
 		that's right because the weather's going to get it exactly
 	
 	
 		and you noticed all the pretty little <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> that are out everything now the native trees
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that still don't have the leaves on them yet that's right that's exactly right
 	
 	
 		they're they know better  they know better  yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i are going through that process now we just bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and we're trying to decide what we want to do with our landscaping and we still have to put a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i'm still trying to decide when when the best time's going to be to do that so uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well you're just about there i think it's
 	
 	
 		that's that's right you know i'd i'd like to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> in before all the rain start and uh you know if we could get it up a little bit then the rain would really just help it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well we moved into this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year old</TIMEX> and the landscaping was semi-in but there was still a lot more to do
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things that uh well they were really selling everybody on back then was this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawthorne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> you know that's the best stuff in the world
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		well  i am somewhat less than enthused about that i've got some out here that's
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five six years old</TIMEX> now and still doesn't look a whole lot different than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> that i put it in
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		and i noticed that a lot of the garden well you know that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawthorne</ENAMEX> that didn't work out quite as well as we thought you know so now they're pushing something else
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Sperry</ENAMEX> hasn't been pushing that real hard and heavy here lately
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well anyway uh like i said if it if it doesn't grow out in the woods here somewhere i'm not sure
 	
 	
 		that's worth planting huh
 	
 	
 		that it's worth planting yeah
 	
 	
 		that's exactly right
 	
 	
 		this uh photinia
 		the red tipped photinia
 	
 	
 		red tipped bush yeah
 	
 	
 		it seems to do pretty good we've got some here that's really taken off
 	
 	
 		well yeah i i i know everybody in our neighborhood has has those <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bushes</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like i say really seem to to do well
 	
 	
 		that and uh the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwarf</ENAMEX> yaupon hollies you know they they seem to or just yaupons period seem to do all right
 	
 	
 		right holley yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		we've got a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Live Oaks</ENAMEX> in the front yard and of course they're
 		they weren't native to this particular spot but they seem to have done pretty good and
 	
 	
 		they sure have and that's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> it sort of stays green most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> you know and
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		yeah it's it's it's a strange one it will kind of scare you if you don't know what it's doing because right now is when it's dropping it's leaves
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you go out there and look at your tree after a good windstorm and the thing is bare and you think oh no
 	
 	
 		the thing's dying
 	
 	
 		but you look look real close and there's all the little new leaves getting ready to come out so it holds it's leaves all winter then loses them in the spring
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that and that red what is it red oak
 	
 	
 		red oak yeah
 	
 	
 		we're thinking about putting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those in
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> thing is those things grow pretty slow you have to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well you know i heard something about that here whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil</ENAMEX> uh here again it may have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Sperry</ENAMEX> they say you know everybody looks at these <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oaks</ENAMEX> and says yeah they grow slow and all that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but most of the time that's the way that the native ones grow because they don't get the water they don't get the they're they're growing under bad conditions
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh if you bring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in and put it under good conditions they'll grow about as fast as any tree
 	
 	
 		so if you really fertilize it and
 		huh well that's surprising
 	
 	
 		so yeah
 	
 	
 		that's good to know
 	
 	
 		so anyway that's that was i guess he was talking about some of the other kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oaks</ENAMEX> i don't know
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		whether the live live <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oaks</ENAMEX> is not really an oak i guess it's something
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i think it's just by name yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it just got the the name of being an oak because it's got a kind of an acorn kind of thing on it
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but uh i think the real honest to gosh <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oaks</ENAMEX> like the what bur <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oaks</ENAMEX> and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pin oaks</ENAMEX> and red <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oaks</ENAMEX> and all that sort of thing they they'll grow a lot faster
 	
 	
 		yeah huh
 	
 	
 		well i guess we were supposed to be talking about the weather but that's
 	
 	
 		at least we had a good conversation anyway yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well are you you with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		yes i am yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		how many these have you gotten very many of these calls at home
 	
 	
 		um probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> i guess yeah
 	
 	
 		okay well i got the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this evening</TIMEX> that i had gotten at home i
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		i'd made a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> at work
 		you know made made several from work but i'd never uh i'd never gotten one yet i was just
 	
 	
 		right
 		gotten <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at home huh yeah i've gotten <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well
 		you know you'd think that this crazy system if you're going to talk about something about the weather they'd have tried to plug you in with plug you in to somebody
 	
 	
 		split it up a little bit
 	
 	
 		like you know  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> or something yeah
 	
 	
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> or somewhere yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		yeah weather difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> and west Plano
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		clear across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		clear across town
 		well when we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albuquerque</ENAMEX> there was such a elevation difference there that there was a weather difference between the valley and the heights
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know it would be snowing up in our area and then the sun would be shining and it would be hot down in the
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		downtown but uh that's not the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plano</ENAMEX> works
 		
 		
 	