
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well do you exercise regularly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i try to ride the stationary bicycle everyday <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about five miles</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i love to walk so if i have a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch hour</TIMEX> with nice weather i get out and and walk what about you
 	
 	
 		well um i uh exercise regularly i work at a university and i swim almost everyday
 	
 	
 		uh very good
 	
 	
 		upwards of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is one of my favorite places to visit uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> and when i go to visit her  i love to get out on that bike trail and either ride the bike
 		oh gosh you can ride a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX>  practically all the way to southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or just get out and walk uh or even jog a little although i don't do that regularly but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s a great place to do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah there are there are lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> paths i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biker</ENAMEX> and he he's done the whole C and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> canal i think it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and eighty</NUMEX> miles with the scouts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so uh but that that somehow takes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> for me it's much easier just the stationary bike you know it's at home i can i can do some of my reading
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		um
 		but
 	
 	
 		do you live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		because i think there're so many parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> where it's not very safe to get out and walk
 	
 	
 		right right and that's it um at work we have a a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> so i'm able to um
 		take advantage of of the environment here um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the neighborhood also i mean we're  within walking distance of of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> so i do
 		now i think um basically is your motive simply um health or because you enjoy it
 	
 	
 		well it's uh it's really both i'm certainly driven by
 		the desire to maintain my weight and be healthy and be in shape and uh
 		and most of the time i enjoy it sometimes i don't but i feel that uh that the discipline it affords me when i do it when i don't wanna is also worth something
 	
 	
 		um-hum right i think
 		pretty much you've summed up my my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">motivations</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		and i often find that even when i don't feel that much like exercising like i'll be really tired and i'll start swimming and i'll actually and i'll actually get energy
 		and i'll be have much more energy when i'm done than when i started i mean i just feel great that happens to me probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> times that i swim
 	
 	
 		oh well that's great that's great
 	
 	
 		that's really a terrific feeling because you just go there at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX> and you figure God i'm ready for bed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you exercise and then it's sort of it's painful for a while but by the time you get done you're feeling really terrific
 	
 	
 		right  and actually in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> i like to swim we don't have facilities for swimming in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> but um
 		and and that's true when i go home from work at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX> if i go up for an hour in the pool
 		i'm much much more awake i'm ready to work in the garden or whatever in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		so are can i just ask you are you <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i'm not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		i'm trying to because you have a you have one funny vowel that's probably gonna drive the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> crazy you say out instead of out you say out
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		
  
 		no i don't know that but i i must say that um
 	
 	
 		did you know that
 	
 	
 		when when i did do a linguistics course in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">school ages ago</TIMEX> um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> had a lot of trouble with my accent
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and it's probably because i i was born in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> area and grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and at and at that point that was sort of a limit but but since then i've been abroad a lot so
 	
 	
 		hm
 		i see
 	
 	
 		it's a mixture
 	
 	
 		i know this isn't on our topic but where did you grow up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Barbara</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay because i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Hollywood California</ENAMEX> i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX> and all that
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well very good and i think we've probably know know each other's exercise habits and um it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well same here thanks for calling bye
 	
 	
 		oh okay bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	