
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		an interesting uh point about sentencing by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> alone doing away with a jury
 		i don't know if i'd be willing to accept the um abuses that would come along with that and that the it would be relatively easy to get some bad decisions or to even get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> from a standpoint of bribery but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or even if he just through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of being on the bench just becomes uh out of touch with uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and he only sees the bad side of life so much that he just ends up making bad decisions
 		however the complexity of some of these uh cases it's just they spend more time educating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> up to the point where they can make a decision
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then it would take if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> just made the decision especially when it is purely um noncriminal uh litigation type uh whatever you want to call it the term
 		civil uh suits as it were or even some corporate uh law
 		when there's not any individual involved and some of those are solved without a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> but uh some some do choose to go before it
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		um what do you think about the aspect of unanimous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> when they do have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> must all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> or twelve uh agree before the the topic be final or or the verdict be final
 	
 	
 		yeah that that is uh a tough situation i mean because
 		you know i mean some sometimes i feel like maybe some of them are just kind of pressured or not really into you know and
 		and you know uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go home and the jury duty is always like you know kind of whining about it all
 		seems like if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were were really you know into the subject and uh
 		i don't know i mean i guess if there if it was more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it would be better if it was just like you know the majority
 		but i guess the smaller number of that if it was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> or twelve which there usually are so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i guess unanimous
 		uh
 		yeah i kind of agree with that
 	
 	
 		okay if it the only thing that i was thinking about as far as having if you had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> holdout out of say twelve
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then is it reasonable or is it or could you assume that there must be some reason for that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to be holding out and obviously the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven or five</NUMEX> cannot convince this person
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that uh they should vote it one way or the other so maybe it is worth having that extra little
 		or going to the the
 		very
 		farthest uh safeguard that can be done and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		trying not to get a wrong decision
 	
 	
 		yeah i can see that
 	
 	
 		the uh system as it stands now i think if if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> were done away with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> could render a decision much quicker
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and you'd you'd feed more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> as it were don't know where we'd put them once we got them through your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think the rate of processing is just about uh reached the rate of housing anyway so keep the keep the normal as it is can't upset the system very much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i heard about um is is there true that there's a if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> takes a a case to court and it's what do they call it um frivolous is that is there still a frivolous law that they can
 	
 	
 		probably yeah i would imagine the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> could throw it out
 	
 	
 		yeah but do you think he would fine the lawyer
 	
 	
 		i would imagine that's left up to the judge i i would assume he could consider it a contempt of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and and uh but anything he wanted whatever his limits are on contempt of court
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah i never i didn't realize until recently that there was actually a fine they could pretty interesting though
 	
 	
 		certainly makes sense because some of this stuff is you know you you're just doing this to do this you know it's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		just doesn't make sense
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that's pretty bad  a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine is a is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> actually you know it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> because we're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Collin County</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he is uh just recently changed from hearing all the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DWI</ENAMEX> type stuff to uh doing what they call more of a family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> where he gets to go listen to all the divorces so it wasn't much of a step up as it were
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh really
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um it's really tough he says in a lot of cases where he has to make the decision so i guess in a lot of those cases it's it's all up to him as oppose to a jury
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		and there's just no good choice as to where to put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> sometimes or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and of course there <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> get kind of spiteful at times and
 	
 	
 		oh that would be really tough
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and you hear it all through the worst side of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> throughout the whole time
 	
 	
 		yeah you really do
 	
 	
 		well let me think here
 		um
 		as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> making the decision
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean because seems like
 		i don't know i mean there's so many different different types of cases that come in i mean it seems like just general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean
 		who are live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and do different things you know you have different opinions kind of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who sits there and listens to cases all the time would would get it start thinking a certain way and go go nuts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's true
 		but then look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that tends to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> duty
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you you either have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who who is uh the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> who can work for a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> that can afford to pay them you know let them go
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and those are shall we say blue collar that that
 		your work the assembly line type or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX> some engineering uh you may not have the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">self-employed businessman</ENAMEX> willing to go because he though he may be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		current on all you know several social issues and have opinions on things like that he just doesn't want to take his time to go to the jury duty so he probably doesn't vote either so he doesn't get called in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">counties</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it i don't know whether it would be wiser to have an educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> even though he may get uh out of touch after a while or whether it would be uh worth it to stick to the class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that end up there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that is hard to say
 	
 	
 		though i have had a judge fact this very judge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine say that he uh does not like to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that are from uh the electronics industry
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i said well me being from the electronics industry i'll bite why why don't you like it and he said well
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he said the majority of them uh tend to dive into their little world of of electronics and be very technically minded and be very absorbed with what their field is
 		and they usually don't um read outside their field they don't read social type uh papers they don't they're not up to date on various uh current affairs as it were and
 	
 	
 		oh i hadn't ever thought of that really
 	
 	
 		and i said well that that's quite possible i said i've discussed some topics with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> even over this situation and and discovered some views that i hadn't thought of in a while i just wondered if i got out of my little realm
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		if i wouldn't run into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with some more diverse views
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh my realm is pretty well technical and those who you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> i have are usually we discuss technical items and we don't uh try to follow the world's problems
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess it's too frustrating
 	
 	
 		yeah it does
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so
 	
 	
 		gosh
 	
 	
 		well i think we've managed to kill a little time on the topic and we'll go ahead and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we'll go ahead and call you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another day</TIMEX> maybe
 	
 	
 		all right well groovy it's been cool talking to you see you around bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye
 		
 
 		
 		
 	