
 
     		
 	
 		okay well personally i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty two</TIMEX> and i'm doing my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC State</ENAMEX> so uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> wouldn't be very convenient for me right now
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		well no they wouldn't would they no
 	
 	
 		so what what how do you spend the time with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well both of mine are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and they
 	
 	
 		and we're into sports i mean as a matter of fact that's what we're doing tonight
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what what are you doing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">uh baseball</ENAMEX> has started
 	
 	
 		oh okay do do they play like uh like does the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight year old</TIMEX> play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh oh yes we start here at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">uh five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and and in in in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> do they have like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> or do they have a standing ball or a machine or what
 	
 	
 		up until it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> pitch until you get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> which my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> so he's going to be with uh regular pitching and my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> of course you know is pitching
 	
 	
 		okay
 		oh okay
 		yeah i i used to play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> when i was that age up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		but yes we're into <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> and it seems like soon as that over with we get into <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> we even have peewee basketball here so there's always something
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah and how about how about like on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> do you do sports or do you go out
 	
 	
 		both if we're not doing sports we go somewhere
 	
 	
 		do you go uh how about like for uh do you go for long vacations like a week or something when they have school off
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> or like in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> time like around now
 	
 	
 		no usually in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> time
 	
 	
 		and where do you go
 	
 	
 		different places <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> we
 	
 	
 		have have you been out of the country
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		oh okay well first they always say get to know your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> first before you leave i mean i i lived in places like when i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> i never went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Washington Memorial</ENAMEX> and then when i went back to visit i went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Memorial</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you know i've heard we have a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> quite often
 		and that must be the thing they really hadn't either they went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Memorial</ENAMEX> you know because when they go it's on business it's not really just to getting to sight see
 	
 	
 		right
 		right well it's it's a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and but the problem is like first example when i was young they they took me to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> and that was the most boring place on earth
 	
 	
 		oh i bet it is too
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i we go different places but our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but when we go with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> we usually kind of stay close
 	
 	
 		yeah did uh did like did you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disneyland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes yes
 	
 	
 		oh okay so but um now i don't know but um but let's see when i was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> i went also to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that that was fun that was and uh then after that i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> so when i was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen fifteen</NUMEX> i went i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> and this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> but basically
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it's uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of years</TIMEX> uh i since my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are are well i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> live down there so all the traveling i do is alone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we were never much of uh a very uh family thing you know may like go skiing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was uh that was a lot of fun but what happens is we used to fight a lot so there's never much of a family  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> thing you know one of those hell family vacations
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 		yes
 		oh yes but we try you know uh i try my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> also we're involved in everything our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> does because uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> died you know when i was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than a year old</TIMEX> so i always just had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> so i always thought when i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know i really want to be involved with them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> all he all he wanted to do was get money for us so he could buy us material things and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		things yes that is yes
 	
 	
 		and and to me you know it's like now i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty two</TIMEX> but i still feel you know it's like yeah we never threw a football or something and the way i was brought up and he wants me now he like he you know like he wants to be best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> now and it's very
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> now yes
 	
 	
 		hard for me because you know it's like you grow up to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years old</TIMEX> and it's always the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and then suddenly he sees that he's getting old
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he wants to be best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> but uh you know it's like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i can only express myself so much because you know of everything that he taught me you know that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> taught me which is very hard to change that all of a sudden from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> to the next and say i'm sorry you know it's like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i love you and let's go out and do things together when i don't feel like it you know
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		and so that's uh that the same thing that you know its like when like like i've seen my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> and his family you know does everything together and you know his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are you know when his little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years old</TIMEX> and everything
 		they uh they would go to the beach and she could go to sleep at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two in the morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and uh i was brought up the same way if if it doesn't matter what age you have if just so long as you can get up to go to class <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next morning</TIMEX> you can stay up you know but his what he does is when he gets home he separates his his work from his house
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		yeah you have to i mean you honestly do now i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that i love to death but and they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> does anything we have to take them and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know to do it and that really gets kind of aggravating after a while because you're saying well i work full time too you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah but uh it's just it's just something that you know my theory is you know when when you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and all you want to do well what i'll do is you know it like
 		i mean you might have a problems but it's not your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> problems you know and you got to try to to be with them as much as you can and to you know like thing is is that you know like if
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if they would ever happen to have a drug problem suppose that they could feel comfortable coming to me and saying i got a problem
 	
 	
 		problem uh-huh
 	
 	
 		you know and uh and that would make any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> feel good and bad at the same time you know <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all you're coming to me and let's see how we can get rid of the problem you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's uh that's very that's very hard to do because once you're best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> then i think everything go a lot better
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah uh i agree with you very much so now we waited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> before we started having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> because we was still in college and we knew
 		time wise or and money wise too would it would not have been a good idea to had them then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was raising <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> before he had me so it was uh
 		you know you're trying to support uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and it's pretty hard you know and i and i told them listen you could have had a lot of money if you would have only had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he goes yeah but then i wouldn't have you i go yeah but then you would have a lot of money you know
 	
 	
 		that's right but you can't take this money with us though  that's how i keep looking at it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		but you know like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> i mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is expensive especially when you consider like especially for for me which i'm paying out of state tuition i'm paying you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three thousand</NUMEX> no what is it <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two thousand six hundred dollars</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one semester</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say you know it's expensive for to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to college but if if an everybody would be a little bit responsible you know it's like what what does it cost it costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semester</TIMEX> suppose that they go to a state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and they live at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and well it costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two hundred dollars</NUMEX> for books
 		but you know <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven hundred dollars</NUMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semester</TIMEX> a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can spare that if they planned ahead you know like
 	
 	
 		oh yeah if you can't if you can yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean it's like if you plan <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> ahead you can probably save up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven hundred dollars</NUMEX> you know one thousand <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four hundred dollars</NUMEX> to send your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to college you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what are you wanting to be
 	
 	
 		oh oh excuse me
 	
 	
 		what degree i mean what are you wanting to do after you get out of college
 	
 	
 		well i i'm doing computer science computer engineering
 	
 	
 		oh that that's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s into uh computers
 	
 	
 		yeah and and now i'm looking for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a job</TIMEX> before they have to send me back home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because since i'm an international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> they want to send me back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> wants me to go back so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and you don't want to no no
 	
 	
 		no no because if you go back there then you can never get out
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		like you don't have any money to to get out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh and uh i was thinking you know like oh my God you know i go back there and then and then i might get married there and then i will have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> there and then i'll never leave the place you know
 	
 	
 		hum
 		then you'll never leave yeah oh
 	
 	
 		yeah i know and that's that's what happened to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> he came to school up here and then when he went down there he was just so bad off you know from not being able to stay up here that
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		his life just went down the drain so
 	
 	
 		well maybe something will open up for you
 	
 	
 		yeah i i've been calling a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> there some of them are interested well at least for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and a half i can work so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well maybe well i've enjoyed talking to you okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		i'll do it
 		all right same here bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	