
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> hi
 		you mentioned model railroading that uh i've been watching a program on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Broadcasting Station</ENAMEX> here uh about model railroading have you ever seen that
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i i always turn on the TV set and it seems like i catch that program in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last five minutes and</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh well it's been very interesting
 	
 	
 		i i think it you know what i see is fascinating and i kind of enjoy it
 		uh
 		i've always had that hobby ever since i was a child
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i refuse to get involved because i never had space for a permanent layout
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years ago</TIMEX> we bought a big old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oaktown Virginia</ENAMEX>
 		and there was uh there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basements</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two</NUMEX> separate furnace rooms
 		and so i took the smaller furnace <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and now it's full of trains
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you should have taken the larger one huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well uh my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lionel</ENAMEX> train set he was a a bit older than i and
 		so when i came along i was interested in uh fooling with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> and since he was was past that stage why he didn't have any objections and
 		uh in fact i started doing a layout uh in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time but
 		i got about as far as sort of painting some uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and things on a piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plywood</ENAMEX> and putting up a few things and it got to be hot summertime when i gave it up
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but uh i've always enjoyed uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> and
 		you know fooling with it and all
 	
 	
 		do you still have the uh train set
 	
 	
 		he has it
 	
 	
 		he has it
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean since it was his i couldn't very well keep it forever
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but uh actually i have had an idea not long ago uh hope to build another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some day</TIMEX> and i was thinking i might uh incorporate some sort of a display space and ask him if he would
 		let me put the train up you know not not as a working type of thing but just to
 	
 	
 		put it on display
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well those uh the early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lionels</ENAMEX> can be quite valuable
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know what year his was bought but probably around
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nineteen forty forty two maybe</NUMEX> i'm i'm just guessing but something like that i would think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well some of those around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the war years</TIMEX> were uh kind of difficult to get a hold of because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lionel</ENAMEX> got involved in manufacturing a lot of uh uh war equipment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i think they almost discontinued production uh in
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nineteen forty two and forty three</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so some of the pre-war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> are quite valuable
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know i don't know if i don't know if he knows i know there's some uh booklets and things you know showing different models and stuff
 		that are quite old that were with it but i don't know if they were original or if they were picked up you know in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i managed to sweet talk my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> out of uh his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lionel</ENAMEX> train set that uh dated back to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about nineteen thirty three</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh he's kind of unhappy i've got it now
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i'm not going to give it back
 	
 	
 		yeah that's probably the way it goes sometimes
 	

 	
 		and i had a uh
 		post uh <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania Electric</ENAMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">GT1</NUMEX> locomotives
 		and it happened to be one of the rare paint jobs
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i understand that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">locomotive</ENAMEX> is worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around seven hundred</NUMEX> and fifty dollars now
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so it's it's sitting on display on top of my bookcase
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it has a prominent spot huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i think those things are neat and and as i say i watch that show and there are some uh really interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> around that uh have good displays and uh
 		i said that well if i ever took a trip i you know might ignore some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> because a lot of them are called childrens <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> or toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that wouldn't really catch my attention but if i knew that they had you know really good train layouts i would wanna go and see what they had
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> used to have uh some commercial displays
 		there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place that was halfway between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harrisburg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Allenstown Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midway</ENAMEX> which suggest it was halfway
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		they had a huge room which was probably uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">forty feet</NUMEX> wide and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">forty feet</NUMEX> long
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and the central portion of that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> was occupied by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> gauge layout running uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lionel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Flyer</ENAMEX> trains
 	
 	
 		wow
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and they had done a lot of work on that with uh scenery and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>
 		and they had trolleys running around and uh a lot of animation in there
 		and uh it was in business for a long long time i don't know it it still maybe in business
 	
 	
 		it might be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well um you mentioned another hobby sailing do you have a sailboat
 	
 	
 		yes uh i bought a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bristol</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five five</TIMEX> for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and we keep it on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chesapeake Bay</ENAMEX>
 		and uh starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next weekend</TIMEX> i'm gonna have to go down and uh
 		fill out for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> season
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we have a cruise plan to sail from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX> up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a two week</TIMEX> cruise and uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> lay days in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that'll be nice
 	
 	
 		they have a a new waterfront uh marina in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> it isn't as developed as uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Water Side</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norfolk</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> uh waterfront
 		but uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">marina</ENAMEX> is only about uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> blocks from the historic district
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so that's quite uh handy for our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> we can take them up and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		show them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Independence Hall</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberty Bell</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yeah and just be right there huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Square</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh we're not uh really <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX> but i want some summer soon to um
 		hire a sailboat with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> since we're not you know versed in that and uh go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		well there are some uh good opportunities for that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Virgins</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		uh that's uh that is almost an ideal sailing area uh
 		if you have a little even a little bit of experience uh i've seen a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go through a uh a cruising class in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Annapolis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where they might get uh maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifteen hours</TIMEX> of sailing experience go down to uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> Tortolla
 		and charter a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> for a week
 		and they take it out and have a grand time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh it's fairly sheltered waters right there and uh
 		you don't need any fancy navigation equipment because you can see all your destinations from one spot
 	
 	
 		right uh it just sound fascinating to me i would love to just go down i've always liked islands and water and that sort of thing anyway and um
 		been on a couple of big cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> so uh you know i kind of had seen it from that point of view but i i think i would like the sailboat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh i've been there several times uh the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trip uh
 		we flew down and uh chartered a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and i had fun that then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years later</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i was racing with uh decided to take his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> down for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> season
 		and so i went offshore with him to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Thomas</ENAMEX>
 		and then we cruised uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Virgins</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> before i flew home
 	
 	
 		which do you think is best <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Virgins</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think the better sight seeing is in the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Virgins</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh there's uh some very nice places like the bass which is a uh sort of a huge monolithic rocks that you can
 		you can walk up the beach and into these uh enormous caverns that are partially submerged and you can wade in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> and so forth very popular tourist spot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bitter End</ENAMEX> is an excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> up in uh
 		which is very easy to get into and there's some very nice reefs in that uh vicinity if you like snorkeling and uh scuba diving
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's neat
 	
 	
 		and uh there are some very nice resort <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> so you can go in and uh enjoy a very classy dinner
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter Island Yacht Club</ENAMEX> is uh extremely exclusive
 		like uh i think they're probably charging <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX> a day for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's getting up there
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		it's there kind of a nice place to visit uh
 		uh it's better being on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> than being on land because uh your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> becomes your hotel your uh your dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi cab</ENAMEX> and uh everything else
 	
 	
 		everything
 		yeah that's why i think it would be neat um
 	
 	
 		well i'd recommend it
 	
 	
 		sounds good
 		
 
 		
 		
 	