
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what kind of coins do you primarily collect
 	
 	
 		um basically i my preference is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
 		coins
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and ancient coins
 	
 	
 		hum i've got a uh
 		i've got a few i don't know i don't know i don't even know if they're real but they seem to be very old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> coins that somebody gave me as i when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 		never done anything with them i still got still got them in a box
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm mostly into uh
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> gold and silver dollars and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		oh very interesting
 		um over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> of course by uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> used to give me silver dollars so i've got a few of those tucked away but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um your <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> coins might you know if if they're um
 		in good condition might be worth something you might want to drag them out and
 	
 	
 		i keep meaning to do that everytime i go to a show i keep saying well i'll take them with me and let somebody look at them
 		they just they just feel phony you know they feel like they're made of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead</ENAMEX> or something
 		and uh they don't have any sort of it's it's got a it's got a like a picture on it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but there's no uh inscriptions or or dates or anything else
 	
 	
 		that would be the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> ones
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay because i think most the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> ones have
 	
 	
 		had something on them
 	
 	
 		right right so this
 	
 	
 		yeah it had a it had a had a has a bust of somebody on there but uh
 		no sort of identifying marks or anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um it the are they silver or
 	
 	
 		no i don't no they're not they're it's it's too heavy for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> it's it's more like lead i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fairly soft</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		bronze
 		oh interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they're fakes
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		did did somebody go over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> where they could have picked up some fakes pretty easily
 	
 	
 		probably  i don't know where they got them from they just came up gave me a whole bag of these things
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's probably about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> of them in there
 	
 	
 		gee that's
 	
 	
 		yeah they
 	
 	
 		you might be sitting on a gold mine
 	
 	
 		wouldn't that be something
 	
 	
 		right um i don't know a lot about um <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> although i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and that is the the primary interest of some ancient uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Numismatic Society Club</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> collect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> with a few collecting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> so every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then we have a program so i've picked up a bit
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		but um if it if they're really soft and very early they could be uh i think they call them <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lydian</ENAMEX> coins
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and um
 	
 	
 		gosh all these years i've been thinking they were fakes maybe they're real
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right i don't uh you know i i guess they say that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> particularly can pick up fakes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know if you go to um uh a fight and then
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say oh look what i just dug out of the ground and they sell you something they made last night
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think that's fairly recent phenomena probably
 	
 	
 		sounds like some of the coin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> i know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		now now  they're supposed to they're supposed to be licensed and the um above board
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		right i used to be a coin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> so i i i know i know those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		oh and you made your own
 	
 	
 		yeah i got a whole roll of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugerrands</ENAMEX> here would you like to buy i just made them last night
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		here's a nice uh twenty dollar gold eagle uh just just manufactured in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> last year
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		was uh was the gold worth i mean was it really gold
 	
 	
 		yeah that they they are gold they're just of course the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the twenty</TIMEX> dollar gold pieces go for coin value not the bullion value
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and amazingly enough you're you're into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> sort of coins the the largest amount of fakes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> is made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is that uh still still true
 	
 	
 		yeah still is
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		yeah that's sort of like a cottage industry industry over there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and there's some very specific things you can find you can even narrow narrow it down to where it was made
 		i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are so aware of these things that there are certain identifying marks on there that would not be on a real one
 		and uh you you can almost tell the area
 		somebody probably even knows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who made them
 	
 	
 		you mean make
 		oh
 		i suppose he he has to protect himself too so that somebody can't say
 		you know when he's selling them that somebody else made it i mean it's
 		so that he gets his own profits
 	
 	
 		yeah well the  yeah coin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> are supposed to be smart enough not to fall for that gimmick but i i have seen a few of them sell these things
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and course you have to you have to be able to prove they they knew it was counterfeit  and that's always very difficult
 	
 	
 		hum
 		oh i see otherwise the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> is
 		responsible i mean responsible
 	
 	
 		well he can he can usually go back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> but if if it's an unscrupulous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> he'll just say hey you know you you had an opportunity to see it you know it's yours
 		course you can always turn around and sell it in court and but you'd have to go in on a fraud count and that wouldn't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		fraud is very difficult to prove
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because you have to you have to show they knowingly did it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that's all he's got to say is well in my in my professional judgment it was a it was a real coin
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you know it's his word against mine
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's one of the reasons i got out of the business there was too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shenanigans</ENAMEX> going on
 	
 	
 		oh that's interesting because i'm more interested in the research and i'm doing some dye link analyses of of these early coins from the
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven hundreds</NUMEX> and so and so i'm not into the the buying and selling business
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um it sounds like i'm wise
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah nowadays the the the way the uh the market is and the and the way the uh
 		grading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> have changed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> that's primarily what got me out of it
 		they they kept changing the grading systems on coins
 		and you know you go out and buy a very nice silver dollar collection
 		and you've graded it at the current grade and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX> they've changed the grading system and now these things are worth a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> of what you paid for them
 		you know it's just it it just got it just got ludicrous after a while
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		what what what the the standards for for an uncirculated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> dollar changed so many times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>
 		and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lost lots of money on that course the the persistent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> will just sit there if they graded them as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M S</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty five then</TIMEX> by golly they're <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M S</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty five</TIMEX> i don't care what you say
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they'll keep them until some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> comes along and buys them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		at inflated prices
 	
 	
 		um-hum i think that's that's the the hardest thing is that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't really know feel sometimes a sometimes for example i know um you know the ancients better but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because it's old they figure it's got to cost you know <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands of dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah i mean it's really it's it silly i mean i i i used to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> walk into my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> with um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> pennies you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they say wow you know this is really old
 		yeah well it's not worth anything
 		i'll give you a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nickel</ENAMEX> for it you know
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and even even some of the rare coins that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have never even seen like um like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two cent</NUMEX> pieces
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and things like that those are not those are not even expensive i mean you can pick up very nice ones for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight nine dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah they're cheap they're super cheap
 		um
 	
 	
 		oh that
 	
 	
 		several i mean it's it's it it's funny the way the business works because there're so many things that are enormously out priced
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		some some later proof sets because they have a slight error in them are are worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of dollars</NUMEX>
 		you know and and the coins themselves aren't worth very much at all face value basically
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		and then of course the silver coins are more and more being traded for bullion than anything else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		you can you can buy bags of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> coins a a bag has a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> face value in it and it's traded for silver
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so basically if if someone isn't really interested in the coins it's not some an investment
 	
 	
 		no it's it's more of a uh it's a commodity purchase really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it is fun though to buy these bags and go through them because you do find some
 		some uh
 		nice coins i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are starting out collections and need to fill holes in their books
 		can fill a whole bunch of them
 		with these uh with these bags
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh especially you you want to get a mixed bag of course dimes <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX> and halves
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but you could fill a whole bunch of uh holes with these things
 		i used to i used to advertise buying <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> pennies um
 		i'd give a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar</NUMEX> a roll which <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two cents</NUMEX> a piece which is basically overpriced
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but i used to go through i i'd get loads and loads of these things i ended up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about uh about about twelve</NUMEX> bags of these things
 		and i'd gone through all of them and i found a couple of them i found a nineteen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> VDB
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh a um a nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> which is fairly scarce
 		i found several good ones out of there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s giving it to me for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two cents</NUMEX> i uh that's okay
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		turn around and sell it for fifteen dollars
 		
 		
 	