
 
     		
 	
 		well what is your view do you consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> a threat
 	
 	
 		i don't know that it's so much a military
 		threat anymore as a
 		
 
 		well you know it's it's it's real confusing right now to know what kind of a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">of</NUMEX> of a threat it is i guess it it takes awhile to to get used to something
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		you know if if they have completely changed  the place has completely turned that much around to where they're not you know not what they used to be uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		it's it's hard to to know anymore if it's uh a threat one way or another because
 		uh it used to be so so  much in the past that whatever the top said the rest fell you know rank and file in behind it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now that with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> is introducing more i guess freedoms or expressions of freedom it doesn't look as though
 		you know everybody's following the same pattern and uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are you know the staunch military conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you never know well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>'s future is like whereas whereas in the past it was seen as you know whoever was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of uh the communist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> was seen as you know untouchable
 	
 	
 		yeah i think you know the the thing that keeps happening is happening so fast and so uh dramatic that you almost think now wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a minute</TIMEX> you know we're getting uh sucked into something here you know if if somebody's about to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to clobber you the first thing they do is sort of say well you know we're we're ashamed we're not going to do that anymore and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		um you know i'd i'd like to think that that isn't true but uh i i you know the evidence is that
 		uh you know he's he's let some some stuff go you know the east <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> situation it's just the whole thing is so incomprehensible you know if i'd have been asleep for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> and read it in a book i'd say no no no that didn't couldn't have happened that way
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		right well it it's amazing just because of the drain it's been on you know both economies that our economy is of course been able to uh withstand that a little better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> economy they you know they i don't know what the percentage is but i heard it one time it's just some ungodly number just to support the military machine
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and finally you know who knows maybe they're finally waking up and saying you know we can't afford this
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> isn't the threat that we've always made them out to be you know even if they're saying that beneath the doors
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it's hard to think that just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can bring that much of a radical change in that short of period even if it is you know the best thing in the long run it just steps on too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s toes who are comfortable with the way the situation is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah i i think you know what i'd have to i i guess i guess to answer the question directly i'm still just a a little bit
 		you know leery of the whole thing what i haven't seen is the uh you know a great stepping back in the military situation you know it's it's one thing you know to let us go ahead and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		sort of disarm and you know i even had a thought once that the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> thing might've been just a a deal to go ahead and let us uh you know expend some
 	
 	
 		expend
 	
 	
 		some military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hardware</ENAMEX> of course it didn't turn out that way and uh uh that that may have been a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a kind of far out way of thinking about it i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well it's interesting anymore the world's getting so small that it doesn't seem to tolerate anymore any kind of the expansionism philosophy that that was here in you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh but of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have challenged that or tried to do on it have  have not been world powers
 		so it's easier for us to say you know to an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> you know uh you can't do this get back you know or we're going to force you whereas you know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> would've
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 		yeah or or we can do something about it yeah
 	
 	
 		who knows what taking over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mongolia</ENAMEX> or or something like that who is really will we've been more just rhetoric uh rather than going in there officially uh or you know physically and try to to remove them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> situation you know the when it looked like that thing was was turning around and then all of the sudden it was like somebody in the
 		in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Square</ENAMEX> or wherever said okay and that's enough and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> came in and you know pretty much took care of that and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		exactly
 		yeah uh that
 		personally i don't see as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> as being maybe a threat and i think he's actually honestly trying to do some change
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i don't believe that he in this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> pass around you know being the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to really turn things around or attempt to is going to be allowed to get away with it either
 	
 	
 		yeah well this would be like if somebody was elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and suddenly took off toward you know just some some pretty hard by the socialism and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know the the reaction
 		you know the the economic well the uh the social structure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> you know it it's it's coming apart at the seams
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and i've heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say well you know it's just like the American <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> will there be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> or not well no it's not the same sort of a thing at all because that
 		the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> system was put together under total force you know there was no
 		as as we are seeing now with a lot of those areas wanting out of it you know they uh nobody voted you know a lot man those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't vote to become part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> they had no choice
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that was always kind of interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have a taken  the stance of you know these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just trying to be free and trying to get away and i'm thinking more of it from a nationalistic you know if i'm
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> and if part of you know south let's say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> wanted to succeed you know succeed
 		am i going to stand for that now i realize that the origins are are different and that we all joined under a common direction and a common bond to begin with
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and that they may have been forced i'm not that familiar with their future but i you know i it's easy to believe that they were probably more forced into a pact than uh a volunteer or willingness to join but
 	
 	
 		yeah there there was uh the whole thing was put together
 		you know by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> there's there's no no real question about that and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that were forced in at the later dates is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baltic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> you know came in in the forties
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's well it's not that they came in it's they were conquered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>  and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> even took it back from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> and never bothered to give it back you know so that's a a little different situation
 	
 	
 		and then just never given back
 		yeah
 		well that whole uh the whole idea idea if you look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> history and i guess all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> the way it used to be is the only way to truly protect your borders was to have a buffer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that was the whole idea of why they had so many buffers and maybe you know more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are seeing or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> hopefully are seeing that
 		that buffer isn't going to help you you can like i guess like with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is a perfect example the reason they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Angolan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Heights</ENAMEX> and the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the uh all their buffer area is between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> was just as a buffer but you know as you can see with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the scuds</TIMEX> go right over there
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah they don't really pay a whole lot of attention to buffers
 	
 	
 		yeah there's there's very little that that buys you anymore in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s technology
 	
 	
 		i knew a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> when they were sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> that said that's the safest place in the world because if a war starts all the bombs are going to go right over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and they're going to land in other places you know that's going to be the safest place to be  yeah
 	
 	
 		that's probably very true very that's very interesting never thought of that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well uh i i guess
 		what they'd have to do to uh
 		i really don't know you know in in the uh in you know i hope that what's happening is exactly the way it appears you know some reason or other
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know is is uh it's kind of a strange thing we've been trying to make something like this happen for so long that when it finally happens you say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whoa</ENAMEX> wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a minute</TIMEX> you know what's uh what's what's really happening here
 	
 	
 		nobody knows to do
 		is it real
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you wonder how well this thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX> who was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">it Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that's running the uh or evidently was elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> which is i guess the
 	
 	
 		right  exactly
 	
 	
 		uh the biggest
 	
 	
 		i get confused between all the which is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">provinces</ENAMEX> versus what are the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">provinces</ENAMEX> versus what are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> but you got uh the the great big area that's just was traditionally known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
 		and then all these little nationality <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> around it you know that were you know was there nineteen of them or or whatever you know and these were all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> autonomists
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they had some real fancy names for them a matter of fact when the uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah what i read when the uh the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> was setup in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> one of the first things the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> wanted to do was bring in each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the uh
 		of these
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">republics</ENAMEX> as a separate country you know so there'd be there'd be nineteen rather than one
 	
 	
 		oh as a as a vote
 		sure sure
 	
 	
 		and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> said well that'd mean we get to bring in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">forty eight</TIMEX> you know and uh that sort of you know they backed down on that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		died down on that i thought it was interesting that recently here the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Warsaw Pact</ENAMEX> no longer exists as a militory military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> but it's merely an economic now
 	
 	
 		yeah well i wonder if that  whether uh whether whether get shot by something that's called uh an economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> or whether it's called a military pact you know it's all you can change the name of something but i wonder if it's still
 	
 	
 		well yeah i mean at yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		exists although i've seen some evidence that you know the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well  the funny thing there is they're not particularly welcome back home because there's they're having a housing shortages now what do you do with all these
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> that have been taken care of by uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bulgaria</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX> and now all of a sudden they're going home and somebody's got to pay for their
 	
 	
 		exactly and and all the
 		well that's what they're saying the whole problem you know with if we were to demilitarize <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>  what are we going to do with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> over there
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's not
 	
 	
 		what's going to happen to the economies that are no longer have uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million</NUMEX> plus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the industry you know in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	