
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay i guess we're on the air now
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh i haven't had too much experience with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>
 		i've uh served on a jury <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and uh i think one of my concerns after that experience was
 		uh finding that there tend to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that can't bring themselves to sentence someone
 	
 	
 		yes i i have my primary experience has been as uh an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert witness</ENAMEX> and and uh and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> murder trials
 	
 	
 		
  
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh in each case it was a retrial and the sentencing was the same each time which happened in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> happened to be uh death
 		but in terms of i well the question also was in terms of mandatory sentencing or mandatory sentences for uh certain crimes
 		i think
 		depending on uh in certain crimes i think that they should be mandatory
 		for example uh armed robbery
 		uh if we have convicted i think uh plea bargaining should should be uh a thing of the past
 		um
 		certain types of uh
 		you know homicides
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm inclined to agree you do need a uh fixed and clear sentence there
 	
 	
 		yes in in homicides related to other than i guess what are called uh crimes of passion uh for example you know as you as you very well know
 		the great majority of homicides are
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> murdering other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they know mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so in those instances uh that's uh i think that there is some leeway there what was is interesting in this regard is the recent case in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolteacher</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the life sentence uh she received
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that was a logical decision there
 	
 	
 		yes
 		and it came very quickly surprisingly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i guess it was uh they brought in their verdict and sentence at the same time did they not
 	
 	
 		well well yeah i think they went back for a brief hearing on the sentence
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but that was that was fairly quick i think that is something that we need in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i know the last time i was down in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>
 		uh we had visited the island of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Thomas</ENAMEX> which is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 		and there were <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX> unsolved murders and nobody seem to be concerned about it
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		at the same time there was one unsolved murder on the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tortola</ENAMEX> and the whole island wanted to know when the hanging was going to take place
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well in answer to you know answer to the question though i still think the sentencing should be in the hands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> even though as you say there are some
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are reluctant i do not think again in the matter of uh uh that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> should have the
 		uh
 		the upper hand or the only hand in that sense because i think if but i i've never served on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> you probably know this better than i um
 		if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> does their job and of course there are those on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that do not i'm sure but and ask the questions and
 		uh correctly and then one of things i've always wondered is uh the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> to to ask questions
 	
 	
 		i've never uh really been sure that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> is entitled to ask a question
 	
 	
 		well that that that and that's an interesting point i've never i you know i've thought about it i've asked myself you know this question before
 		i've never taken the time to do the research to answer my own question but i know that at least during the deliberations of the jury
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they can ask questions
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i don't know whether they can go back and call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> for that though it's it depends on the the transcript they can ask uh points of order of law
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and maybe they can ask for a review of the transcript
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh but uh asking questions during the trial my experience as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> uh well it was a traffic situation uh there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> points of law that had to be made
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> did not make the points
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> took the stand on his own behalf
 		unfortunately  he made the points himself in his own testimony
 	
 	
 		um-hum  may i ask you a question
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		why does your voice sound familiar to me
 	
 	
 		um
 		i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E Systems</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's  that's
 		probably why it does i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		your your voice you know when uh i didn't recognize the name but the more i listen to your voice i
 		uh i know i have heard it somewhere
 		and i was trying to place where i had heard it that's very interesting but now back to the topic
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh because i work for
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Hal Ammon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hal Ammon</ENAMEX> quite well
 	
 	
 		yes i am on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hal Ammon</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so
 	
 	
 		well say hi to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al or Hal</ENAMEX> the next time you see him
 	
 	
 		i
 		i will and which will probably be the uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> as a matter of fact
 	
 	
 		and tell
 		yeah well tell him that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Mayhood sell hi</ENAMEX> said hi
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Bill</ENAMEX> i recognize the name now i and uh my name is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim Moscow</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and uh so i've heard the name
 		and uh well back to the topic i guess we've talked long enough Bill
 	
 	
 		
 
 		all right
 	
 	
 		but uh all right well thank you for calling and nice and have a good weekend
 	
 	
 		thank you good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">good-bye</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	