
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and foremost my immediate fix for the federal budget would be a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> percent straight across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> cut in federal spending in all departments
 	
 	
 		now dealing on the federal level
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> percent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> percent is a good choice but to as far as to increase tax revenues coming in you need to a redesigning of the entire tax structure itself corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is getting away with bloody murder
 		where as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out here are having to pay such a high amount of their actual bring home salaries into taxes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are getting off easy because they're actually paying in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than five</TIMEX> percent of their gross national product
 		or their or their
 	
 	
 		gross national product or profit okay
 	
 	
 		profit rather
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm not knowledgeable in that area so i can only agree with what you're saying
 	
 	
 		if they made it straight across the board everybody pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> percent
 		if their gross
 		national profit
 		was
 		say <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX> then pay <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five five percent</NUMEX> of that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		seems fair to me  also individual level
 	
 	
 		but the um
 		overall it just seem like they've modified the tax laws so bad just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five years</TIMEX> the rich is it's definitely case that the rich are getting richer and the working people
 		middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and
 		you know the lower middle class and the upper middle class are having to carry the entire burden
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i am awfully bored with uh every
 		every tax change uh supposedly having all these built in benefits for the poor because
 		i think we have such a mismanagement of the funds that are designated for the poor so much graft
 		and so much misspending that that money doesn't necessarily go where it's supposed to go
 		uh i know you don't ever cutout greed and corruption but i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of the
 		welfare dollar needs to come back to to the local levels because the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know exactly who needs that money and who doesn't need that money when it's directed from afar
 		i think the chance for misspending is greater
 		i i suppose i'm thinking more in terms i i'm not thinking in terms of increasing taxes i'm just thinking for a quick fix
 		uh a cut in federal spending is i guess my solution
 	
 	
 		as long as you got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> that are getting kickbacks
 		kickbacks from these different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that are getting awarded for the defense contracts that's never going to happen
 	
 	
 		i know  that's well maybe that's what i'm saying as long as greed and corruption is in there how do we get away from that though
 	
 	
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing that i
 		had thought about
 		to help correct that problem you've got career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> that spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty forty years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> that's all they have ever done
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		after they've been there that long they're so deep rooted with their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> network
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think by limiting the number of consecutive terms a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> can hold whether it be a state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> or at the national level limiting the two terms and then they've got to sit out one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i think that's wonderful when do we first when do we then start giving them their lifetime income as a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't think we should ever give them a lifetime income
 	
 	
 		but we do don't we
 	
 	
 		unfortunately
 	
 	
 		yes i know many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have said well if you throw everyone out and start over but then you
 		uh the the amount of them who would be on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX> income is so stupendous there's they have locked their benefits in to the point that once they've served <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> terms they're on gravy train anyway
 		yes i think you're right i don't think we should ever give them a lifetime thing
 	
 	
 		and they're the ones that have screamed so much much much about
 		that don't want to increase taxes and they don't want to do this but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> they vote themselves in a very healthy pay raise
 	
 	
 		it they don't they speak with fork and tongue don't they
 		at least we're in agreement on that aren't we  i'm afraid i have no other thoughts on fixes and i'm not really sure that they would accept our suggestions anyhow
 	
 	
 		i think eventually it's going get to the point where
 		there's going to be a majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have had enough of what it's
 		finally come to we're
 		you getting so far down to where
 		you're being taxed so far down where you can't even afford to change your mind
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's going to come to a point where the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> say we've had enough
 	
 	
 		how do they react then
 		we're prosecuted if we simply don't pay our taxes so i'm not real sure how you believe then that eventually there'll be an overthrow
 		we know communism doesn't work what do we do next
 	
 	
 		well in the form of capitalism that we've got apparently that's not working real good either
 	
 	
 		uh i heard uh someone uh supposedly an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> saying speaking on TV saying that the interest rate as we have known it in the past will never be the
 		that high again and he was speaking in senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> living on their incomes of from interest CD interest and that sort of interest i think
 		the voting block of senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> is a tremendous voting block too but every voting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> is
 		slapped and toward their own special interest and i think that makes it doubly difficult to make a change i guess i'm saying we're all selfish
 	
 	
 		maybe not a case of everybody being selfish
 		every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> carry their own fair burden but not somebody else's
 	
 	
 		yes that's true
 		it doesn't seem to workout that way though does it i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> uh
 		are so protecting what they have in the budget that it doesn't seem to work that every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has to pay his own fair share and maybe that's why corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> gets away with what they're doing
 		because of the kickbacks and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera
 		i'm a bit of a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pessimist</ENAMEX> i don't see a change in my lifetime i'm afraid
 		you're younger perhaps you can foresee one
 	
 	
 		i never put anything beyond
 		as far as when it'll happen
 		that i'm not real sure of if it will happen i have no doubt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes i think you're right i'm just saying that i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are at this point rebellious enough that it will happen in my lifetime
 		yes i think eventually the system will change i still think we have the best system
 		uh with the elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> i i'm not sure that uh
 		it's working right now though
 	
 	
 		it is the best system that's out there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> but it does need some fine tuning at this point
 	
 	
 		absolutely  nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		okay nice talking to you bye
 	
 	
 		bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	