
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i kind of like mysteries like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agatha Christie</ENAMEX> and that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agatha Christie</ENAMEX> how about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D McDonald uh John D McDonald</ENAMEX> you ever read him
 	
 	
 		no i'd actually i plead my ignorance knowledge lack of knowledge i'm not familiar with him what is he is he an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah he's very he uh of course he he's dead now seems like most of the good ones are
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i know they don't write anything like they used to the classics
 	
 	
 		but uh he he was he does quite involved mysteries <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D McDonald</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and have you been reading him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		since well way back in high school
 	
 	
 		that long  we won't talk about that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah that's  matter fact that's one of my favorite hobbies is uh reading
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i'm that's one of mine my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s a little more inclined toward that but i'm not real uh interested in self-improvement books at all i think everything's too topical nowadays
 	
 	
 		yep for when i read i read for enjoyment or escapism and i
 	
 	
 		yeah and i like a lot of things that are uh have to do with politics and uh history there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Palace</ENAMEX> about what goes on at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		did you read are you do you interested in stuff like that or
 	
 	
 		well i have i have i have been in the military so i'm well aware of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Palace</ENAMEX> yes
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		then you probably know even more than i do
 	
 	
 		yeah it it was quite it was quite amusing i used to i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Viet Nam</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> plus extension
 	
 	
 		and i don't know have there been any good books books published on that i know <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> two my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was a uh paratrooper in airborne <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred and one</NUMEX> um but i don't think they have done anything good on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Viet Nam</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		they've got several out uh
 		there's one called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy House</ENAMEX> by uh Profit that's quite good i was involved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> program and stuff of that that nature
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and is it true i mean is it um
 	
 	
 		it's fairly facts whoever he talked to knew what uh the had had been in the program uh  it was probably factual he's kind of overdone a lot of it but um but you have to do that to make the books
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i i kind of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> is um i've i'm interested in law and uh i just got a book for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Law</ENAMEX> and Order it's the history of the justice system and tracks um the the history of uh crimes and of
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		things that have impacted just the the you know evolution of um how we punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and why things are um judged the way they are
 	
 	
 		um i hadn't heard that one i hadn't uh
 		got too heavy into law and order deal most of mine i'm afraid i go either mysteries or uh
 		action adventure stuff
 	
 	
 		oh action adventure i probably
 		you're not talking your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle Steele</ENAMEX> female by any means but on the other hand i won't uh i can't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Sheldon</ENAMEX>'s does come off the shelf  for light reading
 	
 	
 		
 
 		he's uh i read those uh actually i think my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> really right now is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Johnstone</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he writes the uh  action series
 	
 	
 		um-hum i've heard again i'm not familiar with reading him but i've heard of him
 	
 	
 		he's got about twelve out now and it starts out with uh you know after the big war and everything's blown up and he then he's kind of
 		
 
 	
 	
 		a real positive
 	
 	
 		yeah it's kind of it follows his his travels throughout the world
 	
 	
 		there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a book i just got i got it as a gift and i just started it's a little bit heavy but it was kind of interesting it um was on the best seller list for a while there it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Closing of the American Mind</ENAMEX> a little bit heavy about political philosophy
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		those i those i can read for a while but i got to stop and go you know walk around something
 	
 	
 		that's kind of what's happened it kind of does happen yeah uh i'm trying to think of any self-improvement books i've read
 	
 	
 		i've tried to do some of those but after after after after after i read them a while i thought maybe i don't need improvement that bad after all
 	
 	
 		yeah that's exactly right it's kind of like all the talk shows i think i got to get
 	
 	
 		they kind of drag on did you read that one uh let's see uh
 		that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> wrote that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdul</ENAMEX> is going to come uh
 	
 	
 		oh um no i didn't but i i i have it and i haven't read it
 	
 	
 		yeah we got at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> to drive into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and almost buy it undercover at the time they were doing it
 	
 	
 		that's exactly what happened to us we were living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">um</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> at the time and we were getting ready to come back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> um
 		and
 		i went i mean into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waldon's</ENAMEX> and stood in line for like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six hours</TIMEX> it seemed like but i haven't read it there is a good one out though that we've had for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> that i've actually read more than once it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Kingdom of Sound</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah okay
 	
 	
 		and it is really really good about the um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saudis</ENAMEX> and just tracking their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabian</ENAMEX> culture
 	
 	
 		i've read that i got uh i got the interested in when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> came to power i got interested in him and started reading some of his some of the books on him the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		it's well written actually
 		and i think there're going to be more huh
 	
 	
 		oh yes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s just probably totally insane
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's too bad that's not the topic i know self-improvement i think is the only one i got something like that when i got i'd been out of school for quite a while i think um back when it was again real topical um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> my age about then were maybe having trouble with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine bought me something called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Mother and Myself</ENAMEX> and i tried to read it and i went
 		this is i did the same thing i went this isn't anything
 	
 	
 		have you read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Clancy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah
 		yeah in fact i just started her a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of ours turned me on to that i always i always looked at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> novels and i went eh
 		military stuff just never really did anything to me unless it was history
 	
 	
 		which one did you get
 	
 	
 		the um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> the red the the i think it was the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> you'll have to help me out here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt Hunt</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red October</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> the one i went to see the movie for
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that was good uh he's got
 	
 	
 		i was a little bit bored with it compared to some of the other stuff that i've heard he'd done
 	
 	
 		he's uh that's one of the better ones uh i've got i think my favorite that he's done is is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Clear and Present Danger</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes that one i've we actually have that one my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s read that it that one seems like it might be a little more interesting
 	
 	
 		it's pretty factual he's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> out i'm trying to remember what it's called it has to do with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh boy
 	
 	
 		and i started in reading it a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend friend</ENAMEX> of mine whose a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> gave it to me he said uh he said it's a wonderful book you'll love it i started reading it and he went of course he goes into such great detail
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-hu h</ENAMEX>
 		that's what i i was impressed with how much documenting he does
 	
 	
 		you know and i
 		and it lost me
 	
 	
 		how much how much um he's so much like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michener</ENAMEX> he's not as bad in terms of going into so much depth but he he's i like the way he writes
 		and if it's not something that moves with me in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> chapters something like that i just won't keep it you know
 	
 	
 		i can't uh i can't stay with it too long either but that  that i i read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about fifty</NUMEX> pages and then i just said i can't take it
 	
 	
 		that's
 	
 	
 		i just i can't keep all these buttons you know knobs and dials and gauges that are supposed to mean anything i don't want to i can't understand them
 	
 	
 		and his action anecdotes weren't very good at all he he had he jumps around he in that particular book i don't know how his other ones are but in that one he jumped around a little bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subways</ENAMEX> and just just the general transition and i mean it i didn't you know i really you have to be interested in the subject too i think that was part of my problem
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah it's there was just too much detail there for the for the neophyte
 	
 	
 		anything to be real interesting yeah well it's good to talk to somebody i don't read as much as i used to um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIer</ENAMEX> and i'm in journalism so i do a lot of writing um during the normal course of my job and it's kind of um
 		sad when you find out the you know i thought i would get more toward reading and i'm getting less
 	
 	
 		yeah it's well there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> out now though of course i've got several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> that i collect uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Van Lustbader Lustbader</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		any of all years
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he's got several out that i like
 		and uh matter fact
 	
 	
 		and what line does he write under what title does he
 	
 	
 		he's got uh he's kind of um
 		mystic oriental
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		he has one called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Ninja</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael The Siren Black Heart</ENAMEX>
 		then there's uh yeah i think uh i think you'll enjoy him
 	
 	
 		oh that might be kind of interesting is it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh The Ninja</ENAMEX> is of course The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ninja</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> are you know one and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the volumes and then he went off and wrote uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gem Zero and The French Kiss</ENAMEX> and several others and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The White Ninja</ENAMEX> has just hit paperback i understand
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and does he uh in terms of their in terms of their practices and and their culture i mean does he document it or is it strictly
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh no he no he's he's heavy into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> culture
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		he's heavy into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> culture uh along with uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ninja</ENAMEX> the arts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ninja</ENAMEX> and all all the various uh martial arts
 	
 	
 		does he tell it in narrative form or in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> how does he present it
 	
 	
 		it's uh it fluctuates you kind of get flashbacks uh you get some flashbacks but you can really tell it's a flashback because the print goes to italic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and then you still get information too
 	
 	
 		and then you get information too and it's kind of in a flashback and it it's told uh more or less <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> singular
 	
 	
 		and what's his name again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Van Lustbader</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Lustbader</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		yeah spelled as you would expect
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it it's you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van</ENAMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lustbader B A D E R</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Lustbader i'm going to write that one down yeah because
 	
 	
 		he's he's very interesting i think i think you'll enjoy him
 	
 	
 		looking for something different yeah it's you know you walk into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and you just like you said you're overwhelmed by how much there is and you just i don't know if you're like me you you you're much more voracious in terms of how much reading you're doing obviously but i go in and i like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to me it's like being in a bakery but then i just don't find anything i like i pick up like eighteen things and then i'm not sure so i walk out
 	
 	
 		do you like do you like kind of like the historical western or something of that nature
 	
 	
 		uh no that's more no that's not i do actually i like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> cultures  that why i was that's funny that you mentioned that
 	
 	
 		uh you'll then you'll like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Leary</ENAMEX> he's he's he's quite good at it i've got into one that i didn't think i would it's a i'm not it's a kind of a historical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> novel thing by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Colesmith</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		called The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Trail</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> Bit and it's called The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> Bit Saga
 	
 	
 		i thought that was uh do you like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michener</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he's good did you ever read he wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i read that one uh-huh
 	
 	
 		that was good and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> yeah and i've done some of those yeah i like i like things that are those are a few of the ones i can take of his i like it when they actually are giving you information in a novel format i guess would be the
 	
 	
 		you might try Colesmith try and find his uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> Bit Saga it's called the it's called The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Trail</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> Bit is the first yeah by by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Colesmith</ENAMEX> he's a he's a
 	
 	
 		Trail of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> Bit okay
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Emporia Kansas</ENAMEX> and uh he he's been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and a gunsmith and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		all kinds of stuff and uh he he writes it's history from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> point of view starting back when they first got the horse when they first captured the Spaniards
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it just kind of follows forward and i got i got hooked on it and there's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about sixteen</TIMEX> or eighteen
 		
 		
 	