
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what do you think about um
 		the way the criminal justice system handles trials
 	
 	
 		well you know they tell you that you get tried by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of your peers
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you know it's pretty hard to try let's say
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> that's living on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> or somebody that's on a limited income
 		to be tried by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> if most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> that i've served on are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay now they don't understand that you know maybe he needed fifty dollars so he held up the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven eleven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay they don't understand that because they have fifty dollars all the time so you know i think that it a a trial by your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> should be exactly that someone in your own age bracket someone that you know you can't really do it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		ethnically you know but you could do it you could probably get it a little closer but then there's another thing that i disagree with in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is sometimes you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and sometimes you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of twelve
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i don't know why they do that do you have any reason do you know of any reason why they do that
 	
 	
 		well i think the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> is called a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Jury</ENAMEX> and that's mostly to decide whether or not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s actually going to stand trial or it's whether they're acquitted or whether they're actually going to be accused of
 	
 	
 		okay i see
 	
 	
 		you know and held over for trial
 	
 	
 		okay
 		i don't know much about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Jury</ENAMEX> how do you feel about the in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i noticed since i've been here in twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that they they break up the the trial and then the sentencing part of the trial
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know i i think that uh i know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> aren't supposed to be crooked however
 	
 	
 		well we know there's a few out there
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems like if you break the sentencing away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and give it you give it to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you're letting there be a whole lot more of an opportunity for something to either go wrong
 		or for you know if if if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> is not of high moral standards he could be bought off at much easier than twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it's
 		yeah would be pretty hard well i don't think you know i don't think that
 		if i was the criminal that i would like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> passing sentence on me if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> found me guilty then they should be able to decide at the same time what my punishment should be
 		and i think it's not only that it's a waste of our money we have to have a trial for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> down the road we have to sentence sentence
 		excuse me set a sentencing date so now we're back in court again and that's more money spent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it's not so much that i that
 		i haven't seen a lot of really bad sentences passed either by trials or by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> what bothers me is that uh they really don't mean anything
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		someone could be sentenced to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five years</TIMEX> and yet you know the the parole system uh it's going to let them out in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> for good behavior
 	
 	
 		and it's not working either
 	
 	
 		no it's not
 	
 	
 		it seems that we have more and more repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> i know i don't know how you all are there where you're at but where we're at now our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> are overcrowded we just built a brand new one <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i think they're all overcrowded
 	
 	
 		and it's overcrowded
 	
 	
 		they've uh i think i heard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> that uh
 	
 	
 		so now they start turning them loose
 	
 	
 		they've been ordered to do something because their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> is so overcrowded they're not allowed to accept any new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> now what are they supposed to do
 	
 	
 		they turn them loose
 	
 	
 		well no i mean they're not allowed to accept any new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so what are they supposed to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that they need to put in jail you know
 	
 	
 		well the way it it seems the way it's been working here's
 	
 	
 		there
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		go ahead
 		it seems the way it's been working here is they let those out that have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years</TIMEX> out of their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five to twenty</TIMEX> sentence or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> to life
 	
 	
 		um-hum something that is working and i i i really like the system of house arrest
 		where uh a someone's wear someone wears a bracelet
 	
 	
 		yeah they
 		yeah and they
 	
 	
 		like a ankle bracelet that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitor</ENAMEX> and they are not allowed i mean the some of them are even allowed to work they can go to their regular job they come home they have to be home by such and such a time
 	
 	
 		they keep
 	
 	
 		they're instructed uh
 		so that this this electronic monitor is turned on at at a certain time and it connects them up to a system where they know their whereabouts
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		all right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		they can put a they usually install a video monitor in the house
 		and when the parole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> calls to check on them they're instructed to turn it on and stand in front of it
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		so that they can see that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is actually at home in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> doing what they're supposed to be doing and that's working rather well that's a good system that allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to actually continue to be productive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of society while
 	
 	
 		yeah it would allow the
 	
 	
 		they're
 	
 	
 		yeah instead of being completely penned up
 	
 	
 		you know paying back for whatever crime they've committed
 	
 	
 		and that way it would give you know the probation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and parole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> they've got to be overloaded with as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> as we have here in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and that would give you know at least they don't have to drive all over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> trying to find one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> or trying to see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six or seven</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum i've i've really i could go on for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> about the criminal justice system and what i think we ought to do about it but
 	
 	
 		sometimes it's pretty messed up isn't it
 	
 	
 		well something that i really don't understand is when someone goes to jail
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they have a job in jail and they work
 		that they should i and this may sound cruel but i do not think that they should be allowed cigarettes
 		i mean they're in jail for crying out loud what do they need cigarettes for
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well see and there's another thing about the justice system that i don't like and there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that tell me that that maybe my thoughts are wrong i came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when you're in jail they take you out just like they do in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> or anywhere else in what they call a chain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> and they clean the city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i think that's a wonderful idea
 	
 	
 		and they clean the city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> but you know we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> that do nothing but sit on their duff all day
 		and here it costs us seventeen to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eighteen thousand dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to support a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> and i know yeah but i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> myself that have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> that don't make that much
 	
 	
 		more than that more than that
 		i know
 	
 	
 		and they're not you know they're not doing anything to support themselves while they're there
 	
 	
 		the thing that the thing that gets me is that while we're supporting them they're working when they get out of jail they get handed all that money
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that really ti cks me off i think that while they are in jail and they are working their wages
 		should go like i don't know they could uh some percentage like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX> percent of their wages should go toward their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and board
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		figured on um a whatever basis how much it costs to actually support them for a year
 	
 	
 		um-hum see now i also believe in
 	
 	
 		and when they get out they should have uh i don't know you know some reasonable amount of money
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to start like a couple of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> but there should be a limit over which they that it all goes back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> anything that they've earned while they're in prison
 		should go back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> except for that you know there needs to be some allowance for when someone gets out that they have some money to start with
 	
 	
 		yeah to help
 		yeah but at least they would at least that way they would be helping pay for their own
 	
 	
 		exactly absolutely that's the part that i really think we need to change
 	
 	
 		and something else that i would
 		and something else that i would like to see is is uh victim reimbursement
 		you know because they you know like you say these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are in jail and they're working they're getting paid but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that they messed over to get there or they stole something from or beat to death or has nothing you know our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> are victimized period and the law has no
 	
 	
 		has nothing right
 	
 	
 		no uh
 		regulations to deal with that they they know how to deal with the penal system and they know how to deal with the criminal but they don't know how to deal with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> because we as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> i guess haven't laid anything up there for them to deal with on that aspect
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it's
 		but i sure don't i i strongly disagree with any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> passing sentence on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> himself there that
 	
 	
 		um-hum i think it works much better if it's if it's the actual jury
 	
 	
 		yeah because well the see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> is dealing with the seriousness of the crime the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> gets to see the whole trial as does the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> but you know if if they figure there's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe litigating circumstances or something like that whereas maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> does just doesn't care you committed this crime so i'm just going to throw the book at you whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> may have a little
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		shall we say sympathy you know he did this but you know why did he do this is there is there a basis for it
 	
 	
 		yeah in some cases that it it would work that way in some cases it would work the other way
 	
 	
 		yeah in some cases where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> says okay i'll give you you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two to three years</TIMEX> and then
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> would would slam them and and i think that that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> probably has more of a right to sentence than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well they have a stronger debate too because there's twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there they have to decide whether or not he's guilty and then they can sit in the at the same time and decide what his punishment would be and you'd have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s input on it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i think that's probably a much fairer way
 	
 	
 		and you know we're supposed to be and i quote in a democratic society so you know if you can find me guilty then you ought to be able to pass sentence
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> not that i know of but you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> may just sit there and say yeah he's guilty but i don't have to deal with it from here
 		you know so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> takes care of all of that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it might be more it may would be more work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> but it would be a more responsible way to deal with it
 	
 	
 		yeah it would uh serving yeah serving on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> would be definitely more responsible you'd have to be a definitely more responsible person
 	
 	
 		the thing that i i don't really like i i don't know if uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> selection processes that i've seen have been a
 		
 		
 	