
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX> what do you think um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that
 	
 	
 		well i'm more more interested in the long-term effects than the short-term effects in terms of uh balancing budget and so forth um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i tend to view um and i i take a fairly radical view towards economic policy and feel that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well it has to be done somewhat arbitrarily at uh on in some uh instances i think that um goods should cost um real total costs rather than just manufacturing costs
 		and that means uh if you oh produce something that creates uh uh adverse health effects that should somehow be reflected in the product if you uh the cost of
 		forestry that you cut down and such needs to be uh reflected
 	
 	
 		so you think that they that those products should cost more
 	
 	
 		in
 		well i think i think my long-term sense of of budget <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> is that we're going is
 		a lot of others <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s spending goes on goes towards this uh health care and things like that and a lot of causes of poor health or need for health care are
 		brought about by various factors such as such as pollution stress you know work work environment conditions and so forth but generally the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		government or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> end up paying for that rather than the uh some of the source of need for the health care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but that's a very long-term sort of concern
 		um i don't i don't have great short-term effects other than reducing spending and raising taxes and no one likes the idea of raising taxes very much and uh
 		no one likes the idea of reducing spending very much so i don't see any real uh real immediate hope i mean it's the whole quota's living on debt i mean but and they buy things on credits constantly
 	
 	
 		wow um-hum well do they i mean um i never liked doing that and i i didn't up until uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> when it came down to the point of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you you don't have a choice you know if you if you need to have a car then you have no choice and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah well exactly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it it gets even worse when you think about trying to do things like buy a house
 	
 	
 		yes well i  i don't know anyone who paid cash for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that's for sure yeah you don't have much um i
 	
 	
 		really i mean  so what choice do you have then
 	
 	
 		i mean it seems to me one might have choices if one radically restructured the system but that's not really a possibility at this point it has it's own inertia and
 	
 	
 		yeah i did it's just that uh
 		there needs to be some some change take place so that the inertia can begin to go in a different direction and strike down
 	
 	
 		yeah i hope so
 	
 	
 		you know that's the problem that i think we have
 	
 	
 		yeah well i'm i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> and actually i'm in the job market now trying to get a professorship and i'm watching uh the education budget getting cut
 		back so severely um at least in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> where i am where there's a very severe budget crisis because of agriculture was wiped out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and um a number of other things and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because i'm i i have a lot of i have some personal investments in this uh in addition to whatever philosophical investment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there is and i don't know it's amazing that in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> we've gone from a uh a major loaning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> to a major debt nation
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in the in the course of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> um we are  a lot has changed more radically
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		well we were we were in debt before that it just wasn't as apparent
 	
 	
 		yeah it was it's it's uh seems to have worsened considerably
 	
 	
 		somehow we still
 		i guess believed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that we were helping were were eventually going to pay us back
 		and that hasn't happened
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum yeah well uh i can see you know it's it's it's
 		it's kind of funny because we it seems like we loan money you know we money with strings attached and if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> changes and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that we loan the money to
 		um i can see why the might have a different attitude towards paying it back it's a lot us that  you know we don't really loan money to to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> we loan money to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and it's the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's true i hadn't thought of it that way i think
 	
 	
 		and it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> should that that's really what we do you don't go up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or the chair or whatever of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and you loan it to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are representing the government
 		and by extension representing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but when those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are gone and you have some new
 		you know starving <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with a brand new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that threw the previous rascals out um
 		they're personal incentive for repaying that debt is understandably low  because it's they didn't they didn't borrow i mean you know it would be like you paying off the debts of uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> of yours you wouldn't feel very happy about it
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		um
 		so it's a sort of like this is uh  i see a
 		i don't know there's if there's a metaphor going on who are we loaning the money to and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can disagree about who that money is being loaned to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah in some in some cases it uh i think it's actually going to you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that it's intended for in other cases
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and this is all based and this is all up to actually the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that's in control now in some cases the the money actually does filter down to the to where it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		supposed to get to and in other cases it it does not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i i tend to get a little upset about loans to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to obviously corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there a number of them for political reasons because we're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> of the neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or something like that so we give them an either corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> anyway but it's hard to view that so much as a loan as a bribe at that point
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i don't really have a good solution for the budget thing either except for that um i know that they're trying to be they're that they're supposedly trying to be fair with taxes and by making it more equal
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but
 		i can't really understand why
 		um it has to be the same percentage where you have someone that makes
 		um a very low amount of money the same percentage may affect them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> times more severely than the same percentage
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of someone's well if if they earn a great deal of money and i would being somewhere in the middle feel like that it would be a lot more fair to have a little more heavily weighted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		toward the top end if i i can put my you know i think to myself if i had that much money
 	
 	
 		you could afford to pay more taxes
 	
 	
 		i could afford to pay more taxes it wouldn't bother me a bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum um-hum well boy uh i mean i completely agree with you um on
 		the stress that the tax burden for the upper class has actually decreased over the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah they used to have and what do they i don't know what the percentage is now they used to be taxed thirty percent
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's
 	
 	
 		and i remember hearing an interview with uh who was it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who invented <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> Tropic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and he he was talking about that he was talking about nobody went broke over paying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> pays the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> pays less taxes than almost every industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>  um
 	
 	
 		you know
 		well that's
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they they get well it it depends on how you look at that because like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> they pay a lot in taxes but their day care is government subsidized
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah they
 		they get things that they pay for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who want to stay home with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are subsidized to do that they don't have to live um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hand to mouth because it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> there and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> there has placed a very significant value on motherhood
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i think that's um well i think that's an important thing personally um
 	
 	
 		um-hum i think we could learn some things from and the and the health care system you may pay more in taxes but your health care is taken care of and you don't have the corruption and in uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well they
 	
 	
 		medicine that that we have here with the the outrageous charges and
 	
 	
 		yeah i think the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> that i know who are are are sort of antitax a lot of them seem antitax because they're distrustful of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will spend their money wisely
 		and the sense is i can spend the money on myself if i gave it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> they would just waste it
 		seems to be an an an attitude i hear is a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i think you hear that attitude you if you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> you won't hear that as much <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will say well we need those services and we're it makes our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> great so we will are more willing to pay for it uh
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yeah
 		yeah i think that if we could model
 		you know programs after those that are already i mean they did a lot of work finding a program that worked and if we were to do the research take under advisement what they have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		already working and adapt it
 		that that that particular day care system um works very well and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> health plan is probably the best <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in existence today
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well it uh it may not last  once they  i hope it does but it's uh it's uh sad situation part of this this you you hear the phrase creeping socialism
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hum
 	
 	
 		which is uh uh a propaganda phrase used a lot against exactly such types of spending programs and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you usually say creeping socialism to conjure up fears of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> lines in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> um but if you use i mean this creeping
 		
 		
 	