
 
     		
 	
 		and i guess
 	
 	
 		okay um so uh um uh do you have any favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 		i kind of like them all i played for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eighteen years</TIMEX> all all the way through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and then uh kind of hung them up after college but
 	
 	
 		oh i was going to say you played pro ball right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no not quite
 	
 	
 		not quite huh
 	
 	
 		made it yeah made it all the way through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> of college playing ball but
 	
 	
 		well that's pretty good
 	
 	
 		anyway uh being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> you probably like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i'm actually a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> i'm i'm one of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who's actually a
 		die hard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and an avid <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX> hater
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> it the i think it's like one or the other isn't it i mean you either
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's i i i find it very strange um more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> don't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> and real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> don't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> for some reason
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i never found i never quite found a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i've always found a fan you know of of either one or the other and
 		so that of course means that when it comes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American League</ENAMEX> my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		by default because i went to college also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see yeah i i like the uh uh i guess if i had to pick a favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> i'd i
 		anymore uh well as i kind of grew up rooting for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> originally
 	
 	
 		yeah so that that's sort of close enough
 	
 	
 		yeah well we were <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thirty miles</NUMEX> south of them so
 	
 	
 		oh so you were pretty close
 	
 	
 		right yeah right down the river but uh so what are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> going to do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strawberry</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i don't know um there's there's a part of me that says that you know i'm i'm sort of glad <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strawberry</ENAMEX> went away
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know when when he sort of went away i started thinking yeah well he was performing fairly well but he really wasn't worth the baggage you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i think they're okay i think they're you know i think they have enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are
 		who are who are still in their prime you know um i mean certainly if you look at them compared to let's say you know um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just eight years ago</TIMEX> or something they're they're they're they're you know they're sort of in in good standing whereas you know um  i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i certainly don't think that they're the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> anymore
 	
 	
 		uh well i was going to talk to you about that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>  that was that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> that uh they beat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> in uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">extra</NUMEX> innings right
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 		right they were either beat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> in extra innings and then and then they actually won the series by
 		by sort of a sneaky route um against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		when there was the ball that was sort of hit to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buckner</ENAMEX> to Buckner
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i felt real bad about that but hey what can you do
 	
 	
 		hey the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s making <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> he ought to be able to perform right
 	
 	
 		that's right well actually he he he was supposedly um there was there was something wrong with him at the time and i
 	
 	
 		well his knees were bothering him yeah
 	
 	
 		right and i and i understand that and i say hey if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> can't play you don't blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that uh hit it to him you blame the team you know for putting him in
 	
 	
 		yeah for having him out there
 	
 	
 		that's right so
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		so i i i was uh i was also i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX> at the time
 	
 	
 		oh oh boy
 	
 	
 		so i it was actually wonderful because where i was there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> and um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sox</ENAMEX> fans
 	
 	
 		yeah i think we were all pretty much uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astros</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">National National League Championship Series</ENAMEX> but there's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and they they were you know they were they were pretty much without having to say it they were pretty much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> fans
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well i guess they were uh i guess they must have been scared
 	
 	
 		no not really they they were they were pretty much <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> they weren't scared of very much you know
 	
 	
 		after the uh
 		well that's good well yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you don't expect them to be uh much of anything but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> no i know i was born there um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah so i i was i was also born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> so i so i can call myself a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX> although i'm really not
 	
 	
 		okay okay well i'm not to say that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> but these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> were definitely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> and they were from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so i'm kind of hoping i i i guess uh anymore i pretty much pull for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> though they were uh they're they're they're they they have the i think they have the best
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> in the major leagues
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i love going to watch a game in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> it's great
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that that's actually i think that makes something because i think and and and as much as sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> support helps
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it's good to have um
 	
 	
 		the only problem is it's not large enough it only holds about i think they squeezed when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> struck out his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thousandth player</ENAMEX> they they squeezed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about forty thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in there
 	
 	
 		yes it is kind of small
 	
 	
 		yeah so they're they're they have plans i mean the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> tried to move them to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they ended up sticking around in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> and they're going to build a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact not even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> so that's
 	
 	
 		oh that's
 		oh that's great so
 	
 	
 		that's something that we're looking forward to
 	
 	
 		yeah that'll be nice i mean that that i think tends to just keep i think <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> have worked tend to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> happy
 	
 	
 		oh yeah case in point <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		yeah have you seen a game up there
 	
 	
 		uh i haven't been to any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto</ENAMEX> games yet but um
 	
 	
 		oh boy i saw i i was up there on business uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last June</TIMEX> and watched a game in the sky <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> it was just phenomenal that's that's probably the pattern for the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> yeah well i i mean to get up there i mean the the best i've been up here so far you know up in in in up state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX> is uh is um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rochester Red Wings</ENAMEX> game
 	
 	
 		now is is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> where where is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornell University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Cornell</ENAMEX> is in Ithaca
 	
 	
 		Ithaca
 	
 	
 		uh yeah so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX> is about um somewhere uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about two and a half hours</TIMEX> south of south and east of us
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so if you know where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Ontario</ENAMEX> is sort of is uh
 	
 	
 		yeah well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rochester</ENAMEX>'s like right on the shores isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah we're about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> miles south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Ontario</ENAMEX> actually whoever built the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was an idiot in my opinion because they built it they built it far enough from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that it actually couldn't be a port city
 	
 	
 		yeah okay
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um but that
 	
 	
 		uh well they say that from that space needle up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX> you can see the lights of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> on a clear night
 	
 	
 		oh really i never i hadn't actually known that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well um
 		but we have our own um our own triple A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redwings</ENAMEX> which is the uh farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orioles</ENAMEX> so everybody hopes that uh they go all the way around here they're the they're the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah okay
 		yeah
 		those games are fun to watch you you you watch those games
 	
 	
 		oh i yeah i actually we we we make a point of going to a bunch of them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> because they're fun because they're
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		lots of really big you know lots of local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> you know small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> you know um and they'll get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than ten thousand</NUMEX> sometimes you know um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		especially you know and i'll um i'll make a day game or something but they really seem to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um people</ENAMEX> really get into it i mean i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i can't i i again i can't make any predictions about them but i suspect they'll go uh they'll go far
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah we used to like watching my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> lived down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beaumont</ENAMEX> and uh on on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lamar University</ENAMEX> they used to house the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beaumont Golden</ENAMEX> Gators
 		who were a double A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Padres</ENAMEX> i think but uh they they were fun games to watch
 	
 	
 		yeah those those are those are always the i i think those are more fun than major league games sometimes
 	
 	
 		sometimes well there's definitely a lot more hitting
 	
 	
 		yes it's true well
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's one of the advantages of not having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX> who are uh uh you know i guess i guess when you start pitching real well well move them up bam you know there goes the little the uh worst team
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah but um so what
 	
 	
 		so as far as the major league <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> i don't know it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> have been you you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> they they always knock on a door early and then just go into their skid about you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of June</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but they they've got so much young raw talent it's just amazing and then they just haven't been able to put anything together
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well the way i the way i see it is i mean um you know i i can use a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> analogy here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you'll think back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> to when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> were just all this sort of young bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who really were raw talent but weren't very sort of
 		well trained you know back to the you know maybe eighty um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four or or eighty three or or eighty five</NUMEX> you know when they were first when they weren't quite the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that that that they were um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		i that that probably gives the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> a good shot for you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year or next year</TIMEX> i think it you know the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> really sort of has to build itself up
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean they've been
 		they've been young for a while and they're almost almost starting to age a little bit here i just um yeah they they're they're really hurting pitching wise i mean they've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> but you know who knows
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what he'll be able to do he's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> he started having some nagging injuries and
 	
 	
 		right but that that's if if
 	
 	
 		but it'll it'll be interesting to watch i hope to get up there we we usually try to get to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">opening day</TIMEX> game there's several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> from our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> try to go up there
 	
 	
 		oh that must be nice
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i guess we're probably oh maybe a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundred fifty miles</NUMEX> south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well see that isn't too bad  <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no not too bad about it takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about two hours two and a half hours</TIMEX> to get there
 	
 	
 		yeah well it'd take me a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven hours</TIMEX> to get to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shay Stadium</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so so i don't know i don't
 	
 	
 		that's probably because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> you just don't yeah we we've just got a freeway we just get right on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeway</ENAMEX> and just go north
 	
 	
 		yeah well actually we can we can i can take a highway the whole way down but it's still it's um
 	
 	
 		well it's so crowded up there
 	
 	
 		it's it's almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four hundred hours</TIMEX> i mean i mean it it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost four hundred</NUMEX> you know barring traffic it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four hundred hours</TIMEX> i mean i mean <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four hundred miles four hundred</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> right  <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four hundred miles</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		golly
 	
 	
 		barring traffic so it's um it it's uh you know it's it's a heck of a drive we are substantially north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> enough that uh we don't get to go play
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 	
 	
 		too often
 	
 	
 		well i don't know you're you're you're like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> ride from how how far is it across the lake to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada Toronto</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto</ENAMEX>
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only about two hours</TIMEX> yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX> is i mean i i want to go see
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you do you drive there or do you take the ferry or what
 	
 	
 		um i can i've actually i've driven
 		but i've heard about the ferry as well haven't taken it yet though have you taken it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it's a it's a beautiful city
 	
 	
 		yeah um i i really love i i think that's one of the most uh enjoyable things about being up here i'm only up here for school
 	
 	
 		i really like it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i
 	
 	
 		so and then and then you go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> after school
 	
 	
 		uh no probably south maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> actually
 	
 	
 		or New York City
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place</ENAMEX> south and warm i don't i'm not a warm i'm not a big uh i'm not a big uh  cold fan
 	
 	
 		well what what kind of weather are you having right now
 	
 	
 		uh right now we're actually having uh
 		it's getting nice i mean it was in the high fifties <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three and a half weeks ago</TIMEX> we had an ice storm
 	
 	
 		oh boy yeah we've been up in the oh seventies eighties even up in the nineties <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple weeks ago</TIMEX> already
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		we're it's
 	
 	
 		yeah well about that same time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> were falling off ev erywhere and we were actually in a state of emergency for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">golly</ENAMEX> because of the ice
 	
 	
 		okay it didn't make the national national national national news too much which i find really weird
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		but um we were i mean um you know all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> were closed for almost for for over or for for a week
 	
 	
 		golly
 	
 	
 		there were certain parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> where it was illegal to drive
 	
 	
 		huh illegal
 	
 	
 		yeah because they had so many power lines down and so many uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and so many things like that so they were
 		
 		
 	