
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		so what kind of music do you like
 	
 	
 		i like all kinds of music actually
 	
 	
 		yeah that's same here
 	
 	
 		i'm kind of partial to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> western i like that
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		and i like mood music like you know when i'm in the mood for that i like semi-classical
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the real classics i'm not as familiar with as you know the ordinary sounds that you hear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> type of thing
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah that's about that's about all i listen to is the classical stuff we have a we have a really good classical radio station here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's uh gets no money from the state or the feds or anybody it's uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> percent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listener</ENAMEX> supported
 	
 	
 		oh huh
 	
 	
 		and it's a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hour</TIMEX> station
 	
 	
 		oh that's fantastic
 	
 	
 		yeah they they get a lot of support here
 	
 	
 		well we have a similar um radio station here
 		and because of the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i guess being pressured to have advertisers
 		you know a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> have to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> they kind of like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		compromised
 		and they do some of it at like certain <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> but it's not always at a time when you can you know sit down and listen to it so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you you kind of get trapped into listening to whatever there is available type of thing you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's the good thing about them they do no advertising that's it's really nice just music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		we have that on TV we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> public uh broadcasting systems uh channel <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and thirty six</TIMEX>
 		also that are publicly supported and they have excellent programming
 	
 	
 		yeah i like i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yep same thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh PBS</ENAMEX> here you can't get it unless you have cable
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that really upsets me because i won't pay cable prices because there's it's it's useless having cable i think
 	
 	
 		it is it's expensive
 	
 	
 		it's uh it's far too expensive and they don't have anything on there
 	
 	
 		no and the the problem is that they can do it at will you know like up the prices
 		and you're if you have it you just have to pay it
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		you know that's the hard part
 	
 	
 		i've almost given in a couple of times and gotten it every time i get one of those special offers in the mail but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've avoided the temptation so far but i sure do miss <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because they they have lots of good stuff <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Masterpiece Theatre</ENAMEX> and mystery and nature
 	
 	
 		yep
 		see we have cable here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and almost everyone here has cable
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and it it's uh it's good because you don't need the outside antennas with your TV and stuff and it gives you a lot more um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		of the other you know of the widest uh uh television that's available to you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i had cable before i uh came up here
 		and i miss some of it i mean we had pretty good cable where i was but i miss <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discovery Channel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A&E</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's what i like
 		yep right and i love that
 	
 	
 		you know i'm having <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> withdrawal pains
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do you go to the theatre for for music uh
 	
 	
 		every once in a while um
 	
 	
 		have you been to the opera ever
 	
 	
 		uh occasionally down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		yeah it it's it's pretty good
 	
 	
 		i've seen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man of La Mancha</ENAMEX> and uh a few of those you know that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and uh i enjoyed it thoroughly i really did
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 	
 	
 		i've seen a few musicals and i uh go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic City</ENAMEX> once in a while and i always like to catch some shows when i'm there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		especially like when they have special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> and things and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Cage au Faux</ENAMEX> that was excellent
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i been into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> a few times uh i was there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Fourth of July</TIMEX> thing and went out to the um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esplanade</ENAMEX> and listened to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> Pops and
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		well we're <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only about two hours</TIMEX> from there yeah
 	
 	
 		they're good they're really
 		oh really
 		yeah i <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>'s okay i mean i wouldn't want to live there but it's a nice place to visit
 	
 	
 		no
 		right in fact i
 	
 	
 		yeah it's crowded i know that
 	
 	
 		sure is
 	
 	
 		it's murder driving in that place
 	
 	
 		isn't it awful
 	
 	
 		yeah and i always get stuck in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the in the afternoon</TIMEX> traffic
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i i think that the commute to to and from work has to be the worst horror show
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because even the breakdown <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lane</ENAMEX> is used for a passing you know a travel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lane</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's really i think that's a very serious thing you know i'm surprised they haven't had more you know really fatal accidents out there doing that
 	
 	
 		well i tell you the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are driving nowadays i'm surprised we're not killing more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than we are
 	
 	
 		oh i know it's true it's true
 	
 	
 		seems like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> are getting worse and worse every year
 	
 	
 		so what are you majoring in
 	
 	
 		um human factors
 	
 	
 		oh and and what is that
 	
 	
 		that's um well it's sort of difficult to explain it's
 		it's industrial engineering and you look at applications and things from the human from the human factor standpoint how does it interface with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> using it
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		and and
 	
 	
 		yeah we had someone from uh do some ergonomics in our area do you do
 	
 	
 		yeah it that's very similar
 	
 	
 		cover some of that yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah very similar um
 		uh specializing in the computer and you know uh interfacing with computers and software and all that kind of good stuff
 	
 	
 		oh oh oh
 		oh well then this is right up your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> what they're trying
 	
 	
 		yeah this is uh sort of the same sort of thing that's why it's it was the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> who brought this thing in he'd gone to a conference
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		down there and brought this thing up i yeah sure i'll do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		why not
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> wants to give me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> bucks a phone call that's okay
 	
 	
 		sure sure
 	
 	
 		you have to talk to all kinds of neat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all over the place
 	
 	
 		yeah it's true it is in in fact i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine that moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 		she's um an emergency room <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> she does the operating room
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh she's been down there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> and she really loves it
 	
 	
 		where's she at
 	
 	
 		i don't know the city
 	
 	
 		yeah there's
 	
 	
 		all i know is it's down in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> in fact the last time she was up i meant to ask her
 		you know what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> she was in i didn't but she said it's really nice
 	
 	
 		yeah there's not too many not too many big ones around here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no
 	
 	
 		uh matter fact we don't have any big ones
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		after you know after being used to places like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> you come here and you know they <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> is the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and it's small
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what's the population
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Charlotte</ENAMEX> oh what about
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's that's pretty good size though
 	
 	
 		oh it's fairly good size i mean it's it's not it's not small but it's certainly small by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> standards
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		course everything's small consider compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i liked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> too i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> that lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> live there i like
 	
 	
 		they she uh she in fact went from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> then to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> and she really really likes it
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>'s a good city it really is uh you have to get used to that <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton</ENAMEX> picking traffic on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two eighty five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh if you if you miss it at the right time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> then you're okay
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but it always seemed like when i was there i was always finishing i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Duluth</ENAMEX> which is uh north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> well not north it's more east
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh along I eighty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i would always be on the other end of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two eighty five</NUMEX> having to go all the way around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two eighty five</NUMEX> and then onto <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX> to go home and it was always at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i never managed to plan my departure right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>'s something down there
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		oh my God i i swear those  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> going or coming going or coming
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's scary
 	
 	
 		it is it's um
 	
 	
 		it's scary they they rival even uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> on uh departure and arrival uh number of arrivals <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		unbelievable
 		in fact when we went down to visit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time we just sat there and we watched i couldn't believe
 	
 	
 		yeah oh it's a busy it's a busy place and they have amazingly few accidents there
 	
 	
 		the traffic
 		it is
 		i know isn't it
 	
 	
 		amazingly few
 	
 	
 		unreal
 	
 	
 		because uh i mean if you're flying anywhere down here you always go through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> you can't avoid it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's the hub city
 	
 	
 		yep yep
 	
 	
 		and uh God
 	
 	
 		i went there to to visit the Underground when that was you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Underground City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		and i thought that was really neat
 	
 	
 		yeah that's super it's getting even better too
 	
 	
 		that amazing
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah they they just they never stop doing things to it
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		all kinds of good stuff go
 	
 	
 		course i haven't been there in about uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah last well see i left there in uh eighty
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		what was it
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's been it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> for me
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
 		the the growth in that place is phenomenal
 	
 	
 		yeah it just doesn't stop
 	
 	
 		they don't stand still that's for sure
 	
 	
 		i mean it
 	
 	
 		we're having our problems out this way with the banking crisis and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> and all that kind of good stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's starting to effect you know the economy
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		because of uh the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that have their money tied up
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		every place you go you know the
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of years ago</TIMEX> i was thinking about moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> but uh boy i'm glad i didn't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		because it's really going downhill up there
 	
 	
 		it has i don't know what they're going to have to do to boost it but they need to do something quick
 	
 	
 		well you know i i was when when the big boom was going on i was thinking well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> must be an absolute genius
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then i i i really think that all of that was just you know temporary growth and everything to make him look good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential</ENAMEX> election
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because it certainly wasn't sustained
 	
 	
 		sometimes i wonder though if the presidential election isn't what really did everything in
 		because he wasn't really paying attention to business you know
 		you can't do both things well
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah but on the other hand if it if it needed his personal intervention all the time then it wasn't a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		no true but uh
 	
 	
 		you know it should it should have been rolling right along without him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know good a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX> would be able to sit back and not do anything
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		yep that's true
 	
 	
 		hopefully
 	
 	
 		yeah  somebody has to watch the store though you can't really you know without overseeing
 	
 	
 		no that's true and and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX> knows with that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> up there they probably did all kinds of things while he wasn't looking
 	
 	
 		sure sure
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		look at what happened just in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> alone God
 	
 	
 		yeah well you can 't
 	
 	
 		it's mind boggling
 	
 	
 		you can't trust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well it's been interesting talking to you
 	
 	
 		yeah we need we didn't talk too much about music but we had a good conversation
 	
 	
 		but oh yeah right  i hope to hear
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	