
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay so you watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letterman David Letterman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well see our favorite TV show i i i live in a dorm and our favorite TV show is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really yeah that's pretty awesome too i watch it every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> that's hilarious
 	
 	
 		okay well we try it like here they show it like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh serious
 	
 	
 		and then like on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thursdays</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> where the new ones come on
 	
 	
 		oh that's cool
 	
 	
 		but we watch it like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> but i like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late night</TIMEX> we don't watch uh what we do is we stay up until around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one thirty</TIMEX> and then they show the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Twilight Zone</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and so we just stay and watch that
 	
 	
 		Twilight Zone rules man <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twilight</ENAMEX> Zone rules
 	
 	
 		the what
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's all
 	
 	
 		i used i used to live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> owned
 	
 	
 		are you serious
 	
 	
 		yeah it was really it was really
 		oh well it was all full with uh shelves everywhere and we didn't have enough books to fill it up but
 	
 	
 		that's psychedelic
 	
 	
 		but uh so what what do you like why do you like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Letterman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh he just like totally sarcastic and hilarious and i don't know i'm a lot like him in a way so
 	
 	
 		so the
 	
 	
 		and he's got curly hair and so do i so
 	
 	
 		wait did you watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> what he's got what
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">curly</ENAMEX> hair and so do i so hey
 	
 	
 		hey i got long hair wait wait
 	
 	
 		cool how long is it
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> i went into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> asked me to dance all he saw was my hair
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and he goes do you want to dance i turn around and go what
 		he goes do you want to dance i go no no he goes oh oh i'm sorry i go yeah you better be i go you better be so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's hilarious
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but okay so did wait do you watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> yesterday
 	
 	
 		no it with the uh who was on the music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wasn't that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fishbone</ENAMEX> yeah i saw that it was awesome but i didn't see the rest of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no oh you missed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayne</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Wayne's World</ENAMEX> was pretty cool
 	
 	
 		are you serious they're awesome
 	
 	
 		so uh let's see what else uh see like all we do here is like every time we walk in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> we turn on the TV
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		because we don't want to do anything like study or anything so all the all we do is turn like like when i was in high school i used to do like my homework in front of the TV set you know
 	
 	
 		yeah that sucks
 		really uh kind of annoying but that's cool
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		kind of annoying to like in front of TV like trying to do homework you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		trying to write an essay you start talking about you know like
 		In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Living Color</ENAMEX> or something i don't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i i like i i just i just bogused on all my homework so it really didn't matter
 	
 	
 		cool yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BS</ENAMEX> that's the way to do it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i know and i did that all through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and it worked too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		cool yeah works for me
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so uh let's see what else like the news we don't watch because they're boring
 	
 	
 		no unless
 		i watched through the war you know there's only one
 	
 	
 		yeah especially the war i mean it was like i haven't i seen this episode before you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i know i guess they think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't watch TV but i mean if you watch it like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> then it repeats the same thing over and over and over
 	
 	
 		yeah i know
 	
 	
 		it's like oh man
 	
 	
 		and and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> see the the the thing is  like here they just they just give you like local news okay like a house burned down in this little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and were here and i go so what happened worldwide you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's like you know even though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred and fifty thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> died somewhere else they're not going to tell you you know they're going to spend more time on doing a a thing on a on a cross <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> who's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years old</TIMEX> than they are on anything else you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so but uh let's see what else oh we watch like for example uh okay do you watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i haven't seen it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> but i used to
 	
 	
 		okay well i used to hate <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i thought i thought like when it like when i was like in high school and junior high school i used to hate it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but then we started watching it and and like the new ones are pretty cool because because they got like uh like special like especially things that like fuck with your mind
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really
 		oh really that's cool
 	
 	
 		because what happened is  like they have this hologram right where you walk in and you can program and everything looks real and you can touch everything and stuff but it's only a program and it's really great because sometimes it's like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		are you serious oh man
 	
 	
 		the hologram makes up all these things and uh i mean sometimes  sometimes it's funny sometimes it's not but uh you know it's something to pass the time until we do and then and then we watch football
 	
 	
 		that's cool
 		kind of like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pink Floyd</ENAMEX> or something
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">uh yeah basketball</ENAMEX>'s cool but football kind of after a while
 	
 	
 		which basketball
 	
 	
 		which basketball yeah i kind of like college better it's more spirited
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX> or
 		well we got we got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of the ACC going there
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		we got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		cool
 	
 	
 		but i mean the i mean there's nothing to do like for example yesterday
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh they go some some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> goes do you dares want to go to a picnic right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i hear no we're just you know it's like we just woke up we had a hangover and everything you know and so we just woke up and uh we're watching TV and i go no <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> we're just going to dedicate ourselves to watching golf
 	
 	
 		
 
 		golf yeah
 	
 	
 		and bowling you know and everybody was like it was like oh God do you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> really watch that no you know i was like a whole golf tournament it's like for example baseball i hate baseball i mean
 	
 	
 		oh me too
 	
 	
 		somebody told me like that like you can watch <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> and the actual play time that there is is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because by the play time is when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> pitches the ball and it goes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> or when the when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> pitches and it's hit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and that takes like you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five seconds</TIMEX> for the whole play
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		and that's it it i mean maybe a home run could last a little bit longer because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> has to run around all the bases you know but i mean it's it's like that i mean it's was it's just
 		but when i went home that's all like they had on TV so i had to i watched entire games of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> and they're going oh my God and TV in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>'s really bad
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		
 
 		oh really so so why from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argentina</ENAMEX> why'd you come over here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because um i wanted to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		oh that's cool how long did you live there
 	
 	
 		yeah they have better computer science up here than they than they do down there
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so and i also uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> works for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> and we came up here we well we came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seventy six seventy seven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh we lived here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about seven years</TIMEX> then we moved back and so then i said i'm going to move back up there to go to college
 	
 	
 		huh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he goes okay so he goes but do it fast so i did my undergraduate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		that's cool
 		
 
 		oh really awesome
 	
 	
 		so but it's  it's just you know oh well we've been talking for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> that's the only obligation we have
 	
 	
 		that's cool
 		groovy
 	
 	
 		and uh well tell your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> that now he owes you <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> bucks
 	
 	
 		yeah no doubt
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		all right nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		yeah you too
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	