
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so what do you think about it how are we doing in recycling are we
 	
 	
 		well i think we need to do more i i mean i know i need to do more they have programs around where you can reach they uh
 		they come and pick up your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> if you have them bundled up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i have a hard time of being able of separating you know having a place separating my trash and get all the cans from the paper and you know i just haven't gotten that dedicated yet so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and see i do a lot of work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy scouts</ENAMEX> and we try to do a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but there's still a lot more we can do you know i don't recycle my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> myself but i noticed in one of the sales catalogs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> they have a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX>
 		clothes hamper kind of thing that you know you lay your string in then you put your papers in there and tie them all up and bundle them up so i figured i might get me one of those
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because we don't always read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> sometimes it just sits around for a while and then we just chuck it
 	
 	
 		yeah well i don't i don't get the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> but i you know i get it on i try to buy you know the early edition for the coupons you know the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> edition so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but then i just you know bundle it up and put it on the front you know the front walk every you know every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> or every other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		have them pick that up but that's the extent of what i've done i'd like to be able to do more the problem is with a lot of it is you have to go
 		you know it takes a while to drive to these places where you recycle it you know it's not always convenient to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah see and
 		yeah see and here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> everything's so close i can imagine what it's like up there
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm not exactly sure where the you know the can thing is but you know sometimes it's just so seems so much easier just to take it and throw it in the trash and have them pick it up than it is to smash the cans and drive it some place to have them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah see i went out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Payless Cashways</ENAMEX> here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days ago</TIMEX> as a matter of fact and got me one of those little can crushers that i could put on the wall
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then i put me a little <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five gallon</NUMEX> bucket and it's just outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> door so every time we drink a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> or whatever we crush the can and just drop it into the bucket
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do those can crushers work good
 	
 	
 		yeah i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Payless Cashways</ENAMEX> and it's actually metal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's not plastic i didn't want to buy a plastic one
 	
 	
 		yeah because those things i think would just snap you know
 	
 	
 		yeah but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payless Cashways</ENAMEX> has them and they're metal and i don't know what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Payless Cashways</ENAMEX> you have up there but it was only like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> dollars not too bad
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i'd have to check into something like that because i mean we don't drink a whole lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX> around here you know but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know occasionally we have some around but you know for other kind of cans just to it'd probably only take aluminum cans like that don't they
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't yeah i don't think it would crush steel cans it's pretty tough
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so i don't know i don't think you have to to crush the other ones for them to get to take that but
 	
 	
 		no you could probably just you know
 	
 	
 		i need to look into it more you know it's
 		you know it sometimes even with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> they say they'll only take certain types of paper you know they won't take paper that's shiny
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		they won't yeah they won't take any lint free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> or see i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah so does my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		and we do a lot of recycling out there now we recycle all our computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> and our cardboard but that's just now come on board
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know we've been throwing paper out there away for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and we're just now getting on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> to recycling ever since this big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth Day</ENAMEX> thing came out you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i don't know what you know i haven't i'm sure they're probably doing that here some
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm sure they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is doing it pretty well nationwide i'm sure
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i think it's necessary i i like it you know it makes i think it's good that you see these you know like boxes cereal they're now starting to make them you know the packages out of recycled paper and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and i've bought you know i've bought greeting cards that are made out of recycled paper and i think they're just fine
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i bought a i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at work that i bought for one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> there at work it's his birthday we're pretty good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and what it is is a recycled paper bag
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's just got <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Birthday</ENAMEX> printing on it and a cute little phrase inside and it's just a paper bag
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and it's really cute
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i think we're doing better and better all the time i still don't
 	
 	
 		yeah i think we're getting becoming more conscious because we just can't stick everything in landfills any more so
 	
 	
 		no there's not going to be any room shortly
 	
 	
 		no no
 	
 	
 		you know i don't know what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> does about theirs i guess they still ship it out on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">barges</ENAMEX> somewhere
 	
 	
 		yeah it's probably sitting out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">barge</ENAMEX> somewhere
 	
 	
 		yeah so but i think we're getting better at it i think there's quite a bit more we could do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> put that away
 		now
 	
 	
 		but you're right sometimes it does seem like it's more trouble than what it would be worth but
 	
 	
 		yeah i just wish it was a little more convenient convenient to do you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		seems like you're so busy anyway and then that's just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more thing to have to worry about so
 	
 	
 		yeah it sure is
 	
 	
 		i think if you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> locally you know they'd get more programs going so that you could do that it'd make it a lot easier so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well they'll get at it sooner i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> will get into it too sooner or later they
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> interested in it too so
 	
 	
 		you know they have we tried to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> can drive with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cub scouts</ENAMEX> that i have and we just don't have any place to store those kind of cans
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know if we go out and pick up a bunch of cans from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sure they'll save them for us there's no problem there but what do you do with them in the meantime now i don't want a can a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> full of cans
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 		that's right who does that you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't have room for that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you know
 		no they're just not they're not prepared for it
 	
 	
 		no and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> they're just get things like that they just get bugs in them so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they do and you know the more trash you have laying around the more bugs you get that's for sure
 	
 	
 		so you don't
 		that's right so
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i'm pretty lazy about it right now everything goes into one thing and goes out to the  you know pick it up so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah myself about the only thing i really recycle around here is aluminum cans
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		s o
 	
 	
 		yeah well i need to get better get better at it so
 	
 	
 		well if we all try a little bit a little bit goes a long way you know
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		if everybody tries to do just a little bit and a little bit more then
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		we'll get there
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		well thank you for talking to me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well thank you for calling i
 	
 	
 		sure no problem
 	
 	
 		okay take care
 	
 	
 		all righty bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	