
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		anyway uh
 		uh
 	
 	
 		do you work for a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> corporation
 	
 	
 		well i did uh and i'm currently uh consulting now so i'm with this you know a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> um so my benefits are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pretty basic uh
 		medical um
 		i don't get any
 		profit sharing and stuff like that so
 	
 	
 		i uh i work with a medium size <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and we don't have profit sharing but i would enjoy it since we uh it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it would be nice but
 	
 	
 		yeah what uh the current climate is i saw a little flyer and uh i thought it was interesting uh
 		is they are now offering
 		you know flex flexible benefits
 		where you have more control and allocate uh like you can
 		uh pay for uh vacation time if you want to take more vacation you can just buy them out or something like that so i can
 		can do other things and uh
 	
 	
 		that would be nice
 	
 	
 		they actually have a software package that sounds like where you can manipulate different things to see what it costs to you for those benefits
 		so it sounds like they're going to get very more
 		flexible to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> needs which i think is the most important thing because everybody is got quite a few different objectives
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> have different objectives than single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or no no i've got a family <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah are you single
 		okay uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alright</ENAMEX> do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are you single
 	
 	
 		but
 		no i i'm uh single i'm uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		never been married so
 	
 	
 		you are i
 	
 	
 		no i said i've never been married i'm only i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only twenty six so</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you never have
 		oh yeah that's there's still a lot of time for that i had already been married and had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> by that time but um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i still got a few years
 	
 	
 		we uh we've we just kind of started young in life  but uh uh we uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s still with the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> and as a result
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		it has worked out so he's got a real nice benefit package
 		but um
 		it's uh it's nice to be with a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for that reason i guess
 	
 	
 		so what are the most important benefits to you
 	
 	
 		oh the hospitalization um
 		is the hospitalization medical care benefits is what we like the best um because it's a good well rounded program it's you know just eighty percent and then uh the deductible's reasonable
 		i think it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> fifty a year for the family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whereas with my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> they pay <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fifty percent</NUMEX> and the deductible's i think <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred</NUMEX> a year
 		and it costs a lot more i'm with a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		the but the medical stuff itself uh
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		the health plan you're with it only it only covers fifty percent
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		ouch
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's the worst i've ever heard
 	
 	
 		yeah it's not very good
 	
 	
 		it's usually the eighty basic eighty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		besides your initial deductible that's what varies the most i guess uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah or you can go with a HMO you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Maintenance Organization</ENAMEX> where you pay a certain amount a month
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ha um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> every time that you go in or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two dollars</NUMEX> everytime yeah co-payments that's what they are
 	
 	
 		yeah co-payments type stuff
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i think uh obviously i think the the medical is the most expensive or it's the most important
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh coverage uh
 		of the you know you may not even go in
 		to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> but you know if something came up obviously you you know to get covered is important
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		well if we one of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is just is just turned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and her first
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX> of life God well she had one operation she's been to the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> a couple of times i mean she's she's just expensive the other one wasn't nearly that expensive but the but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> just one of those
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		kind of sickly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that has a lot of accidents
 	
 	
 		uh-huh how about any matching programs
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you ever
 		you know what i mean where they contribute contribute contribute <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like a hundred</NUMEX> percent of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to four percent</NUMEX> of you salary into a 401K
 	
 	
 		no  oh
 		yeah yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s got that available that's great
 	
 	
 		is it is it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent or is it fifty percent
 	
 	
 		i think it's fifty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent up to four percent</NUMEX> or maybe it's fifty percent up to eighty percent
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm not exactly sure
 	
 	
 		but that that's a nice i think that's an important benefit
 	
 	
 		yeah that's great
 	
 	
 		uh i don't get that option i i i was at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that had that and i
 		didn't make enough to to be able to put anything in it so i had to leave
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah it's nice we uh we we do a lot of our savings in that manner and then the rest of it through a universal life policy which is
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		money that you can touch but it's tax deferred and yields a higher rate in general than what we can get in CD's and gets life it's a it's a term life policy also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		with an annuity
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah that's what it is you know about insurance i didn't know anything about insurance until i had got until i had children
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		i i the only reason i know a little bit about that is
 		when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> still
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> working and
 		uh during during the summer
 		some how i got a hold of
 		involved in a a marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that marketed
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> replacing those uh whole life policies which aren't very good insurance policies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are losing you know and it losing money or not doing as well as they could
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> was targeting to replace whole life policies with a term life with annuity an annuity and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they would uh you know analyze it
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s current policy and get a computerized computerized you know statement of
 		uh what would happen you know at this age this age this age you know uh what your benefits would be and uh the difference between you know the term life with annuity and the whole life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		was you know there's fairly big discrepancies discrepancies you know so they could try to replace those so i got involved uh on that end
 		and picked it up but i never did tell anyone back at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and i never i never uh did anything with it but
 		uh so i know a little about uh the right now i just do a little basic life thing on my benefits but
 		you know i don't know what i get out maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty thousands</NUMEX> or something just to cover me and cover some expenses and maybe fly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out that i know you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that but uh i'm not worried about that i don't have anybody to to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		until you get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dependents</ENAMEX> it just doesn't matter
 	
 	
 		yeah well i like the idea of having that chunk of money uh to help anybody cover my end you know you don't want to be a burden to anybody else uh
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		but as far as being able to really leave anything
 	
 	
 		so i think
 		yeah i mean i'm not looking to to leave anything there may be a a certain amount and you know that's fine but uh
 		uh you know to get that coverage and know that i'll get you know
 		uh
 		you know flown to wherever i need you know already i need to go i guess i haven't made any decisions like that i guess you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> would do that but uh
 	
 	
 		are your family
 	
 	
 		see i've i've kind of moved around from my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> originally and  um and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> now most of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and i'm out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh anyway as far as benefits um
 		what else is important important uh obviously i think uh
 		a profit sharing is is uh
 		is uh is a important benefit especially in the long run for the long term
 	
 	
 		i've never
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i've
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> does a little bit of profit sharing but my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> doesn't and
 		i'd really like it if my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> did  they turn quite a profit at times but
 		it's not part of uh what's available so
 	
 	
 		yeah smaller the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> it's either
 		the smaller company
 		you you you're in to into the consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> and they'll you'll finish up a project and you'll get the little bonus that type of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i guess you could technically consider that profit sharing
 		um
 		but um most you know most medium or small
 		probably don't
 		do that much profit sharing
 		and while i was at this other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> they never had any profit so
 	
 	
 		it didn't help any to share
 	
 	
 		yeah  they couldn't share any and i guess they had a little bit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i wasn't qualified qualified for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my first year</TIMEX> something you know after
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		so have you have you been just been out of school what i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		little over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		at uh
 		it uh quite a different world isn't it  versus being life before real world life in college
 	
 	
 		versus what
 		
 		
 	