
 
     		
 	
 		well how how do you feel about the immigration laws
 	
 	
 		at currently i think they are a little restrictive uh particularly for uh certain ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> or from certain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> um
 		i think we should permit uh more immigration from eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> for example
 		uh particularly the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> i think we could permit more of them in than we have uh permitted in the last uh several years
 		and i think we have uh uh
 		too much restriction on the uh on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orientals</ENAMEX> also
 		but of course that's just my opinion
 	
 	
 		yeah well i'm not real sure why i got this topic because i don't think i checked it off on the list because i know very little about the current immigration laws
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well we seem to uh to favor certain uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and uh
 		there is no uh uh i have nothing of course against uh the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Americans</ENAMEX> or uh
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> in that sense but i think we uh are more restrictive of the um so called eastern uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> than we uh
 		uh we should be of course that's from my own bias since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my ancestors</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		so i think uh you know the  um embargo we placed on the uh on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian Jews</ENAMEX> although we spent of uh
 		spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> uh lobbying for their release and their ability to um immigrate from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> as soon as that occurred we
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		simply said that uh instead of the uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred and fifty thousand</NUMEX> or so who wanted to immigrate to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> we cut that by uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thirds</NUMEX> so
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		i do not quite go along with that but
 	
 	
 		no that doesn't make a whole of lot sense
 	
 	
 		no
 		and i still think you know again kind of having uh uh within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX> come from a uh
 		uh an immigrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant families</ENAMEX> on both sides both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm a little touchy  every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> about that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		well uh my uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is from uh  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">well</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh have been in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a hundred and fifty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years almost two hundred years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		so i don't have any any uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> that i am or or uh
 		several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> back that i am familiar with their names and how they fit into the family they were all they were all born here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i don't have any real strong ties with any with with the immigration laws i don't because i don't
 		i don't have any personal feelings about them and i i haven't taken the time or effort to learn what they are
 	
 	
 		well i think in a way though uh uh i also have uh an opposite point of view which is uh
 		although i believe we should uh permit uh you know constant immigration into this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think we should uh primarily for economic reasons i think we should have um
 		some quotas of course my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and i again again that was you know my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> came over during the time when uh there were quotas so they had to wait uh
 		you know in uh certain parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before they were permitted to come over
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you know  but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i i
 	
 	
 		i think unrestricted immigration i think is not uh
 		is not best uh
 	
 	
 		well i agree with that i i think if  immigration was entirely unrestricted
 		uh not only would would the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> become over populated well more over populated awfully quickly
 		i think it it would bring in a lot of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are run out of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> or in trouble in in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i think they'd come here trying to find a new market for their their brand of crime
 	
 	
 		um-hum well you know there's another aspect of this too they're also uh
 		uh diminishing the uh health restrictions which
 	
 	
 		i was not aware aware of that
 	
 	
 		well yes there are were some uh
 		regulations over i don't know whether they're laws passed or or whatever they're called uh just recently where
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with certain <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> cannot be excluded uh from immigration <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is one for example and uh recently uh
 		tuberculosis which at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one time</TIMEX> if you had tuberculosis you could not get into this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> uh they dropped that also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i think in in some some aspect some ways we are uh becoming a little too egalitarian in that in that sense but uh
 		i think we should be a little more circumspect about it
 		again my opinion
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		think we've talked long enough
 	
 	
 		i think so
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		well i've enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		or i i i have talked long enough
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX>  thanks
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		thank you
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">good-bye</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		
 		
 	