
 
     		
 	
 		okay we we can uh be recorded while we talk about it
 	
 	
 		okay well is your does your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> have mandatory recycling uh recycling
 	
 	
 		no we don't have mandatory we actually we're kind of slow up here and we've just started doing recycling probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> and it's all voluntary
 		so that's interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> have a mandatory recycling
 	
 	
 		um there there's some places that are strongly encouraging it then that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> will pick it up
 		that's been one of the arguments here i'm just sitting here looking we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> bins of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and plasticine stuff but we have to carry it
 		um some distance and some places um you can sell your uh recyclables and um for example um our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> was was collecting newspapers
 	
 	
 		yeah when when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> we used to collect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and bring them to a recycle thing we got like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">penny</NUMEX> a pound for them
 	
 	
 		well it turns out that so much the problem in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is that uh they've got so much paper now from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> recycling that they've got no way to uh reprocess it
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		that it requires an extremely it requires uh essentially a paper <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> to recycle it and so the value has gone down it turns out it wasn't worth it for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> to do
 	
 	
 		wow i didn't i didn't realize you would think now up here
 		i i suppose they send it all back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> and there are paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mills</ENAMEX> within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple of hundred miles</NUMEX> of uh actually there is one in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> so there's probably a paper <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> that's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">sixty miles</NUMEX> from here i didn't think that
 		you know in the large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that if the next recycling if the next <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> is more like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five hundred miles</NUMEX> away it's a lot of money to transport
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah well see that's in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> there there no plan to build i think that there's some in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Texas</ENAMEX> there's some pulp
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mills</ENAMEX> but uh you have to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and uh it's interesting and then there's places that'll buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal</ENAMEX> and they still buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> can in fact that
 	
 	
 		do you have to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal copper</ENAMEX> is a very good one to collect even aluminum yeah so
 	
 	
 		well do you do do you do recycling
 	
 	
 		uh we do do recycling and our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> will pick up our recyclables they have these little blue bins um i don't recycle personally i i'm saying i want to do it
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but i don't get a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> i don't get a i don't buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> but i do have a lot of uh my trash has a lot of tin cans and a lot of cardboard a lot of different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> and cardboards
 	
 	
 		well do you do you drink <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX> and such in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> cans
 	
 	
 		yes but we have a bottle return a lot of the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and a lot of the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have bottles we've had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five cent</NUMEX> deposits on our bottles for years
 	
 	
 		oh so it's worth taking them back well see we don't have we have we have most of our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soft drinks</ENAMEX> are in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic liter</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two liter</NUMEX> bottles
 	
 	
 		oh they should definitely get um the nickel returnable it's great for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> because see a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get the money from it and it's great for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> scouts running around they knock door to door and the collect the bottles sometimes
 	
 	
 		oh that's interesting you know that you know that there is a down side to all this you know about no good deed going unpunished that uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> sells um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> that they make paper out of and so every time i recycle newspapers
 		uh in fact there's uh there's a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of kleenex and such
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		has a uh a big paper <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> in fact i almost went to work for them i was offered a job and turned it down because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> got it for me but it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thirty miles</NUMEX> from my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> every time you recycle that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> less tree my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> can sell and uh
 		so it's a question should i be diligent and um um
 	
 	
 		and recycle
 	
 	
 		and and recycle and put my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> out of her livelihood
 	
 	
 		uh uh yeah i see that
 	
 	
 		but it it it's an interesting point though that uh you know everybody's so anxious to recycle and i suppose it does provide some gainful employment but uh
 	
 	
 		but it takes away employment from the resource that its using
 	
 	
 		well but in general i think it's a good idea because there's like the glass you can't argue that the glass it doesn't biodegrade and and uh the plastics obviously they don't
 	
 	
 		i do too
 		uh they don't either
 	
 	
 		so we might as well recycle those
 	
 	
 		yeah like i say it's not a very controversial thing everyone thinks we should do it
 		it's just that we're so lazy i mean like personally i don't want to clean my i just have can cat food i don't want to clean the can and take the label off it and put it in a separate bin
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i'd just rather get rid of that thing and throw it in the trash
 	
 	
 		well that's what we've got ours we we started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about New Year</TIMEX>'s we decided we'd get ambitious we took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> load over there and now we've got these containers filling up with stuff and
 		you know it it it's not a very high priority thing to go haul these uh containers over there
 	
 	
 		well i think i i would be like when i bring my bottles back
 		um if if if they're pretty clean and stuff so they can sit in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cellar</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of months</TIMEX> and i get a whole bunch of them and bring them over and bring them over
 		now if i had a recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and i kept it clean like if you said wash all the cans and things i wouldn't mind if it sat around too much but if
 		if it stunk or something i wouldn't like doing it but um i produce quite a bit of trash my you know house
 		and i see it but i don't see so much that i can recycle like i say it's a lot of different type paper and cardboard i'm not a real plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person user</ENAMEX> but a lot of paper
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um pretty much and i and i don't know how they sort that but if if i used a lot of can goods and i do use a lot of laundry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent</ENAMEX> and a lot of plastic bottles i would think that i would i would have a recycling center
 		but now it's just me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> so i don't know
 	
 	
 		but every little bit helps right
 	
 	
 		yeah i know what you're saying like well we have it at work we have a very aggressive recycling at work and i'm the one who will pick the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> out of the trash and bring it to the recycle bin see some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the recycle bin is on their way out
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		instead of carrying your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> when they get done with them at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX> they throw them in the trash
 	
 	
 		well do you have separate trash cans at your desk
 	
 	
 		um no we don't but other other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> do they have a box for papers
 	
 	
 		well we have we have one that's recyclable and and then for uh lunch sacks and and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waste food</ENAMEX> and and they gave us a list of things that aren't recycle and it turns out it's not so bad i i i get a lot of reports that that are covered in plastic
 		or plastic like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saran Wrap</ENAMEX> or something anyway and then uh and cardboard there's a few interesting that we're we're recycling computer type paper
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and and uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> they'll pick up uh the the cleaning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come through and they'll pick up recycled paper and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> they'll pick up the other so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		depending on how much uh you know and there's a lot of uh actually it works pretty well and then we have uh uh waste
 		uh cans for aluminum in the in the break areas at work and so
 	
 	
 		well that's that's a really good idea because um like our uh fruit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit juices</ENAMEX> for some reason when they're in a can don't come with a deposit it
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they're they're thinking about putting a deposit on them because pretty much
 		you have to you're having a whole separate recyclable bin just for these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> cans where they're so much easier just to put a deposit on it because most
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		probably ninety percent of the aluminum cans do have deposits because they're beer and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX> but when they sell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX> it's some strange quirk in the law you don't have to have
 		a deposit on it and even like the you know a very fine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice jar</ENAMEX> does not have to have a deposit on it but if it's got <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX> in it it does so it's a strange
 	
 	
 		that's an interesting distinction that
 	
 	
 		yeah they should they should clean clear that up it wouldn't take them much to put a stamp on uh on the uh juice cans as easily as the soda
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so but redemption <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> are a big thing up here they get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a penny</NUMEX> a can they handle they give you <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five cents</NUMEX> and the when they return the can to the distributor i think they either get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a penny</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two pennies</NUMEX> a can
 	
 	
 		well see well see those of us that don't have state income taxes yet that's the big debate here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that they their the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> wants to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in and it's interesting what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get upset about uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it it really is the the
 	
 	
 		is bottle is bottle return down there a heated debate
 	
 	
 		well no the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the big issue</TIMEX> was is is uh when we moved here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> is whether it was okay for you to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink beer</ENAMEX> while you were driving your pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and throw it out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">at the</ENAMEX> and at uh
 		so
 	
 	
 		well we well well well here you can't can't drink
 	
 	
 		we're we're now civilized now you can no longer you you cannot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink beer</ENAMEX> and drive but uh but it was it was actually legal
 	
 	
 		well
 		yes well i know i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> and you could walk out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> with your drink in your hand but here let me put that in a paper cup for you  so that was strange but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think if some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they have they say well we're not going to start a can deposit because you have to get all these
 		um the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">the</ENAMEX> recycle center you have to deal with the can and then you have to to recycle it and their problem's already solved because they can just come to states that do have bottle deposits
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		see how they handle it and see if it's a good way and then do it that way because as i like to say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are making money on it the cans do are worth something
 	
 	
 		well you know the other
 		well the other thing is it also is is a is a a good habit uh to uh just to conserve resources
 		you know whether you know because when you get in the habit of doing that you think in terms of of uh of of things like saving gas
 		
 		
 	