
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> did you vote in the last uh national election
 	
 	
 		yes we uh uh i haven't missed a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> since i've been eligible to vote
 	
 	
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> did you get to vote at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last one</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i voted in the last national one yeah i'm not sure if i got the last local one
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh yeah and sometimes the the local ones aren't as publicized it seems that uh they should be
 	
 	
 		yeah and you're not sure where to go and vote and all that
 	
 	
 		right and uh there's usually nobody running against you know the incumbents
 	
 	
 		right or you don't know what they stand you know where they stand or anything like that
 	
 	
 		right so uh but i i feel that uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have gotten lazy about voting
 	
 	
 		yeah i think you're right
 	
 	
 		and it's it's they're and also they're fed up with the system and they say well why should i even vote
 	
 	
 		yeah or sometimes they don't like either of the choices
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> so they think well you know why vote
 	
 	
 		right the lesser of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">evils</ENAMEX> is how we usually look at it  oh i know it  the last gubernatorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> was oh that was awful
 	
 	
 		yeah really especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		it really was yeah it was a mess
 	
 	
 		but uh so i don't know i it'll be interesting to see how the next uh
 		few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> go
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		did you think it's a serious problem that half the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't vote or
 	
 	
 		yeah i think well it's it's definitely a problem and i think it could get worse
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know we get this lackadaisical attitude and say huh you know why should we vote
 		and then uh you know it could uh it could lead to some serious things
 	
 	
 		yeah it also seems like maybe another another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> that nobody wants could slip in if you know not enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are voting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right uh yeah we can get uh
 		you know if we get someone in there like that then you know they could make all sorts of changes if they were you know had enough pull
 	
 	
 		yeah it's kind of like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> where that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that's like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ku Klux Klan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> something got elected  kind of scary when you think about that
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and uh who's the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> LaRouche uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LaRouche LaRouche</ENAMEX> uh
 		that uh is sort of the uh
 		socialist not socialist but communist uh he's so off the wall that uh he's gone in and tried to get into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> elections and uh but he's got he's been put away for uh credit card fraud i believe
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lyndon LaRouche</ENAMEX> that's it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh so yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'ll will sit home and assume oh that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> would never get elected next thing you know you've got him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right if you don't go and vote then you know very good chance that they they will because a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they'll strike a chord in something you know in some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that so will say well you know this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s got everything together you know i like what he says you know it'll be so far off the wall that they'll elect him
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know i think that's sort of what happened with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> because because uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> did get elected correct that's what i thought
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so
 		right
 		yeah he sure did
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		so you know it uh but you know they can always fool us you know they might do a good job
 	
 	
 		yeah i think one thing that maybe would help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> vote is if the polls were either open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more days</TIMEX> or you could mail it in or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		something like if you have if you have real strict work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and you can only go like at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven in the morning</TIMEX> or after work and you have to stand in line for so long i think that discourages a lot of people
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		what we do usually is uh vote uh absenteeism
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i know here you know you don't have to have any reason you can just go and vote
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh the polls are open what was it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX> uh the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> are good and it they're even open on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays and a couple of Sundays</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so you we've got plenty of time to go uh because uh down here in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> it's uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lines</ENAMEX> are long
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and they're long here too so
 	
 	
 		so uh but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i voted absentee <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> i really was going to be gone so i i did it but uh it was nice i would be tempted to do it again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well uh i recommend it because you just walk right on in and there's usually not anybody in line
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh you know that vote's just as good as you know the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they should change the whole system so that it's easier i think i think more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would do it if it wasn't such a hassle
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 		um i've yeah i've been involved with uh some of the campaigns and the state conventions of the
 		of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and it's really interesting to see the process as far as what goes through as far as the voting and the uh how the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the not the ballots but uh
 		my mind has gone blank i've been wrestling with a child <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all evening</TIMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what uh how they develop uh what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> stands for the you know the views and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know everybody gets to vote on you know well should he be for this and uh you know on and on and on and uh it's it's interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah that would be i usually vote a lot of times i'll vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a straight</TIMEX> party ticket just because i don't take the time to find out what every
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		you know other than the major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> what they stand for on on what issues so i just trust well the party kind of goes along these lines so i'll go ahead and vote
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh right and uh there for a while that would that works we've uh
 	
 	
 		but that
 	
 	
 		i i know i have uh  i'll stick to uh to uh you know sometimes i'll stick to a certain party depends on the guy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh if it uh gets down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between two</NUMEX> then i'll i'll vote for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>  if i know you know something about the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> or you know they're both just as bad then i'll say well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i know what this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> stands for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as far as</NUMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and um
 		but yeah you know that's not uh the best way but
 	
 	
 		no i guess it'd be best if you knew what each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and  what they stood for and why and everything but
 	
 	
 		right right but it gets to the point where i mean you've got to
 		have the time find the time also to read read about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and and be able to find the information about what he stands for
 	
 	
 		right and try to determine if what you read was objective or not and
 	
 	
 		right or what you've heard on TV which i think is just outrageous i i don't agree with how the uh media handles elections
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i you know i'm i'm tired of hearing about the polls you know you know this is how he stands such and such a day
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they break it out it's just it's just ridiculous
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it could affect the outcome you know could make it unfair
 	
 	
 		um-hum it really could and uh
 		uh then how sometimes how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> will blow things out of proportion and will run an an issue into the ground which is good and dead and they keep dragging it on and it could
 		hamper the uh outcome of an election for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that should have won
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah so uh
 	
 	
 		yeah the press has a lot of power
 	
 	
 		they really do i i sometimes think that that should be limited more
 	
 	
 		yeah oh but boy you try get into that you'd really open a can of worms
 	
 	
 		oh yes or they uh
 		you know i i agree with the freedom of of the press and that's you know all the amendments but sometimes it's for the public's own good that we don't hear things
 	
 	
 		yeah seems like they should regulate themselves a little bit and i don't think they ever care to
 	
 	
 		no they don't
 	
 	
 		well i can't think of anything else really about the polls or voting
 	
 	
 		and
 		well i enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		to talk about well it was good talking to you um bye
 	
 	
 		all right thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	