
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hi Phil</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how you doing
 	
 	
 		pretty good how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> did you say you had
 	
 	
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> i didn't say i i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of them yeah <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> uh i have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> is the oldest and then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> boys
 	
 	
 		wow you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children boys</ENAMEX> girls
 		i have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> as well uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> are uh uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five twenty four and twenty one</TIMEX> the numbers keep changing so it's hard for me to remember
 	
 	
 		yeah well you're doing a lot better than i can i can't rattle them off like that i know my youngest is eighteen he's uh as i said in a senior in high school but i have a
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> he's uh out seeing the world right now he's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the present time</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 		so you don't get a chance to to spend much time with him then until when he comes home
 	
 	
 		well he's yeah he's been gone for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about seven months</TIMEX> now we're expecting him to be getting home here before too much longer hopefully
 	
 	
 		wow  i uh unfortunately didn't spend enough enough time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh
 		where i i had a lot of things that i thought that i needed to do that were more important than than spending time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in fact when they were younger uh i was attending school
 	
 	
 		ouch
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then i found myself short of cash so i uh also went in for a part-time job so by the time that i got home after my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> job
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> either in bed or just getting ready to go to bed and the only time that i got to see them was on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> i had to do my homework so  it uh it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it took away a lot of of time from them we did go out to you know to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> that you typically take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to and we had a lot of fun but it seems as though the time went by so fast that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that i i didn't really enjoy it as much as i could have if i worked at it a little harder
 	
 	
 		i'll bet that story's all too common i uh
 	
 	
 		it's it's unbelievable how fast you know you when when you get to the point where even your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s age they don't want to spend time with you anymore and you know i
 	
 	
 		yeah they sure develop their own interests
 	
 	
 		i can i can remember when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> used to beg me to go with you know even to take them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> or take them someplace and and it just gradually goes away until you have to ask them do you want to come with me and then they start saying no so
 	
 	
 		it can be pretty sudden too
 	
 	
 		well it it's not sudden it's just that it probably doesn't hit the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> uh until it hits them over the head
 	
 	
 		yeah maybe so uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because you  because even even my oldest uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> when he comes uh comes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> he's still he's still my my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and and i don't think of him as an adult yet and uh that that's one of his complaints
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't think i uh i would have to say i probably didn't get to spend as much time as i would have liked to either uh however i did you know uh
 		early on i was in the retail business and i worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late hours</TIMEX> so i saw less of them then but then when i changed over and got into electronics industry i uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i did have more time and i tried to spend some more time with them
 		and uh you know we did things as a family we went camping quite a bit and we uh you know took trips went to see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and
 		and some of those kind of things
 	
 	
 		so you had a bunch a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>  that must have that must have that must have been fun
 	
 	
 		yeah we did we did quite a bit of that  just traveling and we had several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> there for a period of time in our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX> then we did when we were camping and stuff and that made it a little easier or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well camping is one thing that i i could never get used to uh i i used to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to go fishing and things like that but i never went uh never went camping
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that may be the difference in our part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> we live in it's a lot easier to get out outside <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> round uh well pretty near <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> round out here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah up in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> it's uh
 		uh you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four or five months</TIMEX> tops after that you're in the house
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because it becomes so cold out here that uh and sometimes the weather gets to you so you don't want to go outside and drive around
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i guess uh
 		i can think of a uh
 		uh things i would like to have done differently on uh on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		well i can think of of some enjoyable things that that i did with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like we used to go up to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> quite a bit and go to the uh uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">White Mountains</ENAMEX> area and and visit all the you know the nature <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i wouldn't sleep on the ground i went into a hotel  but i used to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to uh you know the things like uh the places where there are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and you go in and and feed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and things like that and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 		petting zoos and things
 	
 	
 		yeah hey you know and the and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> used to enjoy that as well and i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in fact uh one of the things that i notice a dramatic change was that that uh like if i'd be in a supermarket and i'd see a cute little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>  i wouldn't think twice about patting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> on the head
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well as time grew by and i think i had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> with me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and she went strolling away and i saw this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and i patted her on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> turned around and saw me and took the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> away  you know pulled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and i
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i turned around and i realized my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> wasn't there anymore so all she saw was a an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> standing there patting her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> so i i  i didn't realize it until after uh you know after it all happened what what the uh the
 	
 	
 		oh yeah  oh oh
 	
 	
 		the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>  uh it was uh really something
 	
 	
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> played uh
 		ball it wasn't it was like you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little League</ENAMEX> and uh it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dads Oaks Dads Club</ENAMEX> which was a like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little League</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you attend a lot of their games
 	
 	
 		yeah we used to go to the games and we had uh
 		i never did actually coach i'd go do some of the sideline stuff and like that but i never did actually coach but they tried to get me to do that i  but we'd go you know and watch them practice and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh pick them up and carry them there and that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		did you spend as much time with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> as you did with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i personally don't believe i did no for one reason being like i mentioned i was in retail when she was younger
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then
 		you know she being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> i guess she probably uh spent a lot of time with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> more so than with me
 	
 	
 		yeah i i uh i felt that myself myself as i as i grew older my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> grew older that i realized that i didn't spend <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as much time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> as i did my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> because uh i'd want to do the things that i thought
 		that they would like to do and it would always be the things that i wanted to do without realizing it you know things like uh you know fishing and and doing outside things outside and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> didn't like doing those things so she ended up spending more time with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> than uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 		uh
 	
 	
 		than with myself and i think uh she's closer to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> today than than she is to me because of that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's probably the same
 		case in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah it's unfortunate because yeah you know even even though you you think of them as a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> when you do things sometimes you separate them without even realizing it
 	
 	
 		yeah a lot of cases <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> getting get real close to their dads too you know and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah well she was close but yet whenever i wanted to do something  it was always something something different than what she wanted to do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i spent a lot of time with her when i was home uh she'd always be the one you know sitting on my lap or being close to me and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> would be off uh uh playing someplace but it seems like whenever i wanted to do something like go out  for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		and uh she'd always say well i want to go to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or i want to stay home and do this or she had like little projects she was working on at home and things like that
 		so i i kind of missed that um i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> especially uh being with her
 	
 	
 		is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> the uh oldest
 	
 	
 		no she's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">the second</NUMEX> oldest she's uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty twenty three now</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh middle child
 		you uh you have you ever heard much about that theory about the uh you know how their different their their position in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> relates to their uh character you know some of their
 	
 	
 		personality traits and things like that uh no i can't say that i have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mannerisms</ENAMEX> and personality yeah
 		yeah i believe it's true it's my experiences uh what i know about it and then observing it with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at least and then like some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> too it's uh
 		you know it's uh you know the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> is uh is more always more prone to be more like responsible and that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i think you force it on them  and and the youngest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> tends to be the one that's spoiled
 	
 	
 		yeah it is a natural development i think it
 		yeah and uh
 		in our case he he's real sensitive and real uh thoughtful and uh
 	
 	
 		the youngest one is more sensitive that's same with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and it's it's strange
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i don't know if
 		yeah i don't know if that relates to that or not but
 	
 	
 		well it just so happens that my youngest is uh extremely sensitive uh where my oldest one uh you know i can scream at him and yell at him and he'll look at me with with
 	
 	
 		my oldest yeah my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is hard headed as can be
 	
 	
 		but if i say the wrong thing to my youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> he he will he won't cry anymore because he's too old but he gets hurt he bruises very easily and and i can feel that
 	
 	
 		yeah right that's
 		that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX> he's it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> uh he was always he just
 		he'd keep it to himself a lot of times but he'd really kind of well up and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and be ready to cry or whatever
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he's gotten now to where he can take it better he'll dish it back a little bit but
 	
 	
 		i remember when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> took my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out uh fishing and again i was with my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> and not with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> but uh no i was with my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> uh my youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> wasn't old enough or i didn't think he was old enough to take out and uh
 		uh we caught this fish it was uh it was a fairly large size <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and he was very very proud it of he put it on the backseat on the floor and it was waggling around and we we came home and he uh
 		he wanted to show his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> what he caught because it was his first <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and he wanted to put it in the bathtub so she told him no he couldn't do it but he did it anyway fill the water filled the bathtub full of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		huh
 	
 	
 		uh put the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> in it now after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> died from being handled so much uh we brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and he put it out in the swimming pool  so after he realized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> wasn't going to come back uh to life again we went out there and they buried it
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		you know we did did it together and i i come in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and i wash my hands and i turn around and i did something and i saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out there with sticks digging it up again and i went out there said what are you doing he said i wanted to show my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> that i caught
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so he's so he's out there digging it up
 	
 	
 		yeah that was i'm sure it was a powerful experience for him it's something he'll remember
 	
 	
 		yeah well it was his first <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> he didn't he didn't want to hide it he wanted everybody
 		
 		
 	