
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay well i can tell you pretty much my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> favorite shows
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and they kind of are in different spectrums i think um one of them's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantum Leap</ENAMEX>
 		and the other one is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Night Court</ENAMEX> and i think i think they're real different i mean i don't think they have anything in common uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantum Leap</ENAMEX> has i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantum Leap</ENAMEX> is kind of
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 	
 	
 		a comedy in its own way i guess but uh mostly it's it's kind of science fiction and it's um adventure and things like that um and then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Night Court</ENAMEX> is just pure you know weird fun you know just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's nothing serious about it at all so i don't know why the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them happen to be my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> favorite shows but they that's the way it is so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's funny that those are my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> favorite shows too and i enjoy both watching both of them but i used to didn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Night Court</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i and the only reason i think i like it now is because i've seen it so much now i'm involved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i used to think um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Fielding</ENAMEX> was just too too vulgar and too crude for me  and and i told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> that's the whole point but  i i just it's
 	
 	
 		he is
 		yeah that's right i mean
 	
 	
 		i find him degrading at times and i guess that is the point but sometimes it just
 	
 	
 		well they they really have changed him though if if you've watched it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX> um he's becoming i mean he still is in his own way degrading and everything but uh he's involved in that charity
 		and uh it's taking up so much of his time and so much of his thought that he really has in fact there was one show
 		that he even turned down a date with some you know beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> just because the idea that he was his mind was on the ozone layer and you know global warming and all this other kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and he you know was too depressed you know to so that was part of i guess his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> building or whatever but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i i think it adds a probably adds a little bit of depth to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> i haven't watched um
 	
 	
 		which of course he needed
 	
 	
 		i think uh yeah i think so  which in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantum Leap</ENAMEX> you get even though the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is involved in so many other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives you still see a a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in those situations he gets
 		um he's doing amazing things but he's doing them within the bounds of what of normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would do and i think that's i like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right right that's that's good point
 		so what do you what do you consider your favorite shows though
 	
 	
 		um i think my favorite show is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter</ENAMEX> and i i like the old series series better when um
 	
 	
 		okay
 		Deedee
 	
 	
 		Deedee was in there yes
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree
 	
 	
 		and um so uh and then the the blonde that they took out the one that got killed
 	
 	
 		yeah i can't remember what her name is but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i didn't enjoy her i i she was too much of a opposite of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deedee</ENAMEX> and i think that's what they try to do but i think we wanted to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deedee</ENAMEX> there or somebody like her
 	
 	
 		um-hum well but see i read an article about uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide</ENAMEX> about uh about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter</ENAMEX> and about his latest you know latest you know his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> whatever you want to call them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they say that uh that there was absolutely that there was like a a conflict between her and him uh that they never really could get her into uh any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> that they could use i mean you know uh
 	
 	
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> uh-huh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one the blonde uh you know if you think about it they didn't really interact hardly at all i mean they were never partners
 	
 	
 		they didn't yeah she would go her way and he would do his and i think that's what i didn't like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and uh and and even even at the beginning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deedee and and Hunter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		would decide that one of them would go do this while the other one would do would go this but uh it seemed like it was almost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know like like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> and and this other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> was not and you know you kind of you're wondering you know well when did this happen you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so yeah i i i kind of agree with that
 	
 	
 		and i like the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> better but i'd just as soon that they didn't have the romance there i'd just as soon have the the police story without all the romance
 	
 	
 		well i'm afraid that's what they they really wanted to do um
 	
 	
 		yeah i think most shows were doing that and then they went away from it and now they're starting to go back to it and maybe that's what the public wants i don't know but i just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like the the cut and dry solve the mystery and that's what i always enjoyed about it
 	
 	
 		yeah well see there was that spark between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deedee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunter</ENAMEX> for a while but they they like started it and then they'd pull it back and they'd start it and pull it back and that really made it a very interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh show to where you never really knew
 		which which one was going to show up you know whether it was going to where they're going to be real close or whether they're just going to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> you know and that that i kind of thought was good but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's it i guess you know you always kind of sit there and you see these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> together and you always wonder why they don't you know get together or whatever and so i guess that's what they decide to do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		just go ahead and quit the wondering and and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but it's it's always been a formula uh for TV that the minute that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> get married
 		that the show ends up well you know dying
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a a good example of this and uh you know this is uh probably well maybe it's not a good example i've been watching
 		Nickelodeon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all last week</TIMEX> uh because they had uh what they called Maximum Smart they had Get Smart for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">uh ten hours a day from seven o'clock at night</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six or</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five o'clock the next morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		all the Get Smart episodes you could ever see well the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last day</TIMEX> all they did was the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last season</TIMEX> to where the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them got married and that was i mean that was the killer the series died right after that because well go ahead
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		i didn't
 		i was going to say i didn't ever watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moonlighting</ENAMEX> but i heard that's what killed it that that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interplay</ENAMEX> died when they got married and so the show died
 	
 	
 		um-hum the same thing
 		yeah the it it it seems like you can do so much more of the subtle hints and the subtle little plays on things before they they before they get married you know the minute they get married everything's supposed to be cut and dried and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and well of course another one of their mistakes i think is they have a tendency to change <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> or to change the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>'s uh
 		uh personalities um um well especially after they get married um
 	
 	
 		halfway through
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of examples would be um well like i said this one about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">uh Max or Get Well</ENAMEX> Smart uh the female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Feldon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she had been at the beginning the the intelligent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the the one who everyone always solved the things and and figured out and kept
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX> from getting real messed up well toward whenever they got married she got dingy
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know why would they do that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it it made no sense
 	
 	
 		i i'm guess it's going falling back into our traditional stereotypes which a lot of shows
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		unfortunately that's probably true
 	
 	
 		yeah which kind of like in the big soap opera shows which i don't enjoy because of that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		well do you watch um
 		what is that show uh Who's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX>
 		it's uh that's on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		i've seen it before but i don't watch it regularly usually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> i'm out so
 	
 	
 		yeah the well i yeah i hardly ever watch it but uh as as i've seen it they've they've done sort of the same thing to where they've they started to let them get together and then they pulled them apart
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think they're thinking about that exact thing about the idea that if the show lets them uh get together then you lose part of what the show's all about so i always thought that was kind of weird
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it's funny how we uh
 		we we romanticize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh like well for instance when i was a teenager you know you romance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		romanticize a rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> but when he gets married then you don't care anymore or something like that and i think it's the same with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> on TV
 	
 	
 		hum right
 		well do you think that's why most rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> nowadays keep their marriages a secret or at least they keep it quiet
 	
 	
 		probably yeah i know it affected me when i was younger i'm not into rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> too much lately but
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean
 		yeah
 		now like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Penn</ENAMEX> now i don't particularly like either one of them but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh their marriage was so highly publicized
 		that there was no way that they could stay together
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or at least that's the way i look at it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i don't know
 	
 	
 		it would have been hard wouldn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah i would think so
 	
 	
 		i i just the the publicity in and of itself much less the i mean when you get married you've got relationship to develop in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> watch you do that
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it wouldn't be easy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so hum
 		well that's kind of interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so um
 		well i guess i guess that's about all we need to do isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah i think we've covered our time it's been good talking to you
 	
 	
 		yeah it has Becky i really appreciate it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh you're the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i've talked to everybody else has been a female so this is a change
 	
 	
 		well i think i've um you're the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> female i've talked to
 	
 	
 		you've had a little bit of variety huh  okay  well thanks so much bye-bye
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's kind of nice
 		so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh bye-bye</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	