
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um</ENAMEX> regarding health care it's funny because i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> who lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> that's the way it is health care is just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		they have socialized socialized health care
 	
 	
 		right exactly and um the the interesting thing is that it seems that they don't even think about it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's not anything that seems to be um you know costing everybody a lot of money it's not a major topic of conversation it's just something that's done and accepted
 	
 	
 		how do they pay for it how is it financed
 	
 	
 		well um i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> subsidizes most of it but i i believe that that again just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are taxed
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		a little bit more but it's just interesting how something you know that we consider just such a major issue is just in such working order there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know what do you feel about it
 	
 	
 		well i feel like something needs to be done here and i'm definitely in favor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> i just think medical you know medical costs have as i've seen over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> just go up and up and up and already just this year
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know i'm a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> and you know i have to pay for medical insurance and
 		it's just outrageous my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> you know has got <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> and he's got this and he's got that and he broke his arm i mean and you know it's a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> here a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know even though the insurance is paying eighty percent of it you're pay an arm and a leg for the insurance <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all and then you're still paying yeah the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">twenty percent</NUMEX> and so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> percent
 		and and the sad part is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to to you know combat this they just won't go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> or they won't fill their prescriptions
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		or they can't yeah they just can't
 	
 	
 		i mean that you know that's the alternative
 	
 	
 		yeah i've been in positions before where i've had to wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> you know to have a prescription filled because i just didn't have it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i don't think that that's fair i don't think it's fair you know to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are sick and i know that you know
 	
 	
 		i know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has you know their you know their free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> or whatever and i know a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have had experiences in those
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've been fortunate enough not to but i mean you could go down there <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> dead and still wait you know it's hard to see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> from what i've heard
 	
 	
 		oh i know i know oh yeah it's true and i don't think that that burden should be put on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> either i don't think that they should have to assume the responsibility of paying for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s health care
 	
 	
 		well yeah there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that um you know don't work
 	
 	
 		oh yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		you know and don't have it you know any other means they've and so they either don't again don't have it or they have to take it out themselves and pay an arm and a leg for it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i'm thinking of you know i just did my tax return for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> you know if your medical bills are more than a certain percent of your income
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's worthwhile to itemize and and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> we reached that mark
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh you did
 	
 	
 		where my medical where it was worth it to itemize for medical expenses because they were just they were that much of a percentage of my income that it just
 	
 	
 		wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i just did it it's very frustrating  a hot topic for me
 	
 	
 		i know well and well you know you're not the only one though um i'm in a situation where when i started my job they were paying full benefits
 		i thought great you know can't get any better and then slowly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> you know now they're down to seventy <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> and then they went down to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fifty percent</NUMEX> and and i understand they have to do that with the prices going up and up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um you just might as well knock of a couple <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> from your salary you know to pay for this medical care and then i i don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so i'm not worrying about family coverage
 	
 	
 		oh at least at least
 	
 	
 		but once you get into family coverage it's crazy
 	
 	
 		oh it's out it's outrageous and then a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> you know offer you know you can have a certain amount deducted pre tax from your pay check for medical expenses but not covered by insurance but
 	
 	
 		it it's just crazy
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know that's something that's something fairly new and not a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take advantage of it but it's you know it's use it or lose it and i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> you know that have had that money checked out regularly and then it's like well let's see i guess i could go get a new of glasses  you know
 	
 	
 		right they have a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> to spend in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> i know what you mean
 	
 	
 		you know get a big crown done you know things like that but
 	
 	
 		yeah we do that too we're fortunate though <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> somehow how it's only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> and we've already used up our entire amount i don't know if that's good or bad
 	
 	
 		i know
 		yeah um do you think that that that the insurance and all they've got in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> does it cover dental or is it just medical
 	
 	
 		i don't know um
 		i think it covers a portion because like i said my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> lives over there and they they just they just never have to worry about it i think it might not cover full dental but it does cover some and again it covers you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		major things it won't cover cosmetic type things you know if you choose to do something but um it's just like all in it's just all in practice it's all in plan i think that we could learn from that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what motivates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to go into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> you know how how do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know i really don't know i know that they do equally as well there as they do here i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> still have that same status
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they do so they're getting paid
 	
 	
 		i don't know i guess they're getting paid for it one way or another and and i would imagine although i don't know maybe there still are private practices there i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i yeah i don't know either
 	
 	
 		i don't know but um it would be great and and if only i mean
 		health is probably the one thing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should be most concerned with you know especially that makes a good society when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are healthy and they're not you know they're not stealing for money to pay for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' bills
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they're they're going to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> because they're not sick you know i mean just something that should be more of a priority than it is now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i definitely agree and i remember back in high school being on the debate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and that was one of the subjects one of the debates should we have you know national health care and i remember debating for it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum well at least let them start off gradually you know fine so they won't jump into paying full health care let them pay you know partial and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> just you know let's increase it from there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		i don't know but
 	
 	
 		i i don't know it's going to be hard to switch i think that we're going eventually end up end up that way though i just don't see how we can yeah i think it'll take
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it'll take a while maybe our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> will know it
 	
 	
 		i agree it'll take a while but i think we have to be headed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have to be headed in that direction
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well it was nice tal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> to you yeah maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> we'll all have health care
 	
 	
 		nice talking to you too
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> from not from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that i've talked to
 	
 	
 		it's what
 	
 	
 		you're the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> not from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that i've talked to
 	
 	
 		oh i know like i said everyone's been in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> all righty well take care okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	