
 
     		
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> and i've had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Maryland</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		wow that's great you're just getting all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> aren't you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm a non <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> and i always i always feel like when i get someone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that you're probably employed by
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yes i am i am
 	
 	
 		yeah well i was surprised that they had their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the survey but then why not
 	
 	
 		well i didn't realize that i thought all of it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in the survey i i didn't i was the other way around i thought i didn't realize there were outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the survey so
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		uh do you know what they're doing with all this when they're finished
 	
 	
 		um i am not positive um i i probably have gotten about the same information you have because i don't work anywhere even near that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> i'm in even even in a completely different site so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know that that once they get through with this i i've read where they're they may call certain certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> back for like the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> phase or something i'm but i'm not really sure i mean i know do you know why they're you gathering the information right
 	
 	
 		no i don't
 	
 	
 		oh you don't what they're what they're working on is uh the way i understand it is the computer system
 		that you know in the future and who knows how far in the future they they believe that computers will be able to understand human voice where instead of having to have a keyboard and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> in what you want the computer to do
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		you'll be able to tell it what you want it to do and that's why they're gathering the voices in order to do research to enable computers to be able to do that
 	
 	
 		uh
 		in other words they want to know if our voice can direct a machine
 	
 	
 		right that's exactly right
 	
 	
 		well gosh i couldn't direct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i doubt that i can direct a machine are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		direct a machine huh
 		um i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewisville</ENAMEX> which is just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> just about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> yeah so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">north of Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		yeah we uh just came home from an expensive trip west and drove through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Fort Worth</ENAMEX> area without uh stopping for any reason whatsoever and i
 	
 	
 		did you
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we're our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five thousand</NUMEX> so i was very concerned about what the trip the traffic would be like around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Fort Worth</ENAMEX> and gosh we were through there before we even realized that we were in heavy traffic so you've got a good system
 	
 	
 		sure
 		yeah
 		yeah we really do we really do unless you're doing it
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> thing in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> or last thing in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> you know but it's that way anywhere
 	
 	
 		right
 		there is that time of day isn't there  uh
 	
 	
 		there is there is it's that way anywhere you go
 	
 	
 		shall we get on to nursing homes
 	
 	
 		yeah that's fine go ahead
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is seventy will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy nine years old this fall</TIMEX> and has been a nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly three years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so uh i feel like i have uh
 		my decision was not i did not make the decision to send her to a nursing home she made the decision that she could not any longer live in
 		in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> by herself she had long since given up her home and gone into an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and of course that was her decision at the time too so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then in that we are in a small royal a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> i think that makes such a difference too because
 		well as a matter of fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> at that nursing home
 	
 	
 		oh wow how wonderful
 	
 	
 		she yes yes she wasn't at the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but she has since gone to that nursing home so i just feel that i did not have any of the trauma that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk about
 	
 	
 		you sound like you've gotten very lucky you really have
 	
 	
 		well it just did a really marvelous thing and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s mind is good it's her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> that's bad and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for to have the responsibility of putting someone in a nursing home whose mind was not good and could not tell you if they were being mistreated or something it just would all be so different
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah oh definitely we kind of went through a situation with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um diabetic</ENAMEX> he was pronounced a diabetic when he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> and uh had diabetes for all you know many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		you know didn't take quite as good care of himself in the beginning as he should have i mean he was put on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> immediately but his diet he wasn't as careful with as he should have been in the beginning so he deteriorated rather quickly and
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		by the time he was in his mid fifties which is very young he was he was nearly blind and was going into kidney <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">failure</ENAMEX> and couldn't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		couldn't walk for very long periods of time the muscles in his neck and that type of thing had deteriorated to the point that he always had to have something to lean his head back against and and you know we were you know myself and my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> were
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know in the situation of a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a fifty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> looking in to put him in a nursing home which was which was at fifty i'm know it's scary isn't it yeah i mean it was
 	
 	
 		i'm fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		it was just a horrible situation for us to both you know to be in and we just you know because of course like you say like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> his mind was was perfect and wonderful it was he just could not get around to take care of himself
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh we ended up opting for um a live-in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> and you know that came into his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and and we set her up a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in a spare <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and she stayed there with him instead because we just could not imagine
 		a fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a nursing home we just you know we just could not could not imagine doing it
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and we knew that it wouldn't you know we couldn't even do the the live-in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> thing forever you know and but he was just so against and and when you said your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> knew that this is probably where she needed to be it was such a different story because he was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so against going to a nursing home which at that age i can't blame him you know it would just it just scared him to death to be you know that young and who knows you know the thought of being there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another twenty or thirty years</TIMEX> you know just was was just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		too much for him you know so we you know we opted for that route so i kind of know what you mean about the the trauma of you know the thought of doing it you know it was just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was just very hard but i guess you know there's there's there's good ones and there's bad ones i think you just have to be so very careful you know and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know you're lucky if you do have a situation where the mind is is still good and they can tell you if they're being well taken care of i think otherwise you you end up with serious problems
 	
 	
 		um
 		in our locality we have a lot of uh government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Health Care</ENAMEX> and etcetera etcetera which i'm sure they do in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we do not have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to draw from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">from</NUMEX> to find someone who could stay for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day in and day</TIMEX> out with they we just don't have those people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they just are not available even though you would like to make that choice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well you know
 		that was another situation because my this was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> and was in a little small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three thousand</NUMEX> and uh we just got very very lucky and found a woman
 		who was willing to do this and you know someone that we had known from you know had lived in town you know that same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> forever and we knew very well and we knew her history and we knew that she wasn't going to steal from him we knew that she would take good care of him and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we just got extremely lucky to find someone who was willing to do it and she stayed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days a week</TIMEX> and spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>
 		but did go home on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and then we found another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who had been kind of coming in and helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> clean and do that kind of thing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> who said that she was willing to stay on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and help him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so we just got extremely we were like you only the other end we got extremely lucky all the way around that we were able to find somebody  that would stay with him at home
 	
 	
 		hum
 		hum
 		how long
 		how long were you able to maintain that
 	
 	
 		well uh we only made we only did that for um i guess that went on for about all not quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> he passed away after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> there at home which
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		we were very thankful that we were able to keep him at home and that you know he did pass away at home and uh rather than being in a nursing home i know he was much happier spending that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was not living or
 	
 	
 		you know definitely so
 		uh they were they had been divorced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years earlier</TIMEX> yeah so he was he was alone and really had you know and
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh my uh youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> was um <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour and a half</TIMEX> away in college and uh i was you know down here <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six hundred miles</NUMEX> away and then my the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta Georgia</ENAMEX> you know so we weren't really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well we were even right there where we could take care of him you know so it was really a hard situation you know when in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> where everybody kind of gets spread out it's not as easy as it used to be to take care of aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> you know it you know you
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's hard to move them in with you or you move in with them or even you know drop in everyday you know you just
 	
 	
 		i just never considered the moving in with i could not ever have handled that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is incontinent and uh and i don't know i suppose that would have been my excuse uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i don't think had that situation existed not existed that i could have done that at all i'm not
 	
 	
 		that's a that's a real trying experience to try to you know to move back in and and live harmoniously together after all those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> it's
 	
 	
 		i
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RN</ENAMEX> and lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Knoxville Tennessee</ENAMEX> and i think that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had thought in the back of her mind that she perhaps might go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jean's</ENAMEX> and it did take when she first went into the care care center
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she just completely gave up uh just could not even sit up in the wheelchair without being tied in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that went on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost six months</TIMEX> and uh finally my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> came to visit and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was talking about getting better and getting out of the care center
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> is very blunt and she said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> this is going to be your home you might as well get used to it which i could not say to her
 		and from that point on i think within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next six months</TIMEX> she came to accept that as fact and then she began improving and is walking better now than she probably did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		wonderful
 		oh that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		still for the most part she is wheelchair bound or bed bound and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know i guess maybe i have accepted that the nursing home is her home because i've started to decorate her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> more than i ever did in the beginning so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh even though everyone knows that's the way it has to be you still it takes a little bit to accept
 		no no and certainly it's very expensive there's no question about that
 	
 	
 		doesn't make it easy no
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but we had a severe ice
 	
 	
 		no doubt no doubt
 		
 		
 	