
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay so what are your opinion on it
 	
 	
 		well let me preface it i'm a i was a staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty nine</TIMEX> and seventy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm in active reserve now so
 		uh i'm probably not going to have the opinion you think i would have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		it's it was an interesting
 		in that i think that he gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> some uh uh a sense of the fact that that uh wars are really run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i are you old enough to remember the war
 	
 	
 		not not much i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty eight</TIMEX> so no i really don't remember anything about it i guess i was about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> when it ended right
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		i was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty two so</TIMEX> when did it end
 	
 	
 		well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December seventy two</TIMEX> was when uh we bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Vietnam</ENAMEX> and
 		and they released the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early seventy three so</TIMEX> that that time frame
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so i was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> and i don't remember a lot about
 		anything at that time in my life very much in great detail
 	
 	
 		i think the the significant thing is is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> did did you uh did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX> interview with Schwartzkopf
 	
 	
 		no i didn't
 	
 	
 		well they
 	
 	
 		but i i did read the book i have do have i have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> of college
 		so i did read and study about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> though so i am pretty familiar you know i'm more familiar with it than
 	
 	
 		well
 		what what's your perspective on it
 	
 	
 		mine i think uh i think that there was a lot of rebellion in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and that
 		i think it was the right thing to do to try and not to take away to you know just leave their freedoms there
 		and to you know get rid of some of the atrocities that were going on
 		i don't i don't know i don't really i'm tired of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pacifist</ENAMEX> though see on the other hand
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pacifist</ENAMEX> i'm really struggling with it i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pacifist physical pacifist</ENAMEX> i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
 		and i believe that the real warfare is not with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Vietnamese</ENAMEX> but it's in spiritual kingdoms
 		and that the real warfare is done you know in your prayer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> on your knees so
 		in a way in a sense i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pacifist</ENAMEX> but i'm really not you know what i'm saying
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i don't think just lay back and not do anything i think lets go to war but let's go to war praying and let's go to war for that way so
 	
 	
 		well well the difficulty i have is that uh are we our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s keepers
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and this is what i find particularly difficult in that uh if we see injustice and whether it's in a uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> or
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i i think if we see it you know we see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wiley Wiley Price</ENAMEX> hollering injustice i think that's wrong now the question is is was there injustice in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> or was there injustice in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwait</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the difficult i point is is to where do we step in and and i think that we
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's that's the part i have difficulty and the the other part is that the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the</TIMEX> when when your when your
 		when you're looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and you say well
 		is fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight thousand</NUMEX> lives worth it
 		and i don't know that anything is worth fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight thousand</NUMEX> lives
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		still have a problem with uh you know i haven't come to an absolute conclusion on my opinion on this but
 		and i know other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> would disagree with me my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i are kind of not even in agreement on this but we don't fight over it or anything but
 		you know how can you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> says bless your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> and bless those that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> you and it's like be gentle unto all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> apt to teach patient kind so it's like how can you
 		i don't know for me i don't know you know i can't say that i agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> because how can you be gentle unto all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and
 		and then shoot them
 	
 	
 		well the other issue is is is how do you allow uh how how do you allow injustice just like the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how could how could could you stand there and watch them beat that guy
 		if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> were being beaten
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> do we step in well
 		in some cases we would and i i think that's what makes it so difficult
 	
 	
 		yeah it is a difficult thing but then vengeance is mine sayeth the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> and i will pay
 		so i think God ultimately in charge of
 		what goes on in i know like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Tse Chung</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> he did all these terrible things and they were terrible and he's gonna be accountable for them
 		and but if you look back you say wait a minute while he was in power he built <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> he tore down all the temples he
 		he unified the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Chinese</ENAMEX> language it was impossible for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> to do accomplish anything in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		because of all that and so even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North and South Vietnam</ENAMEX> i bet you'd see the same thing
 		and that now he build <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> so then he'd open and then he dropped dead <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five years</TIMEX> premature he just dropped dead and so something good did come out of that in that
 		now you see what i mean it's like now
 	
 	
 		yeah but but the other the other difficulty is is that it's just if if you take the admonition to to feed my sheep
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the question is who are my sheep
 		and the idea do we go out and feed these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when they're hungry
 	
 	
 		well bless your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> is hungry feed him if he if he needs your asks for your shirt give him your coat also
 		so if the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Vietnamese</ENAMEX> they asked us to help them right
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yes uh they did the
 		i think the the biggest difficulty is is that when your at an agrarian economy like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX> was that in reality uh the the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> poor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> was going to pay taxes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the question is who was he going to pay it to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> or the uh alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> uh democratic form of government and i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that's i think i think uh that's a little was a difficult part there and and i we didn't understand the culture we couldn't uh we had uh we had a a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> that was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> that worked in our
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> i was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> of that appeared to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight or nine years old</TIMEX> and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> looked like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i mean you couldn't imagine that one would would would conceal a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and do these kind of things i think culturally it really destroyed a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that went over and saw these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you just couldn't believe that they would
 		that they would be mean and and and drop bombs and kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and then we would turn around and and napalm them you know if
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think there was a lot of a lot of tearing of emotions and i think that if anything that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartzkopf</ENAMEX> he was saying the idea that we learned we learned we learned a lot from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now it was it was it was in general bad but and i don't know the problem is now i'm i'm concerned a little bit that that now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> is on that we're going to think it was a good war and it was okay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to go beat up on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i think that i think we need to a little more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> at home i'm not sure how we get that  whether there's a connection there but
 	
 	
 		yeah but then again yeah i'd say it is wrong to invade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> and i'm not saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> made the wrong decision i think i'm lacking in my
 	
 	
 		in any event
 	
 	
 		i don't think i can come to a complete conclusion on how i feel about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> because i'm going to interpret that
 		through the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> and i've kind of always i have been a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> and i've kind of avoided that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX> hat those the war things and how God approaches that
 		because i think its just now coming up to where i really feel like i need to come you know need to decide what i feel
 	
 	
 		well the difficulty is is if you look in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Testament and</ENAMEX> and the numbers of places that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX> went out and just simply struck down and that was part of the problem when they went into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promised Land</ENAMEX>
 		that they that they uh they didn't destroy everybody and that that's
 	
 	
 		right
 		right they left a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat the sheep</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 		and that that you know and you i think that's one of those things when we get to Heaven we're going to ask God
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		why did you do it that way
 	
 	
 		but then again though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> the grace pushes you beyond the law you know what i'm saying like so he didn't just say don't kill your don't kill your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> but don't only don't kill them bless them you know
 		and so therefore when we have an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> come against us i really feel like
 		but i really feel like i know i do feel this strongly that when if we had someone come and attack us the best way to handle it
 		would be to bless them and humbly go to their other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> or the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> and say what have we done to offend you
 		what can we do to rectify this situation
 		and that God would move in that sovereignly and he would get the glory though no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">no Bush</ENAMEX> wouldn't
 	
 	
 		what do you
 	
 	
 		because it wouldn't make any sense you know what i'm saying it'd look absolutely ridiculously stupid but it would work out because
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if you follow the scriptural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> it's going to work out because those are that's
 		the best way to do it you know but the thing is is that then God gets the glory not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> and i think that's a problem for a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> is they want the glory
 	
 	
 		well and i i and even at the even at the local level when somebody's assaulted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what do you do turn the other cheek
 	
 	
 		no well i believe personally i hope i
 		this is where everyone always says my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> always goes through that i go yeah for one if someone broke in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i would pray that i would have this faith to to to take authority over that
 		and i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have done that i mean i know that there have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> break in their homes
 		and just say i bind you in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> name your  i just and rebuke any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> because i believe it's a spiritual war that's going on
 		and it's not normal for someone to come into someone elses home illegally that's not normal
 		there's something going on there and that i would have discernment by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spirit</ENAMEX> to be able to pray over that
 		do you see what i mean and then the same in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> you would you wouldn't handle <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> the same way you would handle uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i just i have a problem with all the killing but i'm not a new ager i don't believe
 		means that i am not for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> world government i'm not for all these new age things i  i don't have a problem with uh
 		national identity and i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and having different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> and all of this
 		but i am concerned about the killing that went on there because i just feel like God has a better way to handle it than that and
 		
 		
 	