
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		all right there we go
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		so what's what's your prediction on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i don't know about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> but
 		well actually <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>'s gonna to do pretty good i think they'll go to the finals
 	
 	
 		i mean my gosh uh look who <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> beat to get to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> i mean they they beat uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> was good i can't believe
 	
 	
 		and they beat and they beat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> they beat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> they creamed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i can't
 		yeah i can't believe they beat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> would go all the way to the finals
 	
 	
 		well i i thought so too they they just had a letdown in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half</TIMEX> and they couldn't recover
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		well UNLV they say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNLV</ENAMEX> may be the greatest amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> ever
 	
 	
 		they beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>'s  ass last year
 	
 	
 		yeah big time i i'll bet they could hold their own in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		think so really
 	
 	
 		seriously
 		i i bet there're some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> they could beat
 	
 	
 		yeah like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hornets</ENAMEX>  anyone can beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hornets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah possibly
 		yeah actually i'm kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> myself
 	
 	
 		yeah me too i like uh
 		oh the
 		um
 		Magic
 	
 	
 		oh yeah him and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Worthy</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AC Green</ENAMEX>'s pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah he's good coming off the bench now of course the other they got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Perkins</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that that helps
 	
 	
 		i'm not much of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA NBA</ENAMEX> fan
 		myself
 	
 	
 		oh okay well you remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Perkins</ENAMEX> when he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> don't you
 	
 	
 		oh no sure don't
 	
 	
 		see he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammate</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Worthy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the three</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> were  the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pillars of the national championship team <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> had back in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX> i think when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> was just a freshman
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah didn't know that
 	
 	
 		yeah in fact uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> hit the winning basket to win by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point
 		with like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> to go
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		they they gave him the ball he took the shot if he makes it he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> if he misses it he's a goat he made it
 	
 	
 		huh
 		well he made it
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		hm hm so how about what do you think who do you think's gonna win the final
 	
 	
 		well i really don't think anybody anybody can beat UNLV they they might beat themselves but i don't know they're at such a high level of intensity
 	
 	
 		yeah i watched the
 	
 	
 		they they would have to have a really off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> and somebody else would have to have a really on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> and if that if both of those happened at the same time
 		you might have an upset
 	
 	
 		yeah they can keep on the pressure all the whole game
 	
 	
 		yep yep they're absolutely relentless
 	
 	
 		pretty good
 	
 	
 		well they're so close to an undefeated undefeated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> they can taste it and they wanna make history so i don't think they're gonna lack for motivation
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		Duke'll be mighty mad though
 	
 	
 		well i mean it's it's no disgrace to lose in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the final four</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well the disgrace they won't lose lose last year
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNLV</ENAMEX>'s kind of in a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> from everybody else it it's kind of similar to back when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX> was winning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> titles in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty seven to seventy three</TIMEX> back then they they called the invitational
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 		with Kareem
 	
 	
 		well with him yeah and with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Walton</ENAMEX>
 		and they used to call it the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX> invitational
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because they figured everybody else is just coming to just to be there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		been a while since they had the straight winner
 	
 	
 		yeah i i don't know that any one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s gonna be able to dominate for that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> in a row
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		uh partly because the really outstanding many of the really outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> leave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> before they turn seniors
 	
 	
 		yeah like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you don't yeah yeah so you don't really get to keep the the nucleus of your best talent for the whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		well this has been fun i've enjoyed talking with you
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		God bless and you have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> now bye-bye
 	
 	
 		all right you too thanks bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	