
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh
 	
 	
 		uh interestingly enough in my younger days i taught <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> while my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was getting his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> established and i find the changes uh in the school system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think a lot of them very positive
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> since his retirement the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> in nineteen ninety i've gone back to subbing and of course subbing is a very different
 		endeavor than teaching uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		it's very difficult and i've after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost two years</TIMEX> i've become a little bit disillusioned and i'm not real sure that
 		i'm going to go back to it because uh
 		of discipline uh although i've never had a problem with it i guess i've just gotten a little tired of fighting
 	
 	
 		yeah what what do you said you think there're some improvements what do you think the improvements have been
 	
 	
 		i think uh the quality of education in the high school system here is better i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> that we have now are more professional
 		and i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are more education minded than they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i think the problems that i see in the system uh are i i tend to see more in uh
 		large inner city school districts
 		that uh
 		and i've i've noticed that uh suburban or rural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> tend to have much fewer problems at least what i from what i hear than than than the inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> school districts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i think the problem isn't so much the school system as in the things that go on around it
 	
 	
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> itself that spill over so to speak
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum well my my personal opinion is that so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> especially those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who are in a lower income and have to
 		spend more of their energy on work
 		they say okay well i i don't have to teach my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> anything the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s going to do it for me and i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> can't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> can only exist as something to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> out not something to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i find that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> uses the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> as an excuse and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> as an excuse however
 	
 	
 		um that that can be yeah
 	
 	
 		we're in uh as i said a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WASP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> with a student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> in the high school so the setting is very different than it would be in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> or even <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> which is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple hours</TIMEX> south of us
 		uh but to me
 		the
 		the more gifted or the higher intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are more geared to learning than they were they're more into the school system than they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> and uh i find the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Say No to Drugs</ENAMEX> campaign here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to be i think very effective unless i have my head in the sand
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah um
 		that you know kind of goes along it it it's a small enough <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can know each other and and they can work together to thwart off problems when when you've got a high school with you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um there's just no it's it's very difficult to keep track of them all
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh sure there are high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> as large as our community
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which makes a totally different situation
 		i've i've never felt that pouring more tax dollars in was the answer to solving any school problems or most of the school problems
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah the i i find that i i haven't seen any cases where that's been very effective and that seems to be what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to do is just you know put more money into it
 		and i just don't have a whole lot of confidence in that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i also you know i consider for example the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Education Association</ENAMEX> you know they
 		i would like to see them be more of a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> rather than a union
 		because we need you know we need to we need to uh instead of worrying about saving jobs or raising salaries i think we need to worry about uh how well the job's getting done
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> isn't that the way with most groups though they become a self-protection thing uh of saving jobs or getting more salary uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i do i do find that
 		the majority the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> are very professional but then of course we're a stable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and many of them have been in the system for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> which i just can't think you'd find that in a large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> school
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh but you know back to the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> i my my personal feelings is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> need to be taking more responsibility
 		i think the way i like to look at it you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> look at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> whose job is it to teach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> well it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s job i think whose job is it to teach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> well primarily it's the parents job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> spend more time with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> than they spend at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is just there to help the parents
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i think the the number one responsibility is on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of the parents and and we need to get to the idea well if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are
 		are doing poorly in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> need to take some sort of responsibility and and take some sort of action instead of
 		just complaining about what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is doing or not doing and sometimes
 		if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> don't like the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is being run the appropriate action is to have the choice to take that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> out of that school and put him in a different school
 	
 	
 		except we don't have another school
 	
 	
 		yeah that's in in small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> that's a difficult choice but then the small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> are the ones with fewer problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		because they have fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> that have these kind of problems and there i like to see that the parents be able to have a choice saying i don't like the way this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is being run i want to send my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to someplace where they'll be properly uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		properly taught and properly uh trained
 	
 	
 		you don't find that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are getting more involved in your area
 	
 	
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are but some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> don't have the opportunity to do that as easily you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are working <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> jobs or single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> uh that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i think single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> probably contribute a lot of the problems in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> because the system's really getting <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">sixty percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>'s day
 		if if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> certainly would have to work and they're not getting home until probably <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five o'clock</TIMEX> at the very earliest and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>'s out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think really uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> does have more of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>'s time because <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours</TIMEX> of the time that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> is with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> they're going to be sleeping and certainly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> needs some social life besides uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and you know what it feels like to come home after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long day</TIMEX> at work you you just you you want to rest for a little while and and maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh don't want you to rest
 	
 	
 		they might need to be dealt with yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and it's it's a difficult problem and it's one that
 		well basically i think in in in large measure it's it's it's up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to take the responsibility for what's happening
 		to their childrens education i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh And we did have we did recently have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> here formed called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Excellence</ENAMEX>
 		that was formed by concerned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and they see that these these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are getting honor jackets and they're getting certificates and they're getting uh more access to scholarships uh on a par
 		with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> which uh this was formed i think probably in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three years</TIMEX> and that's been a very positive thing for education itself because so often the emphasis is on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">uh baseball basketball and football</ENAMEX> and it gets away from what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is established for originally
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes and here here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> if you don't like football y ou're considered a heretic
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well this is basketball in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yes  that was going to be my guess
 	
 	
 		uh-huh We do all have our sport In fact we've been on a real high here because our <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> won their regional for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in the history of the school So sport is uh
 		has been really <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and foremost here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last month</TIMEX> But we hope that education is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and foremost for the year
 		nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		alright well thank you for the call
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> bye
 	
 	
 		bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	