
  
  
    
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recommended Hotels</ENAMEX>
        Hotel prices in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lisbon</ENAMEX> have risen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> to match
        most western <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> destinations, even surpassing popular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> like
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barcelona</ENAMEX> at the top levels. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> offer special packages (such
        as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> or weekend reductions).
        Central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lisbon</ENAMEX> covers the area from the waterfront, Bairro
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lapa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avenida da Liberdade</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Lisbon</ENAMEX> refers to the area
        around and beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Praça Marquês de Pombal</ENAMEX>. Pousadas, found beyond
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisbon</ENAMEX>, are government-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">inns</ENAMEX>; the ones listed occupy
        historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> are usually among the town’s
        best.
        The price indication given is for a double <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, with
        breakfast, including service and taxes (currently <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> of room
        price) in high <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> (generally <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">April–October</ENAMEX>).
        $$$$$<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 40,000</NUMEX> esc
        $$$$<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30,000–40,000 esc</NUMEX>
        $$$<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20,000–30,000 esc</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$$12,000–20,000</NUMEX> esc
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$</NUMEX> below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> esc
      
    
  
