
  
  
    
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recommended Hotels</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balearics</ENAMEX> were formally a maze of down-market concrete
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block hotels</ENAMEX> brutally clustered right on top of once-pristine beaches
        and coves.<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the trend is toward providing more discerning travelers
        with more authentic and upscale accommodations, frequently in old
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">farmhouses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">manor houses</ENAMEX>, as well as short- and long-term rentals.
        Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> on both islands are still beholden to the large tour
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>. Only a couple of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX> recommended below host
        tour <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>; we make no effort to review the block-booked resort
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotels</ENAMEX>, most of which are resoundingly similar in service, amenities,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>.
        You are advised to book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> well in advance, particularly
        if planning to visit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between June and September</TIMEX>. Regardless of when you
        go, it’s not wise to descend on either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> without reservations
        intact. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> close for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December-March</TIMEX>). As a basic guide
        to room prices, we have used the following symbols (for a double room
        with bath/shower in high <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>; prices do not include the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VAT</ENAMEX>, or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IVA</ENAMEX>, tax):
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$</NUMEX>below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,000</NUMEX> pta.
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$$8,000</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> pta.
        $$$<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15,000-22,000 pta</NUMEX>.
        $$$$above <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">22,000 pta</NUMEX>.
        Spain’s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> code is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX>; the area code for the Balearics
        is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">971</NUMEX>.
      
    
  
