
  
  
    
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recommended Hotels</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX> listed below offer a cross-section of
        local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and should convince you that not everything on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island</ENAMEX> comes with chips (french fries).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> rating in brackets after each entry refers to the
        offfical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> rating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>.
        As a basic guide, the symbols we use indicate what you can
        expect to pay for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-course meal for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, excluding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, tax and
        tip. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drinks</ENAMEX> will add considerably to the final bill.
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">âœªless than 5,000 ptas</NUMEX>.
        âœªâœ<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ª5,000â€“8,000 ptas</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">âœªâœªâœªmore</ENAMEX> than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,000</NUMEX> ptas.
      
    
  
