
  
  
    
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akko</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Acre</ENAMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm Beach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Country Club ââ</ENAMEX>-âââ <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Akko Beach</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">04</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">912 891</NUMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">04</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">910 434</NUMEX>. Acreâ€™s finest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lodgings</ENAMEX>, with a beach
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> clubâ€™s excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        Caesarea
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Caesarea âââ Caesarea</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">626 9111</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) 626
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9122</TIMEX>. By the beach, in its own lovely grounds, next to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israelâ</ENAMEX>€™s only
        18-hole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX>, this is a sports-loverâ€™s paradise. Swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pool</ENAMEX>,
        tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, and many other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">114</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        Eilat
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americana ââ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Beach</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">633 3777</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) 633
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4174</TIMEX>. A popular, well-located <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> with helpful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, swimming pool,
        gym, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sauna</ENAMEX>, and jacuzzi. Live entertainment every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">137</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Eilat</ENAMEX> ââââ <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Beach</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">362 222</NUMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) 362
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">333</NUMEX>. Eilatâ€™s newest and most luxurious hotel (completed at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>) with every imaginable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>,
        virtual-reality <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">simulators</ENAMEX>, and lots for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">382</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gazit Menachem</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bed-and-Breakfast</ENAMEX>) â <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eilat Town</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>)
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">633 3326</TIMEX>. Simple, comfortable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> in the centre of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, a short walk
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Beach</ENAMEX>. It is run by a friendly and helpful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">townâ€™s Tourist Information Centre</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>. You can book at the tourist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Riviera Apartment Hotel ââ</ENAMEX>-âââ <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Beach</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) 633
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3944</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">633 3939</TIMEX>. This smart, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-storey <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> is ideal for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> on a relatively tight budget, and offers a large swimming pool
        and childrenâ€™s play areas. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">172</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Beach</ENAMEX> ââââ <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Beach</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">636 8888</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>)
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">636 8811</TIMEX>. Luxurious recent addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eilat</ENAMEX> with large well-equipped
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rooms</ENAMEX>, many with wonderful views across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf of Aqaba</ENAMEX>. Beautiful
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool</ENAMEX> area with waterfalls. Also health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sauna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> bath,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jacuzzi</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX>, and disco. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">375</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        Orchid ââââ <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coral Beach</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">636 0360</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) 637
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5323</TIMEX>. Charming low-rise <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">â€œThai Villageâ</ENAMEX>€ with cobbled paths, waterfalls,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, and stylish â€œvillage-houseâ€ accommodation, each with
        its own verandah. Ask to be set back as far as possible from the main
        road for the best views and least traffic noise. Fitness <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sauna</ENAMEX>,
        Thai massage, free use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">132 bungalows.</TIMEX>
        Haifa
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Carmel ââââ</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">87</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ha Nassi Avenue</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">04</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">830 6306</TIMEX>, fax
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">04</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">838 7504</TIMEX>. Tops in every sense in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haifa</ENAMEX>, with wonderful views over
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and bay. Most of the usual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, including a charming
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">garden</ENAMEX>, swimming pool, and health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pub</ENAMEX>, restaurant. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">220</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dvir ââ 124 Yefe Nof Street</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">04</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">838 9131</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">04</NUMEX>)
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">838 1068</TIMEX>. The location of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> is excellent, affording as it does
        great views from the front-facing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> (donâ€™t book accommodation in
        the annex if possible). This is one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dan Hotel</ENAMEX> training <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>,
        so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youâ€™ll</ENAMEX> find that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> try a bit harder. Access to swimming
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Colony Hotel</ENAMEX> âââ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Vincent</ENAMEX>, off <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nablus Road</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">627 9777</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">627 9779</TIMEX>. Arguably the
        most atmospheric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> in the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, occupying a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pashaâ</ENAMEX>€™s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">palace</ENAMEX> that dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Facilities</ENAMEX> and attractions include a
        swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pool</ENAMEX>, beautiful gardens, and a tranquil <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> open for
        breakfast, lunch, and dinner. Open-air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, poolside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, dining
        room. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Rooms</ENAMEX> are decorated in either traditional or modern styles. The
        superior <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> are well worth the extra charge. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beit Shmuel ââ 13 King David Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Jerusalem</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">620 3456</TIMEX>. This is a large and modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orthodox Jewish</ENAMEX> cultural
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centre</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>-house complex which enjoys an excellent location with
        good views of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>. There is a friendly atmosphere and staff
        are helpful. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Christ Church Guest House â Opposite the Citadel</ENAMEX>, Jaffa
        Gate, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">627 7727</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">627 7730</TIMEX>. Popular haunt
        with budget travellers. The atmosphere is friendly, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> are
        basic but clean. Breakfast included in the price of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. 32
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King David ââââ</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King David Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Jerusalem</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">620 8888</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">620 8880</TIMEX>. Israelâ€™s best accommodation option,
        according to many travellers, and usually the first stopping place for
        visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. There is a charming <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Old-World</ENAMEX> atmosphere in
        the reception <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>. Ask for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX> walls. The
        grounds and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> are very beautiful, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> also include a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fitness centre</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">257</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lev Yerushalayim Aparthotel</ENAMEX> âââ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">530 0333</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">623 2432</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lev Yerushalayim</ENAMEX> is a
        modern block with well-equipped and spacious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>, situated only
        a short walk from the heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New City</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notre Dame Centre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Guest House Section â Opposite New Gate</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Jerusalem</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">627 9111</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">627 1995</TIMEX>. This
        is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX> guest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, but it is open to everyone. The rooms
        are simple and comfortable, popular with budget travellers. Some rooms
        have balconies. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> has been beautifully restored, and the
        food is good. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palatin Hotel</ENAMEX> ââ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Agrippas Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Jerusalem</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">623 1141</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">625 9323</TIMEX>. This quiet and small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> (with both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">air-conditioning</ENAMEX> and TV in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>) is situated very close to the
        heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New City</ENAMEX>. One notable feature is the contemporary art
        featured in public areas and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX>. Room price includes breakfast.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Andrewâ€™s</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hospice â 1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kikar David Remez</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) 673
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2401</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">673 1711</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Andrewâ€™s Hospice</ENAMEX> occupies a great location
        overlooking the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>, not far from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Khan Theatre</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinematheque</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> are basic but comfortable; there are lovely
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gardens</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> are friendly. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA East Aelia Capitolina</ENAMEX> ââ <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">29 Nablus Road</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">628 6888</TIMEX>, fax <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">627</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6301</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> are quite plain
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA East</ENAMEX> may lack the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA West</ENAMEX>, but it is
        still very good value in a peaceful setting. Good range of sports
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>, which include a swimming pool and squash <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. Dining
        room, grill, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">109</NUMEX> beds (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">balconies</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA West</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arches Hotel</ENAMEX>) ââ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King David Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">569 2692</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">623 5192</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bedrooms</ENAMEX> and public
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> with plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> lie inside this splendid landmark
        building dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>. There is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> and a delightful
        front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCAâ</ENAMEX>€ˆWest also has an indoor swimming pool, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> tennis
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> squash <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sauna</ENAMEX>, basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, and a fitness <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
        Price includes breakfast. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        Near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mizpe Ramat Rachel âââ D. N. Isfon Yehuda</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9900</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>)
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">670 2555</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">673 3155</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the best kibbutz <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, the Mitzpe
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramat Rachel</ENAMEX> occupies a pleasant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> overlooking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judean Hills</ENAMEX>, yet is within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a short</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10-minute</TIMEX> drive of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalemâ€™s Old</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>. Swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pool</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sauna</ENAMEX>, and fitness <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MitZpe Ramon</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramon Inn ââ-âââ</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ein Akev Street</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">658 8822</TIMEX>, fax
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">658 8151</TIMEX>. This new <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4-storey</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> uses local furnishings, fabrics,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> in a successful attempt to create a sympathetic harmony with
        its stunning natural setting. There is a choice of excellent local
        ethnic cuisine. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Apartments</ENAMEX> also available. Access to local swimming
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>.
        NAHARIYA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Panorama ââ 8 Haâ€™ Maâ€™apilim Street</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">04</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">992 0555</TIMEX>. A
        low-rise block with fine sea views from its roof-top <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Facilities</ENAMEX> include a pool. Note: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> may be obligatory during
        high season.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Netanya</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Maxim Hotel ââ 8 King David Street</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">09</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">862 1062</TIMEX>, fax
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">09</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">862 0190</TIMEX>. The renovated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Maxim Hotel</ENAMEX> offers good-quality,
        comfortable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, including several reasonably-priced <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suites</ENAMEX>,
        which are handy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. There are sea views from some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and
        there is also a swimming pool. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        Safed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rimon Inn âââ Artistsâ</ENAMEX>€™ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Quarter</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">920 666</NUMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>)
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">692 0456</TIMEX>. Arguably the bestâ€‚â€”â€‚and perhaps the most <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">historicâ€‚â€”â€‚hotel</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX>, with parts dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX>. There are splendid
        views, a swimming pool, and extensive grounds. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Armon Ha-Yarkon ââ 268 Ha-Yarkon Street</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) 605
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5271</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">605 8485</TIMEX>. This is a small modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, situated
        opposite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX>, across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from the beach, and close to the
        nightspots of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> ââââ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ha-Yarkon Street</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) 520
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2525</TIMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fax</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">524 9755</TIMEX>. It looks dated, but this rainbow-painted
        beachside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> is still reputed to be the finest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> are particularly comfortable, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> are friendly, and there
        is a choice of indoor or outdoor swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX>. Special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX> for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sea</ENAMEX>-view <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">285</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Moriah Plaza</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> âââ-ââââ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">155 Ha-Yarkon Street</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">527 1515</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">527 1065</TIMEX>. This modern high-rise block is
        situated on the beach. It may be the recipient of few architectural
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accolades</ENAMEX>, but its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> are comfortable and very well furnished. The
        staff are friendly and there is a swimming pool. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">346</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Moss Hotel â-ââ 6 Nes Ziona Street</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. and fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) 517
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1655</TIMEX>. This is a fairly well-equipped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> in a central location with
        its own parking (a great asset hereabouts). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiberias</ENAMEX> and the Galilee
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of Scotland Hospice â Tiberias</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">672 3769</TIMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fax</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">679 0145</TIMEX>. Comfortable modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> are offered in unusual
        black <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basalt buildings</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of Scotland Hospice</ENAMEX>, which was
        constructed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century ago</TIMEX> as a missionary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. A friendly welcome
        and a pleasant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garden</ENAMEX> and private beach help to ensure that this place
        continues to be popular. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golan ââ 14 Ahad Ha-Am Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tiberias</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) 679
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">672 1905</TIMEX>. This appealing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> offers excellent value
        with wonderful views over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea of Galilee</ENAMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> include a
        swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pool</ENAMEX> and a peaceful garden. Dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kibbutz Ein Gev Holiday Village</ENAMEX> ââ <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 mile</NUMEX> ) south of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ein Gev Kibbutz</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">665 8027</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">675 1590</TIMEX>. These modern
        cabins come with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>, and air-conditioning, are set on
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea of GaliÂ­lee</ENAMEX>, and make ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> holiday <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. There is a
        good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>, in addition to a well-stocked
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mini</ENAMEX>-market for self-catering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">100 cabins.</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kfar Hanassi Village ââ Near Rosh Pinna</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) 691
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4870</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">691 4077</TIMEX>. Comfortable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> with en <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite bathrooms</ENAMEX>,
        kitchenettes, refrigerators, and TV in lodges set amidst wide <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX> and
        comfortable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> for relaxation or BBQ. Breakfast served in
        dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> of kibbutz. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mizpe Hayamim ââ Safed-Rosh Pinna Road</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rosh Pinna</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">693 7013</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">693 7191</TIMEX>. Set in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12 hectares</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 acres</NUMEX>) of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forest</ENAMEX>, this charming small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> hotel enjoys marvellous views over
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea of Galilee</ENAMEX>. Its healthy-living philosophy offers home-made
        organic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> plus a wholesome diet of massage, yoga, and specialist
        exercise classes. If that is not enough, there are also swimming pool,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jacuzzi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sauna</ENAMEX>, and gymnasium. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nof Ginnosar</ENAMEX> ââ <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 miles</NUMEX>) north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tiberias</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>)
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">679 2161</TIMEX>, fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">679 2170</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nof Ginnosar</ENAMEX> enjoys the reputation of
        being one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israelâ</ENAMEX>€™s best kibbutz accommodations, situated right on
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea of Galilee</ENAMEX> and set in its own gardens. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Facilities</ENAMEX> offered
        include tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and a private beach. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">watersports</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX>
        there is a good selection of kayaks, windsurfers, and sailing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> for
        hire. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vered Ha-Galil â-ââ Korazim-Almagor Junction</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">18 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX>) north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tiberias</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">693 5785</TIMEX>. This
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">ranch-</ENAMEX>restaurant-guest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is something of a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>, not
        to mention a novelty. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vered Ha-Galil</ENAMEX> offers the perfect base for a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Galilee</ENAMEX> riding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX>, in charming rustic accommodation. The cooking
        is good and filling and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> are friendly (heâ€™s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akko</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Acre</ENAMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Christo ââ-âââ Fishermenâ</ENAMEX>€™s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">04</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">910 065</NUMEX>. You
        can choose between the pleasant dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and the waterfront
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">terrace</ENAMEX>. A reputation for serving the best <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> in town.
        Eilat
        Country Chicken â The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Center</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">637 1312</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donâ€™t</ENAMEX> let the name or rather bland modern appearance put you off; this
        is good-value, down-to-earth <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> cooking like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Momma</ENAMEX> used to make (a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rarity</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eilat</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fried</ENAMEX> country <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soups</ENAMEX>, and grills are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">specialities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosher</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eddieâ€™s Hideaway ââ-âââ 68 Almogim Street</ENAMEX>, off Eilot
        Street; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">637 1137</TIMEX>. Eilatâ€™s best-known <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> has been
        serving an inventive menu of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and seafood dishes (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>,
        shrimp, and pepper steak specialities) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 20 years</TIMEX>. They serve
        dinner only. Another treat is the free <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> from your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> that they
        provide.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Gaucho âââ Arava Road; Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">633 1549</TIMEX>. Here the beef
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">steaks</ENAMEX>, veal, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> are cooked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Argentinian</ENAMEX> style, and then
        carved and served in generous portions by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> dressed in Gaucho
        costume. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chefs</ENAMEX> are sometimes imported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. The background music (occasionally live) and the special decor
        complete the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> theme.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fishermanâ€™s House</ENAMEX> â <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coral Beach</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">637 9830</TIMEX>. Here
        you can eat all you wish from a buffet of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> dishes, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX>, and various salads. If you want somewhere to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> or
        to take your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, then this is a good place. Excellent value.
        Last <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Refuge ââ</ENAMEX>-âââ <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coral Beach</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">637 3627</TIMEX>. This
        large, smart beachside <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, serving generous portions of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and seafood, is located next to a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">marina</ENAMEX>. Because of the location
        and the restaurantâ€™s popularity, you must reserve a table. Try to book
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pago Pago âââ Lagoon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Beach</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">637 6660</TIMEX>. This
        popular romantic floating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> serves <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>, and
        Far-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> in a relaxed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Seas</ENAMEX> atmosphere.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Onion â North Beach</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Marina</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>)
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">637 7434</TIMEX>. This is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilatâ</ENAMEX>€™s best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dairy restaurant</ENAMEX>, generously serving
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">delicious</ENAMEX> vegetarian dishes and salads in enormous portions.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tandoori ââ-âââ Lagoona Hotel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kingâ€™s Wharf</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) 633
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3879</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popular</ENAMEX>, award-winning, authentic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> cooking in pleasant
        relaxed atmosphere with traditional decor. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Meats</ENAMEX> are specially cooked
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tandoors</TIMEX> (charcoal-fired clay ovens). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX>.
        Buffet lunch. Open <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon to midnight</TIMEX>.
        Haifa
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Yusufâ</ENAMEX>€™s â <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">1 Ha-Meginim Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris Square</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">04</NUMEX>)
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">866 3723</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Grilled meats</ENAMEX>, hummous, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">staples</ENAMEX> are on offer
        at this locally famous, award-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>. Thereâ€™s no <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
        sign; just look for a basic eating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with large windows and arches
        and happy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La ChaumiÃ</ENAMEX>¨re âââ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">40a Ben-Gurion Avenue</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">04</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">853 8563</TIMEX>.
        Superb <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX>, served in an old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Gaucho</ENAMEX> âââ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yefe Nof Street</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">04</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">837 0997</TIMEX>.
        Large portions of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Argentine</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meats</ENAMEX>. See entry under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Eilat</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rondo âââ-ââââ Dan Carmel Hotel</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85-87</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hanassi Avenue</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">04</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">830 6211</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Continental</ENAMEX> cooking is reasonable, but
        the real attraction is the fantastic view of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haifa</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. Window
        seat essential. Dinner only.
        Herzliya
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Gaucho</ENAMEX> âââ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Medinat Hayehudim Street</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">09</NUMEX>) 555
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">037</NUMEX>. Lively <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>. See entry under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Eilat</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitehall Steakhouse</ENAMEX> âââ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mercazim Building</ENAMEX>, Maskit
        Street; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">09</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">580 402</NUMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> swear that these are the best
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steaks</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Help yourself to unlimited <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> from the
        abundant fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Shukri</ENAMEX> â <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Wad Road</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">627 1538</TIMEX>.
        Legendary hummous, with very little else on the menu. Very basic, with
        formica-top tables, but clean and accustomed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. Quick
        service. No <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>. It is open from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8am</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mid-afternoon</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alumah ââ 8 Yaâ€™Avetz Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New City</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">625 5014</TIMEX>.
        Jerusalemâ€™s quintessential dairy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, serving excellent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vegetarian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> dishes in a typical, beautifully restored and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">decorated Jerusalem</ENAMEX> golden-stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, with garden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">patio</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosher</ENAMEX>.
        Closed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabbath</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Colony Hotel ââ Nablus Road</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">627 9778</TIMEX>. Lunch in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the leafy</TIMEX>, peaceful, sunny <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> of this
        famous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pashaâ€™s palace</ENAMEX>, is a sheer delight at any
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, but the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> barbeque (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> only) is something special.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cacao</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cinematheque â-ââ Cinematheque, 1 Hebron Road</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">671 0632</TIMEX>. A vegetarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> serving great <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pasta</ENAMEX>,
        salads, and desserts in a small, modern, arty dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with views of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX> walls. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lively</ENAMEX>, young, buzzing atmosphere. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosher</ENAMEX>.
        The (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loaves</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fishes</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coffee Shop â Opposite Citadel</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jaffa Gate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">628 6812</TIMEX>. Small pine-panelled cafÃ©
        serving excellent cakes, salads, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soups</ENAMEX> to foot-weary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>.
        Young, friendly, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, quiet relaxing atmosphere to soothe
        your nerves after a day in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Gaucho</ENAMEX> âââ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rivlin Street</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">624 2227</TIMEX>. Lively
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>. See entry under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eilat</ENAMEX> on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">138</NUMEX>. This one is
        housed in a stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interior arches</ENAMEX> and flagstone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosher</ENAMEX>. Closed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kamin ââ-âââ 4 Rabbi Akiva Street</ENAMEX>, off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hillel Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">625 6428</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delightful</ENAMEX>, typical old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> stone house
        with a charming garden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX>. Mixture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dairy restaurant</ENAMEX> and
        international meat dishes, with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> flavour.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kohinoor ââ-âââ Holiday Inn Crown Plaza; Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">581 367</NUMEX>.
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tandoori</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, serving excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
        tandoori dishes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosher</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mishkenot Shaâ€™ananim ââââ Yemin Moshe</ENAMEX>, steps below the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windmill</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">625 1042</TIMEX>. Israelâ€™s finest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>,
        boasting the countryâ€™s largest wine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cellar</ENAMEX>. You can have a business
        lunch of heavenly tastes at down-to-earth prices. Reserve a window seat
        for views of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX> walls.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Oceanus ââââ 7 Rivlin Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New City</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">624 0863</TIMEX>.
        This small, stylish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in an atmospheric, century-old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is
        said to serve the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and shellfish in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. Splash out with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish baked</ENAMEX> in the taboon, or bouillabaisse. Closed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4â</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">€“7pm</TIMEX>.
        Off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Square ââ 8 Ramban Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New City</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) 566
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5956</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pleasant</ENAMEX>, informal dairy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in an old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> with a
        lovely large <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> patio. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosher</ENAMEX>. Closed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabbath</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosemary ââ</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King David Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Jerusalem</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>)
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">625 8157</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popular</ENAMEX>, informal dairy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> with an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> bias
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">â€‚â€”â€‚good pizzas</ENAMEX>, interesting pasta dishes. Eat out on the tree-shaded
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">terrace</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosher</ENAMEX>. Closed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabbath</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tavlin ââ 16 Yoel Salomon Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New City</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) 624
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3847</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Relaxing</ENAMEX>, friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dairy restaurant</ENAMEX> serving good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pies</ENAMEX>, crÃªpes,
        salads, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> in a rustic old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. It has a small seating area
        upstairs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosher</ENAMEX>. Closed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabbath</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Tsriff ââ-âââ YMCA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King David Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">623 1154</TIMEX>. Choose from the inexpensive trendy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cafeteria</ENAMEX>, the charming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Deco</ENAMEX> dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> (more extensive and
        expensive menu), or the front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX>. International cuisine with many
        interesting dishes; the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pies</ENAMEX> are a house speciality.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yemenite Step ââ 10 Yoel Salomon Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New City</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">624 0477</TIMEX>. The oldest and most authentic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yemenite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX>, serving excellent mellawachs (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pancakes</ENAMEX>). Eat in the modern dining
        room of this old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or out on the busy street watching the nightly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promenade</ENAMEX>. Finish off with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yemenite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosher</ENAMEX>. Closed on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabbath</ENAMEX>.
        Nahariya
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore ââ Ha Meyasdim</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">04</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">992 9029</TIMEX>. Youâ€™re spoilt
        for choice at this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> where the menu runs to over
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> items. You should try the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> specials and you must not miss
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX>. Closed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3â</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">€“7pm</TIMEX>.
        Nazareth
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astoria ââ Casa Nova Street; Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">573 497</NUMEX>. This
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurant</ENAMEX> provides a good menu of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> meat dishes,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">specialising</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX>.
        Safed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pinati ââ 81 Jerusalem Street</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">692 0855</TIMEX>. Hearty
        portions of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> are served here, with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX> and veal dishes
        prominent on the menu.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>/Jaffa
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alhambra âââ 30 Jerusalem Boulevard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jaffa</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) 683
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4453</TIMEX>. Donâ€™t be put off by the less-than-salubrious location. This

        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurant</ENAMEX>, serving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX>, is one of the best in the area.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Baobab âââ 43 Ahad Ha-Am Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) 566
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">331</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the trendiest and most delightful places in town, serving
        excellent, innovative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> and international nouvelle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eternity â 60 Ben Yehuda Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) 203
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">151</NUMEX>. This interesting place, run by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Hebrews</ENAMEX> (a sect from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.A.</ENAMEX>), serves the most inventive vegan <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> in town.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Gaucho</ENAMEX> âââ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pinsker Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) 528
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3788</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of popular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Argentine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. See entry under
        Eilat on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">138</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosher</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fishermenâ€™s Restaurant âââ Jaffa Port; Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">681 3870</TIMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the oldest eating places in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX>, with a pleasant
        Mediterranean atmosphere and some excellent specials.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Michelâ€™s Aladin ââ 5</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mifratz Shlomo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Jaffa</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>)
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">682 6766</TIMEX>. An <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">800-year-old</TIMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hamman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> bath) on Old Jaffa
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea Mosque</ENAMEX>, overlooking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>, is the marvellous
        setting for this young, popular cafÃ©-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX>, salads, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kassit ââ 117 Dizengoff Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) 522
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3855</TIMEX>. Unfortunately <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> no longer patronise the
        Kassit, but it is still one of the best cafÃ©-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> to be found on
        Dizengoff Street. Friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hearty Sabbath</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shaulâ€™s Inn ââ-âââ 11 Eliashiv Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yemenite Quarter</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">517 7619</TIMEX>. This is a colourful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern-Yemenite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> (where the downstairs is expensive, and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">upstairs</ENAMEX> is less formal) with an interesting menu of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and offal.
        Not for the squeamish. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosher</ENAMEX>. Closed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabbath</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tandoori ââ-âââ Dizengoff Square</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) 296
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">185</NUMEX>. See entry under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eilat</ENAMEX> on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">138</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitehall Steakhouse âââ</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mendele Street</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) 524
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9282</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tel Avivâ€™s favourite</ENAMEX> steakhouse. See entry under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herzliya</ENAMEX> on page
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">139</NUMEX>.
        Tiberias
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guy</ENAMEX> ââ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ha-Galil Street</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">672 3036</TIMEX>. Here you can
        enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and vegetable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">specialities</ENAMEX> in a friendly
        atmosphere. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosher</ENAMEX>. Closed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabbath</ENAMEX>.
        Kafkas ââ By the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Mosque</ENAMEX>. This unusual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> is
        run by recently-arrived <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">emigrÃ©s</ENAMEX>, producing tasty, filling
        Central <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karamba ââ Waterfront Promenade</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">06</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">679 1546</TIMEX>. A
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pleasant fish</ENAMEX> and vegetarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> with a nice atmosphere,
        inventive dishes, outdoor dining; open very late.
      
    
  
