
  
  
    
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recommended Hotels</ENAMEX>
        The following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> are listed alphabetically in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
        price categories, grouped according to regions within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
        area and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange County</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> are of a high standard, with private
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bath</ENAMEX>, air-conditioning, television, and telephone; most have king- or
        queen-sized beds. Breakfast is not usually included at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US hotels</ENAMEX>,
        except on executive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> and at some budget <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">motels</ENAMEX> that offer morning
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, orange juice, and doughnuts or muffins.
        To make direct reservations with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, we have included
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">addresses</ENAMEX> (all in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, abbreviated CA) and telephone/fax
        numbers. Check-out time is generally <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1pm</TIMEX>, with check-in usually
        available from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2pm</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3pm</TIMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> accept major credit cards.
        Rates vary greatly according to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> and availability;
        many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> offer special weekend packages, business rates, and
        promotions. Ask about such discounts when booking. We have used the
        following symbols to indicate room prices (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> in a double
        room, per <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>):
        ❁❁❁<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> and up
        ❁❁<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100–$200</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">❁under $100</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
