
  
  
    
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recommended Hotels</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> has some of the most luxurious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> in the
        world, with representatives from all the major international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotels</ENAMEX> listed below have full air-conditioning, offer <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-hour</TIMEX> or
        limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">room service</ENAMEX>, and a wide range of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>
        have excellent business services and conference <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>; many have
        shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>.
        Reservations are strongly recommended, particularly in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> and at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. If you do arrive without making advance
        arrangements, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong Kong Hotel Reservation Center</ENAMEX> at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">International Airport</ENAMEX> will be happy to arrange accommodations for you
        on your arrival.
        As a basic guide, the symbols below have been used to
        indicate high-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> rates in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> dollars, based on double
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">occupancy</ENAMEX>, with bath or shower. Unless otherwise noted, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> take all
        major credit cards. A <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> service charge and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> government tax will be
        added to the bill.
        $$$$<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">above HK$2,500</NUMEX>
        $$<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$HK$l,600 to HK$2,500</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$$HK$950 to HK$1,600</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$below HK$950</NUMEX>
      
    
  
