
  
  
    
      
        A‚ÄàBRIEF‚ÄàHISTORY
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> has always been a melange of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>. Apart from some
        pre-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ice Age hominids</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> to arrive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> were
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negritos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Proto-Australoids</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Migrants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> stock from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> seem to have made up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dravidians</ENAMEX>, now
        principally in the southern peninsula.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">b.c. agriculturalists</ENAMEX> made their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> appearance up
        in the hills of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baluchistan</ENAMEX> in the northwest. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indus</ENAMEX> river
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">valley</ENAMEX>, improved techniques permitted the storage of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">barley</ENAMEX>
        beyond <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> needs, and so the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harappa</ENAMEX> and Mohenjodaro
        emerged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2300</TIMEX> b.c. , creating a civilization even more
        advanced than that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aryans</ENAMEX> who came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>.
        The sewage system and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> outside the citadel were better
        constructed than their modern equivalents, and among their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> was
        a major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> contribution to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">world‚Äôs cuisine‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe chicken</ENAMEX>.
        Modern archaeology suggests that this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indus Valley</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">civilization</ENAMEX> was destroyed not by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aryan</ENAMEX> conquerors, but by floods, when
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indus</ENAMEX> river changed course, perhaps due to earthquakes, in about
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1700 b.c.</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus‚</ENAMEX>Äô Ancestors
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aryans</ENAMEX> arrived on the scene <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some 200 years later</TIMEX>.
        Originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, they migrated to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mesopotamia</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and
        then on to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> before entering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. These fair-skinned
        cattle-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breeders</ENAMEX>, who saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX> as an especially sacred <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>,
        cultivated agriculture in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab</ENAMEX> after waging war against the
        Dasas, who then became their slaves.
        Early events surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indo-Aryans</ENAMEX> can be deduced from
        the later writings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rig-Veda</ENAMEX> (priestly hymns), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puranas</ENAMEX> (ancient
        tales of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> and gods), and the epic poems of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mahabharata</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramayana</ENAMEX>. These provided the basis for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hinduism</ENAMEX>; also, the epics‚Äô
        heroic battles suggest there was a prolonged struggle for land rights
        over the fertile plains north and east of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>, followed by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">invasions</ENAMEX> and wars.
        If ancient writings give only a romanticized view, they do
        offer a more precise picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aryan</ENAMEX> society. Their long wars
        against the indigenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> established their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> with a
        hereditary divinity, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brahmins</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>) exchanged for a
        privileged position of their own. The caste system was already taking
        shape. Before the conquests, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aryans</ENAMEX> were organized in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
        classes: <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">warriors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>, and commoners. Then they established <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
        distinct categories known as varna (literally, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äúcolor‚Äù</ENAMEX>).
        As possessors of magical power associated with ritual
        sacrifice and sacred utterance, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brahmins</ENAMEX> were the sole interpreters of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vedic</ENAMEX> scriptures. They laid down a social pecking order with
        themselves in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kshatriyas</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX>),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vaishyas</ENAMEX> (cultivators or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shudras</ENAMEX> (serfs and those of
        mixed blood). This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> became more elaborate as the division
        of labor became more complicated, so the growing number of occupational
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were subsequently defined as jati (subcastes), often living in
        separate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caste</ENAMEX> would preserve its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúpurity‚Äù</ENAMEX> by avoiding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intermarriage</ENAMEX> and not sharing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> with other castes. Outside these
        were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Untouchables</ENAMEX>, those of aboriginal descent.
        By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">600 b.c.</TIMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indo-Aryans</ENAMEX> had formed monarchies in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ganga</ENAMEX> plain, surrounded by smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> resisting the Brahmanic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">orthodoxy</ENAMEX> and its authoritarianism. Within the monarchies, thinkers
        took to the asceticism which has characterized spiritual life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brahmins</ENAMEX> cannily countered this threat by absorbing the new ideas
        into their teachings. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> were less amenable and so became
        the breeding ground for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new religions espousing non-violence,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jainism</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX>.
        While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> fought for control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ganga valley</ENAMEX>, new
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invaders</ENAMEX> appeared at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India‚</ENAMEX>Äôs frontiers; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Persia</ENAMEX>,
        crossed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu Kush</ENAMEX> mountains into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indus valley</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">530 b.c.</TIMEX>
        While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brahman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> exchanged ideas, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> copied
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> coin system. Rock inscriptions left by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darius</ENAMEX>
        probably inspired the pillar-edicts of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashoka</ENAMEX> in the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> b.c.
        The spectacular invasion by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander the Great</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">326 b.c.</TIMEX> ended <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> presence, but apart from opening up
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia Minor</ENAMEX> and the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> left no
        lasting impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the two-year</TIMEX> campaign.
        Alexander‚Äôs dreams of a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> extending eastwards
        across the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ganga</ENAMEX> plain were blocked by mutinous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> fed up with
        upset stomachs, the harsh terrain, and the tough <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> military
        opposition. He returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylon</ENAMEX>, leaving a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frontier</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashoka‚Äôs Empire</ENAMEX>
        Meanwhile, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ganga</ENAMEX> valley power struggle, Magadha
        (modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bihar</ENAMEX>) emerged as the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX>, Chandragupta
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maurya</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">321‚Äì297 b.c.</ENAMEX> ), was also to become the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India‚Äôs</ENAMEX> first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imperial</ENAMEX> dynasty with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataliputra</ENAMEX> (modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patna</ENAMEX>), the world‚Äôs largest
        city at the time, as its capital.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chandragupta</ENAMEX> extended his rule to the northwest with a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rigorous</ENAMEX> campaign against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seleucus Nikator</ENAMEX>. It
        ended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a profitable</TIMEX> marriage alliance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX>, but later
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chandragupta</ENAMEX> turned to more sober thoughts: he converted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jainism</ENAMEX>,
        and finally starved to death at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sravanabelagola</ENAMEX>.
        His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bindusara</ENAMEX> combined his father‚Äôs ambition with a
        taste for the good life and philosophy. He expanded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> as far
        down as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mysore</ENAMEX> and stunned the western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">world</ENAMEX> by asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antiochus</ENAMEX>
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, figs, and a sophist. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> was happy to send the
        wine and figs, but would not, however, consent to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bindusara‚Äôs</ENAMEX> last
        request.
        To control land and sea routes to the south, the Mauryas
        still needed to conquer the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kalinga</ENAMEX> (modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orissa</ENAMEX>).
        The task was left to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bindusara‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashoka</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">269‚Äì232 b.c.</ENAMEX> ), admired
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> as their greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX>, perhaps for his special combination
        of tough authoritarianism and a high sense of moral righteousness.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashoka</ENAMEX> began by killing all his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> before conquering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kalinga</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">260</NUMEX>
        b.c. This left <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> dead, with even more dying from famine and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX> were taken captive.
        Famous inscriptions on rocks and pillars everywhere bore
        testimony to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashoka‚Äôs</ENAMEX> reign. The inscriptions state how ‚Äúhe of gentle
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">visage</ENAMEX> and beloved of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">gods</ENAMEX>,‚Äù as he described himself, was filled
        with remorse and converted to the non-violent teachings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>. But
        metaphysical implications seem to have interested him less than
        enforcing a moral example to unite his far-flung <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> in peace and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fellowship</ENAMEX>, under him. To oversee this mass conversion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashoka</ENAMEX> turned
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brahmanic</ENAMEX> concept of dharma (righteousness) into an instrument of
        public policy, enforced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Righteousness</ENAMEX> he had
        appointed for this purpose. The imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> for this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">undertaking</ENAMEX> demanded a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superintendents</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accountants</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> overseeing commerce, forestry, armory, weights
        and measures, goldsmiths, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX>, chariots, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infantry</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern India</ENAMEX> remained independent,
        but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashoka</ENAMEX> had his hands full with a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> that now extended as
        far north as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> and east to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengal</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 50 years</TIMEX> that followed <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ashoka‚</ENAMEX>Äôs death, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mauryan</ENAMEX> power
        went into decline. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> was not productive enough to finance the
        empire‚Äôs expansion. Also, the unwieldy bureaucracy couldn‚Äôt keep its
        loyalties straight, with the too-rapid turnover in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> vying for
        Ashoka‚Äôs throne.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Invaders Galore</ENAMEX>
        After the break-up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mauryan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>, new invaders
        appeared on the northwest frontier. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to arrive were Bactrian
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> left in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> hills by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexander‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX>. They were
        welcomed for their erudite ideas on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, astronomy, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">astrology</ENAMEX>.
        Joined by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pahlavas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> were
        overrun in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first century</TIMEX> b.c. by bands of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scythian</ENAMEX> nomads known as
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shakas</ENAMEX>. They moved on into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ganga valley</ENAMEX> when other nomads, the
        Yueh-chi from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Asia</ENAMEX>, swept across the frontier.
        Emerging victorious from the struggles between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yueh</ENAMEX>-chi
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shakas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kanishka</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kushan</ENAMEX> established an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> from
        the northern <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Asia</ENAMEX>. His reign was one of
        prosperity, making <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> a trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> and west.
        Kanishka was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mahayana</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Vehicle</ENAMEX>)
        school, which attributed for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time a quasi-divinity to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>;
        his active patronage of the arts led to the creation of the first
        bronze and stone sculptures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> prospered with the new
        east‚Äìwest trade and so were able to finance the magnificently sculpted
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cave</ENAMEX>-temples in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deccan</ENAMEX>, including those at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ajanta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellora</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arts</ENAMEX> also flourished in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> during these early times. Madurai was the
        lively cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dravidian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">poets</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">musicians</ENAMEX>, and also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> who were the precursors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX>
        devadasi temple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gupta Glory</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gupta</ENAMEX> dynasty, founded by the obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bihari</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landowner</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandra Gupta</ENAMEX> I, rose to power during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth century</TIMEX> a.d.
        Marriage-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> and conquest allowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guptas</ENAMEX> to create an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengal</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab</ENAMEX> and from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deccan</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samudra Gupta</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX>, launched lightning
        raids through the jungles to snatch the gold of the south. The Guptas
        also captured the western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">sea</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> and their trade with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>.
        They turned their noses up at trade with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> offered
        many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bounties</ENAMEX>, such as silk, musk, and amber, in exchange for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spices</ENAMEX>, jewels, and perfumes‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇas well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parakeets</ENAMEX> for the ladies‚Äô
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boudoirs</ENAMEX> and monkeys for their cooking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pots</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gupta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> began to crumble in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fifth century</TIMEX>,
        with the onslaught of the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">White Huns</ENAMEX>. They were not clearly
        linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attila‚Äôs Huns</ENAMEX>, but their harsh agenda of exterminating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhists</ENAMEX> does suggest an affinity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Huns</ENAMEX> seized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kashmir</ENAMEX>, and a large portion of the western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ganga</ENAMEX> plain before being
        chased out again.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the seventh century</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> strong king, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harshavardhana</ENAMEX>,
        reigned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX> over northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, and encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> monks
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brahman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> to participate in philosophical discussions. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sages</ENAMEX>
        developed the strict disciplines of yoga and profound metaphysical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">speculations of Vedanta</ENAMEX>.
        In southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, power was shared by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pallavas</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kanchipuram</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pandyas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cholas</ENAMEX> vying for control of Thanjavur
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tanjore</ENAMEX>). The bhakti movement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tamils</ENAMEX> brought a new warmth to
        the hitherto rigid Brahmanic ritual of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hinduism</ENAMEX>. The temples of
        Mahabalipuram were a high point in southern architecture, and it was
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pallavan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> who influenced‚<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> may have helped to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">build‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> temples at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angkor Wat</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borobudur</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> Comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> trade with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> had long since whetted the appetites
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>; when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> plundered their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> off the coast
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sind</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">711</TIMEX>, it provoked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chaldea</ENAMEX> (now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>) to send
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX> horses and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX> camels to conquer the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sind</ENAMEX> rajas and
        offer the alternative of converting to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> or death. When it was
        revealed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chaldea</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinduism</ENAMEX> was in fact a serious
        religion with too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX> to treat in this way, another solution
        had to be found: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX>, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Parsis</ENAMEX> who had fled an earlier
        Muslim persecution in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Persia</ENAMEX>, were given the privileged status of
        dhimmi, dues-paying non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX>.
        For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 300 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> conquest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> was
        confined to this trading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sind</ENAMEX>, but in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>,
        tribesmen from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkistan</ENAMEX>, driven west by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> expansion, set up a
        state at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghazni</ENAMEX> and began raids across the border to plunder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temples</ENAMEX>.
        Sweeping through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gujarat</ENAMEX> across to the
        western end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ganga valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mahmud of Ghazni</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">997‚Äì1030</ENAMEX>) used these
        raids more to finance his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Persia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turkistan</ENAMEX> than to set up
        a permanent foothold in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. Mahmud smashed the infidels‚Äô idols and
        destroyed their temples as he went, but was nonetheless cultured enough
        to use the booty to build a library, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, and a splendid mosque
        when he got back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghazni</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> saw him as a righteous militant
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hindus</ENAMEX> as a brutal monster, neither denied him his title of ‚ÄúSword
        of Islam. ‚Äù In order to understand his ambiguous image, compare him
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Europe‚Äôs heroic crusaders</ENAMEX> who went on the rampage at about the
        same time.
        There was no concerted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> response to the invasions
        because the various kingdoms were busy with wars of their own. The
        Rajput <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior clans</ENAMEX> fought each other for control in what is now
        Rajasthan, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kathiawar</ENAMEX> peninsula, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as far</NUMEX> east as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khajuraho</ENAMEX>. The
        Turco-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> invaders were regarded as a transient phenomenon that
        would either soon disappear or, just like others before them, be
        swallowed up by the great subcontinent.
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>
        At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 12th century</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> arrived: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghur</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mameluke</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Qutb</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ud</NUMEX>-din Aybak
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">seized Ghazni</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1173</TIMEX> and invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajputs</ENAMEX> made a belated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alliance</ENAMEX> and fought valiantly from one desert fortress to another, but
        their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> could not match their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">opponents‚Äô fast horses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX>
        cavalry firing superior crossbows at the gallop. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1193</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX>
        were masters in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peshawar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lahore</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sultan</ENAMEX> returned to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghazni</ENAMEX> and, leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qutb-ud-din</ENAMEX> in charge, moved east to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bengal</ENAMEX>,
        destroying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buddhism</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Nalanda</ENAMEX>.
        After his master‚Äôs assassination in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1206</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qutb-ud-</ENAMEX>din
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">proclaimed</ENAMEX> himself <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sultan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India‚Äôs</ENAMEX> first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dynasty</ENAMEX>. The sultanate lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">320 years</TIMEX>, but the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sultan</ENAMEX> ruled only
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>: he died in a fall from his pony.
        After the shock of the invasion had passed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX>
        proved to be a shot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> language spoken
        at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> enriched <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> literature and combined with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sanskrit</ENAMEX>-based dialects of northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> to create <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hindustani</ENAMEX>.
        Painting and architecture were infused with life, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> were paved,
        and, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 14th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> was pronounced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> traveller
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ibn Batuta</ENAMEX> to be the most magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> world.
        Conversion to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> faith was seen as a means of advancement, and
        those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rajputs</ENAMEX> who didn‚Äôt take advantage of this offer were able to
        sharpen their martial skills in constant guerrilla warfare.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> adopted the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX> and costume as well as
        a modified form of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> caste system. Highest were those of
        foreign extraction such as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghans</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Persians</ENAMEX>, known
        as ashraf (that is, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äúhonorable‚Äù</ENAMEX>). Then came upper-caste <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">converts</ENAMEX> from
        Hinduism, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúclean‚Äù castes</ENAMEX> of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> and artisans, and then
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúunclean‚Äù occupations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scavengers</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> worth noting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">first‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand last‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇMuslim</ENAMEX> woman
        to rule in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qutb-ud-din‚</ENAMEX>Äôs granddaughter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raziyya</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äú Wise</ENAMEX>, just,
        and generous,‚Äù a contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> said of her, ‚Äúbut she
        was not born of the right sex and so all the virtues were worthless. ‚Äù
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years</TIMEX> of her wisdom, justice, and generosity were all they could
        take before they murdered her.
        What they seemed to want was a despot like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ud</NUMEX>-din
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khalji</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1296‚Äì1316</ENAMEX>), who forced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mongol</ENAMEX> invaders back across the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frontier</ENAMEX> and then moved through the peninsula to its southern tip. But
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala-ud-din‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX> did not assert control of the territory. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">south</ENAMEX> remained dominated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vijayanagar</ENAMEX> for the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 250 years</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> sultanate under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tughlaq</ENAMEX> dynasty could no
        longer hold its own in the north, and so <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> kingdoms began to form
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bengal</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deccan</ENAMEX>. The end was hastened by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who made other
        Muslim invaders seem like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pussy cats</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mongol Timur the Lame</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúbarbarous</ENAMEX> and bloody <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tamburlaine,‚Äù</ENAMEX> later written about by Elizabethan
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Marlowe</ENAMEX>.
        On the grounds that the sultans were too soft, he cut
        through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1398</TIMEX>, slaughtering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX> and carrying
        off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> more as slaves. He left behind him famine and pestilence.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks‚Äô Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> in splinters, it passed into the hands of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>-breeders‚<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe Lodi‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwho</ENAMEX> later succumbed to his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughals</ENAMEX>.
        Down on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Malabar coast</ENAMEX>, the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> explorer
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vasco da Gama</ENAMEX> landed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1498</TIMEX>, paving the way for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX> to form
        a settlement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Goa</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> wanted to divert trade away from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>, fearing the enrichment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North African</ENAMEX> Maghreb as a threat
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Europe</ENAMEX>. With them came the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX>, who
        found the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> for their teachings among the low-caste <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX>.
        Around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1548</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Francis Xavier</ENAMEX> began his mission among the pearl
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goa</ENAMEX>, before he set sail for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. To deal with the small
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nestorian Christian ‚Äúheretics</ENAMEX>,‚Äù who had settled
        down on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Malabar</ENAMEX> coast in the mists of antiquity, the then
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Archbishop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goa</ENAMEX> opened a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of the Holy <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inquisition</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> at first tried the soft sell, offering cloth,
        wine, and necklaces for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ivory</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calicut</ENAMEX> were
        insulted at being taken for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúnatives‚Äù</ENAMEX> who could be bought with cheap
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hooch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass baubles</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> turned to the harder sell of
        naval batteries, driving off a trading <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1509</TIMEX> in order
        to control the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Malabar</ENAMEX> coast. With hardly any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> present in the
        colony, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> took <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Goans</ENAMEX> are
        descended from them or from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">converts</ENAMEX> who took the name of their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Mughals</ENAMEX>
        The new conquerors of northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> did not come
        uninvited. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sind</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab</ENAMEX>, who were
        hoping for more autonomy than they had under the lofty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sultan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ibrahim</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lodi</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>, therefore called on Babur the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">King of Kabul</ENAMEX>.
        Babur the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendant</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Timur the Lame and of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genghis Khan</ENAMEX>, accepted their welcome but made no promises. His men
        crushed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sultan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ibrahim‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> with cannons, hitherto unknown in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panipat</ENAMEX>, north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>.
        It was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 April 1526</TIMEX>, the beginning of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">empire of the Mughals‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇ the term used for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babur</ENAMEX> as
        distinct from those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genghis Khan</ENAMEX>, who are referred to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as ‚</NUMEX>ÄúMongols‚Äù
        even though the terms are etymologically the same. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babur</ENAMEX> fought
        resistance from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajputs</ENAMEX> and captured <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agra</ENAMEX>, then conquered
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1529</TIMEX>. He died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX>.
        His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Humayun</ENAMEX>, preferred opium and astrology to complex
        State affairs; he was driven out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Persia</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Sher</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Shah</ENAMEX>, who proved to be a much more able <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, the
        General built new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, created a royal postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>, and set the
        pattern of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mughal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two centuries</TIMEX> before
        dying in battle and leaving the throne to a number of inept successors
        and, eventually, the return of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humayun</ENAMEX>.
        Straightened out for a while, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humayun</ENAMEX> came back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1555</TIMEX>
        with his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> to recapture the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agra</ENAMEX>, but the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> his opium habit caused his death (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX>). He did,
        however, leave a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akbar</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jalal-ud-din Mohammed Akbar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1556‚Äì1605</ENAMEX>) was a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>.
        Typical of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> was the new religion he offered his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>: the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Divine Faith</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Din-Ilahi</ENAMEX>), intended to satisfy orthodox <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> and
        those who, just like himself and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX>, appreciated the idea of a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">semi-divine ruler.</ENAMEX> Keen to win the allegiance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX>, Akbar
        abolished most of the discriminatory taxes on non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, and
        recruited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajputs</ENAMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> after marrying a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of Raja
        Bharmal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amber</ENAMEX>, (though he did not flinch at massacring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another 8,000</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rajput</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>).
        But despite repeated efforts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akbar</ENAMEX> could not extend his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">empire</ENAMEX> south. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1565</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> sultanates of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deccan</ENAMEX> had taken
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vijayanagar</ENAMEX> by means of slaughter, but they were
        not going to hand it all to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akbar</ENAMEX>.
        Although illiterate, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akbar</ENAMEX> had enormous intellectual
        curiosity. He preferred <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sufi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mysticism</ENAMEX> to orthodox <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islam</ENAMEX>, and held
        debates with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brahmins, Jain</ENAMEX> monks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parsi Zoroastrians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuits</ENAMEX>. The
        more orthodox <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> were concerned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> was being abandoned,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rebellions</ENAMEX> sprang up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bengal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bihar</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab</ENAMEX>.
        While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akbar</ENAMEX> was fighting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deccan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1601</TIMEX>, his son
        claimed the throne. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akbar</ENAMEX> rushed back to reassert his power but he died
        soon after, poisoned, it is rumored, by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> called
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">himself Jahangir</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Seizer</ENAMEX>) but once in power he left affairs of
        state to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nur Jahan</ENAMEX>, as he was more interested in writing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poetry</ENAMEX>, drinking a great deal of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, and taking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> excursions up
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>. Here, rich <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> culture dictated taste in dress, d√©cor,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manners</ENAMEX>, and morals, enriched by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> culture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajputs</ENAMEX> in
        literature, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX>, and sexuality. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> were squeezed by
        taxes to pay for the luxury of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mughal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> life, it was a boon for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">country‚Äôs artisans‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇgoldsmiths</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jewelers</ENAMEX>, and weavers. In such an
        atmosphere, incidents of highway banditry increased and the district
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> shared the rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">booty</ENAMEX> in exchange for a pardon when the
        bandits were captured.
        Jahangir‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shahjahan</ENAMEX> became the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spender</ENAMEX> of all
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughals</ENAMEX>. He lavished <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> and mosques, blowing at
        least <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one million pounds sterling</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and jewels for his Peacock
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Throne</ENAMEX>. Despite this, the imperial treasury allotted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only 5,000 rupees</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> for the plague and famine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1631</TIMEX>.
        Of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the emperor‚Äôs harem, his only
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love</ENAMEX> was the now legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mumtaz-Mahal (‚ÄúExalted of the Palace‚Äù</ENAMEX>), by
        whom he had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. She died in childbirth and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shahjahan</ENAMEX> built her
        the most famous memorial a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> ever offered to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> he loved: the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj Mahal</ENAMEX>.
        Shahjahan‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aurangzeb</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1658‚Äì1707</ENAMEX>), who overthrew
        his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and imprisoned him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Agra fort</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last years</TIMEX> of
        his life. A pious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>, puritanical in both clothes and personal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tastes</ENAMEX>, he banished music from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and burned the portraits of
        princes as breaches of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> taboo on graven images. Gone, too,
        was any notion of religious tolerance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sikhs</ENAMEX> were slaughtered, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temples</ENAMEX> in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Varanasi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mathura</ENAMEX> were destroyed, and the
        building of new temples was forbidden. Taxes on non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> were
        brought back; <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> were forced to pay double duties on their
        goods.
        Aurangzeb streamlined the lax <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predecessors</ENAMEX>, but he almost bankrupted the realm with his campaigns to
        expand the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> down to the south, and his battles against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> in
        the north. The most significant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marathas</ENAMEX>, in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">today‚Äôs State of Maharashtra</ENAMEX>, around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mumbai</ENAMEX>. They were led by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fighter Shivaji</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1627‚Äì1680</ENAMEX>), bandit, brave military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>, and an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authentic Hindu</ENAMEX> folk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>.
        Starting out from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pune, Shivaji‚Äôs Marathas</ENAMEX> fought off the
        Deccan sultans at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bijapur</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughals</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purandar</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aurangzeb</ENAMEX> forced
        him finally to submit, but the humiliating reception he was given at
        court sent him back on the warpath again. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shivaji</ENAMEX> then had himself
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowned King of the Marathas</ENAMEX> and, to pay his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, plundered the
        country all the way east to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madras</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Arrive</ENAMEX>
        Meanwhile, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the 17th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> armed merchant <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> had broken through the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> blockade
        to set up their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East India</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> on both coasts. Arriving in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1608</TIMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> to get their foot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> door, at
        the western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surat</ENAMEX>, north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bombay</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Company</ENAMEX> destroyed the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> and took over the protection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> pilgrimage
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mecca</ENAMEX>, but there were no hard feelings; the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> made a
        gift of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bombay</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles II</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1661</TIMEX> as part of the dowry of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braganza</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> were not consulted.
        The Company erected its <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">east-</ENAMEX>coast installations in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 1642</TIMEX> just down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mandaraz</ENAMEX>, pronounced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúMadras‚Äù</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>. Further north, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> gradually gained
        the upper hand over their rivals, now including the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bengali</ENAMEX> trade that was to create <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calcutta</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mughal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years</TIMEX> after
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aurangzeb</ENAMEX> died. Bihar, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bengal</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajputana</ENAMEX> all went their separate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sikhs</ENAMEX> reacted violently to persecution, and the Marathas
        spread to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orissa</ENAMEX>, after which, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1739</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nadir Shah</ENAMEX> of Persia
        invaded and carried off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peacock Throne</ENAMEX> (broken up after his
        assassination). Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> clerk-turned-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clive</ENAMEX> won a long campaign against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madras</ENAMEX>.
        Fearing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> would start carving up Bengal, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nawab</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX>) Siraj-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ud</NUMEX>-daula set up an attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        settlement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calcutta</ENAMEX> on the hot day of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 June</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1756</TIMEX>. Those who did
        not flee to sea were thrown into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort William‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, already known
        as the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Black Hole</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> still being debated whether <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">123</NUMEX> suffocated and
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> survived or <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúonly‚Äù 43</ENAMEX> died, leaving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>, but however many
        died, they were enough impetus for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clive</ENAMEX> to crush <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Siraj-ud-daula</ENAMEX> at the
        Battle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plassey</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clive</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> and placed his own nawab on
        the throne, in exchange for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">¬£500,000</NUMEX> for himself and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Company</ENAMEX>. He
        then annexed <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 2,330 sq km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">900 sq miles</NUMEX>) of land due south of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calcutta</ENAMEX> to provide rents for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> settlement and to guarantee
        himself an income of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">¬£30,000</NUMEX> per year for life. The rise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empire</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> had begun.
        Installing the Raj
        The arrival of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jains, Parsis</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, turned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bombay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madras</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calcutta</ENAMEX> into large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>; the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Company</ENAMEX> discovered a knack for large-scale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. A high sense
        of integrity took the place of what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clive</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúfighting</ENAMEX>, chicanery,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intrigues</ENAMEX>, politics, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX> knows what. ‚Äù In return for fixed
        payments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> collected revenue. With a
        well-paid civil service, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clive‚Äôs successors‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇWarren Hastings</ENAMEX> and Lord
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornwallis‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇavoided the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX> by padding their salaries with
        private deals. With the new title of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor-General</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> and
        then <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cornwallis</ENAMEX> were responsible to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> rather than
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Company</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> began taking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> more seriously. But this new
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">high-mindedness</ENAMEX> had in it the seeds of future discontent. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> were
        removed from key positions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> because Cornwallis
        considered them not yet up to the stricter ethical standards that were
        being introduced. It took a long time for them to be readmitted to
        positions of responsibility.
        Clive‚Äôs example in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calcutta</ENAMEX> set the pattern for territorial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. In the south, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tipu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> of Mysore
        remained a menace to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madras</ENAMEX> until <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Wellesley</ENAMEX>,
        future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wellington</ENAMEX>, defeated him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wellesley</ENAMEX> then turned on the
        Marathas, whose clans controlled the puppet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> and
        much of central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. A few brilliant victories gained control of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orissa</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territories</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> decided all that
        energy would be best directed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX>, and called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wellesley</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
        When territory wasn‚Äôt acquired by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">conquest‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇSind</ENAMEX> from
        Baluchi princes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sikhs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maharashtra</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marathas</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Assam</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Burma‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe British</ENAMEX> annexed it
        by so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Principles of Lapse and Paramountcy</ENAMEX>. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> died
        without direct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> ‚Äúlapsed‚Äù into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> hands. If, after
        repeated warnings, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> was judged guilty of misgovernment, it was
        simply annexed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Power‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> became established. Calcutta became
        the center of a vigorous free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> and the intellectual capital of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1834</TIMEX>, regional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">rupees</NUMEX> of differing value were minted with
        the portrait of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>. Then a national rupee of unitary
        value was issued, with the face of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. In running the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">empire</ENAMEX> effectively, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> installed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railways</ENAMEX>, better <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">telegraph</ENAMEX>, and stamp-post. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> also saw the other side of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial Revolution</ENAMEX> as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton</ENAMEX> left for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manchester</ENAMEX> to come back
        as cloth cheaper than their own.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bentinck</ENAMEX> worked with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brahman Ram Mohan Roy</ENAMEX> to legislate
        against the practice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widows</ENAMEX> becoming sati by climbing onto the
        funeral pyres of their respective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>. Other campaigns were
        launched against female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infanticide</ENAMEX>, slavery, and the bands of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thugs</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kali</ENAMEX>) ranging the countryside.
        Although some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> assimilated the language and behavior
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, to most the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">imperialists</ENAMEX> were offensively aloof. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> had known other conquerors, but at least they had been able to
        gain a sense of them as human beings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Raj</ENAMEX>, though, was
        firmly entrenched in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, and remained resolutely separate.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mutiny</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX>
        The cause of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mutiny</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1857</TIMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The War of Independence</ENAMEX>
        as it is known to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>, was symptomatic of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> insensitivity.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> were trained to bite the cartridges before loading their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rifles</ENAMEX>, but some were greased with animal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fat</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> felt they
        were ingesting either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fat</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX>, sacred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX>, or lard
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX>, abomination to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>. As they had suffered slights
        of either incomprehension or contempt for their religious customs
        before, they simply could not believe it was not deliberate, and mutiny
        broke out at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meerut</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 miles</NUMEX>) north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>.
        The cartridge blunder became a pretext for avenging other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grievances</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> rallying around the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> dispossessed by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lapse or Paramountcy</ENAMEX>. The mutineers then invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>, Kanpur
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cawnpore</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucknow</ENAMEX>, looting treasuries, breaking open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX>, and
        killing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> retaliated with equal savagery against the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mutineers</ENAMEX> and against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> through which the relief
        columns passed. Finally, the last of the proud <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mughals</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bahadur Shah</ENAMEX>, was condemned to exile in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burma</ENAMEX>.
        Nothing could more aptly epitomize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mutiny‚</ENAMEX>Äôs good and
        bad results, from an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> point of view, than the name given to the
        legislation that was to follow: the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1858 Act</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better Government of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> evidently saw the need to improve things for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>, but also decided to tighten their imperial hold.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East India Company</ENAMEX> was replaced by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> with a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Viceroy</ENAMEX> answering to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. The
        bureaucracy was to be streamlined, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> reorganized to raise
        the ratio of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> education was greatly expanded, though less
        successfully in rural areas where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thought it better to be a good
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasant</ENAMEX> than a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX>. Queen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX>, who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1876</TIMEX> would
        add the title <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress of India</ENAMEX> to her roll of honor, proclaimed that
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Civil Service</ENAMEX> would be open to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúour <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of whatever
        race and creed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX> Not a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>, however, could afford the trip
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> to take the examination.
        Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> were at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">premium‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇIndians</ENAMEX> love
        litigation and it was ideal training for future politicians‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand
        politics had been clandestine, because it was so often fatal to express
        an opinion on the wrong (i.e. , losing) side. Now open political debate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flourished</ENAMEX>, especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calcutta</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Marx</ENAMEX> was much
        appreciated.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> developed their own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bombay, Ahmedabad, Kanpur</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madras</ENAMEX>, but the new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> gardens were a
        strictly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> affair. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian agricultural</ENAMEX> products soon found new
        markets in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Suez Canal</ENAMEX> was opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1869</TIMEX>.
        In the arts, architecture was often of the work of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>, and huge sculptures were ordered from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
        rather than from local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. The bright spot was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archaeological</ENAMEX>
        Survey of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1871</TIMEX> to preserve ancient monuments. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> hunting
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tigers</ENAMEX> in the jungle were finding temples and palaces many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> no
        longer knew existed.
        Fighting for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Rule</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Congress</ENAMEX>, the country‚Äôs f irst
        political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, held its inaugural meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bombay</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1885</TIMEX>. As a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parsi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>, supported by a few
        progressive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, it was more national in purpose than in its
        representation. Lacking connection with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX>, it was also
        distrusted by conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX> and by most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>. The goal of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">swaraj</ENAMEX> (self-rule), proclaimed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1906</TIMEX>, was seen by a moderate Left
        Center <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Empire</ENAMEX>, and by a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">breakaway revolutionary Extreme Left</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> as complete
        independence.
        After years of subservience to the West, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> returned
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> themes in their literature, theatre, and music. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>
        applauded the decision of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ripon</ENAMEX> to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magistrates</ENAMEX> to try
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> in criminal cases, but attempts at social reform
        such as protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> brides against rape by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> were
        fought by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traditionalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hindus</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calcutta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pune</ENAMEX> with cries of
        ‚Äúreligion in danger. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù Self</ENAMEX> assertion reigned again: After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of
        peace, hostilities broke out between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maharashtra</ENAMEX>, a cult grew up around the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Maratha</ENAMEX> leader
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shivaji</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>) against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and also the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> whom
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shivaji</ENAMEX> had fought all his life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fundamentalists</ENAMEX> took to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> to
        protest against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> slaughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>. There was a movement to
        convert <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> back to the ‚Äúnational‚Äù religion. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> tried to purify the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> practice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rituals</ENAMEX> which
        had accrued over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>.
        The caste system was affected by this new spirit.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Untouchables</ENAMEX> pressed for better treatment, but their cause was not
        helped by the activism of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX>,
        who gave other castes a good excuse to resist ‚Äúforeign interference.
        ‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dynamic Lord Curzon</ENAMEX>, viceroy from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1899 to 1905</TIMEX>, was driven
        by a lofty imperial vision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> role in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. His grandiose
        life in the viceregal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calcutta</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Simla</ENAMEX> was
        worthy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughal</ENAMEX> emperors.
        Highly active in excavating and restoring the temples and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">palaces</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Curzon</ENAMEX> also did more than any of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>, adding
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9,000 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5,500 miles</NUMEX>) of new railway lines, working to modernize
        farming with an agricultural research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX>, and building an
        irrigation system that would become a model for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>, however, resented his refusal to consult them, and rioted over
        an ill-considered partition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengal</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George V</ENAMEX> became the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> monarch to
        visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. He celebrated the fact by announcing that the capital
        would be moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calcutta</ENAMEX> to a whole new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to be built in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin Lutyens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Baker</ENAMEX> created a
        monumental <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX> with triumphal arches, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>, gigantic
        government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, and sweeping avenues radiating from circles (for
        easy riot control)‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe stuff of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> meant to last forever.
        Without giving up demands for self-determination, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
        fought at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britain‚</ENAMEX>Äôs side in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> Prussian
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX> blinked at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajput</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sikh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">princes</ENAMEX> leading an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infantry</ENAMEX>
        through the trenches of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX> self-determination in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> seemed nearer when
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> announced its plan for ‚Äúthe progressive realization of
        responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">an integral part of the</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> were not letting go, but a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> Act <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years later</TIMEX> promised <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> real executive power at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of provincial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministries</ENAMEX> for education, public works, health, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agriculture</ENAMEX>. The moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> were delighted, but revolutionaries
        saw it as a foot in the door, while many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> retired
        rather than serve under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>.
        Riots over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengal‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partition</ENAMEX> led to new laws for political
        trials without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and also internment without trial. Popular protest
        in the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> took the non-violent form of a
        hartal, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äústrike‚Äù</ENAMEX> called when the soul is shocked by an
        injustice. This idea came from the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohandas Karamchand</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>, dubbed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mahatma‚ÄÇ</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Soul</ENAMEX>) by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabindranath</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tagore</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> returned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915</TIMEX> after working as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> defending
        the rights of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>. The moral strength
        of his non-violent philosophy was immediately tested in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab</ENAMEX>,
        where the hartal erupted into riots. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amritsar</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reginald Dyer</ENAMEX> fired on a prohibited mass meeting, leaving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">379</NUMEX> dead and
        over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,200</NUMEX> wounded.
        As a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gradualist</ENAMEX> reform became discredited and civil
        unrest a feature of everyday life. Declaring that ‚Äúcooperation in any
        form with this satanic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is sinful,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Gandhi</ENAMEX> advocated the
        boycott of elections and the withdrawal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from government
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Moderates</ENAMEX> held on, but the election boycott was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 33</NUMEX>
        percent successful.
        Abandoning <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> dress for his now legendary white
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cotton</ENAMEX> dhoti (loincloth) and shawl, and drawing spiritual guidance from
        all the great religions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> became the simple but powerful
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">symbol of India</ENAMEX>. He supported the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Untouchables</ENAMEX> and defended the rights
        of village artisans and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX>, but his non-violent movement could
        not stop the escalating riots among the religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>.
        Worried by the spread of his civil disobedience movement,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> jailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> at the same
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, for ‚Äúincitement to rebellion,‚Äù was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress Party</ENAMEX> member
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jawaharlal Nehru</ENAMEX>, who was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>-educated but also a Brahman
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intellectual</ENAMEX>, as his honorary title of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pandit</ENAMEX> suggested. He was the
        Mahatma‚Äôs favorite to lead <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> to independence.
        Independence with Partition
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> began to see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India‚Äôs</ENAMEX> independence as
        inevitable; however, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only a few</NUMEX> seemed to understand the vital role of
        the religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> prepared a parliamentary democracy with
        majority rule, but the majority were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hindus‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand Hindus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sikhs</ENAMEX> had been killing each other in war for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many centuries</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nehru‚Äôs Congress Party</ENAMEX>, largely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> with a socialist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, wanted a parliamentary democracy. As counterweight, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        legislation reserved parliamentary seats for religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>, but
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bengal</ENAMEX> had such a complicated mixture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sikhs</ENAMEX> that it was not possible to avoid fights over how
        separate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX> were to be formed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX> of future trouble
        were sown.
        The legislation on reserving seats gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> the
        basis for an alternative to an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> in which they were only a quarter
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partition</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad Iqbal</ENAMEX> proposed
        a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> in the northwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. A small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian Muslims</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> came up with the name <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, using the
        initials of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab, Afghania</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">N.W. Frontier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Province</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sind</ENAMEX> (at the same time producing the word pak, meaning <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äúpure‚Äù</ENAMEX>), and
        adding ‚Äústan,‚Äù the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> suffix for the word ‚Äúcountry. ‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>
        campaign for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partition</ENAMEX> was led by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>-trained <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bombay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad Ali Jinnah</ENAMEX>.
        Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> vehemently opposed any dismemberment of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and tried to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> united by fasting to uphold the
        spirit of love, and by focussing on the common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversary</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>.
        Advocating civil disobedience, he led his famous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> to the sea,
        to scoop up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> and circumvent the hated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> tax. This put
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 60,000</NUMEX> in jail.
        Against this militancy, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> did not elicit the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">solidarity</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> courageously fought alongside the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burma</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> saw
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> as a provocation for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> invasion and was jailed yet
        again, for launching a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúQuit India‚</ENAMEX>Äù campaign in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1942</TIMEX>. Some
        anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> liberator.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston Churchill</ENAMEX> didn‚Äôt want any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> independence and
        so it was probably as well for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> that he was defeated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attlee‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>.
        With riots growing ever more bloody in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bengal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bihar</ENAMEX>, and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab, India‚Äôs</ENAMEX> last viceroy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mountbatten</ENAMEX>, kept a mandate to
        make the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> departure as quick and as smooth as possible. Quick it
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">was‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsix</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> after his arrival‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbut not smooth.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Midnight</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14‚Äì15</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1947</TIMEX>, was a moment, in
        the words of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nehru</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúwhen we step out from the old to
        the new, when an age ends, and when the soul of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, long
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suppressed</ENAMEX>, finds utterance. ‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nehru</ENAMEX> got his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Independence</ENAMEX> and Jinnah his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Partition‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇa
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> whose eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bengali</ENAMEX> portion was to break away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 years later</TIMEX>
        to become <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangladesh</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloodshed</ENAMEX> began as soon as the Partition
        boundaries were set. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab, Hindus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sikhs</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">massacred</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>; in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">west</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Punjab</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> massacred
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sikhs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX>. This was followed by a mass exodus of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> from
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to the other but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convoys</ENAMEX> often ended in slaughter.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> itself was torn apart by communal rampages. The overall death
        toll came to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 500,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahatma Gandhi</ENAMEX> immediately rushed from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calcutta</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>
        to defend <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> against further slaughter. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1948</TIMEX>, he fasted
        for peace in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital city</ENAMEX> in order to force the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> government
        to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> the monies due in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partition‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of assets. A
        Hindu fanatic, enraged by what he felt was an excessively fervent
        defense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> interests, assassinated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> in a prayer
        meeting on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 January</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> Today
        Sensitive and sophisticated, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pandit Nehru</ENAMEX> was also the
        strongest ruler <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> had known since the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mughals</ENAMEX> and, like them,
        he created a powerful dynasty. Rejecting his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi‚</ENAMEX>Äôs faith in a
        village-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nehru</ENAMEX> worked to make <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> a fully
        industrialized society on the basis of democratic socialism.
        Established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> had their taxes raised but were not
        nationalized. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> that were foreign had to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
        financial participation and management.
        He appropriated for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> much of the personal
        fortunes of the princes, but found it harder to curtail the power of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">land-owners</ENAMEX> who had extensive contacts with the more conservative
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress Party</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> remained an unresolved problem of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partition</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> majority in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vale</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilgit</ENAMEX> made it part of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, but the greater part of the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jammu</ENAMEX> was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX>, as was the maharaja. Backed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pathan</ENAMEX> tribesmen
        invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> to force the issue, but were soon repulsed by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> flown in when the maharaja hastily acceded to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kashmir</ENAMEX> was divided between both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, pending a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plebiscite‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwhich</ENAMEX> has never been held. An invasion by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>
        was aborted and has left the issue distinctly moot.
        Applying the principle of geographical integrity, Nehru
        regained <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> Pondicherry by negotiation after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Independence</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portuguese Goa</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>. He was less successful in fighting
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> over territory on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> frontier. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egalitarian</ENAMEX> and agnostic,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nehru</ENAMEX> passed laws against the injustice of the caste system,
        child-marriage, and the treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>,‚ÄÇbut
        century-old customs die hard: before his death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>, he asked that
        his ashes be scattered in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Yamuna</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">river</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ganga</ENAMEX> at
        Allahabad, and without ritual. The mourning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX>, though, ignored his
        last wishes, uttering prayers and crying: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúPanditji has become
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">immortal</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        Coming to power in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1966</TIMEX> after the brief ministry
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lal Bahadur Shastri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indira Gandhi</ENAMEX> proved strong enough in her own
        right for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to stop describing her as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nehru‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as ‚</NUMEX>Äúnot
        related to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahatma Gandhi</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        In fact, she learned much from both, the knack for
        power-politics of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and the massive popular appeal of the other.
        She accelerated industrialization, in particular the nuclear power
        industry, including a first atomic explosion in the desert in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>. Her
        proudest achievement, though, was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Revolution</ENAMEX> that modernized
        wheat and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> farming to give <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in its
        history, self-sufficiency in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> production. Old entrenched
        conservatism hampered her birth-control programs to check the rocketing
        population growth.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indira Gandhi‚</ENAMEX>Äôs tendency toward tough authoritarianism was
        highlighted during the repressive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of emergency she declared in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, describing it as ‚Äúdisciplined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>,‚Äù when she ordered mass
        arrests of opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> who had charged her and her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">malpractice</ENAMEX> and corruption.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> punished her in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> in
        the wilderness, then brought her back with a huge majority. But her
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term was beset with the problems of regional unrest, most
        notably in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Assam</ENAMEX> in the northeastern region of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, where local
        massacres left <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> dead, and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sikh</ENAMEX> militants
        staged violent demonstrations for greater autonomy and even
        independence. It was her order to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> to attack
        armed militants in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sikhs‚</ENAMEX>Äô sacred <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Temple</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amritsar</ENAMEX>,
        resulting in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> dead, that led to her assassination in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months later</TIMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sikh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of her security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX> then
