
  
  
    
      
        A Brief History
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celtic Ireland</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> has been inhabited since very ancient times, but
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> history really begins with the arrival of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celts</ENAMEX> around the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6th century</TIMEX> b.c. , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ireland‚Äôs</ENAMEX> first documented invasion. They brought
        with them iron <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and chariots and codes of custom and conduct
        that quickly became dominant in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. This is the period of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">myths</ENAMEX> and legends, later romanticized by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, that still
        exercise their power <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celts</ENAMEX> were organized along a family- and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX>-based
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celtic Ireland</ENAMEX> became a series of independent kingdoms.
        Nominally these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kingdoms</ENAMEX> acknowledged an elected <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">High King</ENAMEX>, with his
        seat at fabled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tara</ENAMEX>, as overlord. There were no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX> was
        the medium of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>. Learning was revered, games were played, and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> was held in awe. Law and religion were important in Celtic
        culture. The religion was druidic, and the law was an elaborate written
        code, interpreted by a class of professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> known as brehons.
        The brehon laws gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> a high status‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthey could own property,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">divorce</ENAMEX>, and even enter the professions.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christianity</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mission</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Patrick</ENAMEX> first came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX>, captured in
        an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> raid on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">settlement</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. He eventually escaped
        and returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> as a missionary in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 432</TIMEX>. By the time of
        Patrick‚Äôs death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 465</TIMEX>, the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was effectively
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christianized‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa</ENAMEX> peaceful process, without a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX>, which
        speaks for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Patrick‚Äôs</ENAMEX> natural diplomacy as well as his powers of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persuasion</ENAMEX>. Many legends surround his mission. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Patrick</ENAMEX> who
        used the example of the shamrock to explain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Trinity</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Laoghaire</ENAMEX> and an assembled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tara</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> was converted
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> has been a symbol of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> ever since.
        With Christianity and the sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Celtic</ENAMEX> culture
        successfully fused, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> entered its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúGolden Age‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">a.d. 500</ENAMEX> until
        around a.d. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> monasteries during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time</TIMEX> were the major
        preservers of learning and literacy in the so-called ‚ÄúDark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ages</TIMEX>. ‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> became ‚Äúthe light of the known world,‚Äù sending its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> out all over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. The importance of this phase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
        history, for both the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> themselves and civilization in general,
        cannot be overrated. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> with its Celtic cultural
        base developed differently from the emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> world in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
        and was eventually superseded by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> and its centralized
        administration.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings Arrive</ENAMEX>
        Throughout this period, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ireland‚</ENAMEX>Äôs political organization
        continued much as it had under pagan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtic</ENAMEX> rule. There were still no
        towns; the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> was only a crossroads, known as Baile Atha
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cliath (‚ÄúCity of the Hurdles</ENAMEX>,‚Äù a designation still seen on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Communities</ENAMEX> clustered around monasteries and castles. From a.d. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">795,</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> was subject to repeated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX> raids. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> sacked the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> centers of learning for their treasures. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>
        they built a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fort on the Liffey</ENAMEX> and founded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ireland‚Äôs</ENAMEX> first <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">town‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇDubh
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Linn or ‚ÄúBlack Pool</ENAMEX>.‚Äù The remains of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX> fortifications can be seen
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> beneath <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin Castle</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> also introduced coinage and
        better ship-building techniques.
        In a.d. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">988</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> finally united under the king
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Munster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Bor√∫</ENAMEX>, and in a great battle drove the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> north
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liffey</ENAMEX>. Their influence waned, and they began to be absorbed
        into the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> now held <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1038</TIMEX> the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">first Christ Church Cathedral</ENAMEX> was founded.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> Under the Normans
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1169</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Normans</ENAMEX> landed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wexford</ENAMEX>, beginning the
        struggle between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> that was to dominate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> history
        until independence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> incursion began with an internal power
        struggle. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leinster</ENAMEX> invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard de Clare</ENAMEX>, known as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúStrongbow</ENAMEX>,‚Äù to come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> to help him reclaim his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>
        (Strongbow‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> can be seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christ Church Cathedral</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
        invaders brought with them armor, the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> in battle, and the
        feudal system. Successive waves of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> invaders followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strongbow</ENAMEX>.
        Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>, they favored centralized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, and enforced
        their rule with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> of fortified castles. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1171</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">king</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry II</ENAMEX>, came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>. He granted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> a charter in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1174</TIMEX>
        that gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> rights to free trade. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1204</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin Castle</ENAMEX> was the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> of English administrative power in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> elected its
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1229</TIMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> was held for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1297</TIMEX>.
        Beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pale</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Normans</ENAMEX>, following the pattern of earlier invaders,
        became rapidly assimilated. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next two centuries</TIMEX> were characterized
        by unrest and repeated attempts by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> to rid themselves of their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> overlords. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 15th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> held only a
        small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>, walled off from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> inner city and
        known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pale</ENAMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> themselves outside.
        All this changed under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry VIII</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
        I were determined to subdue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, and sent in massive military
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">expeditions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry VIII‚Äôs</ENAMEX> break with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> and the dissolution of the
        monasteries meant that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1558</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dublin‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two cathedrals</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Christ Church</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Patrick‚Äôs</ENAMEX>, had become <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> (as they remain <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, which
        sometimes surprises <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> I left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity College</ENAMEX>
        as her <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">legacy‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇshe</ENAMEX> founded it as a seat of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> learning, and it
        remained just that well into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-20th century</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> continued to fight, but the semi-independent
        kingdoms were never able to achieve real cohesion. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1607</TIMEX>, they were
        left leaderless by the ‚ÄúFlight of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earls</ENAMEX>.‚Äù The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ulster</ENAMEX> earls,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O‚ÄôNeill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">O‚ÄôDonnell</ENAMEX> went into exile on the Continent, along with many
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lords</ENAMEX>.
        From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cromwell</ENAMEX> to the Boyne
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1649</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ireland‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most hated conqueror, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Cromwell</ENAMEX>,
        arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>. His ruthless campaigns resulted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 600,000</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> dead or deported. There was a massive dispossession of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
        from their fertile lands in the east, and they were driven west of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shannon</ENAMEX>; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cromwell‚</ENAMEX>Äôs phrase they could go to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúHell or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connaught</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
        Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> still spit when they hear his name.
        At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the century</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James II</ENAMEX> came
        to the throne, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> felt they had no choice but to back him. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
        was defeated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William of Orange</ENAMEX> just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle of</ENAMEX>
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boyne</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1690</TIMEX>; the defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> straggled into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX> fled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. As a result, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> enacted the
        Penal Laws of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1704</TIMEX>, which disenfranchised the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic Irish</ENAMEX>; their
        purpose was to keep the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> and powerless.
        The Ascendancy
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The 18th century</TIMEX> was not a good time for the native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>,
        but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant Ascendancy</ENAMEX> flourished. However, like others before
        them, they had come to identify themselves as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>, and they were
        anxious to achieve at least a measure of self-government for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1782</TIMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX>) was formed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>, largely
        through the energies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Grattan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Grattan
        succeeded in having most of the penal laws against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>
        repealed. But the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> was short-lived‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇagainst
        Grattan‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX>, and through bribery and corruption, it voted to
        dissolve itself in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1800</TIMEX>.
        In the meantime, the influential ideas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
        Revolution were spreading. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Irishmen</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe Tone</ENAMEX>, was
        founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1791</TIMEX>, a nonsectarian movement that sought the freedom of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe Tone</ENAMEX> secured aid from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, but a storm scattered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> of the invading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. Tone was
        captured and either was murdered or committed suicide. He remains a
        revered figure in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pantheon</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ascendancy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> enjoyed an elegant lifestyle
        during this period. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> and music flourished. Dublin‚Äôs importance
        grew dramatically as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> became the center of social and business
        life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>. Great public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs House</ENAMEX> and the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Courts</ENAMEX> were constructed, and private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powerscourt</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leinster House</ENAMEX> were built. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Craftsmen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> were imported from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> squares like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Merrion Square</ENAMEX> in south
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> were created at this time.
        The glory of this lively and cosmopolitan city lasted until
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1801</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> brought <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> under direct rule from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. Quite suddenly, everything came to a standstill: The rich and
        powerful left for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> became a provincial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> in
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of long, slow decline.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">O‚</ENAMEX>ÄôConnell
        Under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Act</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> now
        served in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1803</TIMEX> there was yet another failed rebellion, led
        by the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Emmet</ENAMEX>. His speech from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX> and his
        horrendous execution have become the stuff of legend. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel O‚</ENAMEX>ÄôConnell
        carried on the struggle. He formed the peaceful but powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1829</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wellington</ENAMEX>, in a bid to avoid a
        civil war, passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Emancipation Bill</ENAMEX>, which allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> to sit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O‚ÄôConnell</ENAMEX> was made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lord mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1841</TIMEX>, but failed in his bid
        to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> repealed and an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> parliament
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re-established</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Famine and Home Rule</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Famine</ENAMEX> struck in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1845</TIMEX> with a blight on the staple
        food of the poor, the potato. It lasted until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1848</TIMEX>, and it is estimated
        that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> died and as many emigrated to escape
        the ravages of the catastrophe. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 1800s</TIMEX> the population
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was virtually halved. Ironically, there was plenty of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food around‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇcorn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>, and flour‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbut it was not available
        to the poor.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> was formed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Brotherhood</ENAMEX>, known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fenians</ENAMEX>. Their rebellion was
        aborted, but the society remained active and was influential in the
        efforts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Land League</ENAMEX>, founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1879</TIMEX>, which sought to
        change the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant system</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Stewart Parnell</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>, took up the cause, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land Acts</ENAMEX>, which enabled
        hard-pressed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> to buy their land, were passed.
        Parnell‚Äôs other cause was the demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Rule</ENAMEX> for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>. For a time, it looked as if the campaign was going to succeed,
        but political events, together with the citing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parnell</ENAMEX> as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-respondent in a scandalous divorce case led many to withdraw their
        support.
        The bill for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Rule</ENAMEX> finally became law just as <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>
        I broke out, but with the proviso that it was not to be enacted until
        hostilities ended.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Easter Rising</ENAMEX> and War
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years</TIMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, 24 April</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1916</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter Rising</ENAMEX> began when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizen‚Äôs Army</ENAMEX>, led by trade
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unionist James Connolly</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Brotherhood</ENAMEX>, led by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poet Padr√°ig Pearse</ENAMEX>, took control of a number of key <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in the
        capital. Pearse read out a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Office</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">O‚ÄôConnell Street</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Countess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constance Markievicz</ENAMEX> led a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> to occupy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Stephen‚Äôs Green</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were urged to fight, but to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dubliners</ENAMEX> it all seemed
        rather unreal‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇin fact, while it was happening it received little
        public support.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were killed and many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>
        building, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal College of Surgeons‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbefore the Rising was put
        down. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fifteen</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> were executed, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearse</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wounded Connolly</ENAMEX>, who was brought to his execution in an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ambulance</ENAMEX> and
        shot tied to a chair. Of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eamon De Valera</ENAMEX> was spared,
        probably because he was an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Markievicz</ENAMEX>, because
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> did not want to execute a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> retribution
        galvanized the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Irish‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> in the words of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats‚</ENAMEX>Äôs poem, ‚ÄúAll changed,
        changed utterly.‚Äù
        In the general election of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX> an overwhelming number of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinn F√</ENAMEX>©in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republicans</ENAMEX> were returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>. Instead of going to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn F√©in</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> set up Dail √âireann in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>
        and sparked the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Independence</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX> the conflict resulted in a
        partial victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1921</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Partition Act</ENAMEX> enabled the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> to remain in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>,
        while the remaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> became independent. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following year</TIMEX>,
        however, civil war broke out between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Collins</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Griffith</ENAMEX>, who had signed the treaty, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eamon De Valera‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>. The civil war lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX> the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Free</ENAMEX>
        State was born.
        Independence and After
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Valera‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republican</ENAMEX> constitution took <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>
        out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Commonwealth</ENAMEX>, and the new republic elected its first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Hyde</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>. During <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, though bombs
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> fell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> remained neutral.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> severed its last ties to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neglect</ENAMEX>, conquest, and isolation, however, had taken their
        toll, and at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> was characterized by a parochial
        and narrow-minded approach to affairs, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> was content to let
        its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> heritage decay. In some cases, modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> were
        erected in their place that are not admired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> has
        always looked to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> for friendship and support, and gradually it
        began to define itself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. It joined the European
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> city <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX> was marked by the
        restoration of many fine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and by new statues and monuments
        created by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> (some of these works more successful than
        others). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year</TIMEX> before the celebrations, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> had elected its first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">in 1990 Ireland</ENAMEX> chose the dynamic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Robinson</ENAMEX> as
        its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman president</ENAMEX>.
        The ultimate accolade came in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> was
        designated a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European City of Culture</ENAMEX>. As capital of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe‚</ENAMEX>Äôs fastest
        growing economy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, this new, self-assured <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> is now very much a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
