
  
  
    
      
        A Brief History
        The earliest signs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> are the remains of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arawak</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Amerindian</ENAMEX> society that originated on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">north</ENAMEX> coast of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arawak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> migrated to various <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> islands,
        arriving in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the eighth century</TIMEX>. They were
        peaceful and lived by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚Äúslash-and-burn‚</NUMEX>Äù farming. For <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>, they bred
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX> and ate iguana, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> to the island. They were highly
        skilled in such manual activities as thatching and weaving. In fact,
        the hammock was an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Amerindian</ENAMEX> invention that remains with us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>; it
        is an object which, more than any other, evokes an image of a warm
        sunny <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> on a tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">isle</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arawak</ENAMEX> left a legacy of paintings in
        places such as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Runaway Caves</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Discovery Bay</ENAMEX>, and shards of pottery
        found at their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">settlements</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nueva Sevilla and Spanish Town</ENAMEX> have
        added a little to our knowledge about them. Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arawak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> have
        been identified, and it is said that when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> arrived in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arawak</ENAMEX> living on the island.
        They called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jamaica ‚ÄúXaymaca‚Äù (‚</ENAMEX>Äúland of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> and water‚Äù).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> and the Arrival of Europeans
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbus</ENAMEX> first arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 May 1494</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discovery</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX>, where there is now a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> in his honor. He stayed for only a
        few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> but returned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1502</TIMEX>, landing here when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> of his fleet
        became unserviceable; he waited at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Ann‚Äôs Bay</ENAMEX> for help to arrive
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. After the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1505</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> became the
        property of his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>, who dispatched <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Juan de Esquivel</ENAMEX> to the
        island as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esquivel</ENAMEX> arrived in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1510</TIMEX> and created a base called Nueva
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sevilla</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Ann‚Äôs Bay</ENAMEX>, from which he hoped to colonize the rest of
        the island. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> immediately began subjugating the Arawak
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, many of whom died under the yoke of oppression and of
        diseases carried by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>. A number of them committed suicide
        rather than live the life created for them by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>.
        The site of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nueva Sevilla</ENAMEX> proved to be unhealthy and
        mosquito-ridden, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1534</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> founded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Villa de la</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vega</ENAMEX>,
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> known as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish Town</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pig</ENAMEX> breeding was the main occupation of
        these early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>, but they also planted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar cane</ENAMEX> and other crops
        that required large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX>. The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arawak</ENAMEX> had
        already fallen dramatically, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> began to import slaves from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX> to work the land; the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> arrived in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1517</TIMEX>.
        The opportunities that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> had to offer were never
        really exploited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>. They were much more interested in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and other treasures to be found in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>. However, they
        had to protect the shipping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> in order to get their treasure home,
        and this meant keeping hold of as much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> (or the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúSpanish Main</ENAMEX>,‚Äù as it was then known) as possible. They fortified the
        more strategic islands, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> was deemed less important than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>
        or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> and, consequently, was poorly protected.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Rule</ENAMEX>
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1654</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Cromwell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord Protector of England</ENAMEX>,
        dispatched a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> to break the stranglehold
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>. They were repulsed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hispaniola</ENAMEX> by a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> and decided to take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> as a consolation prize. They sailed
        into what is now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingston Bay</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1655</TIMEX> and sent an ultimatum to the
        capital. The small <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> considered its position and decided to
        retreat, heading to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">north</ENAMEX> coast and sailing to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. Before they
        left, they freed their slaves, who fled into the interior of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> attempted to retake the island in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1658</TIMEX> at the
        Battle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rio Bueno</ENAMEX> but were defeated; however, this did not alleviate
        Jamaica‚Äôs problems. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> began to put pressure on the
        defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> naval power in the area was badly
        stretched. Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Modyford</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>, offered a deal
        to pirate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> already well established in the area: if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX>
        protected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> assets, then they were free to harass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> shipping
        with impunity. They agreed; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Modyford</ENAMEX> issued letters of accreditation
        which authorized the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> to act in the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown</ENAMEX>.
        These <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúprivateers‚Äù</ENAMEX> were welcomed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Royal</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
        settlement on the southern tip of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX>, and it quickly
        developed a reputation as the wickedest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the world. Plunder was
        now legitimate business and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was awash with money and booty
        from the numerous pirate raids. There was little evidence of religion
        or of the rule of law. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Morgan</ENAMEX> was chief among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirate leaders</ENAMEX>.
        He and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> conducted a successful series of bloody raids on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">settlements</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>, culminating in the sacking of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>, the major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Spanish Main</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1670</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> officially ceded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        rule as part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Treaty</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> began a
        systematic process of settlement, offering land and aid to prospective
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>. They rescinded their agreement with the privateers and began
        the process of evicting them from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Royal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Morgan</ENAMEX> was offered
        the post of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lieutenant Governor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> and charged with driving
        out his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohorts</ENAMEX>. The erstwhile pirate thus became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>
        during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last years</TIMEX> of his life. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1588</TIMEX> before his task
        was complete, but nature finished what he had started: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> suffered
        a powerful earthquake in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1692</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Royal</ENAMEX> sank into the sea, taking
        with it many of the treasures stolen from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>. The surviving
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pirates</ENAMEX> took to the sea once again.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plantations and Slavery</ENAMEX>
        As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX> began, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX>
        was putting the disaster at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Royal</ENAMEX> behind it. The trade in sugar
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cane</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX> was becoming profitable. However, there was a problem.
        Plantation work was labor intensive, but there were very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX>
        on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> had disappeared into the inhospitable
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interior</ENAMEX> and the native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arawak</ENAMEX> had been decimated by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. The
        decision was made to import a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Africa</ENAMEX>, resulting in
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 600,000</NUMEX> slaves being transported to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> over the next few
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> died en route, and many more died of
        disease once on the island. However, there seemed to be an
        inexhaustible supply sailing across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>. On the back of this
        cruel system, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> gradually became the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> in
        the world and a very wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> indeed.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> slowly became better organized. Thirteen
        administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">parishes</ENAMEX> were created, forming the basis of government
        that we still see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> voice of the monarch,
        commissioned a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> (or custos) in each parish. Powerful
        land-owning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> organized an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assembly</ENAMEX> to run the everyday affairs
        of the island, but many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landowners</ENAMEX> continued to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, where
        they exerted tremendous influence in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>. They ensured that the
        interests of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>, or at least their own interests on the island,
        were always at the forefront of decisions made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>.
        However, even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these early days</TIMEX> there were slaves who
        fought against the tyranny of the system. The original slaves whom the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> had released after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1655</TIMEX> became known as ‚ÄúMaroons,‚Äù from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> word cimarr√≥n (which means ‚Äúwild‚Äù or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äúuntamed‚Äù</ENAMEX>). They made
        their settlements in the hills away from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> rule but began to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attack colonists</ENAMEX> in a program of raids now remembered as The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
        Maroon <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> suffered constant harassment at their hands
        and even named a part of the island <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúThe Land of Look Behind‚Äù in</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> of the surprise attacks they suffered. Eventually the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> began to force the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maroons</ENAMEX> into more isolated and remote
        pockets of land.
        This war of attrition ended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1739</TIMEX>, when agreement was
        reached between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maroons</ENAMEX> were allowed self-rule in
        certain designated areas in return for not inciting or helping the
        plantation slaves. This agreement is at the root of Maroon
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-government</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The slaves themselves also began organizing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revolts</ENAMEX> (the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1760</TIMEX>), but their situation remained the same.
        Treatment of slaves was for the most part cruel and inhumane, with
        family life virtually destroyed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> were systematically split
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
        During the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American War of Independence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> came under
        threat again from other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> powers, which saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Britain‚</ENAMEX>Äôs problem to
        the north as a chance to capture its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>. Some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">islands</ENAMEX> were taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Admiral Rodney</ENAMEX> saved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> by
        defeating the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Saintes</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1782</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> thereafter became an island of strategic importance for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, who based a large naval <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Charles</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Emancipation</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">French Revolution</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1789</TIMEX> sent ripples of discontent
        through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> peasants‚Äô cry for freedom prompted
        another <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Maroon War</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>, after which many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Maroons</ENAMEX> were deported
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nova Scotia</ENAMEX>. There was, however, a growing movement against slavery
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1807</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> made the trade in slaves illegal, but
        the powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> lobby exerted pressure and slavery continued on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plantations</ENAMEX>. The slaves were angry and dispirited, but nonconformist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">churches</ENAMEX> broke the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of England</ENAMEX> and encouraged the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slaves</ENAMEX> to stand up and take action against injustice. This intervention
        guaranteed the popularity of these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> denominations; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, you
        will find <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adventist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> in almost every settlement,
        their congregations still as strong <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1800s</TIMEX>.
        The momentum for change was growing, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1831</TIMEX> a black
        lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúDaddy‚Äù Sam Sharpe</ENAMEX> led a revolt of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> slaves at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montego Bay</ENAMEX>. After a campaign of great destruction, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>
        assured them that slavery would be abolished. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharpe</ENAMEX> and approximately
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1000</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> surrendered peacefully, only to be rounded up and
        publicly executed. This news was met with revulsion in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, and
        moves to liberate the slaves culminated in full freedom in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1838</TIMEX>. Many
        retreated into the hills to make their own way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forefathers</ENAMEX> of
        today‚Äôs small-scale, self-sufficient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>.
        Unfortunately, being ‚Äúfree‚Äù solved none of the problems
        suffered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. There was no economic infrastructure
        outside the plantation system, and power remained in the hands of a
        small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> of white and mixed-race <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX> were invited to take up the work previously carried out by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slaves</ENAMEX>; their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> can still be found on the island,
        particularly around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little London</ENAMEX> in the west. As a further blow to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Parliament</ENAMEX> passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sugar Equalization Act</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1846</TIMEX> as part of a new free-trade policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica‚Äôs</ENAMEX> protected market was
        effectively gone.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1865</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morant Bay</ENAMEX>, there was another uprising,
        led by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Bogle</ENAMEX> and by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Gordon</ENAMEX>, a mulatto
        (mixed-race) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landowner</ENAMEX>. It brought savage retribution from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, and both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> were executed. But it prompted the
        dissolution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica Assembly</ENAMEX>, which was dominated by plantation
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>. The island became a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown Colony</ENAMEX> ruled directly from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>,
        and over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX> there were several reforms to its political
        and social systems.
        As the sugar trade declined in importance, economic
        disaster loomed. Fortuitously, another crop found favor withthe
        industrial world: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> became the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX>. The first
        consignments were exported in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1866</TIMEX> and, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a few years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousands</NUMEX>
        of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> were being shipped to markets in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>
        carrying the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana crops</ENAMEX> also fostered the beginnings of the tourist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> arrived as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> on them, spending time
        around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Antonio</ENAMEX>. Charmed by the tropical paradise, they quickly
        spread the word about the beauty of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>.
        Still there was little change in conditions for the black
        majority, who had no economic or political power. The world-wide
        depression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1930s</ENAMEX> brought a new wave of demonstrations in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>, and a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> emerged to lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
        pave the way for nationhood. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus Garvey</ENAMEX> called for black
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-reliance</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Bustamante</ENAMEX> formed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial Trade</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> and later the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica Labour Party</ENAMEX> (JLP). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica Trades</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Workers Union</ENAMEX> allied themselves to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People‚Äôs National Party</ENAMEX> (PNP), led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Manley</ENAMEX> in opposition to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bustamante</ENAMEX>. Together, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> fought for local rule, which
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX> resulted in universal voting rights for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>.
        At the same time, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> brought
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> who were no longer able to travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX>. Jamaica‚Äôs popularity as a tourist destination was now
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">undeniable</ENAMEX>.
        Independence and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> Rule
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the postwar period</TIMEX> there continued to be constitutional
        changes, including self-government for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> hoped
        to create a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation of Caribbean Islands</ENAMEX> in the region. But the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaicans</ENAMEX> voted instead for full independence, which became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> on
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1962</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> is also a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonwealth</ENAMEX>.
        Since independence the political culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>, which
        started out with such confidence and optimism, has been fraught with
        problems. Violence and corruption have been constant factors in the
        political process.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1962 until 1972</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JLP</ENAMEX> held power. The party‚Äôs broad
        aims were to support capitalist policies and to continue close ties
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonwealth</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, however, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">left-wing PNP</ENAMEX> was elected with a massive majority but with little
        change in the economic power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Manley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>, led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and pushed for policies that brought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX>
        closer to independent nonaligned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manley</ENAMEX> was made out to be a
        second <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>, foreign investment quickly dried up, many wealthy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamaicans</ENAMEX> left the island, and the economy collapsed. The uncertain and
        volatile situation led to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> violence, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> seemed to be
        heading for civil war. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JLP</ENAMEX> came back to power following a
        campaign that saw the deaths of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Seaga</ENAMEX>, reintroduced capitalist policies and foreign investment
        began to trickle back.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> in the 1990s
        Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PNP</ENAMEX> has once again been in power, this time
        under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Percival Patterson</ENAMEX>. He and his
        party are charged with forging a positive path for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. Energy is being focused initially on using the cultural wealth
        of the island to create a real national identity. But the problem of
        economic and social inequality remains, and violence, which accompanies
        political allegiance, remains a part of everyday life in the ghettos of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingston</ENAMEX>.
        Notwithstanding its status as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonwealth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> now looks much more toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> for its future.
        Its proximity to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">US‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇonly <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90 minutes</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> by air‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇmeans
        that cultural influences for the young are found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
        entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> and sports. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> seeks to combine these
        influences with its own strong identity to create an independent and
        stable society.
      
    
  
