
  
  
    
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢‚Ä¢</ENAMEX>
        ‚Ä¢
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢‚Ä¢</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢‚Ä¢</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Ä¢A Brief History</ENAMEX>
        ‚Ä¢ A handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronze Age</ENAMEX> relics has fostered an assumption
        that prehistoric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> inhabited Ibiza <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>.
        Greater evidence of such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is found on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mallorca</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menorca</ENAMEX> than
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibiza</ENAMEX>, but one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balearics‚</ENAMEX>Äô most important sites is actually on
        the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Formentera</ENAMEX>, where the megalithic monument/<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ca Na</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa</ENAMEX> has been dated to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> b.c.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢Ibiza‚Äôs</ENAMEX> key location between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX> and ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iberia</ENAMEX> made
        it a convenient stopover for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> seafarers, such as the
        Phoenician <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, who called the island <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibosim</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> dubbed it
        Ebysos, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romans</ENAMEX> called it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebusus</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moors, Yebisah</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢The Carthaginians</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Ä¢A</ENAMEX> detailed history of the island doesn‚Äôt begin until it
        became a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carthage</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 7th century</TIMEX> b.c. (see also pages
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14-15</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carthaginians</ENAMEX> originally came from the area comprising
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">present-day Lebanon</ENAMEX>, and from their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Africa</ENAMEX> and what‚Äôs
        now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, they challenged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Empire</ENAMEX> for domination of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean region</ENAMEX>. Their interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ibiza</ENAMEX> lay partly in its vast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">salt</ENAMEX> flats, which to this day remain the source of a profitable
        industry. They capitalized on the natural resources by using the salt
        to cure <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, which they exported to their home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carthaginians</ENAMEX> also carried out <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead</ENAMEX> mining and continued to be of
        significance up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>. It is believed that the lead
        pellets which were used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carthaginian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannibal</ENAMEX> were made
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibiza</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢The Carthaginians</ENAMEX> also considered the island a holy place,
        and here in great splendour they buried <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> in
        a huge necropolis on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puig des Molins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windmills</ENAMEX>) below
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dalt Vila</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Town</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibiza</ENAMEX>. Under the gnarled olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>
        archaeologists have uncovered a treasure trove of statues, jewellery,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pitchers</ENAMEX>, tools, and coins, which are now displayed in the town‚Äôs two
        archaeological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢The Romans</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢The Romans</ENAMEX> never really infiltrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ibiza</ENAMEX>, and even after
        the defeat of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hannibal</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">202 b.c.</TIMEX> during the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Punic War</ENAMEX> their
        influence was restrained. Only with the fall of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carthage</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">146 b.c.</TIMEX>
        did they manage to make inroads, but, as local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> stress, Ibiza
        was neither conquered nor annexed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, but confederated, retaining
        remarkable autonomy. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> to come the old Carthaginian
        traditions were allowed to continue on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibiza</ENAMEX> alongside the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of life. Meanwhile on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iberian</ENAMEX> peninsula, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> was leaving a
        decisive imprint on the area‚<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Äôs language</ENAMEX>, culture, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and
        particularly in its engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> in the construction of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>,
        aqueducts, and monuments.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢The Romans</ENAMEX> also exploited <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ibiza‚Äôs</ENAMEX> natural resources. They
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">exported salt</ENAMEX> from the southern end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> and lead from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mines of Sant Carles</ENAMEX>, and at the same time extracted a purple <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dye</ENAMEX> from
        shellfish which was used for imperial cloaks. In addition they found a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moneymaker</ENAMEX> in an exotic, aromatic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> of decomposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">innards</ENAMEX>.
        Called garum, it was considered a great delicacy by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX>
        alike. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it is but a historical footnote; local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cooks</ENAMEX> use nothing
        more pungent than a hint of garlic. )
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢The Moors</ENAMEX>
        ‚Ä¢After centuries of peace and productivity, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> a.d.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">426</TIMEX> marked the beginning of an era of strife, violence, and
        destruction. Ibiza, along with the rest of what is now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, was
        invaded and sacked by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vandals</ENAMEX>, who occupied
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> and quickly imposed their culture. Centuries of almost
        constant repressive foreign rule followed, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vandals</ENAMEX> being
        succeeded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Byzantines, Saracens</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moors</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢The Moorish</ENAMEX> conquest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balearics</ENAMEX> was complete by a.d.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">903</NUMEX>, and except during the periodic outbreaks of violence typical of
        that time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moors</ENAMEX> devoted themselves to developing the island
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> and agri¬≠culture. However, little evidence remains of that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">era‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsome ceramics</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, a few fortifications, a network of
        irrigation ditches. For the most part, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moorish</ENAMEX> legacy is manifested
        in a few local place names, some words in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibicenco</ENAMEX> dialect, and an
        indelible influence on the island‚Äôs folk music. Indeed, perhaps the
        most vivid reminder of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moors</ENAMEX> are the dark, brooding eyes of so many
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">islanders</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢Christian Reconquest</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢The Moors</ENAMEX> were determined to carry Islam into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. To
        this end they invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> itself and even reached up into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>
        until they were beaten by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Martel</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">732</TIMEX>. But
        after the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Crusade of Pisa</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> power waned, and in
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 13th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibiza</ENAMEX> was embraced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Reconquest</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King James</ENAMEX> I of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aragon</ENAMEX> authorized the occupation of the islands under
        forces commanded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guillermo de Montgri</ENAMEX>, a solid Catalonian citizen
        with titular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ecclesiastical</ENAMEX> rank. After a few skirmishes, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catalonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> were ready to deal the death blow. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> pincer
        battered its way through the rebuilt city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX>, while the other‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇso it
        is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">said‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇinfiltrated</ENAMEX> through a secret passage revealed to the invaders
        by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> of the sheik himself. According to legend the embittered
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">traitor</ENAMEX> gave the game away because the passionate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheik</ENAMEX> had seduced his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢Thus</ENAMEX>, violently, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1235</TIMEX>, both Christianity and the
        Catalonian language came to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibiza</ENAMEX> to stay. On the mainland, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconquista</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconquest</ENAMEX>) continued for another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-half</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">centuries</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moors</ENAMEX> suffered a major setback in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1212</TIMEX> at the battle of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navas de Tolosa</ENAMEX> in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Andalusia</ENAMEX>, but they still clung to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">kingdom of Granada</ENAMEX> and were only finally evicted from there in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1492</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢Booty</ENAMEX> and Plunder
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢Elsewhere</ENAMEX>, great events were changing the shape of the
        world. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferdinand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabella</ENAMEX>, the unity of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> as the country
        we know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> was finally achieved, and it was carrying their flag that
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1492</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christopher Columbus</ENAMEX> sailed westwards and discovered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.
        Soon <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> found itself the recipient of immense wealth in the form of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>, eager for more, turned their
        attention away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibiza</ENAMEX> towards both the New
        World and the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> ambitions rapidly
        expanded. Ibiza became a mere backwater, largely forgotten but for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shipwreck</ENAMEX> or plague.
        ‚Ä¢The moment that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monarchs</ENAMEX> looked the other way,
        the daring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Barbary Coast‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇand
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">elsewhere‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇmoved</ENAMEX> in. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibicencos</ENAMEX> fortified the bulwarks and built
        additional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> and fortresses throughout to help shield themselves
        against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> incursions. Despite their efforts, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ibiza</ENAMEX> was
        menaced by so many hostile flotillas that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> took the
        unprecedented step of forming their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of privateers. To the
        Berbers‚Äô amazement the tables were turned, and it wasn‚Äôt long before
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibicencos</ENAMEX> were boarding the enemy‚Äôs brigantines on the open seas
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúliberating‚Äù the pirates‚Äô booty‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇ‚ÄÇ</ENAMEX> even that of the greatly feared
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúPope‚Äù</ENAMEX> (see box). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> an obelisk in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ibiza‚Äôs</ENAMEX> port honours the daring
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corsairs</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢Reminders</ENAMEX> of the permanent threat posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> can be
        found everywhere on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibiza</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> it is notable that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>
        and other focal points from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX> were built on an elevated site
        to provide lookout posts and early warning systems. In many isolated
        regions, meanwhile, last-ditch defences in the form of round stone
        towers were built, a few of which are still inhabited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. An unusual
        collection of such <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> can be seen from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sant Joan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> in a
        hamlet with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moorish</ENAMEX> name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balafi</ENAMEX>, near the village of Sant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loren√ß.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢Political Turmoil</ENAMEX>
        ‚Ä¢In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 20th centuries</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> was both
        economically weak and politically unstable. It lost its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>, and then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923</TIMEX> suffered a humiliating defeat
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX> at the hands of local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Alfonso XIII</ENAMEX>
        neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX> nor constitutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was able to create
        and sustain domestic tranquillity, with the result that following
        anti-royalist election results in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> went into exile.
        ‚Ä¢The turbulence continued under the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> continued
        to be turbulent, however, with bitter ideological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">factions</ENAMEX>, involving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> as well. Finally, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>, a
        large section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Franco</ENAMEX> rose in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">revolt</ENAMEX>, claiming the support of the monarchists, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>, and the right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falange</ENAMEX> par¬≠ty, the fascist movement which
        had been founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX> and which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco</ENAMEX> subsequently declared to be
        the only legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>. Opposing him was a collection of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republicans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">socialists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communists</ENAMEX>, and anarchists.
        ‚Ä¢The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Spanish Civil War</ENAMEX> became one of the causes <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">c√©l√®bres</ENAMEX> of
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX>, with support for both sides being rallied in many
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>. In Ibiza several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> were torn in their
        loyalties between the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nationalist</ENAMEX> causes. The bloodshed
        lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> and cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of lives, and almost
        every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ibiza‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇnot</ENAMEX> to mention the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mainland‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwas</ENAMEX> touched by
        tragedy. Ibiza, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Formentera</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menorca</ENAMEX> were all captured by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loyalist</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forces</ENAMEX>, who used the islands as a base for their naval operations.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hardship</ENAMEX> was compounded with the advent of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, even though
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> stayed neutral throughout the war.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢The</ENAMEX> shattered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> economy inched forward during the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">post-war</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibiza</ENAMEX> the breakthrough came in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, with the
        introduction of wide-bodied <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> and a significant surge in tourism.
        Following the expansion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, the island entered the big
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">league</ENAMEX> of international holiday <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX>.
        ‚Ä¢After the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Carlos</ENAMEX> I
        restored democracy to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>. In free elections in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1977</TIMEX>, moderates
        and democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">socialists</ENAMEX> emerged as the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. Ibiza‚Äôs new
        freedom meant the renaissance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Ibicenco</ENAMEX> language and culture
        after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of suppression, and participation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Catalonia‚</ENAMEX>Äôs newly
        won autonomy. Free speech and free elections were not the only
        innovations: gambling was legalized and nude bathing was sanctioned.
        Change swept through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibiza</ENAMEX> dramatically, irrevocably, almost
        overnight.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Ä¢Modern Times</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢Since</ENAMEX> then, the development of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibiza</ENAMEX> has continued, and
        the island‚Äôs fortunes are now almost completely derived from tourism.
        Changes on mainland <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> have inevitably been felt on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibiza</ENAMEX> also, but
        their effect has been largely beneficial. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist Workers‚Äô Party</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felipe Gonz√°lez M√°rquez</ENAMEX> was elected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> and his government
        committed itself to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spain‚Äôs</ENAMEX> integration into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>
        (formerly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Community</ENAMEX>). As a precondition to admission, the
        border with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibraltar</ENAMEX> was reopened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> after a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16-year</TIMEX> hiatus, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> was admitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>. In spite of high unemployment and
        separatist rumblings, the country‚Äôs economic growth rate remained one
        of the highest in all of western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. Although
        Ibiza‚Äôs popularity as a holiday destination has never waned, the events
        of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years‚</TIMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇSeville Expo ‚Äò92</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barcelona Olympics‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇhave
        ensured its continued success.
      
    
  
