
  
  
    
      
        A Brief History
        In the popular mind, the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, long the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">entryway</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> for Westerners, begins in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1841</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        occupation of the territory. However, it would be wrong to dismiss the
        long history of the region itself. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archaeologists</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are working to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uncover Hong Kong‚</ENAMEX>Äôs past, which stretches back <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. You
        can get a glimpse into that past at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lei Cheng Uk Museum‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1,600-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial vault</ENAMEX> on the mainland just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kowloon</ENAMEX> (see
        page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX>). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, when construction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chek Lap Kok</ENAMEX> was
        begun, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,000-year-old</TIMEX> village, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pak Mong</ENAMEX>, was discovered, complete
        with artifacts that indicated a sophisticated rural society. An even
        older <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone Age</ENAMEX> site was discovered on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lamma Island</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.
        While <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> remained a relative backwater in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early days</TIMEX>,
        nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guangzhou</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canton</ENAMEX>) was developing into a great trading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with
        connections in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. By a.d. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">islands</ENAMEX> had become a lair for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> preying on the shipping in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl River Delta</ENAMEX> and causing a major headache for burgeoning
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guangzhou</ENAMEX>; small bands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> were still operating into the early
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years of the 20th century</TIMEX>.
        In the meantime, the mainland area was being settled by
        incomers, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">‚ÄúFive Great Clans‚Äù</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tang, Hau, Pang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liu</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man</ENAMEX>. First
        to arrive was the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tang</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX>, which established a number of walled
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Territories</ENAMEX> that still exist <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. You can visit
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kat Hing Wai</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lo Wai</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> with their walls still intact.
        Adjacent to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lo Wai</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tang Chung Ling Ancestral Hall</ENAMEX>, built in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16th century</TIMEX>, which is still the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX> activities.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> to arrive in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pearl River Delta</ENAMEX> were
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX>, who settled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macau</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1557</TIMEX> and for several centuries
        had a monopoly on trade between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>. As
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macau</ENAMEX> developed into the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>, it also became a
        base for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jesuit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX>; it was later a haven for persecuted
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese Christians</ENAMEX>. While Christianity was not a great success in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, it made local headway, evidenced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by the numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">churches</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macau‚</ENAMEX>Äôs historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. Intermarriage with the local
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> created a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macanese</ENAMEX>, whose culture can still be
        seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macau‚</ENAMEX>Äôs architecture and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Arrive</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äú Albert</ENAMEX> is so amused,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúat my having
        got the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù Her foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palmerston</ENAMEX>,
        was not so amused; he dismissed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> as ‚Äúa barren <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> with
        hardly a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> upon it. ‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong Island</ENAMEX> formally became a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> possession two
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later in 1843</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> had a base for the thriving trade
        they had carried on from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canton</ENAMEX>. Trading conditions, however, were not
        easy. The attitude expressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qianlong</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britian‚Äôs</ENAMEX> first
        attempt to open trade with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1793</TIMEX> continued to prevail: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúWe</ENAMEX>
        possess all things,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>, ‚ÄúI set no value on objects
        strange or ingenious, and have no use for your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">country‚Äôs</ENAMEX> manufactures.‚Äù
        Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> would accept nothing but silver bullion in
        exchange for its goods, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Britian</ENAMEX> had to look for a more abundant
        commodity to square its accounts. Around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 18th century</TIMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> found a solution: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Opium</ENAMEX> was the wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> that would
        solve the problem. Grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, it was delivered to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canton</ENAMEX>, and
        while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> outlawed the trade in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1799</TIMEX>, local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cantonese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were
        always willing to look the other way for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúsqueeze money‚Äù</ENAMEX> (a term still
        used in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>).
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1839</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> appointed the incorruptible
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lin Tse-hsu</ENAMEX> to stamp out the smuggling of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúforeign mud</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        Lin‚Äôs crackdown was indeed severe. He demanded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canton</ENAMEX> surrender their opium <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, and to back up his
        ultimatum he laid siege to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, who, after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> tense <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>,
        surrendered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 20,000</NUMEX> chests of opium. To Queen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lin</ENAMEX>
        addressed a famous letter, pointing out the harm the ‚Äúpoisonous drug‚Äù
        did to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, and asking for an end to the opium trade; his arguments
        are unanswerable, but the lofty though heartfelt tone of the letter
        shows how unprepared the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> were to negotiate with the West in
        realistic terms.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year later</TIMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1840</TIMEX>, came the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> retaliation,
        beginning the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Opium Wars</ENAMEX>. After a few skirmishes
        and much negotiation, a peace agreement was reached. Under the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convention of Chuenpi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> was given the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, and
        on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26 January 1841</TIMEX>, it was proclaimed a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Opium Wars</ENAMEX>
        The peace plan achieved at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chuenpi</ENAMEX> was short-lived. Both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peking</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> repudiated the agreement, and fighting resumed. This
        time the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 3,000</NUMEX> strong but in possession of
        superior <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and tactics, outfought the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shanghai</ENAMEX> fell and
        Nanking was threatened. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Treaty of Nanking</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1842</TIMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> was
        compelled to open <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> to foreign economic and political
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">penetration</ENAMEX>, and even to compensate the opium <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smugglers</ENAMEX> for their
        losses. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong‚</ENAMEX>Äôs status as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> and a free <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> was
        confirmed.
        In the aftermath of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Opium Wars</ENAMEX>, trade in ‚Äúforeign mud‚Äù
        was resumed at a level even higher than before, although the major
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, by now respectable and diversified, stopped their trading in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1907</TIMEX>. Opium-smoking continued openly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>; in
        mainland <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> abolished it when they came to
        power in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> and Wealth
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Pottinger</ENAMEX>,
        predicted it would become ‚Äúa vast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">emporium of commerce</ENAMEX> and wealth. ‚Äù
        Under his direction, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> began its march toward prosperity. It
        was soon flourishing; with its natural harbor that attracted <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> leaped to the forefront as a base for trade. Both the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and the economy began to grow steadily. A surprise was the
        sizable number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> who chose to move to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>.
        In the meantime, the opening of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> was the last blow
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Macau‚Äôs</ENAMEX> prosperity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inroads</ENAMEX> had already been made by the arrival of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macau‚</ENAMEX>Äôs loss to them of the profitable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> trade.
        From then on, until its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1970s</NUMEX> comeback with electronic and other export
        goods, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macau</ENAMEX> sank into obscurity.
        Despite the differences between the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX>, relations were generally cordial. Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Davis</ENAMEX>, an early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, disgusted with the squabbling of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, declared: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúIt is a much easier task to govern the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> than the few <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
        There were a few incidents: On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 January 1857</TIMEX>, somebody
        added an extra <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredient</ENAMEX> to the dough at the colony‚Äôs main
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bakery‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇarsenic</ENAMEX>. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> continued to enjoy their daily
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rice</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, eating their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, were dropping like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flies</ENAMEX>.
        At the height of the panic, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> were deported from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. No one ever discovered the identity or the motive of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">culprits</ENAMEX>.
        Conditions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>, however, did
        not favor the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> lived along the
        waterfront in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX> (now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>) and on the cooler slopes of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Peak</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> were barred from these areas, and from any
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> neighborhood. They settled in what is now known as the Western
        District. It was not uncommon for several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> to
        share <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in crowded shantytowns. So it is not surprising that
        when bubonic plague struck in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1894</TIMEX>, it took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 30 years</TIMEX> to fully
        eradicate it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western District</ENAMEX>, you can still wander
        narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> lined with small traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ginseng</ENAMEX>,
        medicinal herbs, incense, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>, and funeral objects.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860</TIMEX>, a treaty gave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> a permanent beach-head on
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mainland‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe Kowloon</ENAMEX> peninsula, directly across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">harbor</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1898</TIMEX>, under the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Convention of Peking</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> leased the New
        Territories and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">235</NUMEX> more islands to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> for what then seemed an
        eternity‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ÄÇ99 years</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">20th Century</ENAMEX>
        The colony‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> has always fluctuated according to
        events beyond its borders. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> revolution
        overthrew the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> flocked to the safety of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>.
        Many arrived with nothing but the shirts on their backs, but they
        brought their philosophy of working hard and seizing opportunity.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> more arrived in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> invaded
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. By the eve of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> and
        a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half million</NUMEX>.
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A few hours</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1941</TIMEX>, a dozen <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">battalions</ENAMEX> began an
        assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hong Kong‚</ENAMEX>Äôs minimal air force was destroyed on
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airfield</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kai Tak</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>. Abandoning the New
        Territories and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kowloon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> retreated to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> island,
        hoping for relief which never came. They finally surrendered on
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Day</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX>. Survivors recall <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and a half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of
        hunger and hardship under the occupation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, who deported many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kong Chinese</ENAMEX> to the mainland. A number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong Kong‚</ENAMEX>Äôs monuments were
        damaged during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. John‚Äôs Cathedral</ENAMEX> was turned into a
        military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, the old governor‚Äôs lodge on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peak</ENAMEX> was burned down,
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commandant</ENAMEX> of the occupation forces rebuilt the colonial
        governor‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> style.
        At the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> took stock of what
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">remained‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇthe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> was down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a million</NUMEX>, and there was no
        industry, no fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX>, and few <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and public services.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> Comes Back
        China‚Äôs civil war sent distressing echoes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>.
        While the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> drove towards the south, the flow of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> multiplied, and by the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic of China</ENAMEX> was proclaimed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>, the total <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX> had grown to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The fall of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> brought another flood of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, among them many wealthy people
        and skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artisans</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">industrialists</ENAMEX> who became
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong Kong‚Äôs</ENAMEX> now famous textile industry. In the late
        1970s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> became the conduit for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs goods, investment, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tourism</ENAMEX>. It also found itself famous as a worldwide bargain shopping
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>.
        Housing was now in desperately short supply. Housing had
        always been scarce for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong Kong‚</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Äôs Chinese</ENAMEX>. The problem became an
        outright disaster on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Day</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>. An uncontrollable fire
        devoured a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of squatters‚Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shacks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kowloon</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>
        were deprived of shelter. The calamity spurred the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to launch
        an emergency program of public-housing construction; spartan new blocks
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> put cheap and fireproof roofs over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX>
        of heads. But this new housing was grimly overcrowded, and even a
        frenzy of construction couldn‚Äôt keep pace with the demand for living
        space. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> the colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> closed the border with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
        but even this did not altogether stem the flow of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>: The next
        arrivals were the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> boat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
        Into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">21st Century</ENAMEX>
        As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> drew <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearer</NUMEX>, it became clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
        government had no intention of renewing the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">99-year</TIMEX> lease on the New
        Territories. Negotiations began, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> signed the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sino-British Joint Declaration</ENAMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
        confirmed the transfer of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Territories</ENAMEX> and all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. For its part, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> declared <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> a ‚ÄúSpecial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrative Region‚Äù</ENAMEX> and guaranteed its civil and social system for
        at least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years after 1997</TIMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚Äôs Basic Law</ENAMEX> promised that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong‚</ENAMEX>Äôs existing laws and civil liberties would be upheld, refugees
        began flowing the other way. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Nationality Act</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>) had in
        effect prevented <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> from acquiring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>,
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, anxious about their future under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs rule,
        were prompted to apply for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> elsewhere, notably in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>. The protests in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beijing‚Äôs Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> sparked
        sympathy marches in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, and further increased tension with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> moved their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>.
        Ironically, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">handover</ENAMEX> approached, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> granted
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> more political autonomy than they had done since
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> was founded, including such democratic reforms as elections
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislative Council</ENAMEX>.
        Since the handover in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has generally
        followed a hands-off policy. Many who fled have returned. What controls
        heartbeats in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> are the fluctuations of the Hang Seng Index,
        foreign currency exchange rates, and skyrocketing property prices. In
        short, the status quo prevails. Everybody hopes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> will remain
        stable, but everyone also has their doubts. In the meantime, the
        philosophy is to seize present-day opportunities in the thriving
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
