
  
  
    
      
        A Brief History
        The appeal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French West Indies</ENAMEX> today is that nothing
        much happens on them. Not so in the ‚Äúbad <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">old days</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Unlikely</ENAMEX> as it
        seems now, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> islands were close to center stage
        as the great powers of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> warred fiercely for world commercial
        domination. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> knew a good thing when she seized <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, but then so
        did <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>.
        It all began much more peacefully. Perhaps <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,000 years ago</TIMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> sometimes called <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúSaloides‚Äù</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Orinoco</ENAMEX> basin in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> began migrating up the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Antilles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>, reaching <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Martinique</ENAMEX> and
        Guadeloupe before a.d. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>. A volcanic eruption on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Martinique</ENAMEX> prevented
        these early island-hoppers from staying long; they soon vanished from
        history, leaving only the scantiest archaeological traces.
        By a.d. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>, a new and larger wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amerindians</ENAMEX> from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Orinoco</ENAMEX> basin settled on islands throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>. These were
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arawaks</ENAMEX>, who lived from fishing and planting, and produced
        beautiful pottery. For centuries these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had the islands to
        themselves.
        Then came the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribs</ENAMEX>, and the tranquility was shattered.
        These <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX>, also from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>, swept north in fast
        seagoing canoes, attacking and either eating or driving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arawak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> off
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island</ENAMEX> after island, then appropriating their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. A ritualistic mark
        of bravery for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Carib warriors</ENAMEX> was cannibalism, and it‚Äôs for this that
        history most remembers the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> who invented the hammock and gave
        their name to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>. In fact, their staple diet usually
        consisted of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, crabs, conch, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>.
        Enter <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
        On his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> voyage to what he evidently thought were the
        islands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far East</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christopher Columbus</ENAMEX> first discovered Dominica
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1493</TIMEX>. Then he stopped at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marie-Galante</ENAMEX>, which he named after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
        his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX>, before crossing over to the large neighboring island. This
        he called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guadeloupe</ENAMEX> after a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribs</ENAMEX> here, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> with bow and arrow, were
        demonstrably displeased to see the explorer. But he stayed long enough
        to see his first parrots and to marvel at the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>
        spoke <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three languages‚</TIMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇone strictly between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX>, another for
        the mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arawak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> for ordinary communication between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.
        Sailing north to find and claim islands for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> named <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint-Barth√©lemy</ENAMEX> after his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and
        another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saint-Martin</ENAMEX>, probably after the saint on whose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">feast day</TIMEX> he
        had spotted it. Not until his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> transatlantic journey in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1502</TIMEX> did
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> reach <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Martinique</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX> wasn‚Äôt very excited about the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lesser Antilles</ENAMEX>. The big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX> was gold, particularly in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>,
        so for a while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> regarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> chain as <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúislands of Peru‚</ENAMEX>Äù
        where the galleons could stop for fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> rather half-hearted
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> attempts to establish footholds on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guadeloupe</ENAMEX> were repulsed by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribs</ENAMEX>.
        But as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> went by, the conquistadors rounded up even
        more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> to work in gold <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> elsewhere. They also introduced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sugarcane</ENAMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> to the islands, but
        never founded any significant settlements. That situation, plus the
        gradual decline of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> naval power, proved very tempting to
        others.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardinal Richelieu</ENAMEX> (the powerful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statesman</ENAMEX>) for one dreamed of conquest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World</ENAMEX>. At his
        bidding, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">buccaneers</ENAMEX> and adventurers, some of them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">noblemen</ENAMEX>,
        started planting the flag on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> real estate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1625</TIMEX>. At first
        they shared a base with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Englishmen</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Kitts</ENAMEX> (then called
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint-Christophe</ENAMEX>). Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman gentleman Pierre Belain</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">d‚ÄôEsnambuc</ENAMEX>, whose statue you can see in the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">de</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Some years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonizers</ENAMEX> moved south to both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guadeloupe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martinique</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lienard de l‚ÄôOlive</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Duplessis</ENAMEX>
        d‚ÄôOssonville put ashore at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pointe-Allegre</ENAMEX> in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guadeloupe</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1635</TIMEX>. But it took until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1640</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> to prevail
        against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribs</ENAMEX>, who were fighting to retain the island they
        loved.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1635</TIMEX>, d‚ÄôEsnambuc led a party to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martinique</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">constructed Fort Saint</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre</ENAMEX>, where a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of that name stands <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
        Here too, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribs</ENAMEX> resisted savagely, with the result that for some
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> they were left the eastern section of the island. It wasn‚Äôt
        all warfare‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> taught the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> fishing and weaving
        techniques still in use <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribs</ENAMEX> were expelled from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> domain, remaining for a period on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dominica</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1648</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> staked claim to their part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> and to
        nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saint-Barth√©lemy</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Sugar</ENAMEX> and Slaves
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Sugar cropping</ENAMEX>, destined to change the face and fate of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>, began booming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as the 1640s</TIMEX>. To work <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX> on
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> islands as well as those belonging to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX>, slaves were shipped in from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. The traffic soared
        incredibly: by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1745</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martinique</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60,000</NUMEX> slaves and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 16,000</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guadeloupe</ENAMEX> had even more slaves and fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. Some of
        the slaves were able to gain freedom in return for special services
        rendered. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of colons and slaves were free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>.
        By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1674</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis XIV</ENAMEX> took formal control of the islands
        from the debt-ridden commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martinique</ENAMEX> had become
        France‚Äôs colonial capital in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lesser Antilles</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX> rule was to
        last for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a century</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Indian</ENAMEX> sugar helping to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">catapult France</ENAMEX> to economic supremacy in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> versus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">France</ENAMEX>
        This was the period when nautical marauders variously
        called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">buccaneers</ENAMEX>, corsairs, privateers, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> stalked the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shipways</ENAMEX> and bays of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">undermanned</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guadeloupe</ENAMEX> and
        Martinique, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> were critically important: in return for
        a safe haven, they carried in supplies, raided enemy merchant <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX>,
        and joined battles against invading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>.
        France‚Äôs enemy number one in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>, as elsewhere,
        was the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> naval attacks by the redcoats were against
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guadeloupe</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1691 and 1703</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> of fighting followed, with
        blockades, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>-raiding forays against the major islands, and three
        short seizures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>.
        During the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Seven Years‚Äô War</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1756‚Äì1763</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conquered Guadeloupe</ENAMEX> and held it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>. Ironically, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guadeloupe‚Äôs</ENAMEX> economy a big boost: between
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000 and 30,000</NUMEX> more slaves were transported in and new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cane</ENAMEX>-grinding
        windmills built, all of which spurred the sugar trade to unprecedented
        prosperity. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> also set a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> in operation at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pointe-√†-Pitre</ENAMEX>, thus establishing the importance of this advantageously
        located <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.
        If there was any doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Treaty</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1763</TIMEX>) dispelled it: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> elected to take back
        her little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Indian</ENAMEX> islands and leave the ‚Äúfew snowy acres‚Äù of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>.
        During the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American War of Independence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">France‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        sympathies were undisguised: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> were granted safe anchorage
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FWI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">privateers</ENAMEX> raiding from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint-Barth√</ENAMEX>©lemy‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coves</ENAMEX> sank many
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> merchantman, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martinique</ENAMEX> regiment fought the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> at
        Savannah, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 April 1782</TIMEX>, in the sea channel near
        Guadeloupe‚Äôs little off-shore islands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Saintes</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> fleet
        gained historic revenge against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Admiral de Grasse</ENAMEX>, of Yorktown
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fame</ENAMEX>, in a battle that is still talked about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Grasse‚</ENAMEX>Äôs fleet of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">warships</ENAMEX> was escorting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">convoy</ENAMEX> of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> cargo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santo Domingo</ENAMEX> (today‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dominican Republic</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>) planning to join a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> naval <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britain‚</ENAMEX>Äôs base
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. British <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Admiral Rodney</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> and a crucial
        superiority in cannon (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3,012 to 2,246 French</NUMEX>), struck off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Saintes</ENAMEX>.
        As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">islanders</ENAMEX> watched from their hills, the more mobile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        mercilessly chopped up the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">convoy</ENAMEX> until finally <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Grasse</ENAMEX>
        surrendered. This disastrous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> naval defeat is known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Saintes</ENAMEX>.
        Slavery Declines
        When, during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">French Revolution</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convention</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ambitiously</ENAMEX> declared slavery abolished, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martinique‚</ENAMEX>Äôs wealthy plantation
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> frantically objected. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Opting</ENAMEX>, as a dubious <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> best, for
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1794</TIMEX>, the island managed to retain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slavery</ENAMEX> and avoid the revolutionary terror that Guadeloupe
        underwent.
        After <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> seized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guadeloupe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Hugues</ENAMEX>, commissaire
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Convention</ENAMEX>, wrenched the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> back, proclaimed slavery
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abolished</ENAMEX>, and set about guillotining the old-guard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colons</ENAMEX>. His
        corsairs became the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scourge</ENAMEX> of the sea, the indiscriminate attacks
        leading to a diplomatic blow-up with the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
        Hugues‚Äô reign on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guadeloupe</ENAMEX> didn‚Äôt last long, but it was bloodthirsty
        enough to be recalled vividly even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1802</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">France reclaimed Martinique</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> through
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Treaty of Amiens</ENAMEX>. Bonaparte, as <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Consul</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, reinstated
        slavery in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FWI</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> still argue over the role played in
        that decision by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josephine</ENAMEX>, a native of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martinique</ENAMEX> (see
        page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sugarcane</ENAMEX> was revered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">planters</ENAMEX> and government
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúwhite gold‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">l‚Äôor blanc</ENAMEX>) for the immense wealth it
        brought. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1799</TIMEX> doom was signaled for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cane</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> with the
        appearance of the cheaper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar beet</ENAMEX>. The end also became inevitable
        for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> system upon which the sugar industry was based: the
        example of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santo Domingo‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> revolt, which led to the independence
        of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>, was electrifying, causing an entirely
        new attitude to the whole problem of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> trade. Liberal ideas
        began mushrooming in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> itself, and after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX> destroyed
        Napoleon‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle of Trafalgar</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French West Indian</ENAMEX>
        planters‚Äô lifeline with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> was all but destroyed as well. In
        addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX> formally banned the trade in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slaves</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abolition</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beyond</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> was now set for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French West Indies‚</ENAMEX>Äô greatest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Schoelcher</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parisian</ENAMEX> porcelain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX>,
        Schoelcher was inspired to wage a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year</TIMEX> struggle to free the slaves
        by what he saw on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> trips to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>.
        When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> was proclaimed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1848</TIMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schoelcher</ENAMEX> drafted the emancipation decree that freed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">87,500</NUMEX> slaves in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guadeloupe</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72,000</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Martinique</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the smallest hamlets on both
        islands honor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schoelcher</ENAMEX> with busts, full statues, and street names.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martinique</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> named after him.
        No slaves meant almost no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> production, until the first
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 80,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hindus</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,000</NUMEX> free <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> began
        arriving as contract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guadeloupe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Martinique</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX>.
        Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> remained and established small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FWI</ENAMEX>, their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> becoming an important and colorful segment of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> (see box, page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>).
        To help stimulate the economy, the islands were finally
        relieved of the long-standing and controversial requirement that, as
        colonial appendages of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, they could trade only with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
        and usually only in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Rum</ENAMEX> now began bringing in
        considerable legal (as opposed to contraband) revenue.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1871</TIMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Third Republic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martinique</ENAMEX> and Guadeloupe
        were granted representation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Assembly</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, which
        they have retained ever since. Gradually, metropolitan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> and
        the benefits of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> were extended to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FWI</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1877</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> bought back <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint-Barth√</ENAMEX>©lemy from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweden</ENAMEX>
        for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">320,000</NUMEX> gold <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">francs</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis XVI</ENAMEX> having ceded the little island <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years earlier</TIMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Gustav III</ENAMEX> in return for duty-free
        trading rights in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothenburg</ENAMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">20th Century</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FWI‚</ENAMEX>Äôs worst modern tragedy came in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1902</TIMEX> when the
        sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre</ENAMEX> was totally destroyed by the
        eruption of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Pel√©e</ENAMEX>. The victims‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇover <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30,000‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</NUMEX>ÄÇincluded most of
        Martinique‚Äôs social and managerial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henceforth Fort-de-France</ENAMEX>
        would be the island‚Äôs only significant center and the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">French Antilles</ENAMEX>.
        When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> fell in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FWI‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Admiral Georges Robert</ENAMEX>, decreed allegiance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vichy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>,
        although most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">islanders</ENAMEX> were against the move. Fearing German
        occupation and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">submarine</ENAMEX> use of the islands, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Allies</ENAMEX> imposed a
        painful blockade and threatened to use military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
        resigned and the islands swung immediately to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Gaulle‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Free French</ENAMEX>.
        With the war monopolizing shipping, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FWI</ENAMEX> suffered great economic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">privation</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guadeloupe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinique</ENAMEX> became full d√©partements of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1946‚</NUMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa source of great pride to many. More importantly, it
        meant much needed, larger financial contributions from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. The
        smaller islands, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Saint-Martin and Saint-Barth√©lemy</ENAMEX>, are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">administrative</ENAMEX> sub-prefectures (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">sous-pr√©fectures</NUMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guadeloupe</ENAMEX>.
        While <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX> exports resumed to a degree
        after the war, the islands‚Äô economies have not kept satisfactory pace
        with their burgeoning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. The recent surge of tourism has
        helped, but not enough. Unrest and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">political extremism</ENAMEX> have
        surfaced from time to time, but since aid from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> is so vital, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> customs so ingrained, it seems almost inconceivable that the FWI
        will seek total independence as other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> islands have done.
      
    
  
