
  
  
    
      
        A Brief History
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> grew up around the steep, ragged cliff
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Rock</ENAMEX> and its easily defended summit. Archaeological
        excavations have revealed evidence of habitation here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as long ago</TIMEX> as
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX> b.c. Very little, however, is known about the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock</ENAMEX> and its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> between its first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX> and the time
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacAlpin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX>. A few shadowy details have been left to us by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> and by an epic poem from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the seventh century</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> and Britons
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Romans</ENAMEX> invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> in a.d. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78‚Äì84</NUMEX>, where they met a
        fierce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Picts</ENAMEX>, whom they drove north. They consolidated
        their gains by building <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Antonine‚Äôs Wall</ENAMEX> across the waist of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>
        between the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Firth of Forth and the River Clyde</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about a.d.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">150</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman legions</ENAMEX> encountered the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strongholds</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Rock</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Arthur‚Äôs Seat</ENAMEX>, held by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Britons</ENAMEX> known as the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Votadini</ENAMEX>. Little is recorded about this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, but they were probably
        the ancestors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gododdin</ENAMEX>, whose feats are told in a
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Welsh</ENAMEX> manuscript. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gododdin</ENAMEX> was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Din Eidyn</ENAMEX> (the ‚ÄúFort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eidyn</ENAMEX>,‚Äù almost certainly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Rock</ENAMEX>),
        whose name lives on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edin</ENAMEX>- of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Din Eidyn</ENAMEX> fell to the
        Angles in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">638</TIMEX> and became part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anglian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northumbria</ENAMEX>. It
        was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of many times that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fort of Eidyn</ENAMEX> would change hands
        between the kingdoms of the north and the south.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">MacAlpin Kings</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> distinct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> once inhabited the land now known as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Picts</ENAMEX> in the north, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britons</ENAMEX> in the southwest, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invading Angles</ENAMEX> in the southeast, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX> in the west. The Scots
        were Gaelic-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> from the north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
        MacAlpin, who ruled as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunadd</ENAMEX>, acquired the Pictish
        throne in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">843</TIMEX>, uniting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">River Forth</ENAMEX> into a single
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">kingdom</ENAMEX>. He moved his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">capital‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇalong</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone of Destiny</ENAMEX> (on
        which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> were crowned)‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇto the sacred <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pict</ENAMEX> site of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scone</ENAMEX>,
        close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perth</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-great-great-grandson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm II</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1005‚Äì1034</ENAMEX>),
        defeated the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Angles</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle of Carham</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1018</TIMEX> and extended
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> as far south as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">River Tweed</ENAMEX>. These new lands
        included the stronghold of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX> II‚Äôs own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Canmore</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1058‚Äì1093</ENAMEX>),
        often visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Saxon princess</ENAMEX>. They
        crossed the Forth from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunfermline</ENAMEX> at the narrows known to this day as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queensferry</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX> was a deeply pious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was subsequently
        canonized, and her youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> I (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1124‚Äì1153</ENAMEX>), founded a church
        in her name on the highest point of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Rock</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Margaret‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chapel</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> also founded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey of Holyrood</ENAMEX> and created several
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">royal</ENAMEX> burghs (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> with special trading privileges), including
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canongate</ENAMEX>; the latter was under the jurisdiction of the
        monks, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúcanons,‚Äù of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holyrood</ENAMEX>.
        At this time <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> was still a very modest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, but
        David‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm IV</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1153‚Äì1165</ENAMEX>), made its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> his main
        residence. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 12th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edinburgh‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> was used
        as a royal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">treasury</ENAMEX>. The town‚<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Äôs High Street</ENAMEX> stretched beneath the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">castle</ENAMEX> along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ridge</ENAMEX> to the east (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Mile</ENAMEX>), past the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giles</ENAMEX>, and out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netherbow</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>
        ended and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canongate</ENAMEX> began.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wars of Independence</ENAMEX>
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1286</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacAlpin</ENAMEX> dynasty ended, leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>
        without a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX>. There were a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">claimants</ENAMEX> to the throne, among
        them <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Balliol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galloway</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert de Brus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annandale</ENAMEX>. The guardians of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> were unable to decide who should
        succeed and asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward I</ENAMEX>, to adjudicate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>,
        seeing this invitation as a chance to assert his claim as overlord of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Balliol</ENAMEX>, whom he judged to be the weaker of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> treated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> as a vassal. However, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward</ENAMEX>
        went to war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1294</TIMEX> and summoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> along with other
        knights, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> decided he had had enough. He ignored
        Edward‚Äôs summons and instead negotiated a treaty with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>,
        the beginning of a long association between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> that
        became known as the ‚ÄúAuld <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alliance</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> was furious, and his reprisal was swift and bloody.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1296</TIMEX> he led a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 30,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> and captured
        the castles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roxburgh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stirling</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone of Destiny</ENAMEX>
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> crown <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jewels</ENAMEX> were stolen, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotland‚Äôs Great Seal</ENAMEX>
        was broken up. Oaths of fealty were demanded from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nobles</ENAMEX>,
        while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were installed to oversee the running of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> became little more than an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>.
        But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX> did not take this insult lying down. Bands of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> (such as those led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Wallace</ENAMEX>) began to attack the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> garrisons and make raids into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> territory. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>
        was captured, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scots</ENAMEX> looked for a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> and discovered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert the Bruce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert de Brus</ENAMEX> rejected by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1292</TIMEX>. He was crowned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King of Scots</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scone</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1306</TIMEX> and began his
        campaign to drive the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> I died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1307</TIMEX> and was succeeded by his ineffectual
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward II</ENAMEX>, who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1314</TIMEX> led an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 25,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to confront
        Bruce‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bannockburn</ENAMEX>, near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stirling</ENAMEX>. Though outnumbered, the
        Scots gained a famous victory and sent the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> packing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX> the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX> continued to harass the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> until they were forced to sue for
        peace. A truce was declared, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Treaty</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northampton</ENAMEX> was
        negotiated at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1328</TIMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the recurring themes of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> history are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>
        inheriting the throne and divided loyalties. Although many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX>
        nobles were dedicated to the cause of independence, others either bore
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grudges</ENAMEX> against the ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> or held lands in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> that they
        feared to lose. These <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">divisions‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇlater hardened</ENAMEX> by religious
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">schism‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwould</ENAMEX> forever deny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> a truly united voice.
        When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert the Bruce</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1329</TIMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX>, was only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years old</TIMEX>. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> the wars with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
        resumed, aggravated by civil war at home as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Balliol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John)</ENAMEX> tried to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> throne with the help of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">king</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward III</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stewart Dynasty</ENAMEX>
        During these stormy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> was
        occupied several times by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> garrisons. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1341</TIMEX> it was taken from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William of Douglas</ENAMEX>. The young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David II</ENAMEX> returned from
        exile in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and made it his principal royal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>, building a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower house</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">David‚Äôs Tower</ENAMEX>) on the site of what is now the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Half Moon</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battery</ENAMEX>. He died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1371</TIMEX> and was succeeded by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX> II.
        David‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marjory</ENAMEX> had married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter the Steward</ENAMEX>, and their son
        was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of the long line of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> (later spelled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stuart</ENAMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monarchs</ENAMEX> who would reign over <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Scotland‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX>, subsequently, Great
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Britain‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇuntil the ‚ÄúGlorious Revolution‚Äù</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1688</TIMEX>.
        The strength and wealth of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> increased during the
        reigns of the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stewart</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX>. New castles were built and new
        weapons acquired, including the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúMons Meg</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> emerged as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotland‚</ENAMEX>Äôs main political center and was declared
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James III</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1460‚Äì1488</ENAMEX>) to be ‚Äúthe principal burgh of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James IV</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1488‚Äì1513</ENAMEX>) confirmed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edinburgh‚</ENAMEX>Äôs status as the
        capital of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> by constructing a royal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holyrood</ENAMEX>. He
        cemented a peace treaty with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> by marrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Tudor</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry VII‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Marriage</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thistle</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇbut this did not prevent him from making a raid into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1513</TIMEX>. The attack culminated in the disastrous <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Battle of Flodden</ENAMEX>, near
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">River Tweed</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> was killed. Fearing invasion, the
        Edinburgh town <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> built a protective wall (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúFlodden Wall‚Äù</ENAMEX>)
        around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> boundaries.
        Yet again a minor‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James V‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsucceeded</ENAMEX> to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">throne</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX> nobles were divided as to whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> should
        draw closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> or seek help from her old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adult James</ENAMEX> leaned toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1537</TIMEX> took a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guise</ENAMEX>. She bore <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> who both died in infancy, but by the time
        she was about to give birth to their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> lay dying
        at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Falkland Palace</ENAMEX>. On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1542</TIMEX> a messenger arrived with news
        that the queen had produced a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linlithgow</ENAMEX>. A
        few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days later</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> was dead, leaving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week-old</TIMEX> baby girl to
        inherit the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crown</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen</ENAMEX> of Scots
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Stuart</ENAMEX>, who at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of nine months</TIMEX> was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crowned Queen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chapel Royal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stirling</ENAMEX>. When the news
        reached <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry VIII</ENAMEX> saw his chance to subdue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> again and
        negotiated a marriage between the infant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> and his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX> refused, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> sent an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> rampaging through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> on a
        campaign known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚ÄúRough Wooing</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> ordered his
        general to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúburn <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> so there may remain forever a perpetual
        memory of the vengeance of God lightened upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        But more was at stake than simply <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland‚Äôs</ENAMEX> independence:
        there was now a religious schism within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. In order to divorce
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aragon</ENAMEX> and marry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Boleyn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry VIII</ENAMEX> had broken with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> and brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> under his own control. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> was
        thus now a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, caught between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic France</ENAMEX> and the
        Scots with their new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX> themselves were divided, many embracing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Protestantism</ENAMEX> in the spirit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reformation</ENAMEX> while others remained
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">staunchly Catholic</ENAMEX>. However, fear of the rampaging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> led the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX> again to seek help from their old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and the young
        queen married the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dauphin Fran√ßois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fran√ßois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1559</TIMEX> but died soon
        after. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1561</TIMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> returned to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> in the grip
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reformation</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> had taken control of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish parliament</ENAMEX> and abolished the authority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>. Her
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Tudor</ENAMEX>, was on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> throne, but
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elizabeth‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe ‚ÄúVirgin Queen‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇhad no heir. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> was next in line for
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> crown, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> was suspicious of her intentions.
        The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary‚Äôs</ENAMEX> reign were turbulent ones. She
        clashed early on with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edinburgh‚</ENAMEX>Äôs famous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
        Knox, who held sway in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Giles</ENAMEX> but later adopted an uneasy policy of
        religious tolerance. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1565</TIMEX> she married her young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>, Lord
        Darnley, much to the chagrin of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darnley</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Tudor</ENAMEX> and thus also had a claim to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> throne). On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1566</TIMEX>, in the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh Castle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> gave birth
        to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>.
        Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darnley</ENAMEX> was murdered, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary</ENAMEX>
        immediately immersed herself in controversy by marrying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Earl</ENAMEX> of
        Bothwell, the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forcedto</ENAMEX> abdicate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1567</TIMEX>, and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant prince</ENAMEX> was crowned as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James VI</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> sought asylum in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, only to be imprisoned by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> kept her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> in captivity for 20 years
        and finally had her beheaded on a trumped-up charge of treason. So it
        was bitterly ironic when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> died without an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary‚Äôs Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, inherited the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> throne.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1603</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James VI of Scotland</ENAMEX> was thus crowned James I of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>, marking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union of the Crowns</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> was still a
        separate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> would from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> be ruled by the
        same monarch.
        The Covenanters
        Edinburgh‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> grew fast <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1500 and 1650</TIMEX>, and
        a maze of tall, unsanitary tenements sprouted along the spine of the
        High Street. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> was extended, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1582</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Town‚Äôs College</ENAMEX>
        (the precursor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>) was founded. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> died
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1625</TIMEX>, succeeded by his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles I</ENAMEX>, who proved an incompetent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ruler</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1637</TIMEX> his attempt to force the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Presbyterian Church</ENAMEX> to
        accept an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> liturgy and the rule of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishops</ENAMEX> led to civil revolt
        and rioting.
        The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">churchmen</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nobles</ENAMEX> signed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Covenant</ENAMEX>, a declaration condemning the new
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liturgy</ENAMEX> and pledging allegiance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Presbyterian</ENAMEX> faith. The
        Covenanters, as they were called, at first sided with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Cromwell‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliamentarians</ENAMEX> in the civil war that had erupted across the border.
        But when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries beheaded</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> I in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1649</TIMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX> rallied round his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> II. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cromwell‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> then invaded
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, crushed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Covenanter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, and went on to take <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> suffered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> of military rule under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Cromwell‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonwealth</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotland‚Äôs</ENAMEX> troubles continued after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles II‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        restoration to the throne in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1660</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Covenanters</ENAMEX> faced severe
        persecution at the hands of the king‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, who had decided to
        follow his father‚Äôs policy of imposing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishops</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Covenanters</ENAMEX> were imprisoned and executed.
        In the end <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> underwent the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúGlorious Revolution‚</ENAMEX>Äù of
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1688</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James II</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scotland‚Äôs James VII</ENAMEX>) was deposed and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Protestant William of Orange</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1689‚Äì1702</ENAMEX>) took the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crown</ENAMEX>.
        Presbyterianism was established as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotland‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Covenanters</ENAMEX> prevailed.
        Act of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>
        On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 May 1707</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> were formally joined
        together by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúAct of Union‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇestablishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parliaments‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇand the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> was born. Despite the fact that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> was allowed to retain its own legal system, education system,
        and national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presbyterian Church</ENAMEX>, the move was opposed by the great
        majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of the deposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">VII</ENAMEX> and his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">successors</ENAMEX>, exiled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, were known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúJacobites</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù Several
        times during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 40 years</TIMEX> they attempted to restore the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stuart</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dynasty</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> throne, though by this time the crown had passed
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Hanover</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Edward Stuart</ENAMEX>, known as the ‚ÄúOld <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretender,‚Äù</ENAMEX> traveled
        up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Firth of Forth</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1708</TIMEX> but was driven back by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> and
        bad weather. Another campaign was held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1715</TIMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacobite Earl</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mar</ENAMEX>, but it was the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1745</TIMEX> rising of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles Edward Stuart</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúYoung Pretender</ENAMEX>,‚Äù which became the stuff of legend.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX>, known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie Prince Charlie</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">VII</ENAMEX>), raised an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacobite</ENAMEX> highlanders and swept through
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>. They occupied <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> (but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>) and defeated a
        government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle of Prestonpans</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> of that year
        he invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, capturing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlisle</ENAMEX> and driving south as far as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Derby</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only 200 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">130 miles</NUMEX>) short of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>.
        Finding his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> outnumbered and overextended here, the
        young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> beat a tactical retreat, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> army hounded him
        relentlessly. The final <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">showdown‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇat Culloden</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1746‚</NUMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsaw the
        Jacobite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> slaughtered. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charlie</ENAMEX> fled and was pursued over the
        Highlands before escaping in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>. He died in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1788</TIMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disillusioned</ENAMEX> and drunk.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Enlightenment</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacobite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uprisings</ENAMEX> found little support in such lowland
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>. Here there was a growing sense that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> was
        around to stay. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young Pretender‚</ENAMEX>Äôs occupation of
        Holyrood, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Edinburgh‚Äôs</ENAMEX> town <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> proposed a plan to relieve the
        chronic overcrowding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Mile</ENAMEX> tenements by constructing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Town</ENAMEX> on land to the north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1767</TIMEX> a design by a young
        and previously unknown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Craig</ENAMEX>, was approved and work
        began.
        This architectural renaissance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> was followed by
        an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual flowering</ENAMEX> in the sciences, philosophy, and medicine
        that revolutionized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> society in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 18th century</TIMEX> and saw
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> dubbed the ‚ÄúAthens of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äù Famous Edinburgh residents</ENAMEX>
        of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">period‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇlater</ENAMEX> known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Enlightenment‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇincluded
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hume</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Treatise of Human Nature</ENAMEX> and one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britain‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Smith</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wealth of Nations</ENAMEX>, a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pioneer</ENAMEX> in the study of political economy; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Black</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> who discovered the concept of latent heat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Burns‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poems</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Scott‚Äôs</ENAMEX> novels rekindled interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        history and nationhood; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> especially worked hard to raise
        Scotland‚Äôs profile.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern City</ENAMEX>
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> was swept up in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial Revolution</ENAMEX>. The coalfields of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lothian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fife</ENAMEX> fueled the
        growth of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">baking</ENAMEX>, distilling, printing, and machine-making industries,
        giving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">epithet ‚ÄúAuld Reekie‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Smoky</ENAMEX>). With the
        arrival of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railways</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1800s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> grew almost
        exponentially as new lines led to the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> suburbs such
        as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marchmont</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morningside</ENAMEX>.
        During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> became a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> center
        of learning and culture. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> has made
        outstanding contributions to various fields. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Festival</ENAMEX> (held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>) is acknowledged as
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the world‚Äôs most important arts festivals. In addition, the
        city‚Äôs rich history and architecture have made it one of the most
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">popular</ENAMEX> tourist destinations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nationalism</ENAMEX> never completely disappeared, however, and in
        the latter part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> there has been a concerted (though
        peaceful) effort to gain self-determination for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX> were in disarray when a referendum was defeated, and
        further efforts came to nought during <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservative</ENAMEX> rule in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1990s</TIMEX>. But the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone of Destiny</ENAMEX> was returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> soil in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">1996‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ700 years
        after it had been taken south by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.
        The general election of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1997</TIMEX> proved to be a turning
        point. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Labour Party</ENAMEX> supported the return of domestic
        policy-making power to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>. When it was victorious at the ballot
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">box</ENAMEX>, among the new government‚Äôs first tasks was to organize a
        referendum on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> devolution. This took place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1997</TIMEX>,
        with the majority supporting the creation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>,
        although many strident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX> thought the proposals did not go
        far enough. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotland Bill</ENAMEX> was put before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Parliament</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1998</TIMEX> and became law as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúScotland Act‚</ENAMEX>Äù in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1998</TIMEX>.
        Political power thus returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 300</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Elections were held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1999</TIMEX>, and the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> opened
        on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first of July</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> now buzzes with energy and confidence as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPs</ENAMEX> and policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> gather to make plans for the future of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
