
  
  
    
      
        A Brief History
        According to the earliest official accounts, the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighth-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kojiki (‚ÄúRecord of Ancient Matters‚Äù</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nihon</ENAMEX>-shoki
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">(‚ÄúChronicles of Japan‚Äù</ENAMEX>), the islands of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> were born of a marriage
        between the god <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Izanagi</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Izanami</ENAMEX>. They also‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbut only
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">later‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇgave</ENAMEX> birth to the sun, in the form of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amaterasu</ENAMEX>,
        who endowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> with its regalia of bronze
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mirror</ENAMEX>, iron <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX>, and jewel. The mirror is kept to this day at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shinto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ise-Shima</ENAMEX>.
        Before you dismiss all this as the mere ‚Äúmyth‚Äù of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">origins</ENAMEX>, remember that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> continued to trace the imperial
        dynasty directly back to those deities until <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hirohito</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">denounced ‚Äúthe</ENAMEX> false conception that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> is divine. ‚Äù Many
        followed <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs best-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yukio Mishima</ENAMEX> in deploring this
        formal break with tradition, and the creation myth has persisted in the
        popular imagination, side by side with more realistic versions of
        Japan‚Äôs origins.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prehistory</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Early Chronicles</ENAMEX>
        As evidenced by bones, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, and pottery most recently
        uncovered by archeologists, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> equivalent of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Neanderthal Man</ENAMEX>
        crossed a now-submerged land <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">bridge</ENAMEX> from eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Siberia</ENAMEX> to what is now
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sakhalin Island</ENAMEX> and northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some 100,000 years ago</TIMEX>. These
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">migrants</ENAMEX>, who later settled throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archipelago</ENAMEX>, were
        the ancestors of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">present-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ainu</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucasoid</ENAMEX> facial and body
        hair distinguished them from subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
        Manchuria, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, and perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Malay Peninsula</ENAMEX>. It was the growth
        and military assertion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> that drove the ‚Äúhairy people‚Äù
        (as they were labeled) back north to their present concentration in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hokkaido</ENAMEX>.
        The oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone Age</ENAMEX> settlements to be discovered (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">b.c.</ENAMEX> ) are known as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Jomon (‚Äúcord pattern‚Äù</ENAMEX>), after the style of their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">handmade</ENAMEX> pottery, which was among the earliest to be found anywhere in
        the world and of rich and imaginative design. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> dwelled
        in sunken pits and lived from hunting, fishing, and the gathering of
        roots and nuts. It wasn‚Äôt until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third century</TIMEX> b.c. that techniques
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice cultivation</ENAMEX> (and wheel-made pottery) arrived from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, along
        with irrigation methods that are still in use <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
        The scarcity of flatlands suitable for cultivation made it
        possible for a small aristocratic elite to gain quick control of the
        food resources. This set the pattern of hierarchic rule that was to
        prevail right up to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last half of the 19th century</TIMEX> (some would
        claim, in economic terms at least, that it still persists <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>).
        Although there are no reliable accounts of this period,
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> documents speak of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priestess-queen</ENAMEX>,
        Himiko, ruling over a land of law-abiding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who enjoyed alcohol
        and were divided into classes distinguished by tattoo marks. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Five</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kojiki</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nihon</ENAMEX>-shoki chronicles describe
        the creation of the imperial dynasty in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 660</TIMEX> b.c. : the first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">emperor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Jimmu (‚ÄúDivine Warrior‚Äù)‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇgreat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sun Goddess‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandson‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇembarked</ENAMEX> on an expedition of conquest from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Kyushu</ENAMEX> along the
        Inland <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea</ENAMEX> coast to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Yamato</ENAMEX> plain of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kinki region</ENAMEX> (near
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">modern-day Nara</ENAMEX>).
        Plausible chronicling, laced with a dose of mythology,
        begins with the arrival of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scribes</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> around
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">a.d. 400</ENAMEX>, at a time when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> also had a military foothold in southern
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yamato</ENAMEX>, as early <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> was known, was organized
        into uji, or clusters of clans, together with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinate guilds</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX>, weavers, and potters, all subject to the
        dominant uji of the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> Influences
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> were forced out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> peninsula in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixth century</TIMEX>, but not before the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Koreans</ENAMEX> had bequeathed to the Yamato
        court copies of the sacred images and scriptures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX>.
        Just as Christianity introduced <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> culture into
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northern Europe</ENAMEX>, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddhism</ENAMEX> brought <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> culture into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Japanese</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>. Throughout the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighth centuries</TIMEX> numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>
        monks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> made the perilous trip west across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to study <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> religion, history, music, literature, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">painting‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇlater</ENAMEX> to be brought back for further development in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.
        An outstanding figure of this time was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shotoku</ENAMEX>, who
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">604</TIMEX> developed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúSeventeen-Article Constitution</ENAMEX>,‚Äù outlining a code
        of human conduct and the ideals of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> as a basic law for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
        He also established relations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sui dynasty</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Through
        him, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> developed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> patterns of
        centralized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, with its formal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> court
        ranks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> calendar was used to calculate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> by counting back the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1,260 years</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> cosmological
        cycle. Thus, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">660</NUMEX> b.c. is still the official date celebrated
        nationwide.
        At this early stage in its history <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> was already (for
        the most part) only nominally ruled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De</ENAMEX> facto power was
        exercised by the militarily and economically strongest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sogas</ENAMEX> had promoted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX> as an imperially sanctioned counterweight
        to the native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shinto</ENAMEX> religion, along with the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> customs, to
        weaken the influence of their more conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>. But they in
        turn were ousted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 645</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nakatomi Kamatari</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the great
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fujiwara</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX>, which was to rule <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> affairs for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of years
        and provide prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> even up to the 19th
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nara Period</ENAMEX>
        Another of the new ideas was to set up a permanent
        residential capital for the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, initially at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naniwa</ENAMEX>
        (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">present-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Osaka</ENAMEX>) and then a little to the east, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nara</ENAMEX>, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">710</NUMEX>.
        Laid out like a chessboard (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China‚</ENAMEX>Äôs similarly
        designed capital, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chang‚Äôan</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nara</ENAMEX> had its imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> at the
        northern end, with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">court residences</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> monasteries, and Shinto
        shrines stretching to the south. In those peaceful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, without
        threat of foreign invasion or civil war, there were no city
        ramparts.
        The era known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nara Period</ENAMEX> was marked by the
        religious fervor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> monks and also by their accompanying
        artistic achievements. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> were attracted more to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ritual</ENAMEX> and art than to its complex philosophy, rendered all the more
        difficult because its texts were, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several centuries</TIMEX>, available only
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, the language of a small court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> monks
        initiated great progress in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> architecture, bronze-casting,
        bridge-building, and sculpture. To this day, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> art
        find the best surviving examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tang</ENAMEX>-dynasty architecture among the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>- and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighth-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">temples</ENAMEX> in and around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nara</ENAMEX>.
        By marrying his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> of the reigning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>
        and then engineering timely abdications, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fujiwara</ENAMEX> contrived always to
        be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> behind the throne. Very often
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> was only a minor, so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fujiwara</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> acted as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">regent</ENAMEX>. He then persuaded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> to abdicate soon after his
        majority, and the regency would continue for the next youthful
        incumbent. The important thing was to have the emperor‚Äôs sanction for
        the regent‚Äôs political decisions.
        Very few emperors were reluctant to submit to Fujiwara
        domination. The burden of his spiritual functions as high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shinto</ENAMEX> and the tasks of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> led the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> to welcome an
        early abdication, frequently to retire to a life of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> meditation
        and scholarship. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fujiwara</ENAMEX> resented the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> clergy‚Äôs great and
        growing influence in imperial affairs. There were too many monasteries
        in and around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nara</ENAMEX>. It was time to move the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Heian Era</ENAMEX>
        The geomancers in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">794</NUMEX> decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Heian-kyo</ENAMEX> (modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX>)
        would be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an auspicious</TIMEX> site for the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. It was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">indeed‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇuntil 1869</ENAMEX>.
        Grants of tax-free land over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> had been made to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> temples and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> aristocracy. The most
        powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> thus carved out for themselves whole regions that
        were to become the fiefdoms of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> feudalism. By the end of the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighth century</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clans</ENAMEX> had created a hierarchy of shiki, or rights,
        from the highest to the lowest ranks of society. The aristocrat or
        court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX> lent his prestige to a powerful provincial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietor</ENAMEX>, who
        employed a competent estate-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> to oversee smallholders, who in
        turn worked their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> with dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX>. This elaborate
        structure of interdependent rights and obligations was to serve
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> society right into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX>.
        Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Heian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> life blossomed in an effusion of
        aesthetic expression. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princes</ENAMEX> and princesses judged the merits of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insects</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, roots, or seashells. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Literary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> games held
        in ornate palace gardens required each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> to compose a small poem as
        his wine cup floated toward him along a miniature winding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Expeditions were organized to the best viewing points for the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> spring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cherry blossoms</ENAMEX>, and special pavilions were built to watch
        the rising of the full moon. Every gesture, from the most banal opening
        of an umbrella to the sublimest act of lovemaking, had its appropriate
        ceremonial. Conversation often took the form of elegant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">improvised</ENAMEX> verse.
        The changing role of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> culture in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> life was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epitomized</ENAMEX> in the language itself. In the absence of an indigenous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alphabet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> had with the greatest difficulty tried to
        adapt the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> ideograms of monosyllabic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> to the essentially
        polysyllabic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>. Thus developed the katakana system used as a
        vehicle for writing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> names and concepts.
        After rival <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fujiwara</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> had been struggling for years
        to gain control of the imperial throne, they turned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taira</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Minamoto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1156</TIMEX> to wage the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year</TIMEX> war that heralded the end
        of the golden age of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Heian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taira</ENAMEX>, controlling the region
        along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inland Sea</ENAMEX>, defeated the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Minamoto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> based in the Kanto
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> east of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>.
        Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 20 years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Minamoto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX> acquired new
        strength by offering better guarantees to local landowners‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">armies‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇthan they could expect from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. Eventually a new offensive,
        the decisive <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gempei War</ENAMEX>, was launched in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1180</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years later</TIMEX>, the
        Taira were overthrown after being defeated in the straits between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">western Honshu and Kyushu</ENAMEX>, at the titanic sea battle of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dannoura‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwhich</ENAMEX> has a place in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> annals comparable to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waterloo</ENAMEX>
        or Stalingrad.
        Enter the Shoguns
        Japan‚Äôs austere, ruthless, but statesmanlike new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoritomo Minamoto</ENAMEX>, set up his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kamakura</ENAMEX> (just south of
        modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>), well away from the ‚Äúsoftening‚Äù influence of court life
        that had been the undoing of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kiyomori</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> of the
        national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> to take the title of sei-i tai-shogun
        (‚Äúbarbarian-subduing great general‚Äù), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minamoto</ENAMEX> expanded and
        consolidated his power by confiscating lands from some of the defeated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taira</ENAMEX> and redistributing them to his samurai <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">vassals</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minamoto</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1199</TIMEX>, and the feudal structure passed
        intact to the tutelage of his widow‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hojo</ENAMEX>, who were
        content to play regent to a figurehead shogun, in much the same way as
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fujiwara</ENAMEX> had done with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>. The fiction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imperial</ENAMEX> power had become infinitely extendable. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kyoto‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇstill</ENAMEX> seconded by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fujiwara</ENAMEX> regent at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">court‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇlegitimized a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minamoto</ENAMEX> who was himself a military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> controlled by a Hojo
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">regent</ENAMEX>. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where form and substance were inextricably
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interrelated</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things counted in politics: symbolic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> and
        real power. Neither could exist without the other.
        A thwarted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mongol</ENAMEX> invasion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1274</TIMEX> weakened the Kamakura
        regime. The fighting brought none of the usual spoils of war that
        provincial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warlords</ENAMEX> and samurai had come to expect as payment. And the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treasury</ENAMEX> was empty after earthquake, famine, and plague had crippled
        the economy. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> monasteries were using their private armies to
        support imperial ambitions to bring power back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX>. Worst of all,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Kamakura warriors</ENAMEX>, resenting the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> referred to
        them as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúEastern barbarians</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> sought refinement in a ruinous taste for
        luxury: extravagant feasts, rich costumes, and opulent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. Kamakura
        was falling apart.
        Creative Turmoil
        The subsequent power struggle at first split the country
        into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, and then effective control of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> was
        splintered for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two centuries</TIMEX> among scores of daimyo (feudal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">warlords</ENAMEX>).
        Eventually, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashikaga</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> shoguns settled down in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyoto‚Äôs Muromachi</ENAMEX> district, which gave its name to the new creative
        period that followed. The gruff, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bluff warriors‚Äô</ENAMEX> taste for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">art‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇcalligraphy</ENAMEX>, landscape painting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> ceremony, music, dance,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">theater‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇcoincided</ENAMEX> with a renewed interest in things <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>,
        above all the teachings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zen Buddhism</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zen</ENAMEX> had been present
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 12th century</TIMEX>, its ascendancy began under the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamakura</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, which found the mystic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> philosophy admirably
        suited to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> sensitivity, impressionism, and love of form and
        ritual.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashikaga</ENAMEX> shoguns and their samurai were greatly
        attracted by an essentially anti-intellectual doctrine that transmitted
        its truth from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> to disciple by practical example rather than
        scholarly study of texts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enlightenment</ENAMEX> (satori) was to be achieved
        through self-understanding and self-discipline, combining tranquillity
        and individualism. After their savage battles, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX> recuperated
        through meditation in the peace of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> rock garden.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1467 to 1568</TIMEX>, civil war constantly raged up and down
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 260</NUMEX> daimyo, from which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> finally emerged
        victorious. They had fought with mass armies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infantry</ENAMEX> rather than
        relying on the old cavalry elite. Although swords, bows, and arrows
        remained the mainstays of warfare, suddenly matchlocks, muskets, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cannons</ENAMEX> made their appearance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> had arrived.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1543</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> explorers reached <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanegashima Island,</ENAMEX>
        off southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyushu</ENAMEX>, followed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decade</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portuguese</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jesuit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX>, headed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St Francis Xavier</ENAMEX>, who
        landed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kagoshima</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1549</TIMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kyushu daimyo</ENAMEX> adopted Christianity as
        a means of winning favor with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, without
        necessarily abandoning their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> beliefs or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shinto</ENAMEX> practices.
        Converted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years earlier</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daimyo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omura</ENAMEX> founded the port of Nagasaki
        as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> trade in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1571</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> was handed over to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuits</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1579</TIMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1582</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">converts</ENAMEX> were estimated at
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX>; by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1615</TIMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a million</NUMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
        (Through all the vagaries of persecution and war, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nagasaki</ENAMEX> has remained
        the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> Christianity. )
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Portuguese‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand the Dutch‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇlaunched a</ENAMEX>
        craze for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX>, clocks, pantaloons, and eyeglasses,
        the latter very often worn as a chic symbol of intellectual superiority
        rather than as an aid for poor eyesight.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Momoyama Unification</ENAMEX>
        By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1568</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> was at last seized from the Ashikaga
        shogunate, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">ruthless generals‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇNobunaga</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hideyoshi</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tokugawa‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇhad</ENAMEX> banded together to eliminate all remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX>.
        Realizing the importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> military technology, Nobunaga
        mastered the manufacture of gunpowder and made firearms from
        melted-down temple bells. The triumphant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trio</ENAMEX> were the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to develop
        the appropriate defenses against the new firepower. They replaced the
        old small castles on high ground protected only by wooden stockades
        with large central fortresses out of range behind broad moats,
        surrounded by solid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone ramparts</ENAMEX> and earthworks strong enough to
        resist cannon fire.
        Cleverest of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nobunaga</ENAMEX> used another Western
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weapon</ENAMEX>, Christianity, against the principal remaining threat to his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">authority‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe strongholds</ENAMEX> surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX>. While sending out armies
        to destroy the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> monasteries and confiscate their lands, he
        simultaneously fostered Christianity to win <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adepts</ENAMEX> away from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> faith.
        Nobunaga was assassinated by one of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1582</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hideyoshi</ENAMEX>, who had started out as a simple infantryman,
        succeeded him. Seeing in Christianity a threat to his central
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority, Hideyoshi</ENAMEX> systematically suppressed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> activity; in
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1597 six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">converts</ENAMEX> were crucified at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nagasaki</ENAMEX>. He was also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of the art of conspicuous consumption,
        contrasting sharply with the restraint shown by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashikaga</ENAMEX> shoguns in
        their more subtle displays of wealth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gigantic castle</ENAMEX> he erected at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Osaka</ENAMEX> was the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> had ever seen, requiring a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Perhaps his most astounding coup was the monstrous Kitano
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tea</ENAMEX> ceremony attended by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of rich and poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>, who were
        all obliged to stay to the end. It lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten days</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> Takes All
        When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hideyoshi</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1598</TIMEX>, he hoped to have his
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> continue his ‚Äúdynasty,‚Äù initially under the tutelage
        of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five regents</NUMEX>. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the regents was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ieyasu Tokugawa</ENAMEX>, who had
        been biding his time at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edo</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years</TIMEX>, nurturing dynastic ambitions
        of his own. Of the cunning, ruthless triumvirate that came out on top
        at the end of the country‚Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> of civil war, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> was without
        doubt the most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, the most prudent‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand most treacherous. He
        moved quickly to eliminate his strongest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>, crushing them in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1600</TIMEX>
        at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sekigahara</ENAMEX> (near modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nagoya</ENAMEX>).
        During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its subsequent two and a half centuries</TIMEX> of rule from
        the new capital established at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edo</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> organized a tightly
        controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">some 260 daimyo</NUMEX> in strategic strongholds
        throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The allegiance of this highly privileged and
        prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was ensured by cementing their ethical principles in
        the code of bushido, ‚Äúthe way of the warrior‚Äù: loyalty to one‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>,
        defense of one‚Äôs status and honor, and fulfillment of all obligations.
        Loyalty was further enforced by holding the vassals‚Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
        hostage in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edo</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edo</ENAMEX>, the most famous being the Tokaido
        Highway, had checkpoints for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> coming in and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> going
        out.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most effective ways of keeping a tight rein on
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was to cut it off from the outside world, to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>. At first, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ieyasu Tokugawa</ENAMEX> was eager to promote foreign trade.
        He wanted silk and encouraged the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> as good,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">nonproselytizing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX> just interested in trade. But he didn‚Äôt
        like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX>, who he felt were
        undermining traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> values. He banned their activities in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1612 and two years later</TIMEX> ordered the expulsion of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> and
        unrepentant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">converts</ENAMEX>. Executions and torture followed.
        Converts were forced to renounce their faith by trampling crucifixes
        and effigies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> has counted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,125</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">martyrs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1597</TIMEX> (beginning under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hideyoshi</ENAMEX>) to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1660</TIMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1635</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> were forbidden, on pain of death, to
        attempt to travel abroad, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> already overseas were
        prevented from returning, in case they brought back subversive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> doctrines. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> books were banned, as were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> books
        that mentioned Christianity. After the purge of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>, only a few
        stayed on, strictly confined to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dejima Island</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nagasaki Bay</ENAMEX>.
        This isolation slowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs technological and
        institutional progress almost to a halt. But it also had the effect of
        permitting a great, distinctive cultural growth with a strong national
        identity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> thus celebrated the ancestral religion of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shinto‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇglorified</ENAMEX> by the monumentally opulent shrines they built at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikko</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Combining Shinto</ENAMEX> ritual with official <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> conformity, they
        revived the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confucian</ENAMEX> ideals of filial piety and obedience to authority
        to bolster their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> thrived, partly in response to the extravagant
        demands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Merchants thronged</ENAMEX> to the large cities
        that were growing up around the castles at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> already 1
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Osaka</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">400,000</NUMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nagoya</ENAMEX> and Kanazawa
        (each <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100,000)‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</NUMEX>ÄÇall huge in comparison with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. Japan‚Äôs overall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX> was already about
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30 million</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Merchants</ENAMEX> played an active role in creating the urban
        culture that burgeoned at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 17th century</TIMEX>, the so-called
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genroku</ENAMEX> era. Before these hard-working family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> went home from work,
        they liked to drink strong <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of actresses and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX>. These were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">forerunners</ENAMEX> of the geisha‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇliterally
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúaccomplished person‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwith</ENAMEX> a beauty and refinement that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX>
        did not seek in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>, whom they valued for their childbearing
        and good housekeeping. These were also halcyon days for the classic noh
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theater</ENAMEX>, the more popular kabuki, and the puppet theater (today‚Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bunraku</ENAMEX>) at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Osaka</ENAMEX>, which was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs cultural capital at a time when
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edo</ENAMEX> had more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>.
        In the end it was the very rigidity of their unshared
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that brought about the downfall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokugawa</ENAMEX>.
        Without access to foreign markets, there was no way to counter the rash
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">catastrophes‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇplague</ENAMEX>, drought, floods, and famine‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇat the end of
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uprisings</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> and countryside began to pose
        serious threats to the shogun‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> reaction was
        characteristic: a reinforcement of the austere values of the samurai
        and a rigorous clamp-down on the merchants‚Äô high life. There was no
        more gambling, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> were arrested, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were
        segregated in the public bathhouses, with naked government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX> to
        enforce the (short-lived) new rules.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> Are Coming
        The feeling began to grow that the only way out of the
        crisis was to open the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to foreign trade and new ideas. The
        Tokugawa shoguns, however, sensed that the internal strains might be
        contained, by sheer brute force if necessary, as long as new pressures
        were not exerted from outside by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> once again offering
        disgruntled daimyo new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of income.
        The stubborn <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> came back again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1853</TIMEX>, with
        Commodore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Perry</ENAMEX> bringing for the shogun (whom he mistook for
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>) a polite but insistent letter from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millard</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fillmore</ENAMEX> and a promise to return <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX>, with a bigger squadron,
        for a positive response.
        In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1854</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry</ENAMEX> duly negotiated the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Treaty of Kanagawa</ENAMEX> (now
        part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yokohama</ENAMEX>), opening up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shimoda</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Izu Peninsula</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hakodate</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hokkaido</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">short time</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, similar treaties were
        signed with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> had driven in the thin end of
        its wedge. More and more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> were opened to foreign trade, and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> were obliged to accept low import tariffs.
        As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoguns</ENAMEX> had feared, this opening of the
        floodgates of Western culture after such prolonged isolation had a
        traumatic effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> society. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> had successfully
        persuaded the samurai that traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> values might suffer,
        and now the samurai felt betrayed, rallying under the slogan ‚ÄúSonno
        joi! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù (‚</ENAMEX>ÄúHonor the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>, expel the barbarians! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX> ).
        Before they could even think of accepting contact with the
        outside world, national integrity had to be restored, under the renewed
        moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>. Bands of samurai assassinated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1863</TIMEX>, the daimyo of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Choshu</ENAMEX> (in western
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honshu</ENAMEX>) fired on foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimonoseki</ENAMEX> Straits. In response,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>, and French combined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> to smash the
        Choshu fortified positions, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> retaliated for the
        assassination by practically leveling the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kagoshima</ENAMEX> in southern
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyushu</ENAMEX>. The local daimyo of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satsuma</ENAMEX> was so impressed that he started to
        buy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>, which became the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of the future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meiji Restoration</ENAMEX>
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satsuma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Choshu</ENAMEX> clans, never a real threat
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> authority as long as they remained <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>, joined forces to
        overthrow the shogun and restore the authority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>, the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitsuhito</ENAMEX>. Edo was renamed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokyo (‚ÄúEastern Capital‚Äù</ENAMEX>), and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitsuhito</ENAMEX> took over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> as his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>.
        But important though the resuscitated imperial authority
        undoubtedly was, the real power under the restoration known as Meiji
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">(‚ÄúEnlightened Rule‚Äù</ENAMEX>) was in the hands of a new generation of
        forward-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>, who set about abolishing the ancient
        feudal apparatus in favor of a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> based on merit rather
        than ancestry. They emphasized the need to acquire Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> and
        industrial skills and technology with which to confront the West itself
        and eliminate unfair trade tariffs and other unjust aspects of the
        foreign treaties.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>, commerce, and traditional manufacturing were
        expanded to provide a sound economic base for investment in the modern
        technology of textiles and other industries. Shipbuilding and weapons
        manufacture were already under way; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railways</ENAMEX> and telegraph lines
        quickly followed. And to show just how fast Japan‚Äôs new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> were
        catching on, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> punitive expeditions were launched against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in the grand manner of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">gunboat</ENAMEX> diplomacy.
        There was an inevitable reaction to rapid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westernization</ENAMEX>.
        Traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> theater, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> ceremony, ikebana flower
        arrangement, and the old martial arts all came back into favor. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890</TIMEX>
        an important imperial edict on education was issued, promoting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
        (that is, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>) values in culture and stressing loyalty
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> and general harmony. If the singing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of
        military songs such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúCome, Foes, Come</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äù or ‚ÄúThough the Enemy Be</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tens</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> Strong‚Äù seems excessively belligerent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, we
        should not forget jingoistic attitudes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> made a dramatic debut on the international stage,
        with military actions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1894</TIMEX> Sino-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>
        War for control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> markets and the strategic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern Manchuria</ENAMEX> was a triumph for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Japan‚Äôs</ENAMEX> modernized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> over
        China‚Äôs larger but much less well-organized forces. More impressive
        still was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs success against the powerful war machine of Czarist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1904‚Äì1905</ENAMEX>), beginning with a surprise nighttime attack on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX>, to be repeated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years later</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> was forced to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs occupation of southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manchuria</ENAMEX> and
        the annexation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just 40 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> had
        established itself as a viable world power.
        Triumph and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Disaster</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The 20th century</TIMEX> saw a stupendous release of energies that
        had been pent up for the 250 years of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> isolation. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX>
        raw-material production had tripled the figure of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>, manufactured
        goods had increased twelve-fold, and heavy industry was galloping
        towards maturity. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> led the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> in large orders
        for munitions, while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> expanded sales of manufactured goods to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> and other markets cut off from their usual <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>.
        Merchant shipping doubled in size and increased its income <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>-fold as
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleets</ENAMEX> were destroyed.
        Setbacks in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> caused by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> postwar slump
        were only a spur to redouble efforts by diversifying heavy industry
        into the machine-making, metallurgical, and chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX>. Even the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">terrible 1923 Tokyo earthquake</ENAMEX>, which cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 100,000</NUMEX> lives and
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX>, provided another stimulus due to the construction
        boom that followed.
        Riding the crest of this economic upsurge were the zaibatsu
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conglomerates‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa</ENAMEX> dozen family-run <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">combines</ENAMEX>, each involved in mining,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturing</ENAMEX>, marketing, shipping, and banking. These tightly
        controlled commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX> were the true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> to the old feudal
        structures.
        Japan‚Äôs progress toward parliamentary democracy was halted
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> by the growing nationalism being imposed on government by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> and admirals. They proclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚Äôs</ENAMEX> mission to bring
        progress to its backward <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> in language not so very
        different from that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Revolution</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> was
        regarded as a major threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Japan‚Äôs</ENAMEX> security, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> felt it
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">needed Manchuria</ENAMEX> and whatever other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> territory it could control
        as a buffer against <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX> advances. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> occupied
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchuria</ENAMEX>. And then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>, with the popular support of
        ultra-right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> overrode parliamentary resistance in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> and went to war against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese Nationalists</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>, they
        held <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nanking, Hankow</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canton</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> expansionist policies were leading to direct
        confrontation with the West. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> hoped that war in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> would
        divert the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> from interference in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Asia</ENAMEX>, giving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> a
        free hand both in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and, through its alliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indochina</ENAMEX> after the defeat of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> responded to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indochina</ENAMEX> with a trade and fuel embargo, cutting
        off <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Japan‚Äôs</ENAMEX> supplies. The result was the attack on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1941</TIMEX>) and total war.
        Early successes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borneo, Malaya</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch East Indies</ENAMEX> enabled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to establish the
        so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater East Asia Co</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosperity Sphere</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúliberation‚Äù</ENAMEX> of
        these old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> created the basis for postwar independence
        movements proclaiming the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> slogan ‚ÄúAsia for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        Despite this, the various occupied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> quickly found themselves
        suffering harsher and more brutal treatment than they had ever
        experienced under their former colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midway</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1942‚</TIMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇdestroying Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> aircraft <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> and soon thereafter its merchant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">navy</ENAMEX> and
        remaining naval air-power‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇcut <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> off from its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas MacArthur</ENAMEX> was back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> to direct the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">island-hopping</ENAMEX> advance that ended in the massive fire-bombing of
        Japan‚Äôs mostly wood-built <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. In an air raid by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">130</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B29s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> was
        devastated and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants perished</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> was
        reluctant to sue for peace because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Allies</ENAMEX> were demanding
        unconditional surrender with no provision for maintaining the highly
        symbolic role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>, still considered the embodiment of
        Japan‚Äôs spirit and divine origins.
        Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> intelligence reports and monitored
        communications indicating the desperation of large sections of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for peace, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> rejection of the Potsdam
        Declaration calling for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs unconditional surrender was the excuse
        for unleashing the ultimate weapon of the war. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 August 1945</TIMEX>, a B29
        (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enola Gay</ENAMEX>) dropped an atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hiroshima</ENAMEX>,
        inflicting a level of destruction that astonished even the bomb‚Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three days later</TIMEX> another atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> devastated the southern
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">port of Nagasaki</ENAMEX>.
        On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8 August</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">battlefront</ENAMEX> and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> marched into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchuria</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five days later</TIMEX>
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> heard the voice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hirohito</ENAMEX>, in his first
        radio broadcast, announcing that ‚Äúthe war situation has developed not
        necessarily to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs advantage. ‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> renounced his divinity,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> took formal control of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.
        Peace and Prosperity
        After years of government propaganda predicting the worst
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">atrocities</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> were surprised at the warmth and
        friendliness of the occupying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">postwar period</TIMEX> began,
        however, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of displaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people homeless</ENAMEX> and starving. To
        counter a perceived communist threat from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
        quickly set to work reconstructing the economy by transforming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> and devising a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pacifist</ENAMEX> constitution. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Article 9</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">renounced Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs right to maintain armed forces, although the
        ambiguous wording was later taken to permit the creati on of a
        ‚Äúself-defense‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>.
        The zaibatsu <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX> that had proved so instrumental
        in boosting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs militarism were disbanded, later to re-emerge as
        the keiretsu trading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX> that dominated the economy once
        again. The entire economy received a massive jump-start with the
        outbreak of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean War</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> ironically becoming the chief
        local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> it had battled so furiously just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>
        earlier.
        The occupation lasted until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>, having already planted
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs future stunning economic success. Economic output
        was back to prewar levels, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> auto <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> provided the
        support needed to get <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan‚Äôs</ENAMEX> auto industry back on its feet. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> then enthusiastically imported any Western technologies they
        could get their hands on. This included transistor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">technology‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇinvented</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> but then considered to have only
        limited applications‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇfor the surreal sum of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX>. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan</ENAMEX>
        that produced the world‚Äôs first transistor radio. The electronic
        technology spurt that followed is now legendary.
        Parliamentary democracy finally came into its own, albeit
        with distinctly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> characteristics reflecting the dislike of
        debate and confrontation and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>-oriented preference for
        maintaining the appearance of harmony at all times. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>,
        through the powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finance Ministry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ministry of International</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade and Industry</ENAMEX>, generously supported favored private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>:
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> shipping, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, then electronics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> basked in the warmth
        of the government‚Äôs loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attentions</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> overtook <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> economically in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of</TIMEX>
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚Äôs</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> largest economy in the world‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇless
        then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX> after the war had left the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in ruins.
        Prosperity was not without its own problems: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> caused by
        ‚Äúdirty‚Äù industries, a high incidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stomach ulcers</ENAMEX> (even suicides)
        among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX> pressured by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-ambitious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, and the
        awkward questions of what to do about nuclear energy.
        The famous coziness among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>, and
        private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, together with the strong cultural emphasis on
        relationship-building and a lack of transparency and accountability,
        eventually led to corrupt practices of endemic proportions.
        Breach-of-trust scandals became common. In an increasingly producer-led
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> dominated by price-fixing cartels operating with the
        government‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blessing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> were left to foot the bill.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inevitable Collapse</ENAMEX>
        The start of asset inflation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> led to the
        ‚Äúbubble economy,‚Äù with anyone owning land becoming richer by the
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point the land value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Imperial Palace</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> was
        thought to be worth more than the entire real-estate value of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>.
        With astonishing sums of money sloshing around the economy and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
        products considered world-beaters everywhere, it seemed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
        that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> had finally achieved its rightful place in the
        world.
        Everyone expected the double-digit growth rates to continue
        indefinitely. However, crashing real estate prices had a domino effect
        on the rest of the economy, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> slipped
        quickly into stagnation and then recession. Seemingly endemic
        corruption was compounded by a remarkable dearth of political
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and decisive action. Indeed, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs consensus-based
        management system, the response of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>, and
        business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> seemed to be to look the other way and hope bad news
        would disappear.
        The government‚Äôs gradual and reluctant admission that,
        despite previous assurances, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> were sitting on staggering‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long-concealed‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇamounts</ENAMEX> of unrecoverable loans (originally secured
        against land values) caused an unprecedented crisis of confidence.
        Growing economic decline brought record corporate bankruptcies and the
        end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX> employment, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were forced to improve
        efficiency in order to survive.
        The irony is that although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> has continually triumphed
        over externally imposed adversity and upheavals, it seems unable to
        implement effective reforms to its own systems before problems reach
        crisis proportions. The rote-learning educational system is still
        failing to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> develop the individual analytical and
        problem-solving skills required in the information age. Another example
        is the banking crisis, which grew to globally alarming proportions over
        an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight-year</TIMEX> period before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> even admitted a problem
        existed.
        Despite these formidable challenges, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> will probably
        end up confounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pessimists</ENAMEX>. It will likely emerge in the 21st
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> as a regional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in more than just economic terms. No
        matter what the future holds, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> will remain one of the world‚Äôs most
        intriguing destinations for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> everywhere.
      
    
  
