
  
  
    
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢‚Ä¢</ENAMEX>
        A BRIEF HISTORY
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> has only existed as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">since 1871</TIMEX>. Before then,
        despite the peninsula‚Äôs obvious geographical unity bounded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alps</ENAMEX>
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>, its story is a fragmented tale of
        independent-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, regions, and islands‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand the outside
        powers who coveted them.
        We have abundant evidence of the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Etruscan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, but know very little of the country‚Äôs
        earlier, prehistoric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>. Vestiges of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dwellings</ENAMEX> survive‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇcabins
        on stilts in the frequently flooded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Po valley</ENAMEX>, larger <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> on
        the western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marshlands</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sardinia‚Äôs</ENAMEX> still visible domed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dry-stone nuraghi</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX>? Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Africans</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eastern</ENAMEX> Europeans peopled the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ligurian coast</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adriatic</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">south</ENAMEX> may have been settled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia</ENAMEX>
        Minor.
        Nobody knows much about the early <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Etruscans</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>
        believe that they were the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native Italians</ENAMEX>; others believe they
        arrived from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia Minor</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">era</ENAMEX>, their civilization reached north beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Po valley</ENAMEX>
        and south toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX>. At a time when early <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> were still primitive, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Etruscan</ENAMEX> society ‚Äî itself savage in many
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">respects ‚Äî</ENAMEX> was also aristocratic and highly sophisticated. Solid gold
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">workmanship</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal</ENAMEX> ornaments and tools showed a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
        influence, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Etruscans‚</ENAMEX>Äô vaulted architecture, town planning, and
        irrigation systems were indigenous.
        Arriving in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the eighth century</TIMEX> b.c. , the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> set up
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">city-states</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sicily</ENAMEX>, dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syracuse</ENAMEX>, as well as other
        settlements on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> mainland, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paestum</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taranto</ENAMEX>. Together they formed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magna Graecia</ENAMEX>, whose zenith was reached
        during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 6th and 5th centuries</TIMEX> b.c.
        After defeats by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> in the south, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latins</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallic</ENAMEX> invaders in the north, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Etruscan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> faded in the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> b.c. As <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> colonial power grew weak from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sparta</ENAMEX> rivalry back home and pressure from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenicians</ENAMEX> in
        Sicily, the vacuum was filled by an uppity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">confederation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sabine tribes</ENAMEX> living on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> hills known collectively as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>.
        The Romans
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Legend</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> was founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romulus</ENAMEX>, sired with twin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remus</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vestal Virgin</ENAMEX> and abandoned on the Palatine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> to be suckled by a she-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wolf</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Historians</ENAMEX> agree with the mythmakers
        that the site and traditional founding date of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">753</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">b.c.</ENAMEX> are just about
        right.
        Under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Etruscan</ENAMEX> domination, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> had been a monarchy until a
        revolt in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">510</NUMEX> b.c. established a patrician republic, which lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">centuries</ENAMEX>. In contrast to other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> weakened by internal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rivalries</ENAMEX> and unstable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> drew strength from a solid
        aristocracy of consuls and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">senate</ENAMEX> ruling over plebeians proud of their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> and only rarely rebellious.
        Recovering quickly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gallic</ENAMEX> invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">390 b.c. ,</ENAMEX>
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> took effective control of the peninsula by a military
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conquest</ENAMEX> reinforced by a network of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> with names that exist to this
        day: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Appia, Flaminia, Aurelia</ENAMEX>. All roads did indeed lead to‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">from‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇRome</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">250 b.c.</TIMEX> , the city‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> had grown to an
        impressive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> power extended throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> with a
        victory in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Punic Wars</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carthage</ENAMEX> (now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tunisia</ENAMEX>) and conquests
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia Minor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">southern France</ENAMEX>. The rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>
        participated only by tax contributions to the war effort and minor
        involvement in commerce and colonization. Resentment surfaced when
        former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Etruscan</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capua</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syracuse</ENAMEX>, and Taranto
        supported <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hannibal‚Äôs</ENAMEX> invasion in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">218</NUMEX> b.c. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> followed up defeat of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carthaginians</ENAMEX> with large-scale massacres and enslavement of their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> and final <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Punic War</ENAMEX> ended in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">149 b.c.</TIMEX> ,
        though national solidarity was still a long way off.
        Under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius Caesar</ENAMEX>, elected in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">59 b.c.</TIMEX> , provincial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>
        won the privileges of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>. His reformist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>,
        bypassing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">senate</ENAMEX> to combat unemployment and ease the tax burden,
        made dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. After being appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> for life, he was
        assassinated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brutus</ENAMEX>, among others, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ides</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> b.c.
        This led to civil war and the despotic rule of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Octavian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius Caesar</ENAMEX> whose new title of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augustus Caesar</ENAMEX> signified the
        collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Republic</ENAMEX> and the beginning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Empire</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">27 b.c.</TIMEX>
        Conquest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> accelerated rather than halted the
        influence of their culture in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>. Romans infused <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> refinement
        with their own energy to create a unique mixture of elegance and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">realism</ENAMEX>, delicacy and strength, which have remained the essence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> life and art.
        In architecture, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> made a quantum leap forward
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> of columns and beams by developing the arch,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vault</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX>, well suited to the needs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>. The Romans
        built basilicas for public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, pioneered the new
        engineering of aqueducts and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>, and erected triumphal arches for
        victorious armies. They adopted the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Greeks‚Äô gods</ENAMEX>, convertingZeus into
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aphrodite</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Venus</ENAMEX>, and placing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">emperor‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇ</ENAMEX> serving the
        interests of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> state‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇat the apex of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">gods</ENAMEX>.
        Throughout the centuries of imperial expansion, decline,
        and fall, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> took a back seat as the realm of power moved with the
        armies away from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, east to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Byzantium</ENAMEX> and to the north as far as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaul</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>.
        Despite the dramatic persecution under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Nero</ENAMEX> in the first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">century a.d.</ENAMEX> , Christianity spread from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> through southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>,
        then continued northward. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constantine the Great</ENAMEX> declared Christianity
        the official state religion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 313</TIMEX>; he later boldly transferred
        the capital to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byzantium</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constantinople</ENAMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">324</TIMEX>. At the end of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodosius the Great</ENAMEX> organized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> into
        dioceses, making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ravenna</ENAMEX> the new capital of the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> (with
        Constantinople as capital of the Eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> would never be
        the same again. The position of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bishop of Rome</ENAMEX> as primate of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Church</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> derived from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúpapa,‚Äù the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> word for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>),
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> claimed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second century</TIMEX>, was later asserted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope Leo</ENAMEX> I
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">440‚Äì461</ENAMEX>), who traced the succession back to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Peter</ENAMEX>.
        The invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attila‚Äôs Huns</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goths</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vandals</ENAMEX> who
        came to sack, rape, murder, and pillage <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> brought an end to the
        Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">476</TIMEX> with the abdication of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romulus</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augustus</ENAMEX>.
        After the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>
        Wars between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goths</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byzantines</ENAMEX> followed by new waves
        of invasions made <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> unity impossible.
        The dual influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> culture persisted.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emperor Justinian</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">527‚Äì565</ENAMEX>) and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodora</ENAMEX> reannexed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> and codified <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> law as the state‚Äôs legal
        system. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heraclius</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">610‚Äì641</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> was extended to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> as its
        official language.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hellenistic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX> influences were most evident in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX>. Byzantine ritual colored the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> liturgy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
        basilica‚Äôs long colonnaded nave leading to an apse gave way to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> cross with a central space surrounded by arches and topped by a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dome</ENAMEX>. Sculptural reliefs flattened out to symbolic decorative,
        non-human forms, and painting and mosaics were rich in color, but more
        rigid and formal. Spiritual preoccupations turned away from the world‚Äôs
        few joys and woes in the present, to mystic contemplation of the
        ineffable hereafter.
        Things were much too ineffable, it seems, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italian</ENAMEX>
        tastes. The monastic movement, founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Benedict of Umbria</ENAMEX> in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixth century</TIMEX>, reasserted involvement in the realities of social life.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benedictine</ENAMEX> order emphasized moderation in the austerity of its
        food, clothing, and sleep, not unlike the habits of any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasant</ENAMEX> of the
        times. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flagellation</ENAMEX> and similar rigors introduced into other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
        monasteries by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk Columbanus</ENAMEX> were soon modified by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gentler Benedictine</ENAMEX> rule.
        By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the eighth century</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Byzantines</ENAMEX> held the balance of
        power with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lombards</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>), who had invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> in
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">568</NUMEX> and set up their capital at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pavia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years later</TIMEX>. The Lombards
        controlled the interior in a loose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">confederation</ENAMEX> of fiercely
        independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">duchies</ENAMEX>. Lombard territory split <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> up into
        segments ruled from the coasts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> resulted in Veneto
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX> and its hinterland), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emilia</ENAMEX> (between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ravenna</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modena</ENAMEX>), and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentapolo</ENAMEX> (between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rimini</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perugia</ENAMEX>), plus <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX> (with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sicily</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calabria</ENAMEX>).
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, the highly political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">popes</ENAMEX> played the Lombard
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">duchies</ENAMEX> against those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>. They cited a forged
        document, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constantine</ENAMEX>, supposedly bequeathing them
        political authority over all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>. Seeking the powerful support of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope Leo III</ENAMEX> crowned their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlemagne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Day</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">800</TIMEX>. But in turn the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> had to kneel in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">allegiance</ENAMEX>, and this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of spiritual blessing for military
        protection laid the seeds of future conflict between the papacy and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secular rulers</ENAMEX>, compounded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">962</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto</ENAMEX> I was crowned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> of
        the newly formed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Roman Empire</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>, founded on its islets and lagoons in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> by mainland <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> fleeing Lombard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">raiders</ENAMEX>, prospered from a
        privileged relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Byzantium</ENAMEX> and an uninhibited readiness to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> and others farther east. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>
        that were the backbone of the Most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serene Republic</ENAMEX> were only too happy
        to dessiminate their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX> cargoes of exotic goods to the dour lives
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lombards</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Po valley</ENAMEX> and beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alps</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northern Europe</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naples</ENAMEX> held on to its autonomy by combining links with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constantinople</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> conquered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sicily</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>
        and turned to the mainland, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX> at first sought an alliance. But as
        the invaders advanced north towards <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX> successfully linked up
        with the then powerful maritime <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> of neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amalfi</ENAMEX>. Despite
        military expeditions by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byzantines</ENAMEX>, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>
        remained on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> scene for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two centuries</TIMEX>. Their influences in
        the sciences and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> they brought with them are still felt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
        The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Middle Ages</TIMEX>
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 11th century</TIMEX>, the adventurous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Normans</ENAMEX> put an end to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sicily</ENAMEX> and southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>. Exploiting a natural genius
        for assimilating the useful elements of the local culture rather than
        indiscriminately imposing their own, they adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>-style tax
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX> and customs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX>-admirals for their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">navy</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palermo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mosques</ENAMEX> stood side-by-side, feudal
        castles next to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> and their exotic gardens.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crusades</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> threat to Christendom
        brought great prosperity to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Italy‚Äôs</ENAMEX> port <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. Pisa sided with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Normans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sicily</ENAMEX> and profits from its new commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> in the
        western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> paid for its magnificent cathedral, baptistery,
        and campanile (today‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Leaning Tower</ENAMEX>). Genoa‚Äôs equally powerful
        merchant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> spread from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of the art of playing all sides, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>
        stayed out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Crusade</ENAMEX> to expand its trade with the faraway
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> while ferrying pilgrims to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>. Later, when Byzantium
        threatened its eastern trading privileges, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX> persuaded the armies
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fourth Crusade</ENAMEX> to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constantinople</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1204</TIMEX>; conquering
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Byzantium</ENAMEX> strengthened its position even more.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Po</ENAMEX> valley‚Äôs economic expansion through land clearance
        and new irrigation works brought a rapid decline of feudalism. Dukes,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">administrators</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX> lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> rather than isolated castles,
        absorbing the hinterland into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">communes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">forerunners</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">city-states</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">communes</ENAMEX> were strong enough to confine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Barbarossa‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> ambitions to the south, where he secured
        Sicily for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hohenstaufen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> by marrying his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">royal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Ruling from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palermo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barbarossa‚</ENAMEX>Äôs highly cultured but
        brutal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick II</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1194‚Äì1250</ENAMEX>) was a prototype for the future
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX>.
        His power struggle with the papacy divided the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> into
        two highly volatile camps‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇGuelfs supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> and Ghibellines
        supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>. The backbone of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guelfs</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">communes</ENAMEX> such
        as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genoa</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1266</TIMEX>, they financed the mercenary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles d‚ÄôAnjou</ENAMEX> to defeat the imperial forces‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand take the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sicilian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">throne</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palermo</ENAMEX> rose up against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> in the murderous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sicilian Vespers</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1282</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> massacred everyone who spoke
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> accent and forced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> to move his capital to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sicilians</ENAMEX> offered their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crown</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aragon</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guelf</ENAMEX>-Ghibelline conflict became a pretext for settling
        family feuds (such as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> typified in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shakespeare‚Äôs Romeo and</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juliet</ENAMEX>) or communal rivalries, from which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genoa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florence</ENAMEX> emerged
        stronger than ever. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, the dissolute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">popes</ENAMEX> repeatedly switched
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> for temporary advantage and lost all political and moral
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> in the process.
        After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two centuries</TIMEX> of religious heresy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> needed
        a spiritual renewal, finding the perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> of Assisi
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1182‚Äì1226</ENAMEX>), pious without being troublesomely militant. His sermons
        had immense popular appeal. He chose not to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> corruption
        but instead to preach the values of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christly</ENAMEX> life. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Franciscan</ENAMEX>
        order provided a much needed manageable revival. The architecture of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> built in his name at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assisi contradicted Francis‚</ENAMEX>Äôs humble
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">testament denouncing ‚Äútemples</ENAMEX> of great dimension and rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ornament</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assisi‚</ENAMEX>Äôs frescoes of the saint‚Äôs life, painted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cimabue</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disciples of Giotto</ENAMEX> (which barely survived the severe earthquake of
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>), proved an immensely effective act of artistic propaganda against
        the prevalent libertinism and heresy.
        The City-States
        By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 13th century</TIMEX>, with the independent-minded
        communes growing into full-fledged city-states, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> was clearly not
        to be subjugated to the will of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX>.
        The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Middle Ages</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> were far from being the murky era
        that many humanist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> liked to contrast with the brilliance of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bologna</ENAMEX> founded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>, famous
        above all for its law studies, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 11th century</TIMEX>, followed by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> of learning in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Padua</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Modena</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Siena</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salerno</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palermo</ENAMEX>. Unlike other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>-dominated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> emphasized the sciences, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, and law over
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theology</ENAMEX>.
        In the absence of political unification, it was the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> that awakened the national consciousness. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Scholars</ENAMEX>
        traveling across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> needed a common tongue beyond the elitist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin</ENAMEX> to break through the barriers of regional dialects. It was a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">foreigner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick II</ENAMEX>, who launched the movement for a
        national language at his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palermo</ENAMEX>, but Florentine-born Dante
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alighieri</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1265‚Äì1321</ENAMEX>) provided the ardor, moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, and
        literary example to bring it to fruition.
        The maritime <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genoa</ENAMEX> rose to challenge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Venice‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supremacy</ENAMEX>. It dislodged <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pisa</ENAMEX> in the western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>, whittled
        away at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venice‚</ENAMEX>Äôs hold on eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX>, and set up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> on the
        Black <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea</ENAMEX> for trade with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and faraway <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathay</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genoa‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1381</TIMEX>
        participation in the ruinous <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Chioggia War</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venetian</ENAMEX> lagoon
        exhausted its resources. Its newly formed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of St. George</ENAMEX> had to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> off overseas <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX>. It ran the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> like a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for
        the benefit of a local oligarchy, seeking future prosperity as
        international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financiers</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Repubblica</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serena</ENAMEX> rebounded to turn to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mainland</ENAMEX>, extending its <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Veneto</ENAMEX> territory from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Padua</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Po</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">valley</ENAMEX> as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergamo</ENAMEX>. After relying exclusively on overseas trade,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX> created a new land-owning aristocracy through this
        expansion.
        In its fertile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Po valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> prospered from trade with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, principally in textiles and armor. Escaping unscathed from the
        Black <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of 1348</ENAMEX> and subsequent plagues, it built up a sound
        economic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> and maintained a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> with plentiful manpower.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florence</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to mint its own gold
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coin</ENAMEX> (fiorino or florin), a prestigious instrument for trade in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> markets, and it organized textile manufacture on an advanced
        large-scale basis. Despite uprisings such as that of the Ciompi
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>), the resilient <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florentines</ENAMEX> were well-fed and highly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">literate</ENAMEX> compared to the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The wealthy and ambitious
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medici</ENAMEX> (not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, as their name implied) emerged as the dominant
        merchant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Cosimo the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elder</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1389‚Äì1464</ENAMEX>) became the city‚Äôs ruler
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medici</ENAMEX> dynasty in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1434</TIMEX>. A building boom underlined
        the prosperity: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giotto‚Äôs Campanile</ENAMEX> was at last completed, as were
        Ghiberti‚Äôs great baptistery doors, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brunelleschi‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cathedral</ENAMEX>.
        Divided in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 14th century</TIMEX> between the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> in Sicily
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX>, southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> remained solidly feudal. Its
        almost exclusively agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">economy</ENAMEX> suffered much more than the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">north</ENAMEX> from plague and famine. Landlords resorted to banditry to
        replenish their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">treasury</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palermo</ENAMEX> was in decline, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX> flourished
        as a brilliant cosmopolitan capital. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1443</TIMEX>, it was reunited with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sicily</ENAMEX> and known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sicilies</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Alfonso V</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aragon</ENAMEX>.
        With the papacy in comfortable exile in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Avignon</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1309</TIMEX>,
        the brutal rule of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orsini</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colonna</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> reduced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> to a
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-urban, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">backwater village</ENAMEX>. Self-educated visionary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cola</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">di Rienzo</ENAMEX> governed briefly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1347</TIMEX> until the nobles drove him out.
        After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX>, the papacy returned.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>
        A new national fraternity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> with expertise in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arts</ENAMEX>, sciences, and law emerged as itinerant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> to visionary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> eager to make their city-states centers of cultural prestige and
        political propaganda.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Battista Alberti</ENAMEX>, brilliant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect-mathematician-poet</ENAMEX>, brought about a new spirit of inquiry and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scepticism</ENAMEX>. From their detailed study and translation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">philosophers</ENAMEX>, they developed principles of objective scientific
        research, independent of all the political, religious, and emotional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bias</ENAMEX> characterizing medieval scholarship. The emphasis switched from
        heaven to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo da Vinci</ENAMEX> eagerly applied the new method to
        architecture, civil and military engineering, urban planning,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">geography</ENAMEX>, and map-making. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giorgio Vasari</ENAMEX>, facile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> but
        first-rate chronicler of this cultural explosion, who allegedly dubbed
        it a rinascita, or rebirth, of the glories of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy‚Äôs Greco</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> past.
        But even more, it proved, with the humanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX> and the political realism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machiavelli</ENAMEX>, to be the birth
        of our modern age.
        Unfortunately, the creative ferment by no means precluded
        new horrors of war, assassination, persecution, plunder, and rape. It
        was the heyday of the brilliant but lethal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> Borgias:
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lecherous Rodrigo</ENAMEX>, who became <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope Alexander VI</ENAMEX>, and treacherous son
        Cesare, who stopped at nothing to control and expand the papal lands.
        His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucrezia</ENAMEX>, forever smeared by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Spanish</ENAMEX> propaganda of the
        day as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> of both her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, was in fact, as Duchess
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferrara</ENAMEX>, a generous patroness of the arts and benefactress of the
        poor.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX>, where his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> had to fight tooth and nail
        to hold on to their supremacy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenzo ‚Äúil Magnifico‚</ENAMEX>Äù de‚Äô Medici
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1449‚Äì1492</ENAMEX>) found time to encourage the art of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perugino, Ghirlandaio</ENAMEX>,
        Botticelli, the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo</ENAMEX>, and tempestuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>. But
        decadence set in and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dominican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk</ENAMEX> and rabble-rousing preacher
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Girolamo Savonarola</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1452‚Äì1498</ENAMEX>) denounced the corruption of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>
        and society more devoted to pagan classics than to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
        gospel. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnival</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1494</TIMEX>, he shamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florentines</ENAMEX> into
        throwing their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúvanities‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇnot</ENAMEX> only clothes, jewelry, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cosmetics</ENAMEX>,
        but books and paintings, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Botticelli</ENAMEX> contributing some of his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">own‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇonto</ENAMEX> a giant fire on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piazza della Signoria</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four years later</TIMEX>,
        when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Savonarola</ENAMEX> declined to test the validity of his apocalyptic
        prophesies with an ordeal by fire, he was arrested, hanged, and
        ironically burned on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piazza della Signoria</ENAMEX>.
        On the international scene, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> conquest of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constantinople</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1453</TIMEX> closed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Genoa‚Äôs Black Sea</ENAMEX> markets, but competitor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX> worked out a new deal in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cyprus</ENAMEX> and even a modus vivendi in
        Constantinople itself. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venetians‚</ENAMEX>Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> declined as they lost
        their taste for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> of commerce in favor of the safety of
        their landholdings. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1494 to 1530</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Spanish Hapsburgs</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> turned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> into a battleground for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom of Naples</ENAMEX> and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duchy</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>. Genoa sided with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles V</ENAMEX> access, via <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, to his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> territories, and later
        became a lucrative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clearinghouse</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spain‚</ENAMEX>Äôs newly discovered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> was plundered by imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1527</TIMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medici</ENAMEX> were
        driven out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX> and returned to power only under tutelage of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>, who won effective control of the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
        When the dust of war settled, it was the dazzling cultural
        achievements that left their mark on the age. The true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rome‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        High <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope Julius II</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1503‚Äì1513</ENAMEX>) began the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Peter‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cathedral</ENAMEX>, and commissioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX> to paint the ceiling of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vatican‚Äôs Sistine Chapel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael</ENAMEX> to decorate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanze</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Architect</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donato Bramante</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nicknamed maestro ruinante</ENAMEX> because of all the
        ancient monuments he dismantled to make way for the pope‚Äôs megalomaniac
        building plans. With the treasures uncovered in the process, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius</ENAMEX>
        founded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican‚</ENAMEX>Äôs magnificent collection of ancient sculpture.
        Counter-Reformation
        Badly shaken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant Reformation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>
        convoked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent</ENAMEX> (north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Garda</ENAMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1545</TIMEX>.
        Non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishops</ENAMEX> urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> to carry out its own reform,
        hoping to democratize relations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>. But the threat of
        Lutherans, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calvinists</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">heretics</ENAMEX> shifted the emphasis to
        repression, culminating in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counter-Reformation</ENAMEX> formally proclaimed
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1563</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> reinforced the Holy Office‚<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Äôs Inquisition</ENAMEX> and the
        Index to censor the arts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuits</ENAMEX>, founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1534</TIMEX>, quickly became
        an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologians</ENAMEX> to combat <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">heresy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian Protestants</ENAMEX> fled and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> were restricted to a ghetto (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years later</TIMEX> than the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX> ghetto, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>) and expelled from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genoa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucca</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardinal Carlo Borromeo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope Pius IV</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Archbishop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1565‚Äì1584</ENAMEX>), was the exemplary spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italy‚Äôs Counter-Reformation</ENAMEX>. In alliance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuits</ENAMEX>, he weeded
        out corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerics</ENAMEX> and what he considered too soft <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Umiliati</ENAMEX> order of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laymen</ENAMEX>. As a symbol of his crusading spirit, he consecrated
        Milan‚Äôs new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Flamboyant Gothic cathedral</ENAMEX>, which took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> to
        complete and remains one of the world‚Äôs largest and most famous Gothic
        structures.
        Art proved to be a major instrument of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counter</ENAMEX>-Reformation
        propaganda, but it had to undergo some important changes. The vigor and
        intellectual integrity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Renaissance</ENAMEX> had softened into the
        stylized sophistication of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mannerism</ENAMEX>, the transition from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baroque</ENAMEX>. Condemning the preoccupation with pagan
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gods</ENAMEX> and worldly decadence, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> to deliver a
        strong, clear message to bring the troubled flock back to the fold. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annibale Carracci</ENAMEX> further paved the way for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baroque</ENAMEX>, attracting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX> with a sensuous image of ideal beauty,
        while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caravaggio</ENAMEX> made a more brutal, but no less effective, appeal with
        a proletarian <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> and barefoot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostles</ENAMEX>. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> regained
        ground, it promoted a more triumphant image, epitomized by the works of
        Bernini, the most productive of them all: His grandiose Baroque altar
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Peter‚</ENAMEX>Äôs speaks rather effectively to the time.
        But such self-confidence had its limits. For example, in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1633</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Galileo</ENAMEX> to deny the evidence of his own eyes,
        as assisted by the new telescope he had designed, and stop teaching
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">God‚Äôs earth</ENAMEX> was only one of many planets in orbit around the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sun</ENAMEX>.
        After a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16th century</TIMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX> had become the largest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Europe‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇand one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">liveliest‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> south was increasingly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oppressed</ENAMEX> and impoverished. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> had to crush revolts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sicily</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX> against heavy taxes and conscription for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spain‚</ENAMEX>Äôs wars in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northern Europe</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Towards Nationhood</ENAMEX>
        Lacking the solidarity to unite and too weak to resist by
        themselves, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kingdoms</ENAMEX> and duchies were reduced to convenient
        pawns in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Europe‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> dynastic power plays. At the end of the
        Wars of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polish Succession</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austrians</ENAMEX> had
        taken over northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age of Enlightenment</ENAMEX>
        engendered a new cultural ferment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Scala</ENAMEX> opened in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Fenice</ENAMEX> opened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>. Stimulated by the ideas of
        Voltaire, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rousseau</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diderot</ENAMEX>, the country‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> were more
        keenly aware of being <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>, but also <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX>.
        The hopes of progressives were raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> reforms
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lombardy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX> (where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medici</ENAMEX> dynasty had fizzled to an end
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1737</TIMEX>). The results included fairer taxes; less <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> influence in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>; more public education; and removal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inquisition</ENAMEX>,
        Jesuits, the death penalty, and instruments of torture. Outside the
        Austrian sphere of influence, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> remained solidly conservative.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX> stagnated under the rule of a small entrenched √©lite, drawing
        nostalgic comfort from the city‚Äôs petrified beauty as painted in the
        vedute of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canaletto</ENAMEX>. The papacy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> had lost prestige
        with the dissolution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuits</ENAMEX> and the crippling loss of revenue
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hapsburg Church</ENAMEX> reforms. The south‚Äôs aristocracy resisted all
        significant social reforms proposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Carlos</ENAMEX>, a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">descendant of Louis XIV</ENAMEX> who saw himself as a southern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sun King‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇwith
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caserta Palace</ENAMEX> as his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Versailles‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇis best remembered for launching the
        excavations of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pompeii</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1748</TIMEX>.
        On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">northwestern Alpine</ENAMEX> frontier, a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> had
        appeared on the scene, destined to lead the movement to a united <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>.
        With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savoy</ENAMEX> split in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>,
        its foothill region southeast of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alps</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX>, had come into the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> orbit. Sidestepping the stagnant economic burden of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
        domination, the sparsely populated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">duchy</ENAMEX> expanded quickly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turin</ENAMEX> was
        little more than a fortified village of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1600</TIMEX>, but
        it rose to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century later</TIMEX>. The pragmatic dukes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX>
        liked <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>-style absolutist monarchy but tempered it with a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> to bypass local fiefdoms. They copied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis XIV‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">centralized</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> and tax-collection, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turin</ENAMEX> was a sparkling royal capital built, quite unlike any other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, in classical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> manner.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Napoleon Bonaparte</ENAMEX>, with his seductive ideas of Italian
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúindependence</ENAMEX>,‚Äù was welcomed after driving out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austrians</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1797</TIMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> soon proved just as great a burden on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> treasuries, used to support their war effort and the Bonaparte
        family. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Napoleon</ENAMEX> did not exactly ‚Äúliberate‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, he did shake up
        the old conservatism from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lombardy</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX> by creating new
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> and high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, streamlining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>, creating a
        new legal system with his <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Napoleonic Code</ENAMEX>, and generally awakening the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> nationalism.
        Caution was the watchword among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> restored to
        their lands after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon‚</ENAMEX>Äôs defeat. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX> seized the occasion to add
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veneto</ENAMEX> to its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lombardy</ENAMEX> territories. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1823</TIMEX> conclave of zelanti
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zealot</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cardinals</ENAMEX> elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch-</ENAMEX>conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo XII</ENAMEX> to help the papacy
        recover from its Napoleonic shock. On the lookout for any contagiously
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progressive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austrians</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bourbon King Ferdinand</ENAMEX> of
        Naples crush an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1821</TIMEX> revolt for constitutional monarchy and foiled a
        similar uprising in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX>. The danger became clear in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1831</TIMEX> when
        insurrection spread through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bologna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Modena</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parma</ENAMEX> to the Papal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> of central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austrians</ENAMEX> defeated a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX> government
        of ‚Äúunited <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">provinces</ENAMEX>,‚Äù weakened by regional rivalries and
        conflicting personal ambitions.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Risorgimento</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúresurrection‚Äù</ENAMEX> of national identity,
        took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">conflicting paths</ENAMEX>. Genoese-born <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giuseppe Mazzini‚</ENAMEX>Äôs Giovine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young Italy</ENAMEX>) movement sought national unity by popular-based
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">insurrection</ENAMEX>. He opposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piedmontese</ENAMEX> patricians and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Moderates party</ENAMEX>, seeking reform through a pri¬≠vilege-conscious
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confederation</ENAMEX> of Italian princes blessed by the papacy‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwith <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX>
        providing the military muscle. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Moderates</ENAMEX> feared a new proletarian
        militancy among factory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. Landowners bringing in cheap migrant
        day-labor faced mounting peasant resentment. Food riots broke out in
        Lombardy, revolts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX>, and southern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> demanded a share of
        common land.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Composer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuseppe Verdi</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Risorgimento‚</ENAMEX>Äôs towering
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. His operas‚Äô romantic humanism inspired fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriots</ENAMEX>, who saw
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabucco Freedom Chorus</ENAMEX> a positive call to action.
        Outright rebellion erupted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 March 1848</TIMEX>, a
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> of revolution all over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emissaries</ENAMEX> flew by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX> to
        nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reinforcements</ENAMEX> that freed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> from the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,000</NUMEX>-strong <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garrison</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venetians</ENAMEX> restored their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>,
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Piedmontese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> joined up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX>, the Papal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX>, and a new democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Republic</ENAMEX> was proclaimed.
        But the hesitant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlo Alberto</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austrians</ENAMEX> time to
        recover and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> gains toppled like dominoes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX> unity was
        again sabotaged by provincial rivalries.
        Conceding the need for more reform, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vittorio Emanuele II</ENAMEX>, became a constitutional monarch with a
        moderate-dominated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>, Count Camillo
        Cavour, a hard-nosed political realist, won over moderate left-wing
        support for a program of free-trade capitalism and large-scale public
        works construction. Among the political exiles flocking to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> was
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> of the earlier revolts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giuseppe Garibaldi</ENAMEX>.
        With their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magenta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solferino</ENAMEX> to secure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lombardy</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1859</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year later</TIMEX>, Cavour
        negotiated the handover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emilia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX>. But it was the adventure
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Garibaldi‚Äôs Red Shirts</ENAMEX> that imposed the unification of the peninsula
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860</TIMEX>. With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> steamers, antiquated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">artillery</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">94,000 lire</NUMEX> in
        funds, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garibaldi</ENAMEX> set sail from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Genoa</ENAMEX> with his ‚ÄúExpedition of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thousand</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äù The heroic Red Shirts seized Bourbon Sicily</ENAMEX> and crossed to
        the mainland. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teano</ENAMEX>, outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX>, they met up with Vittorio
        Emanuele, who was proclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">King of Italy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX> unity was
        completed with the annexation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veneto</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1866</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, the new
        capital, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1871</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Era</ENAMEX>
        Despite its extraordinarily fragmented history, unified
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> took its place among modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> as an unexceptional
        centralized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, careful to protect the interests of its industrial
        and financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> and granting reforms to the working classes
        only under the pressure of their united action.
        From working as migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> and farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> brought back expert knowledge of union
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> and strikes. But in keeping with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italians‚</ENAMEX>Äô traditional
        local attachments, their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> were camere <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">del lavoro</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">regionally</ENAMEX> based <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX> of labor linking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commune</ENAMEX> rather than their individual trade.
        Both the politically left and the right wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> to
        join the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> for colonies‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇtheir eyes fixed on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ethiopia</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> supported expansion for reasons of national
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prestige</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socialists</ENAMEX> talked of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Italy‚Äôs ‚Äúcivilizing mission‚Äù</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>, seeking to divert the flow of emigrants (heading
        increasingly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Americas</ENAMEX>) to experimental collectiv e land
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> in new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tripoli</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrenaica</ENAMEX>.
        At <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, in addition to traditional textiles, industry was
        expanding fast in metallurgy, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>, and machinery. The national
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love</ENAMEX> affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> had begun‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇfrom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> produced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900 and 70</TIMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1907</TIMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9,200</NUMEX> rolling out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX>, most of
        them from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiat</ENAMEX>, which was founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1899</TIMEX>.
        With wily <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giovanni Giolitti</ENAMEX> manoeuvering the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of capital and labor, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its 20th century</TIMEX> in a blithe
        state of calm and prosperity known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italietta</ENAMEX>. Vacations were spent
        by the sea or in the mountains; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> listened to soothing operas like
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Puccini‚Äôs La Boh√®me</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Madame Butterfly</ENAMEX>; the first silent-movies of
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Days of Pompeii and Quo Vadis</ENAMEX> were made; one could partake in
        intellectual conversations in open air caf√©s at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hour</TIMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">passeggiata</ENAMEX>.
        They were less amusing when hailing <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX> as the
        ‚Äúworld‚Äôs hygiene. ‚Äù Previously committed to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triple Alliance</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> remained neutral in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX>. The following
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, acting with what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Salandra</ENAMEX> acknowledged to
        be ‚Äúsacro egoismo,<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">‚Äù Italy</ENAMEX> signed a secret treaty to enter the war on
        the side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> in exchange for the post-war
        annexation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX>-held <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trento</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Tyrol</ENAMEX> (now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alto Adige</ENAMEX>), and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trieste</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were at first cool to the war, despite the
        jingoism of flashy aristocratic aesthete and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriele D‚</ENAMEX>ÄôAnnunzio
        and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, an ex-socialist newspaperman named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benito Mussolini</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> was the least well prepared of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">combatants</ENAMEX>, lacking
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">artillery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine guns</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>, and properly trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, but the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infantry</ENAMEX> showed remarkable courage in the trenches. After the disaster
        at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caporetto</ENAMEX>, the planned Austro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX> advance across the Veneto
        plain was held until the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> counterattack of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">October‚</ENAMEX>ÄìNovember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1918</TIMEX>
        permitted a triumphant entry into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trento</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trieste</ENAMEX>.
        For most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX>, particularly the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">petit</ENAMEX> bourgeois, war in uniform was their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> real experience of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> nationality. Enthusiastic war-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D‚ÄôAnnunzio</ENAMEX>, who
        captured the popular imagination by flying over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX> to drop
        propaganda leaflets, were acclaimed as patriots, while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">pacifist republicans</ENAMEX> were dismissed as defeatists. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>, which
        was denied knowledge of the secret war treaty until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX>
        Conference of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX>, was exposed as impotent.
        The political left was in disarray. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialists</ENAMEX> won the
        elections but split over support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Russian Revolution</ENAMEX>, leading to
        the formation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1921</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>. In an atmosphere
        of economic crisis‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇstagnant productivity, bank closures, and rising
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unemployment‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇconservatives</ENAMEX> wanted somebody tougher, more dynamic than
        eternally compromising old-style <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. As the black-shirted
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fasci Italiani di Combattimento</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> combat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>) beat up Slavs
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trieste</ENAMEX> and union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bologna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX> filled the bill.
        Threatened by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Fascists‚Äô March on Rome</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vittorio</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuele III</ENAMEX> invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">il Duce</ENAMEX>, to form a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
        The now all-too-familiar process of totalitarianism set in:
        Opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> were assassinated; their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, and
        free press all abolished. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> was upset when the fascist youth
        movement dissolved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Boy Scouts</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Lateran Treaty</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>
        had created a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> state and perpetuated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catholicism</ENAMEX> as
        Italy‚Äôs national religion with guaranteed religious education in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> fascism remained more of a style than a coherent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ideology</ENAMEX>, typified by the raised-arm salute replacing the ‚Äúweakling‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">handshake</ENAMEX>, bombastic architecture, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mussolini‚</ENAMEX>Äôs arrogant harangues
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Palazzo Venezia‚Äôs ‚Äúheroic balcony‚Äù</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duce‚</ENAMEX>Äôs motto
        of ‚ÄúBetter to live <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX> than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100 years</TIMEX> as a sheep‚Äù
        contrasted with the one he gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúBelieve</ENAMEX>, obey, fight. ‚Äù
        Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions nor sheep</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> survived with lip-service and
        good humor, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communists</ENAMEX> re-allied with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">socialists</ENAMEX> in the
        anti-fascist underground, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partisans</ENAMEX> linked up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allies</ENAMEX>
        during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX> diverted attention from the worsening
        economic climate at home with an invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ethiopia</ENAMEX> and proclamation
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitler‚Äôs Luftwaffe</ENAMEX> on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Franco‚</ENAMEX>Äôs side in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Spanish Civil War</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">socialists</ENAMEX> fought on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> side). Following the
        Germans‚Äô lead in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>, racist legislation was introduced against the
        country‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> and, after
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">France‚Äôs</ENAMEX> collapse in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1940</TIMEX>, plunged with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.
        Its poorly equipped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> were defeated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">desert</ENAMEX> and by the mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">snows</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Allies</ENAMEX> landed in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sicily</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1943</TIMEX>, and liberated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year later</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX>,
        toppled soon after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> landings and reinstated briefly as a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> puppet in the north, was caught fleeing in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> uniform to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> border. He was executed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1945</TIMEX>.
        The sordid hardships of post-war <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Italy‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇunemployment</ENAMEX>, the
        black market, and prostitution‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇhave been made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graphically</ENAMEX> familiar
        through the brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neo-realist cinema</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rossellini</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Sica</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fellini</ENAMEX>. Today, the remarkable economic recovery has silenced the old
        condescension about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italy‚</ENAMEX>Äôs technological and managerial talents. In
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> has more than held its own in heavy industry,
        agribusiness, and the new electronics industry. A specifically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ingredient</ENAMEX> has come from highly productive <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">clandestine‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> as a
        result, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">untaxable‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇmanufacturing</ENAMEX> and other activities parallel to the
        open market.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> didn‚Äôt take easily to national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. They
        had existed through most of their history without it and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX> had
        spoiled their appetite. Now, fatigued by his excesses, they rejected
        the militant left for a little dolce vita with the less adventurous but
        less disturbing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian Democrats</ENAMEX>. Their perpetually changing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coalitions</ENAMEX> hardly constituted real national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, but the people
        seemed to function quite well regardless. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, a pragmatic
        few years of unusual stability. Corruption and tax-evasion continued,
        but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> clamped down on the political terrorism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Brigades</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">neo-Fascists</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age-old</TIMEX> criminality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>.
        Sadly enough, as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> put on its best face for the
        nationwide celebration of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jubilee 2000</TIMEX>, a series of corruption scandals
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tangenti</NUMEX>) revealed the dirty and deep-rooted hold of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and
        business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoons</ENAMEX> alike that began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early to mid 1990s</TIMEX>. Much of
        the dust is only now settling, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> get on with their daily
        lives. They‚Äôre administering the changes of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new century</TIMEX> while
        continuing to preserve their unparalleled past, much of which got a
        long overdue dusting off. Billions of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">lire</NUMEX> were spent on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> alone for
        the record-breaking numbers of pilgrims and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> who flocked to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, one of the world‚Äôs greatest tourist destinations during the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 2000</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HISTORICAL LANDMARKS</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Ä¢Early Settlements</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢9th</ENAMEX> circa b.c.First signs of pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> Etruscans
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢8th</ENAMEX> circa b.c.<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> colonize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sicily</ENAMEX> and other southern
        regions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢Roman</ENAMEX> Era
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Ä¢753 b.c.Rome</ENAMEX> founded
        ‚Ä<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">¢510Establishment</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Republic</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢264‚</ENAMEX>Äì241Rome defeats <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carthage</ENAMEX> (now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tunisia</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Punic</ENAMEX>
        War
        ‚Ä¢44Julius <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> for life, assassinated on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢27Nephew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius Caesar, Octavius</ENAMEX> (Caesar
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augustus</ENAMEX>), founds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Empire</ENAMEX> and embarks on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">200 years</TIMEX> of peace
        and prosperity
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Ä¢a.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">d.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54‚Äì68</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persecutions</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nero</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢79Vesuvius</ENAMEX> volcano buries <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pompeii</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢306‚</ENAMEX>Äì337Emperor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constantine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">converts</ENAMEX> to Christianity,
        making it state religion. Capital transferred to Byzantium
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constantinople</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢410Visigoths</ENAMEX> sack <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Ä¢476 The Fall of the Roman Empire</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark Ages</TIMEX> begin
        ‚Ä¢600s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lombards</ENAMEX> invade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> and much of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>
        founded on lagoon
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢800Pope</ENAMEX> crowns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankish King Charlemagne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢827‚</ENAMEX>Äì1060Arabs invade and settle in Sicily
        ‚Ä<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">¢1000‚Äì1100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Normans conquer south; First Crusade</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢Middle Ages</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢1182‚Äì1226St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> of Assisi
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢1198‚</ENAMEX>Äì1250Frederick <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">II of Hohenstaufen‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Palermo</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢1271‚</ENAMEX>Äì1295Marco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polo</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far East</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚Ä¢1305Giotto paints Padua Chapel</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢1309‚</ENAMEX>Äì1377Papacy exiled to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avignon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢1312Dante</ENAMEX> writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inferno</ENAMEX>
        ‚Ä¢1347Cola <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">di Rienzo</ENAMEX> rules <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢1378‚</ENAMEX>Äì1381Maritime <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republics Venice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genoa</ENAMEX> fight for
        supremacy
        ‚Ä¢Renaissance
        ‚Ä¢1434Cosimo I begins <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medici</ENAMEX> rule in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX>
        ‚Ä<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">¢1442Spanish</NUMEX> rule <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sicily</ENAMEX>, the ‚ÄúTwo
        Sicilies‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢1494‚Äì1559Spanish</ENAMEX> and French fight over
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢Naples</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Ä¢1497Leonardo‚Äôs Last Supper</ENAMEX>, height of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢1498Savonarola</ENAMEX> burned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢1508‚</ENAMEX>Äì1512Michelangelo paints <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sistine Chapel</ENAMEX> ceiling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Ä¢1527Sack of Rome</ENAMEX> by imperial troops
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢Counter-Reformation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enlightenment</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢1545‚</ENAMEX>Äì1563Council of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢1633Trial of Galileo</ENAMEX>
        ‚Ä<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">¢1748Excavations</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pompeii</ENAMEX> begin
        ‚Ä¢1778La Scala theatre opens in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢1796‚</ENAMEX>Äì1814Napoleon invades north then much of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>
        ‚Ä¢Risorgimento
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢1815‚</ENAMEX>Äì1832Austrians crush insurrection; national political
        movement (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Risorgimento</ENAMEX>) begins
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢1831Mazzini</ENAMEX> founds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">la Giovine Italia</ENAMEX> to combat
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Austria</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢1848‚Äì1849Abortive</ENAMEX> countrywide revolts
        ‚Ä¢1859Franco-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Piedmontese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> takes Lombardy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢1860Garibaldi‚Äôs Expedition</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> to Sicily/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Ä¢1861Kingdom of Italy</ENAMEX> created; interim <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turin</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florence</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢1871Rome</ENAMEX> named capital of unified <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢Modern</ENAMEX> Era
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢1915Italy</ENAMEX> joins <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>
        I
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢1919Trento</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Tyrol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alto Adige</ENAMEX>), and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Ä¢Trieste</ENAMEX> acquired from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>
        ‚Ä¢1921Italian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> founded.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢1922Mussolini</ENAMEX> begins <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fascist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>,
        declaring himself <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> then Duce
        ‚Ä¢1929Lateran <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Treaty</ENAMEX> establishes separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> state
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢1936Mussolini</ENAMEX> annexes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abyssinia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ethiopia</ENAMEX>), bombs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Ä¢Republican Spain</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Ä¢1940Italy</ENAMEX> joins <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢1943‚</ENAMEX>Äì1944Allies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sicily</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX>
        arrested
        ‚Ä<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">¢1945Execution</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>
        ‚Ä<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">¢1946Abdication</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Emanuel III</ENAMEX>; proclamation of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
