
  
  
    
      
        A Brief History
        Early History
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Humans</ENAMEX> have been active in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> for at least
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8,000 years</TIMEX>. The once densely forested fells and valleys were a safe
        and bountiful territory for prehistoric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter-gatherers</ENAMEX>, and later,
        around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2500</TIMEX> b.c. , after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">forests</ENAMEX> had receded due to changes in
        weather patterns, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> used the clearings in the lowlands for
        small-scale farming. The mysterious stone circles that dot the
        landscape are thought to be primitive calendars that helped the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inhabitants</ENAMEX> decide when to plant and when to harvest. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castlerigg</ENAMEX> near
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keswick</ENAMEX> is the best example. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone Age</ENAMEX>, these early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>
        devised ways to make axes and other tools from the harder rocks in the
        area, and as time passed, permanent settlements began to be established
        in this sheltered backwater.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman Influence</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Romans</ENAMEX> occupied this region in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first century</TIMEX> a.d. ,
        but there is very little evidence to show that they actually conquered
        it. They built <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only a few</NUMEX> settlements and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> in this part of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, which was very near the northernmost reach of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>.
        Sturdy forts protected the mountain passes, and though the remains of a
        bathhouse at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ravenglass</ENAMEX> suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature comforts weren‚</ENAMEX>Äôt entirely
        lacking, life for the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> was fairly harsh. A trip to
        remote <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hardknott Fort</ENAMEX>, which protected the route through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eskdale</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hardknott Pass</ENAMEX>, provides a stark impression of what the invaders from
        the south were up against. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> stayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> until
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">a.d. 400</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hardknott</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mediobogdum</ENAMEX> as it was known in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>, had
        been abandoned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as the end of the second century</TIMEX>. Whether the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">northern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> made the pass difficult to defend by their constant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">raiding</ENAMEX> is still debated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>, but it is known that the local
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants weren‚Äôt</ENAMEX> willing to give the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Romans</ENAMEX> free rein over the whole
        territory. Even after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadrian‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wall</ENAMEX> was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second century</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">a.d.</ENAMEX> , marauding bands from the north figured out a way to circumvent
        this formidable line of defense by launching their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> across the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solway Firth</ENAMEX>, landing on the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cumbria</ENAMEX> south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wall</ENAMEX>, and
        attacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> from behind.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celts</ENAMEX> and Christianity
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celts</ENAMEX> arrived in the wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> withdrawal at the
        end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth century</TIMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fifth century</TIMEX> a number of Celtic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tribes</ENAMEX> came together to form the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom of Rheged</ENAMEX>, which is said to
        have stretched north over what is now the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> border and south as
        far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">River Mersey</ENAMEX>. Little is known about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>, though it
        is documented that at this time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtic</ENAMEX> monks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Kentigern</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert</ENAMEX> introduced Christianity to the region. Place names attest to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Celtic</ENAMEX> influence at every turn. It was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh Celtic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> that
        named the northern stretches of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> ‚ÄúCumbria‚Äù (the area was
        officially known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cumberland</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penrith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blencathra</ENAMEX> are
        also <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Celtic</ENAMEX> names, established during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this early</TIMEX> period of settlement.
        Later, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the seventh century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anglian Christians</ENAMEX> moved in from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> and took over much of the land; from that point up until the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century the Lakelands</ENAMEX> were ruled from neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northumbria</ENAMEX>. The
        Angles settled in the eastern lowlands, pushing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celts</ENAMEX> onto higher
        and less fertile ground and west toward the coast.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Conquests</ENAMEX>
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early tenth century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX> raiding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scandinavia</ENAMEX> began skirmishing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Celtic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> along the coast.
        Eventually, however, the warring gave way to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX> settlement and
        intermarriage with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celts</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races coexisted</ENAMEX> in the higher
        valleys, clearing tracts of land and establishing small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>. It is
        Viking vocabulary used <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to describe many of the features of the
        landscape: fell (highland plateau), tarn (small lake), and force
        (waterfall) are all words from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX> languages. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> also
        left a legacy in unusual place names, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ullswater</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patterdale</ENAMEX>.
        Large stone crosses at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gosforth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irton</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the few physical
        remnants of their presence here.
        The defeat of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1066</TIMEX> enabled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> forces of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> to assume royal power. Life
        changed fundamentally: vast tracts of land were given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> lords
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX> religious orders. The monasteries and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">priories‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇincluding the very powerful abbey at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furness‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇassumed</ENAMEX> total
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> over all activities, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> became serfs to these
        new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX>. This new form of economic management changed the
        landscape of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> once and for all. Climate changes had
        already had the effect of reducing the amount of forest land; the monks
        accelerated this process by clearing many more acres in order to make
        room for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ever-growing herds</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>. This growth in animal husbandry
        led to the extinction of many of the non-domesticated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> that had
        roamed the countryside; numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, including the wild boar, died
        out by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of the 13th century</TIMEX>.
        Although remote from larger urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeland</ENAMEX>
        area did not escape the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Death</ENAMEX>, suffering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> outbreaks in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-14th century</TIMEX>. At the same time, marauding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clans</ENAMEX> began to
        attack the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX>. The border between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> was disputed,
        and the area was a constant battleground. <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> defeat at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bannockburn</ENAMEX>
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1314</TIMEX> heightened the tension. Kendal became a frontier <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>, and
        pele <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">towers‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsquare</ENAMEX> defensive structures, from the word pel, meaning
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stake‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwere</ENAMEX> attached to the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX> were to provide
        additional protection. You can still see these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muncaster</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalemain</ENAMEX>. The defeat of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flodden</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1513</TIMEX> finally
        turned the tables, and the pressure on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX> decreased.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tudor Upheaval and the Statesmen</ENAMEX>
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the 16th century</TIMEX>, the whole of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
        underwent a period of great turmoil. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1536</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry VIII</ENAMEX> broke away
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic Church</ENAMEX> and declared himself head of a new
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> faith, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of England</ENAMEX>. The great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">abbeys</ENAMEX> and
        priories, which had been the backbone of the economy, were destroyed by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>; social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> was replaced with terror and
        confusion.
        The monetary wealth and vast tracts of land owned by the
        monasteries were redistributed according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry‚Äôs</ENAMEX> favor. Many of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who benefited were absentee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX> who needed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to manage
        the land for them. This resulted in the emergence of a new class of
        so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äústatesmen‚Äù</ENAMEX> or yeomen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>, who came to comprise a new
        middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. These permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> paid rent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landowner</ENAMEX> and
        made all the important decisions about the use of the land. As a class
        they came to even greater power and wealth by organizing trade and
        controlling the flow of goods in the area. Many were eventually able to
        buy the land they had been farming, and over time grand manors came to
        replace the more humble farmhouses earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of yeomen had
        occupied. It was these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statesmen</ENAMEX> who created a relatively secure
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">micro</ENAMEX>-economy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX> region, an economy based on agriculture and
        small-scale industry such as the production of textiles, bobbins, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">charcoal</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Industrial Revolution</ENAMEX>
        The yeoman, or statesman, economy thrived for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 300</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, but with the rise in automation brought by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial</ENAMEX>
        Revolution in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 18th century</TIMEX>, the demand for hand-crafted goods
        such as cloth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plummeted‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇmachine-</ENAMEX>produced goods were more plentiful
        and considerably less expensive. And in another shift in the economy,
        it was found that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX> could be raised more cost-effectively on lowland
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">farms‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇin</ENAMEX> part because of the richer, more nutritious grazing land
        available <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">there‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> as a result <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> became less
        profitable. New <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> brought competition from outside the area, which
        broke the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statesmen</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lakes</ENAMEX>
        region began to decline as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> left to find a better life in the new
        industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manchester</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liverpool</ENAMEX>. Only Keswick
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thrived</ENAMEX>, primarily because of the pencil industry, for which it was
        world-famous.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Writers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Victorian Tourist Invasion</ENAMEX>
        At the same time that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Industrial Revolution</ENAMEX> was
        wreaking havoc, however, a small but influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poets</ENAMEX> settled in the area and began to write about its natural beauties
        and its lifestyle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Wordsworth</ENAMEX>, the most famous of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>,
        was a local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cockermouth</ENAMEX>. He encouraged many in his
        literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">circle</ENAMEX> to experience the beauty and peace of his native
        landscape, and as result of his efforts, its fame began to spread.
        The improvements in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and means of transportation that
        had in part been responsible for the decline of the yeoman economy now
        made it possible for more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to view the natural beauty of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes region</ENAMEX>. Many of the high packhorse routes had ceased to be used
        for the transportation of goods, but these old ‚Äúrights of way‚Äù for foot
        and bridle traffic were now transformed into an extensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of
        marked and mapped routes ideal for recreational <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">walkers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hikers</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preservation and Conservation</ENAMEX>
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1857</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Western Railway Company</ENAMEX> built a main line
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, skirting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX> on its way north. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Some years later</TIMEX> it
        submitted plans to expand the line into the heart of the region in
        order to link the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windermere, Ambleside, Grasmere</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keswick</ENAMEX>. This appalled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wordsworth</ENAMEX>, who said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> District
        should be viewed as ‚Äúa sort of national property, in which every man
        has a right and interest who has an eye to perceive and a heart to
        enjoy. ‚Äù After much debate, a line that terminated at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windermere</ENAMEX> and
        spared the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> was completed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windermere</ENAMEX> and
        nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowness</ENAMEX> became major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">resort towns</ENAMEX>. Then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1879</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchester</ENAMEX>
        Corporation obtained permission to create a reservoir at the site of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Thirlmere lake</ENAMEX>. Outraged at the threatened loss of a beautiful
        natural valley, a group of concerned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> formed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Defense Association</ENAMEX> to protect the lakes environment from
        further destruction and to oppose commercial exploitation. This
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> was the precursor to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Trust</ENAMEX>, which was founded
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1895</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúhold places of national interest and natural beauty for the
        benefit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù It didn‚Äôt win every battle, but assisted by
        high-profile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatrix Potter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Trust</ENAMEX> slowly
        came to exert more influence. It now owns a number of important areas
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many hundreds</NUMEX> of historic sites all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>. As
        the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> continued to decline, the number of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> continued to grow; it seemed that tourism could at least
        breath some life back into the region.
        The Pressure of Popularity
        Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Trust</ENAMEX> was founded, the area has
        benefited from increasing protection. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forestry Commission</ENAMEX>, set up
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX>, is responsible for areas like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizedale Forest</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District National Park</ENAMEX> was created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX> to preserve the entire
        landscape and allow public access to areas of natural beauty.
        Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX>, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> has continued to grow, as
        has the volume of motor traffic. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> encourages and
        welcomes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, its popularity can damage the landscape and tax
        local transportation services.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> a total reorganization of local government
        throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK</ENAMEX> did away with the old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cumberland</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westmoreland</ENAMEX> and created the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cumbria</ENAMEX>. Today, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Park Authority</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Trust</ENAMEX> work with the Cumbria
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Council</ENAMEX> and professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Tourism</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservation Partnership</ENAMEX> to formulate sensible plans for the
        future. Traffic and transportation policies are coordinated to
        alleviate bottlenecks, and footpath preservation allows continued
        access to the fells and remote valleys. All of these efforts are aimed
        at balancing the needs of the land, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>,
        ensuring that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> remains a beautiful, natural place with
        many secrets to be discovered.
      
    
  
