
  
  
    
      
        A Brief History
        Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the centuries</TIMEX>, the living here has always been easy
        enough to attract a steady stream of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bountiful</ENAMEX> food sources
        might have made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> an inviting place for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java Man‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇin 230,000 b.c. But thus far, the country‚Äôs earliest traces
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homo sapiens</ENAMEX>, found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Niah Caves</ENAMEX> of northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarawak</ENAMEX>, are
        fragments of a skull dating to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> b.c.
        On the peninsula, the oldest human-related relics (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">b.c.</ENAMEX> ) are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone Age</ENAMEX> tools of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negritos</ENAMEX>. These small, dark
        Melanesians are related in type to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> aborigines and are
        confined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">forests</ENAMEX> of the northern highlands.
        By <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,000 b.c.</NUMEX> , these timid, gentle <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">nomads</ENAMEX> hunting with bow
        and arrow were driven back from the coasts by waves of sturdy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> arriving in outrigger canoes equipped with sails. Mongolians
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polynesian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> islands settled along the rivers of the peninsula
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northern Borneo</ENAMEX>. They practiced a slash-and-burn agriculture of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yams</ENAMEX> and millet, a technique that exhausted the soil and imposed a
        semi-nomadic existence from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> jungle clearing to another. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX>
        lived in wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">longhouses</ENAMEX> like those still to be seen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> among the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarawak</ENAMEX>. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> was added on to the communal
        dwelling each time a marriage created a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Other tough
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">migrants</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Seas</ENAMEX> settled along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">coasts‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsailors</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fishermen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> (for the most part <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pirates)‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇknown</ENAMEX> euphemistically
        as orang laut (sea <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Influence</ENAMEX>
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early centuries</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> era, the peninsula‚Äôs
        advantageous position made it an ideal way-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> for trade with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengal</ENAMEX> and southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, and attracted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianized colonies</ENAMEX> from the
        Mekong valley of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indochina</ENAMEX>. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> introduced <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">culture, Brahmin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> to govern, and an elaborate court
        ritual.
        What is now the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kedah</ENAMEX> benefited from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plow</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> farming practices. An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> described
        the prosperous <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bujang Valley</ENAMEX> settlement as ‚Äúthe seat of all felicities.
        ‚Äù From its golden era, a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Candi</ENAMEX> Bukit
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Batu Pahat</ENAMEX>, has been restored on the southern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slopes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Jerai</ENAMEX>. On
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">east</ENAMEX> coast in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Terengganu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelantan</ENAMEX>, the weaving and metalwork
        still practiced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> trace their origins to this early colonization.
        So do the region‚Äôs wayang kulit shadow plays inspired by the dramas of
        the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">epics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramayana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mahabharata</ENAMEX>.
        Srivijaya, most powerful of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianized colonies</ENAMEX> and a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> learning, built a maritime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> from its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> on
        the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumatra</ENAMEX>. With the orang laut <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, Srivijaya
        controlled the Straits of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX> (known in colonial times as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malacca</ENAMEX>),
        a key link between the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indian Ocean</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China Sea</ENAMEX>. Its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonies</ENAMEX> on the peninsula‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">west</ENAMEX> coast brought with them the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>
        language (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malayu</ENAMEX> was the name of a state on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumatra</ENAMEX>).
        As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Srivijaya</ENAMEX> declined in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 14th century</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">peninsula</ENAMEX> was carved up among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, and the Javanese
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Majapahit</ENAMEX>. Around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1400</TIMEX>, fighting over the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island of Singapore</ENAMEX> drove the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Srivijaya</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parameswara</ENAMEX> to seek
        refuge up the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">peninsula</ENAMEX> coast with his orang laut <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirate friends</ENAMEX> in
        their small fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Glory</ENAMEX> of Melaka
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX>, if you were not a pirate or a mosquito,
        Melaka was not much of a place to live. The land was infertile, just a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">swampy</ENAMEX> plain, the river small and sluggish. But it had a sheltered
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">harbor</ENAMEX>, protected from the monsoons by neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumatra</ENAMEX>.
        Later, the strategic location and deep-water channel close
        to the coast brought in the bigger vessels of the trade-wind traffic
        crossing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indian Ocean</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to realize the larger commercial
        potential, as so often throughout the country‚Äôs subsequent history,
        were the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1409</TIMEX>, under a new directive from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chu Ti</ENAMEX> to
        pursue trade in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Seas</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indian Ocean</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> fleet of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> headed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Admiral Cheng Ho</ENAMEX> called in at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX>. They made
        Parameswara an offer he could not refuse: <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port facilities</ENAMEX> and an annual
        financial tribute in exchange for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> protection against the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marauding Thais</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1411</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parameswara</ENAMEX> took the money to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>
        himself, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor gratefully</ENAMEX> made him a vassal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty years later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> withdrew again from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Seas</ENAMEX> trade. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sri Maharajah</ENAMEX>, switched his
        allegiance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> trading fraternity by marrying into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX>, wedding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sultan</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumatra</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> won its place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaya</ENAMEX> not by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">conquest‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇas</ENAMEX> had been
        the case in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Africa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Europe‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbut</ENAMEX> by trade, dynastic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliances</ENAMEX>,
        and peaceful preaching. Bengali peddlers had already brought the faith
        to the east coast. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melaka</ENAMEX> and throughout the peninsula, Islam
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thrived</ENAMEX> as a strong, male-dominated religion of individuality, offering
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dynamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and preaching brotherhood and self-reliance‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇall
        qualities ideally suited to the coastal trade. At the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sufi</ENAMEX>
        mystics synthesized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> teaching with local <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> traditions of
        animistic magic and charisma, though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> did not become the state
        religion until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muzaffar Shah</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sultan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1446‚Äì1459</ENAMEX>).
        But the key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> in the sultanate was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tun Perak</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bendahara</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>) and military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>. He expanded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        power along the west coast and down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> and the neighboring
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bintan</ENAMEX> islands. He also had orang laut <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> patrolling the seas to
        extort tribute from passing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>. After allied district <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> had
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">repelled</ENAMEX> assaults from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX>-controlled armies from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pahang, Tun</ENAMEX> Perak
        personally led a famous victory over a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Batu Pahat</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1456</TIMEX>. To smooth things over, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sultan</ENAMEX> sent a peace mission to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and, for extra coverage, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, reconfirming
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muzzafar Shah‚Äôs</ENAMEX> title as most obedient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vassal</ENAMEX>.
        By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1500</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX> had become the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, drawing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Javanese</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> away from
        the hitherto vital <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pasai</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumatra</ENAMEX>. Governed by the great
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bendahara Mutahir</ENAMEX> with more diplomacy than military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sultanate</ENAMEX> asserted its supremacy over the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> peninsula (except
        for the northernmost <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX>-held <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patani</ENAMEX> region) and across the Melaka
        Straits to the east coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumatra</ENAMEX>. Prosperity was based entirely on
        the entrepot trade: handling textiles from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX> from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, silk and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porcelain</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and pepper from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumatra</ENAMEX>,
        camphor from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Borneo</ENAMEX>, sandalwood from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> tin from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perak</ENAMEX>.
        Court life was luxurious, though <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> scholarship did
        find a place next to worldly pleasures. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> aristocracy preferred
        to leave commerce to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>, principally to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tamil</ENAMEX> and Gujarati
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians, Javanese</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portuguese Conquest</ENAMEX>
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX> fell victim to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portugal‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> crusade in the campaign to break the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>-Venetian
        domination of commerce between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> visit of a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1509</TIMEX> ended badly, as embittered Gujurati
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> poisoned the atmosphere against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years</TIMEX>
        later, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> sent their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afonso de Albuquerque</ENAMEX>,
        to seize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melaka</ENAMEX>. No match for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> invaders, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> fled
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">south</ENAMEX>, establishing a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> power in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johor</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albuquerque</ENAMEX> built a fortress, which he named A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Famosa</ENAMEX> (‚ÄúThe
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Famous‚Äù</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Paul‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> on the site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sultan‚Äôs palace</ENAMEX>. He
        ruled the non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> community with <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> kapitan headmen and the
        foreigners‚Äô shahbandar harbor-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX>. Relations were better with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> than with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>.
        The 130 years of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> control proved precarious. They
        faced repeated assault and siege from neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">malaria</ENAMEX> was a constant scourge. Unable or unwilling to court the old
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vassal Malay States</ENAMEX> or the orang laut <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> to patrol the seas, the
        new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> forfeited their predecessors‚Äô commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> in the
        Melaka Straits and, with it, command of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moluccas</ENAMEX> spice trade.
        They made little effort, despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jesuit</ENAMEX> presence in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, to convert local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> to Christianity or to expand their
        territory into the interior. They hung on for private profit. The
        original <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> intermarried with local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to form a
        large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eurasian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, served by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> and living in an
        elegant luxury that won their trading post the name ‚ÄúBabylon of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orient</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> Take Over
        Intent on capturing a piece of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> trade in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pepper</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Java</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch allied</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1633</TIMEX> to blockade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX>. The trade blockade was to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last eight years</TIMEX>,
        and ended in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-month</TIMEX> siege. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> surrendered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1641</TIMEX>,
        wracked by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> and dysentery and denied their usual reinforcements
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Goa</ENAMEX>. By then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> had become a stagnant backwater.
        Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> decided to do business
        with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johor</ENAMEX>, who controlled the southern <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the
        peninsula together with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> and the neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Riau</ENAMEX> islands. A
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> treaty gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX> of the spice trade but reserved
        Johor‚Äôs rights in tin exports from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perak, Selangor</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klang</ENAMEX>. Without
        ever retrieving the supremacy of the old Melaka sultanate, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johor</ENAMEX> had
        become the strongest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> power in the region. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johor</ENAMEX>
        provided a buffer against other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>.
        Meanwhile, fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> came in with the migration into the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern</ENAMEX> interior of hardy <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Minangkabau</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumatra</ENAMEX>, while
        tough <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bugis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX> from the east <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> Celebes (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sulawesi</ENAMEX>) roved
        the length and breadth of the peninsula. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minangkabau</ENAMEX> custom of
        freely electing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> provided the model for rulership
        elections in modern federal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">confederation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">States</ENAMEX>
        became today‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Negeri Sembilan (‚ÄúNine States‚Äù</ENAMEX>), with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seremban</ENAMEX> as its
        capital. The name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Minangkabau</ENAMEX> itself means <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly ‚</NUMEX>Äúbuffalo horns‚Äù and
        is reflected in the distinctive upward <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">curving</NUMEX> roof in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> and
        government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> built in the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Minangkabau</ENAMEX> style.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bugis</ENAMEX> were energetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> and great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>. With
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> concentrating once more on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moluccas</ENAMEX> in the 18th
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bugis</ENAMEX> took advantage of the vacuum by raiding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perak</ENAMEX> and
        Kedah, imposing their chieftains in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Selangor</ENAMEX> and becoming the power
        behind the throne in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johor</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bugis</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johor‚</ENAMEX>Äôs administration
        provided much of the spirit in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State‚</ENAMEX>Äôs independent stand in the
        19th and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20th centuries</TIMEX>.
        Throughout this period, the east coast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> enjoyed a
        relatively tranquil prosperity, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terengganu</ENAMEX> notably thriving from its
        textile industry and trading in pepper and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thais</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cambodians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, under the private auspices of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East India Company</ENAMEX> (EIC), were beginning to poke their noses into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borneo</ENAMEX>.
        And Then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 18th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> had projected
        little interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaya</ENAMEX>, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIC</ENAMEX> had made an abortive attempt
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1773</TIMEX> to use <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Borneo</ENAMEX> as a base for its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trade. That changed
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1786</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kedah</ENAMEX> granted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> representative
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Light</ENAMEX> rights to the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penang</ENAMEX> and the strip of mainland
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coast</ENAMEX> opposite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Province Wellesley</ENAMEX> (now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seberang Perai</ENAMEX>) as a
        counterweight to the pressing demands of the neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thais</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burmese</ENAMEX>. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Portuguese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> trading posts in the region,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penang</ENAMEX> was declared a duty-free zone, attracting many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>. An added lure was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Light‚</ENAMEX>Äôs decision to import large
        quantities of opium from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1801</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> was over
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>, most of them in the island <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>, which was named
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1805</TIMEX>, a dashing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas Stamford</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bingley Raffles</ENAMEX>, came out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penang</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 24</TIMEX>. His knowledge of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> customs and language, broad-ranging interests in zoology, botany,
        and cartography, as well as a humanitarian vision for the region‚Äôs
        future, made him a vital factor in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain‚</ENAMEX>Äôs expanding role in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX>.
        He served as lieutenant-governor in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Java</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumatra</ENAMEX>,
        during which time he wrote a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">History of Java</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raffles</ENAMEX> secured his
        place in history by negotiating with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johor</ENAMEX> the creation
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> trading post, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1819</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> became the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Straits Settlements‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIC</ENAMEX> called its <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> holdings
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">incorporating Penang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Melaka‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> was the linchpin of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britain‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">150-year</TIMEX> presence in the region.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Straits Settlements</ENAMEX> were formed after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Dutch</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treaty of London</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1824</TIMEX>). This colonial carve-up partitioned the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>
        world through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX> Straits. The peninsula and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumatra</ENAMEX>, after
        centuries of common language, religion, and political, cultural, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> traditions, were divided. The islands south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>,
        including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumatra</ENAMEX>, went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>. Peninsular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">northwest Borneo</ENAMEX> remained under the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, but their influence was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limited</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1826</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> law was technically in force (except for
        Muslim custom), but in practice few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> lived in the Straits, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> community affairs were run by merchant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> serving as
        unofficial kapitans.
        Apart from the few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX> in the settlements‚Äô rural
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Province Wellesley</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX> hinterland, most still
        lived inland along the middle reaches of the rivers, away from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coastal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marshlands</ENAMEX> dominated by the orang laut <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX>. Unity among
        them and the east coast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> trading with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thais</ENAMEX>,
        Indochinese, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> came from their shared <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> economy, language,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> culture, and political and social customs inherited from the
        Melaka sultanate.
        After the painful experience of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Revolution</ENAMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIC</ENAMEX> conducting business from the islands of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>
        epitomized the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> policy of insulating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> from local
        politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Province Wellesley</ENAMEX> merely acted as a mainland buffer for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penang</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX> similarly turned its back on affairs in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hinterland</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kedah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perak</ENAMEX> sought <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> help against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> sided with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thais</ENAMEX> to quell revolts‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇanything for a
        quiet life. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1870s</TIMEX>, under the Colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>, the handsome
        profits gained from exporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malayan</ENAMEX> tin through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> forced the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> to take a more active role in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> affairs.
        The lucrative tin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of</ENAMEX>
        Selangor, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sungai Ujong</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Negeri Sembilan</ENAMEX>, and of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Larut</ENAMEX> and Taiping
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perak</ENAMEX> were run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> providing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coolie</ENAMEX> labor. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> secret societies waged constant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> wars for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>, bringing production to a halt at a time when
        world demand for tin was at a peak. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1874</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Clarke</ENAMEX>
        persuaded the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selangor</ENAMEX> to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        Residents as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> affairs. In return, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
        offered protection and mediation in the conflicts.
        It began badly. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, the high-handed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Resident</ENAMEX> in
        Perak, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Birch</ENAMEX>, was assassinated after brazen efforts to impose
        direct <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> served on a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consultative State council</ENAMEX> alongside the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kapitans</ENAMEX>. Birch‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Low</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1877‚Äì1889</ENAMEX>),
        proved more diplomatic. He spoke <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>, was familiar with local custom
        and religion, and respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> alike. The reforms he
        got the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> to accept‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇorganizing revenue collection, dismantling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slavery</ENAMEX>, regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">land‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwere</ENAMEX> precisely the changes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birch</ENAMEX> had sought
        but for which his arrogant approach got him murdered.
        The peninsula‚Äôs unity was enhanced by the expanding network
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">railways</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Weld</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1880‚Äì1887</ENAMEX>) extended the
        residency system to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negeri Sembila n</ENAMEX> and the more recalcitrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pahang</ENAMEX>,
        where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wan Ahmad</ENAMEX> was forced to open the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuantan</ENAMEX> tin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> prospectors. For <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johor</ENAMEX>, astute, tough-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Bakar</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">avoided</ENAMEX> protectorate status by going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> to negotiate a straight
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alliance</ENAMEX>, getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consul</ENAMEX> rather than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Resident</ENAMEX>. In exchange, he
        agreed not to extend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johor‚Äôs</ENAMEX> rule to neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. This
        cooperative spirit guaranteed him access to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> as a market for
        Johor‚Äôs agricultural products.
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay States‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇSelangor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perak</ENAMEX>, Negeri
        Sembilan, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pahang‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwas</ENAMEX> proclaimed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1896</TIMEX> to coordinate an economic
        and administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Swettenham</ENAMEX> became first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Resident-General</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> as the
        capital.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Rajahs</ENAMEX> of Borneo
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Borneo</ENAMEX> remained relatively
        undeveloped. Balanini <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX>, fervent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, disputed the coast of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">northeastern Borneo</ENAMEX> (modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sabah</ENAMEX>) with the sultanate of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brunei</ENAMEX>.
        Sarawak‚Äôs coast and jungle interior were controlled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Iban‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇSea
        Dayak <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land Dayak</ENAMEX> slash-and-burn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>. (The Dayaks
        practiced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">head-hunting</ENAMEX>, a ritual that was believed to bring spiritual
        energy to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. ) The region was unproductive and without
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great resources</ENAMEX>, except for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sarawak river valley</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
        mined for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and antimony. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brunei chiefs</ENAMEX> traded the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metals</ENAMEX> through
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1839</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Brooke</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1803‚Äì1868</ENAMEX>) to promote trade links with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brunei</ENAMEX>. He had
        been an audacious cavalry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Burmese</ENAMEX> wars and now
        exploited the situation for his own benefit. In exchange for helping
        the regent end a revolt of uppity <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke</ENAMEX> was made Rajah
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarawak</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1841</TIMEX>, with his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuching</ENAMEX> (founded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just 11 years earlier</TIMEX>). He tried to halt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayaks‚</ENAMEX>Äô piracy and
        head-hunting while defending their more ‚Äúmorally acceptable‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">customs</ENAMEX>.
        His attempts to limit the opium trade met with resistance
        by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bau</ENAMEX>, who revolted. His counter-attack with Dayak
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">warriors</ENAMEX> drove the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bau</ENAMEX> and across the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sarawak</ENAMEX> border.
        Thereafter, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> settlement was discouraged and did not achieve the
        commercial dominance it enjoyed on the peninsula.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1863</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke</ENAMEX> retired to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, handing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarawak</ENAMEX> over to
        his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>. More reserved and remote but a better administrator
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX> than his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Brooke</ENAMEX> imposed on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> his own
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">austere</ENAMEX>, efficient style of life. He brought <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dayak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> onto his
        ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> but favored the time-honored colonial practice of
        divide-and-rule by pitting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> against another to keep the
        peace.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast Borneo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sabah</ENAMEX>) was ‚Äúrented‚Äù from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brunei</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Dent</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dent</ENAMEX> was operating a royal
        charter for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British North Borneo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Company‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇa charter similar to
        that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIC</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1888</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarawak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brunei</ENAMEX>, and what is now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sabah</ENAMEX> were at
        last grouped together as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> protectorate, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Borneo</ENAMEX>, but it
        did not gain the status of a crown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>.
        On to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twentieth Century</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> extended their control over the peninsula by
        putting together the whole panoply of colonial administration‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇcivil
        service, public works, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary force</ENAMEX>, police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, and land regulation‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwith <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> to go with it.
        At the same time, the tin industry, dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
        using labor-intensive methods in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>, passed increasingly
        into Western hands, who employed the modern technology of gravel pumps
        and mining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dredges</ENAMEX>. Petroleum had been found in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Borneo</ENAMEX>, at
        Miri, and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brunei</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Dutch Shell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> used <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>
        as its regional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">depot</ENAMEX> for its oil supplies and exports.
        But the major breakthrough for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> economy was the
        triumph of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rubber</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singapore‚</ENAMEX>Äôs new garden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Ridle</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">(‚ÄúRubber Ridley‚</ENAMEX>Äù to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúMad Ridley‚</ENAMEX>Äù to all doubting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomases</ENAMEX>)
        had developed new planting and tapping methods and painstakingly spread
        his faith in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rubber</ENAMEX> around the peninsula.
        World demand increased with the growth of the motor<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-car</ENAMEX> and
        electrical industries, and sky-rocketed during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I. By 1920</ENAMEX>,
        Malaya was producing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">world‚Äôs rubber</ENAMEX>, which had
        overtaken tin as its main source of income.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> ruling class again took a back seat. Together
        with effective control of the rubber and tin industries, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        now firmly held the reins of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The sultans were left in
        charge of local and religious affairs, content with their prestige,
        prosperity, and security.
        The census of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX> served as an alarm signal for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>
        national consciousness. Bolstered by a new influx of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> to meet
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rubber</ENAMEX> and tin booms of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>, non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX> now slightly
        outnumbered the indigenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Depression of 1929</ENAMEX>
        stepped up ethnic competition in the shrinking job market, and
        nationalism developed to safeguard <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> interests against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> rather than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> imperial authority.
        Though hampered by the peninsula‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">States</ENAMEX>
        and the Straits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Settlements</ENAMEX>, relatively conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> and community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> came together at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-Malayan
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malay Congress</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> the following
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, they were joined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarawak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brunei</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teachers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> urged the revival of the common
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> consciousness, split by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anglo-Dutch</ENAMEX> dismemberment
        of the region in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>. This spirit became a factor in the
        gathering clouds of war.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Occupation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1941‚Äì1945</ENAMEX>)
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pacific War</ENAMEX> actually began <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">70 minutes</TIMEX> before the attack
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Malaysia‚Äôs east coast</ENAMEX>, near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kota Bharu</ENAMEX>. It was
        there, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes past midnight</TIMEX> local time on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1941</TIMEX> (when
        it was still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> on the other side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Dateline</ENAMEX>
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>) that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> landed from assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX> on Sabak
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beach</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> coveted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malay‚</ENAMEX>Äôs natural resources, namely rubber,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>, and the port of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> through which they passed. A
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúGreater East Asia Co</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosperity Sphere</ENAMEX>,‚Äù as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> called it, would be
        the ultimate aim of this invasion. And as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burma</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> appealed to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> nationalism to throw off the
        Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">imperialist</ENAMEX> yoke in a movement of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solidarity‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇan ‚</ENAMEX>ÄúAsia
        for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asians‚</ENAMEX>Äù spearheaded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚Äôs Imperial Army</ENAMEX>.
        Not expecting a land attack, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonwealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> on the
        peninsula were ill-prepared. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> infantry inflicted heavy losses
        from their bunkers on the beaches but finally succumbed to the massive
        onslaught. The landings were launched from bases ceded to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Marshal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P√</ENAMEX>©tain‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indochina</ENAMEX> and backed
        up by new high-performance fighter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>.
        More <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infantry</ENAMEX> poured in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> to capture
        key <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kedah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelantan</ENAMEX>. To counter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kota Bharu</ENAMEX> landings,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> overseas fleet‚Äôs proudest battleships, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repulse</ENAMEX>, sailed north. But without air cover, they were spotted
        off the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuantan</ENAMEX> and sunk by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>
        naval <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> was left empty. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> fell on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 January 1942</TIMEX>, and
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five weeks later</TIMEX> the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> was captured. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX> Borneo
        was quickly overrun, but the oil fields of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miri</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brunei</ENAMEX> were
        pre-emptively sabotaged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>.
        If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> of war in Malaya
        was notoriously brutal, the attitude towards <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> was more
        ambivalent. At first, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> curtailed the privileges of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Malay rulers</ENAMEX> and forced them to pay homage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. But
        then, to gain their support, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> upheld their prestige,
        restored pensions, and preserved their authority at least in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">custom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> religion.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, especially those identifying with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Tse</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tung‚Äôs</ENAMEX> combat against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>, were at first massacred in the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>, but later courted as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">middlemen</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>-run business
        operations. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1943</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communists</ENAMEX> led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malayan People‚Äôs Anti-Japanese Army</ENAMEX>, aided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> to prepare an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> return. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Japanese wooed Malay Indians</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX> for a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">short-lived ‚ÄúIndian National Army‚</ENAMEX>Äù to fight the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Insurrection</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Independence</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> surrender left in place a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,000</NUMEX>-strong
        resistance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> led by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communists</ENAMEX>. Before disbanding‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand
        stashing its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> in the jungle‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> wrought revenge on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX>
        who had collaborated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>. This in turn sparked off a
        brief wave of racial violence between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, dramatizing
        the ethnic conflicts that would hamper the post-war quest for national
        independence.
        To match their long-term stake in the country‚Äôs prosperity,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> wanted political equality with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nationalists</ENAMEX> in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Malays National Organization</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UMNO</ENAMEX>)
        resented this ‚Äúforeign‚Äù intrusion imposed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> economic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>.
        To give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX> safeguards against economically dominant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> created the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation of Malaya</ENAMEX>
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>. Strong central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> under a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Commissioner</ENAMEX> left
        considerable powers in the hands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">States‚Äô Malay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown</ENAMEX>
        colony status was granted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Borneo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, the latter
        excluded from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation</ENAMEX> because of its large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, considering that they had been more loyal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> cause
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, felt betrayed. Some turned to the radical solutions of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>-led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malayan Communist Party</ENAMEX> (MCP).
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four months</TIMEX> after the creation of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation</ENAMEX>, three
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rubber planters</ENAMEX> were murdered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perak</ENAMEX>. They were the first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> in a guerrilla war launched from jungle enclaves by communist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> using the arms caches left there by the disbanded Malayan
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People‚Äôs Anti-Japanese Army</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> sent in massive troop
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reinforcements</ENAMEX>, but the killing continued, mainly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> in
        the tin and rubber industries. The violence reached a climax in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>,
        with the assassination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Commissioner Henry Gurney</ENAMEX>.
        His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Gerald Temple</ENAMEX>, stepped in to deal
        with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúEmergency</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù He intensified military action, while cutting
        the political <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> from under the communists‚Äô feet. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Templer</ENAMEX> stepped up
        self-government, increased <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> access to full citizenship and
        admitted them for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malayan Civil Service</ENAMEX>.
        Under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>-trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tunku Abdul Rahman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kedah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UMNO‚</ENAMEX>Äôs conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX> formed an alliance
        with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>-educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bourgeoisie</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malayan Chinese</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malayan Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Amid the turmoil of the
        Emergency, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> were eager for
        compromise. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alliance</ENAMEX> won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX> seats in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX> election on a
        platform promising an equitable multiracial constitution.
        Independence or merdeka (freedom) came in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>, and the
        Emergency ended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years later</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Alliance‚Äôs English</ENAMEX>-educated
        elite seemed to imagine that multiracial integration would come about
        through education and employment. With a bicameral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> under a
        constitutional monarchy (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>), the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation</ENAMEX> made
        Malay the compulsory national language and Islam the official religion.
        Primary school education might be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, but
        secondary education must be <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tunku Abdul Rahman</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, reversed his
        party‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Chinese</ENAMEX> policy by offering <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Singapore</NUMEX> a place in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation</ENAMEX>. With the defeat of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singapore‚</ENAMEX>Äôs moderate Progressive party
        by left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tunku Abdul Rahman</ENAMEX> feared the creation of an
        independent communist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> on his doorstep. As a counterweight to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, he would bring in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Borneo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sabah</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarawak</ENAMEX>, granting them special privileges for their indigenous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> and funds for the development of their backward
        economies.
        To embrace the enlarged territory, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation</ENAMEX> took on
        the new name of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1963</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> soon clashed
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> privileges that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, with its
        multiracial policies, sought to dismantle. Its effort to reorganize
        political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> on a social and economic rather than ethnic basis
        misread the temper of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>. Communal riots broke out in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tunku Abdul Rahman</ENAMEX> was forced by his party‚Äôs right wing to
        expel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> wept all the way to the
        bank, its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> and service industries making it, after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, the
        wealthiest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penang</ENAMEX> was hit by serious riots, which highlighted
        the fact that political and social harmony could not be taken for
        granted. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four days</TIMEX> of racial riots in the Federal capital in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> led
        to the suspension of the constitution and a state of emergency. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">constitution</ENAMEX> was not restored until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1971</TIMEX>. The riots proved to
        be a warning for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, with legislation passed at the time
        such as granting special rights to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX> and even restrictions on
        public gatherings.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tun Abdul Razak</ENAMEX> took over the post as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> upon
        the retirement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tunku Abdul Rahman</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdul Razak</ENAMEX> had earlier
        played a key role in combating the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> insurrection years
        earlier. Under his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, emphasis was placed on improving the
        status and position of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX> and ‚Äúother indigenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù The
        government‚Äôs aim was to broaden the distribution of wealth held by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX> to be undertaken over a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year</TIMEX> period. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> language,
        Bahasa <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, was also officially encouraged.
        Upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tun Abdul Razak‚</ENAMEX>Äôs death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>, the post of prime
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> was taken up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Datuk Hussein Onn</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UMNO</ENAMEX>. Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UMNO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> strengthened its
        position, which came as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> exports were also growing. Combined
        political and economic strength set a sound base for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Datuk Seri</ENAMEX> Dr.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahathir bin Mohamad</ENAMEX>, when he took up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1981</TIMEX>.
        Under ‚Äúthe businessmen‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>,‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahathir</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> has achieved remarkable prosperity as the economy built on the
        gains of the earlier post-war <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>.
        The profitability of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rubber</ENAMEX> has declined somewhat, but tin
        has continued as an important source of income. This has been
        supplemented by the spread of lucrative palm oil <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX>, the
        discovery of rich new reserves of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">petroleum</ENAMEX> and natural gas off the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">north</ENAMEX> coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borneo</ENAMEX> and the east coast of the peninsula, and
        development of manufacturing and tourism industries. Timber, which in
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1970s</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1980s</ENAMEX> brought valuable revenue to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> as a whole and
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sabah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarawak</ENAMEX> in particular, has been cut back to preserve and
        replenish the dwindling rainforests. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more recent years</TIMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturing</ENAMEX>, and in particular electronics, has represented a new
        direction away from dependence on commodity exports.
        While occasional ethnic tensions arise, they rarely flare
        into the kind of violence such rivalries foster elsewhere in the world.
        The main upset now has been political protests amid aspirations and
        concerns over political change.
        Into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">21st Century</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> enters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next millennium</TIMEX> a wealthy and
        increasingly economically sound and prosperous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, with the goal
        of becoming a fully developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2020</TIMEX>. Elections are due to be
        held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, and the issue of who will succeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahathir</ENAMEX> has
        already begun to come to the fore in political debate.
        Hoped-for economic revival after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economic crisis
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1990s</TIMEX> is also likely to set the stage for further progress,
        in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> well-placed for their being able to enjoy the good
        life.
      
    
  
