
  
  
    
      
        A Brief History
        The history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> reads like the story of a mythical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">kingdom</ENAMEX>. The first wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polynesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> crossed the equator and
        arrived from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marquesas</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pacific</ENAMEX> perhaps as early as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">a.d. ‚ÄÇ 400</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant voyages</ENAMEX> were breathtaking and treacherous,
        requiring the crossing of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,500‚ÄÇmiles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4,000‚ÄÇkm</NUMEX>) of open seas aboard
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dugout</ENAMEX> catamarans and outrigger canoes. Their destination was even more
        resplendent with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">forests</ENAMEX> than the paradise we see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, but hoary bats
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk seals</ENAMEX> were the only mammals in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>. The first Polynesian
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">settlers</ENAMEX> brought much of what they needed, however, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX> and taro, the root <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> that would sustain them.
        Paddies of taro are to this day a signature <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> in rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>.
        A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polynesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tahiti</ENAMEX> arrived
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries later</TIMEX>. By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">a.d. ‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1300</TIMEX> they had erased the‚ÄÇvestiges of a
        Marquesan <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">outpost</ENAMEX> and developed a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> society of their own. Rival
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chiefs</ENAMEX> ruled each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>; fish <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> and temples were laid out; and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tribal</ENAMEX> and inter-island warfare was common. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> governed their
        feudal domains by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, ritual, and taboo. The system of taboo (kapu)
        gave society its laws and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a complex moral code. To fend off
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">natural</ENAMEX> and cosmic cata¬≠stro¬≠phes, the rituals of human sacrifice came
        into play, intended to placate the more violent of the local gods, such
        as those of the volcanoes and typhoons. While such island societies
        might seem less than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edenic</ENAMEX>, the early <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawaiians</ENAMEX> led a pleasurable
        life, singing their own histories to the beat of gourds, riding the
        waves on long wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfboards</ENAMEX>, and developing an elaborate, graceful
        form of story-dance, the hula.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Captains</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX>
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Westerner</ENAMEX> to reach <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain James Cook</ENAMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> whose mission was to dis¬≠cover the mythic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Passage</ENAMEX> linking the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> oceans. He, too, had
        set out from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tahiti</ENAMEX> when he came upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islands</ENAMEX>. The year
        was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1778</TIMEX>; his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">landfall</ENAMEX> was the northerly island of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kauai</ENAMEX>; and the name
        he gave his new discovery was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sandwich Islands</ENAMEX> (after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Admiralty</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Earl</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Sandwich</ENAMEX>). The name did not stick, and had
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Cook</ENAMEX> known his fate, he would not have stuck around either. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">natives</ENAMEX> seemed friendly enough, rowing out <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">to‚ÄÇgreet Cook‚Äôs ships</ENAMEX>, which
        received much-needed provisions in exchange for fastenings and other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trinkets</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> later tied up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Big Island</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kealakekua Bay</ENAMEX>, he was hailed as the god <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lono</ENAMEX> and feasted on a grand
        scale. But returning later to regroup after being slapped by an angry
        storm, a dispute arose over stolen property. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> took a chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostage</ENAMEX>,
        and in turn he was ritualistically hacked to pieces.
        Cook‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohorts</ENAMEX> had opened fire, to no avail. Among those
        wounded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> was the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who would soon unite the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">kingdom</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in its long history. Known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kamehameha</ENAMEX> the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>, he considered the unification of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> his divine fate, one
        which he was to fulfill before he turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>. He did so with the help of
        a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">navy</ENAMEX> vessel. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cook‚</ENAMEX>Äôs voyage, a small but steady flow of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX>, already engaged in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trade,
        started to use <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> as a convenient, much-needed stopover. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warring chiefs</ENAMEX> demanded <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in exchange for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. Kamehameha, as chief
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Big Island</ENAMEX>, not only got his share of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, but finally captured
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cannon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maui</ENAMEX> fell <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oahu, Lanai</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molokai</ENAMEX>. Kauai, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> had begun his fateful voyage of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX>
        discovery, became <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kamehameha‚</ENAMEX>Äôs vassal in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1810</TIMEX>.
        As the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kamehameha</ENAMEX> established a
        new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> that preserved the old ways, including the rituals performed
        at the outdoor temples (heiau), while creating an overlay of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viceroy</ENAMEX> ruled each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        pleasure. These Western ideas, which seemed to amuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kamehameha</ENAMEX>, were
        introduced by a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, another famous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">explorer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Captain</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Vancouver</ENAMEX>, who had once served under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Cook</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>
        encouraged the arrival of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Westerners</ENAMEX>, giving land grants to some of his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite foreigner visitors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vancouver</ENAMEX> had left scores of cattle and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> on the islands to supply passing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>. To round them up, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> brought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, initiating the paniolo
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> cowboy) tradition. Another seafarer, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American John</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kendrick</ENAMEX>, launched the sandalwood trade in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1791</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> had run out
        of its own supply. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1825</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Hawaii‚Äôs sandalwood forests</ENAMEX> had been
        thoroughly cut away, too, and non-native <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flora</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fauna</ENAMEX> were imported
        to fill in, altering the landscape of paradise.
        There were other changes, too. Among the commodities
        exchanged when foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> called were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, who soon
        gained a measure of economic independence through prostitution and
        other endeavors involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>. Foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> carried new diseases
        to the islands as well. Measles, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cholera</ENAMEX>, and syphilis soon riddled the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, which was cut in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just a few decades</TIMEX>. By the time
        the first great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> died, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1819</TIMEX>, the underpinnings of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native</ENAMEX> society were disintegrating.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Missionaries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Whales</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sugarcane</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The year of 1820</TIMEX> was a pivotal one in the story of the
        King¬≠dom of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>. It was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> arrived from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. But more immediately, it was when the kapu system of taboos
        broke down completely under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kamehameha II</ENAMEX>
        (the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> king‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liholiho</ENAMEX>) and the regent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaahumanu</ENAMEX> (the
        favorite of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>). Hawaii‚Äôs royalty resisted
        replacing the old religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX> with newly-arrived Christianity
        until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaahumanu</ENAMEX> was nursed back to health and converted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiram Bingham</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madam Regent</ENAMEX> attended
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> and the mission <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> (which you can still visit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu</ENAMEX>)
        and burned images of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gods</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamehameha II</ENAMEX>
        entertained lavishly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1824</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>
        decided to travel abroad, but immediately upon disembarking in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
        he contacted measles, dying in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>.
        Many in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and among the native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> viewed
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King‚</ENAMEX>Äôs overseas death as a judgement. The regent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaahumanu</ENAMEX>, ruling
        in the name of her young charge, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kamehameha III</ENAMEX>, seized the opportunity
        and followed many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strictures</ENAMEX> favored by the Calvinist
        Congregationalists, who were modernizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> through the
        establishment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and the printing of books in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX>
        language (which they formulated in a written form for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time).
        Among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kaahumanu‚</ENAMEX>Äôs many reforms was the banning of prostitution, a
        ruling which led to pitched battles in whaling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lahaina</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> sales, gambling, and dancing were banned for a time in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calvinistic</ENAMEX> reforms were soon reversed when Kaahumanu
        died and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kamehameha III</ENAMEX> ascended to power in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1824</TIMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> resumed
        the ways of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> previous monarchs, abolishing laws against adultery
        and prostitution and taking up with his half <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>; but powerful
        interests, particularly those of the flourishing foreign business
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> (which would be increasingly dominated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX>), were intent on usurping the throne, in effect
        if not in name. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> was eventually persuaded to issue a decree
        guaranteeing religious freedom, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1840</TIMEX>, he established
        a constitutional monarchy.
        The most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hawaii‚</ENAMEX>Äôs new political
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> was an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> missionary and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerrit P. Judd</ENAMEX>, who
        served in the post from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1842 to 1854</TIMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this period</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>
        were allowed to buy large parcels of land for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first time</TIMEX> (much of
        it used for the sugarcane <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX>), and ties to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, both
        economic and political, were dramatically tightened, with talk of
        possibly annexing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> reaching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. However, many
        Hawaiians were opposed to surrendering their sovereignty. When a new
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">king</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kamehameha IV</ENAMEX>, ascended to the throne in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1854</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judd</ENAMEX> was tossed
        out. The missionary influence waned, and the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> asserted its
        power, as well as its love of luxury. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> economy was rising,
        sustained in part by whaling. But the demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whale oil</ENAMEX> would
        decline steeply after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1859</TIMEX>, with the discovery of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
        and the start of the American <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860</TIMEX>. No <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">matter‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇHawaii</ENAMEX> had
        a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> in reserve: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">refinery</ENAMEX> appeared in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1849</TIMEX> on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maui</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cane</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX>, increasingly in the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tycoons</ENAMEX>, found a ready market in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>. Duty-free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> imports from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> were eventually granted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>, in exchange for rights to a
        military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> in the future.
        The growth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> market led to waves of immigration
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1852</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azores</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1878</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1885</TIMEX>). Native
        Hawaiians were finding themselves overwhelmed and outnumbered. Disease
        had lowered the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 20%</NUMEX> of what it was when
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Cook</ENAMEX> arrived. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kamehameha</ENAMEX> line ended with the death of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kamehameha‚ÄÇV</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1872</TIMEX>, and the election <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Lunalilo</ENAMEX>, then
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kalakaua</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1874</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawaii‚</ENAMEX>Äôs constitutional monarch.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merry Monarch</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> loved their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX>, who was soon dubbed
        the ‚ÄúMerry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monarch</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1881</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kalakaua</ENAMEX> launched a world
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tour</ENAMEX>, visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, he built himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iolani</ENAMEX>, which can
        still be toured in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu</ENAMEX>. He also legalized the hula, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawaii‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        traditional dance. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">King‚Äôs</ENAMEX> nationalism upset the vested
        interests of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanford Dole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of a missionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and
        others led a successful movement to curb <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Kalakaua‚Äôs</ENAMEX> powers. When the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> died during a tour of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1891</TIMEX>, he was succeeded by
        his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liliuokalani</ENAMEX>, who proved to be an expectedly fierce
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> ways and the monarchy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and others thought it
        high time for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> coup, and they were able to persuade the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> naval
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> to assist in deposing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1893</TIMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> refused to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">annex Hawaii</ENAMEX>, and instead demanded the reinstitution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen</ENAMEX>, the
        sugar industry simply declared <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanford B. Dole</ENAMEX>
        its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. A new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McKinley</ENAMEX>, made annexation official
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1898</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> became a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US Territory</ENAMEX>; the first territorial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>. Queen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liliuokalani</ENAMEX> lived out her life near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu</ENAMEX>,
        quietly and defiantly; she composed songs, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawaii‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most
        famous, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aloha Oe</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pineapples</ENAMEX> and War
        The mythical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> was now a dream of the past.
        Political and economic power resided with non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaiians</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and other
        business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> were turning vast fields into pineapple <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX>
        and importing new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to plant and cultivate them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puerto Ricans</ENAMEX>
        began arriving in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>, followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Koreans</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Filipinos</ENAMEX> from
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1907</TIMEX> on. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> before them, many
        of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> would stay on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, adding to the ethnic and
        racial mix that has become a hallmark of the islands. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1920</TIMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> outnumbered Hawaiians <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
        Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> was still an island paradise in the eyes of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">travelers</ENAMEX>, if not in those of its original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Kilauea volcano on
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Big Island</ENAMEX> had been attracting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1860s</TIMEX>, but it
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wasn‚Äôt</ENAMEX> until after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX>, with the opening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moana Hotel</ENAMEX> in
        Waikiki, that organized tourism took hold. Steamships of the Matson
        Line soon were arriving regularly at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Aloha Tower</ENAMEX>, bearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> who had been at sea for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five long days</TIMEX>. America‚Äôs rich
        made up a goodly portion of these early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>. They arrived with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">maids</ENAMEX> and trunks, and often stayed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan American</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airways</ENAMEX> introduced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> passenger air service from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>. The
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> had increased to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 30,000</NUMEX> by the time
        <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> began.
        The war broke out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> as nowhere else in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> with
        the surprise attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1941</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> declared
        war on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America‚</ENAMEX>Äôs western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">outpost</ENAMEX> and major <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>
        military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>, was ruled by martial law. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waikiki</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> housed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>; the white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sands</ENAMEX> were strung with barbed wire; and even the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> currency in local circulation was stamped as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">HAWAII</ENAMEX> dollars,
        so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> could not spend it on the world market if the islands
        fell.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statehood and Tourism</ENAMEX>
        After the war, sugarcane and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pineapple</ENAMEX> production remained
        strong for a time, but tourism began its rise to ascendancy. Spurred on
        by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúHawaii Calls‚</ENAMEX>Äù live radio program broadcast <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waikiki</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> fell under the spell of a
        new island paradise of surf and hula aimed at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Trader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vic‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        opened garish Polynesian-themed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Godfrey</ENAMEX> brought the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ukulele</ENAMEX> to television; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burt Lancaster</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debra Kerr</ENAMEX> rolled in the wet
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sands of Oahu</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> air service brought in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vacationers</ENAMEX> by the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred thousands</NUMEX>. The surge was topped off by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawaii‚</ENAMEX>Äôs statehood, on
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 August 1959</TIMEX>, but the vision of a mythical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> frontier was still expanding. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilton</ENAMEX> built a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">resort village</ENAMEX>
        right on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waikiki Beach</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheraton</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel chains</ENAMEX> followed. Among
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> lured there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> were huge waves of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vacationers</ENAMEX>, newly rich and ready to spend big bucks in an
        East-West paradise. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> was welcoming <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 7 million</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> times its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident population</ENAMEX>, which is
        the most ethnically and racially diverse in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">same year</TIMEX>, the
        University of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manoa</ENAMEX> became the site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for</ENAMEX>
        Cultural and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Technical Interchange Between East</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> (popularly
        known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East West Center</ENAMEX>), a unique and venerated resource for
        advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Rim</ENAMEX> studies.
        More recently, the overwhelmed native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> culture
        underwent a renewal as well. The return and preservation of ancient
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">traditions</ENAMEX> was a response, in part, to the increasing demand of savvy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> for a cultural as well as a leisure experience, but a leading
        component was a growing movement by native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaiians</ENAMEX> to restore the
        rights stolen from them when the royal monarchy was overthrown. This
        movement has led to calls for self-determination and increased native
        sovereignty, even full independence as a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> for the estimated
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> ancestry. But perhaps the greatest legacy to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> who arrive at the world‚Äôs premier island beach resort
        is the warmth, friendliness, and sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> culture
        has created in the land of its rise, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX>, and renewal.
      
    
  
