
  
  
    
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> and Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> is an ever-changing combination of the earthly and
        the spiritual. It can be caf√©s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> set in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th-century</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lanes of Nahlat Shiv‚Äôa</ENAMEX>, or it can be the sky lit with an ethereal
        sunset over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX> as muezzins call from the minarets of ancient
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mosques</ENAMEX>. It is medieval bazaars, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">quartet</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> musicians
        performing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible Lands Museum</ENAMEX>, or the echo of a soprano‚Äôs voice
        inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crusader Church of St. Anne</ENAMEX>. A walk of a few blocks can take
        you into different worlds and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> has been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy City</ENAMEX> longer than any other place
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>. It is holy to not merely one religion but to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> great
        Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monotheistic</ENAMEX> faiths: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>, Christianity, and Islam. Its fate
        was changed forever <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3,000 years ago</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Covenant</ENAMEX> to rest in a tent amid the gardens beside the waters of
        Jerusalem‚Äôs ancient source of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gihon Spring</ENAMEX>. With those
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">waters</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings of Judah of the House of David</ENAMEX> were anointed for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">centuries</ENAMEX>. In those gardens, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Song of Songs</ENAMEX> was written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX>.
        On the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prophets</ENAMEX> walked and spoke; on a hill
        beside the city‚Äôs walls, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> was crucified; from a rock on the
        then-ruined <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prophet Muhammad</ENAMEX> made a miraculous ascent
        to enter <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX>. In no other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the world are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> so conscious of the portentous lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who lived here
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, historic moments can become mythic legend. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">saintly Omar Ibn el Khattab</ENAMEX>, second successor to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muhammad</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> conqueror of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 638</TIMEX>, declined an invitation from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patriarch</ENAMEX> to pray at the Holy Sepulcher for fear his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> might then want to turn the site into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>. On a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>
        day in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British General Allenby</ENAMEX> rode up to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jaffa Gate</ENAMEX> and
        dismounted from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> because he would not ride where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> walked;
        he then accepted the surrender of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> had
        fled (the flag of surrender was a bed-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sheet</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Colony</ENAMEX>
        Hotel). And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have seen the photograph of an unknown
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> fervently praying at the Western Wall <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> after
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> captured the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>.
        Being at the center of so much history allows for a
        bewildering religious and ethnic diversity in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. Bitter
        rivalries exist between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> of the major religions as well as
        among the sects within those religions. Reform and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Jews</ENAMEX> come
        to blows at the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wall</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> of different <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>
        traditions break into fist fights over the rights to millimeters of
        space inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of the Holy Sepulcher. But each tradition is a
        component of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem‚</ENAMEX>Äôs greatness. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A dozen</NUMEX> languages echo from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dome</ENAMEX> above the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of the Holy Sepulcher, and some of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopkeepers</ENAMEX> in the labyrinthine bazaars speak all of them and more.
        In few other modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> are you likely to see such a
        variety of costumes. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hasidic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> wear black hats, often trimmed with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fur</ENAMEX>, and long black or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">brocaded coats‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇgarb</ENAMEX> dating from their origins
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian Arabs</ENAMEX> might be clad in
        flowing robes and keffiyes (head scarves) or in blue jeans. Nuns are in
        their habits and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in military uniforms. In the bazaars
        you‚Äôll pass robed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Orthodox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bedouin</ENAMEX> tribeswomen in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">richly embroidered</ENAMEX> dresses. At holy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> you‚Äôll find <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ethiopian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> wrapped in delicately handwoven white robes.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> is the spiritual and governmental center of a
        bustling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> with a lively contemporary cultural scene and a
        per-capita income that ranks among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> highest in the world. Both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> have undergone enormous change in a very short
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. At the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Israel‚Äôs War</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Independence</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>, the nation‚Äôs
        population numbered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>. During the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">half-century</ENAMEX> of its existence, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has absorbed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 2.5</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, displaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Nazi Holocaust</ENAMEX>. The country‚Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first 20 years</TIMEX> were consumed with
        the struggle to house, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX>, and educate the new arrivals, despite
        austere economic conditions and the constant threat of military attack
        from neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 6 million</NUMEX>,
        of whom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 4,780,000</NUMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900,000</NUMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">130,000</NUMEX> are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christians</ENAMEX>. There are also nearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Druze</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a religious
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> that broke away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 11th century</TIMEX> and now live
        primarily in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Galilee</ENAMEX> and on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Carmel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is facing major
        decisions about the nature of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>, about the relationships
        between the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> who live here, and also about hopes for the
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">country‚Äôs</NUMEX> reconciliation with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. Nowhere
        are these issues more acute than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> are from many lands and differ
        in culture, language, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customs</ENAMEX>. Some have lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>, but most have arrived (or are descended from those who
        arrived) from every part of the world since the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zionist</ENAMEX> movement
        began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 19th century</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ashkenazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> come from central and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">eastern Europe</ENAMEX>. Among them are the mystical, ultra-observant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hasidim</ENAMEX>;
        their enclave in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mea She‚Äôarim</ENAMEX> neighborhood, is a small
        remnant of those traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lithuania</ENAMEX> that were consumed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. Ashkenazi <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>
        include <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early-20th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">idealists</ENAMEX> from eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> who founded
        Israel‚Äôs famous kibbutz movement, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who escaped from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frankfurt</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> and built fashionable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
        neighborhoods such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehavia</ENAMEX>, lined with stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> influenced by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauhaus and International</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of architecture.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sephardic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>
        community exiled from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1492</TIMEX> at the time of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inquisition</ENAMEX>.
        They established <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in lands surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> and
        elsewhere. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sephardic Jewish</ENAMEX> neighborhoods of cities
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tangier, Fez</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salonika, Istanbul</ENAMEX>, and Aleppo
        echoed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladino</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Castilian</ENAMEX> dialect (sprinkled with
        Hebrew words) spoken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">exiles</ENAMEX> wherever they settled.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mizrahi</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äúeastern‚Äù</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Asia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Africa</ENAMEX>, including black-eyed, high-cheekboned Yemenite
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> from the mountains of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdistan</ENAMEX> and the dusty plateaus of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bukhara</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> existed from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babylonian Captivity</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixth century</TIMEX> b.c. until modern times.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> are famous for their beef
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">barbecues</ENAMEX>; many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Israelis</ENAMEX> lovingly celebrate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July many decades</TIMEX> after leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. On the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">you‚Äôll</ENAMEX> notice signs in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ethiopian Amharic</ENAMEX> and
        overhear <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> spoken by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> from the
        former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>. Whatever their ancestors‚Äô cultural and ethnic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">origins</ENAMEX>, however, all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> are called
        sabras, who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> make up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
        The exotic, walled <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX> (excluding the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jewish Quarter</TIMEX>)
        is a treasure house preserving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1,300 years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> culture and
        architectural achievement, and remains the center for the many modern
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> neighborhoods of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> comprise one
        of the most educated and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cosmopolitan populations</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>,
        and within the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇin the bazaars and neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enclaves</ENAMEX> that
        surround the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> holy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sites‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇan intimate</ENAMEX> and
        very traditional urban style of life is maintained, filled with the
        courtesy and caring found in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">communities</ENAMEX> where there are no
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strangers</ENAMEX>.
        As you plunge into this fascinating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, you‚Äôll find that
        planning your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> is not easy. Each religion has a different Sabbath
        and different religious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX>. A day‚Äôs itinerary is often
        confounded, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, mosques, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> are closed for
        religious or patriotic festivals, prayers, traditions, or a summer
        afternoon‚Äôs siesta. But if some places close abruptly, others open just
        as suddenly: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> is never completely at rest.
        In the midst of this amazing amalgam of cultures is a
        passion for continuity. Before any change can take <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">place‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇeven</ENAMEX> moving
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">candlestick‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇdozens</ENAMEX> of beliefs and traditions must be consulted and
        respected. By general agreement and city ordinance, all <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> must
        be faced with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">limestone</ENAMEX>, giving the city‚Äôs different worlds
        an architectural unity and tying the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in a special way to the land
        on which it rests. Sheltered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> made of the same rocks, revering
        the same stories, sharing the same history, many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> neighbors
        who come from very different backgrounds have forged unique and
        extraordinary friendships. Their stories are the city‚Äôs ongoing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">miracles</ENAMEX> and the source of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem‚</ENAMEX>Äôs hope.
      
    
  
