
  
  
    
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
        Its famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet trains</ENAMEX> zip through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up to</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">300 km</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">186 miles</NUMEX>) per <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hour</NUMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> feature the latest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of industrial robots that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">don‚Äôt</ENAMEX> eat, don‚Äôt sleep, and never
        strike. Its high-tech consumer electronics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have placed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">affordable‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand notoriously reliable‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇelectronic products</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> around the world.
        But peel back a layer and a different picture starts to
        emerge. In many ways, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is not yet a truly modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> roots still lie deeply in its past as a feudal society of
        countless closely knit agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> dominated by a small
        political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is still trying to define its place in a world in
        which it is constantly accused of being an economic whale but a
        political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minnow‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇjust one of the pieces of the puzzle that is modern
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. Truly, any examination of political, economic, and social issues
        invariably raises more questions that it answers. One pattern that
        quickly arises is an apparently never-ending series of
        contradictions.
        Where lies the real <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>? Simply put, it is all around you.
        For <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is truly a kaleidoscope of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lifestyles</ENAMEX> and images, local
        cultures and beliefs: the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> in rural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">heartlands</ENAMEX> and the
        subway <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of teeming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zen Buddhist</ENAMEX> monks and the
        fad-obsessed teenaged fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>; the solemn temple ceremony or
        the hellish din of the pachinko parlor; exquisite temple architecture
        or all-pervasive soulless concrete apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. All represent
        different, often contradictory, facets of the greater whole that is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Japan‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇone</ENAMEX> of the world‚Äôs most intriguing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
        The meticulous planning that helped the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to rise from
        the ashes of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> to become the world‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> largest economic
        power has in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> created a prolonged slump. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so
        justifiably famous for hospitality, politeness, and respect also
        produced an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> whose brutality during its occupation of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> during the war remains a stumbling block to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúnormal‚Äù international
        relations. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> whose indigenous religion centers on nature
        worship for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> has tolerated appalling environmental
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">damage‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇcommercially</ENAMEX> exploiting its own nature reserves for timber,
        lining river <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and beds with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concrete</ENAMEX>, and filling its air, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>,
        and land with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dioxins</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX>.
        These are just some of the issues facing anyone wishing to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúunderstand‚Äù Japan‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇif</ENAMEX> such a thing is indeed possible. After all, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> themselves are constantly analyzing their own nature. In fact,
        they have devised the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nihonjinron</ENAMEX> (the ‚Äútheory of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japaneseness‚Äù</ENAMEX>), books on which sell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of copies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> and
        cover such bizarre topics as the unique chemistry of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>,
        the special configuration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> brain, and other examples of
        what supposedly sets them apart from the rest of humanity.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unquestionably</ENAMEX>, few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> will come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> truly free
        of preconceptions. There is no shortage of stereotypes: the beleaguered
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workaholic salaryman</ENAMEX>, the exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">geisha</ENAMEX>, the long-suffering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX>. Regardless of the degree of truth in these images, the
        secret of any successful and satisfying exploration of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is to cast
        aside preconceived notions and come with an open mind.
        This is certainly a challenging task, but the rewards for
        doing so are the myriad windows and doors into this fascinating country
        that will open for you. For despite its reputation for homogeneity,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is in fact a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of astonishing contrasts.
        Despite the concrete sprawl of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs postwar urban
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, you can still find tranquillity in a brilliant-green,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">moss-covered</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> garden or in the alcove of a traditional restaurant
        with its tatami-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mat flooring</ENAMEX>, shielded from the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> by shoji
        (paper screens<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">)‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇremnants</ENAMEX> of a not-so-distant past.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> themselves have no trouble wandering easily
        from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> such context to another. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Home</ENAMEX> again after a hard day at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of a consumer electronics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> who wears a
        business suit in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> sees nothing strange about buying
        cigarettes from a machine located <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">inches</NUMEX> from a sacred <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shinto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX>.
        Once home, he might change into a garish velour leisure suit or an
        elegant yukata (light <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton kimono</ENAMEX>), the traditional informal attire
        for both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.
        Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs disaffected youth, normally sporting dyed
        hair, nose-rings, and torn T-shirts (and whatever else constitutes the
        latest street fashions to be slavishly copied), will attend an
        important festival in an expensive traditional costume, perhaps
        indicating that, despite their parents‚Äô concerns about their
        superficial appearance, some old values have not been entirely
        abandoned.
        Everywhere you go, you‚Äôre likely to find this constant
        contrast <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between old</TIMEX> and young, traditional and modern, past and
        present. Oftentimes, these polar opposites come together: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ise-Shima</ENAMEX>,
        the most sacred of all sanctuaries of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shinto</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs ancient,
        nature-worshipping indigenous religion) reinforces <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs profoundly
        intimate links with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Goddess</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX>, the God of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. Although it was established <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 1,700</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, the main
        shrine you‚Äôll see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> was erected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christianity‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        massive gothic cathedrals, designed to convey a strong sense of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">permanence</ENAMEX>, this austere wooden structure is dismantled every 20 years
        and replaced by a new one. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚Äôs Shinto</ENAMEX> deities are believed to
        permeate the natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">surroundings‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇin this case, a beautiful cedar
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">forest‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe man-made shrine</ENAMEX> is just there for the fleeting present
        moment.
        This strong sense of transience and impermanence has
        doubtless arisen as a natural response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs devastating geography
        and seismology. The string of islands that make up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is in fact a
        highly volatile archipelago dotted with volcanoes and regularly
        subjected to earthquakes and typhoons. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
        built everything of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">wood‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> then waited fatalistically for them to
        burn down, collapse, or be blown away in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> catastrophe or another,
        after which they commenced another cycle of rebuilding.
        Not until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 20th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Lloyd</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>, arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> to build the earthquake-resistant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial</ENAMEX>
        Hotel was it considered possible‚<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ÄÇ‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇlet alone desirable‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇto</ENAMEX> attempt to
        defy the ravages of nature.
        Today, office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">blocks</ENAMEX> and apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are of course
        constructed with modern <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX>. However, the failure of many to
        withstand the powerful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hanshin earthquake</ENAMEX> that struck the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kobe</ENAMEX>
        area exposed the inadequacy of many construction methods and standards.
        The postwar obsession with comfort, convenience, and the latest
        electronic gadgetry has led most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> to forsake the traditional,
        simple, and elegant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of wooden walls, heavy tiled roofs,
        tatami-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mat floors</ENAMEX>, and sliding panels for a modern <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚ÄúWestern-style‚</NUMEX>Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> designed to exchange the austerity of the past for the prosperity
        of the future.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> lies on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Rim</ENAMEX> at the edge of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. It
        comprises <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> main islands, dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honshu</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hokkaido</ENAMEX> to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">north</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shikoku</ENAMEX> across the narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inland Sea</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyushu</ENAMEX> to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southwest</ENAMEX>. Together with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 3,900</NUMEX> smaller islands from northeast
        to southwest, the archipelago would stretch from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX> all the way
        down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>.
        The climate correspondingly varies from the snowy northern
        tip of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hokkaido</ENAMEX>, which offers excellent skiing, to the subtropical
        region of southern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kyushu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Okinawa</ENAMEX>, with its popular coral reefs.
        Honshu, the main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> and home to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Osaka</ENAMEX>, enjoys a
        temperate climate of unusually distinct <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX>: bitter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> and
        hot, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">humid summers</TIMEX>. Winters are milder and sunnier on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coast</ENAMEX>, permitting a welcome double crop of the all-important
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">staple‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇrice</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> advantage of living on what amounts to a long string of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">volcanoes</ENAMEX> is the proliferation of onsen, or hot springs. The profusion
        of these natural phenomena has long made ‚Äútaking the waters‚Äù an
        integral aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> culture and lifestyle. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Onsen</ENAMEX> range from
        naturally occurring outdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rockpools</ENAMEX> to large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>-style resorts
        designed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> to cast aside the stresses of the outside world as
        they soak for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> in communal hot tubs. Spending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least one night</TIMEX>
        in a traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> inn-style onsen is an experience every
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> should enjoy.
        The jagged mountain ranges and dense forests leave less
        than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-fifths of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> suitable for habitation and farming.
        Japan‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> have to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> the coastal plains and
        the narrow river valleys despite a total land area greater than
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germany‚Äôs.</ENAMEX> In terms of the ratio of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> to usable land, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is
        the most densely populated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the world.
        Does such crowding account for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs legendary tradition
        of politeness, self-discipline, and resigned acceptance? In some ways,
        this is the only way to make an intolerable situation somehow
        manageable. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> are amazed at the apparent harmony that reigns
        amid the bustle of city life, especially the absence of the levels of
        violent crime that seems endemic in much of the rest of the developed
        world.
        But as with many theories, the reality is less
        straightforward. Crime rates are rising, especially violent crimes
        involving the young. Even sexual assaults are increasing‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇalthough
        this might reflect a reduction of social stigma in what remains a
        deeply conservative society, where previously the number of reported
        incidents was severely constrained.
        Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> remains one of the safest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the
        world to live or visit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Historians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologists</ENAMEX> like to explain it
        all as a continuation of the feudal spirit of rigidly reinforced social
        hierarchies, with company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> as latter-day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoguns</ENAMEX> and middle
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> as reincarnated samurai <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX>. Whatever the validity of
        such parallels, the prevailing social harmony clearly owes much to the
        homogeneity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. From a stock of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mongolian</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX>, and perhaps also <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has had
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several thousand</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to develop a solidly unified ethnicity. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
        has never experienced the kind of large-scale immigration or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">even‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇuntil the postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1952‚</NUMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇforeign
        invasion that has made for social conflict in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
        But this does not mean <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> society has remained
        totally free of social discrimination. The country‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">670,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Koreans</ENAMEX>,
        many of them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>, regularly
        protest against their second-class status. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ainu</ENAMEX>, an ethnically
        distinct community regarded by anthropologists as the islands‚Äô original
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> and now grouped almost exclusively in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hokkaido</ENAMEX>, campaign for
        civil rights in a movement similar to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>.
        A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, not of different ethnic origin from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> mainstream but unquestionably inferior in status, are the
        burakumin (‚Äúvillage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwellers</ENAMEX>,‚Äù a euphemism for their old caste
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">name‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇmeaning ‚Äúmuch filth‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwhich</ENAMEX> was officially abolished at the end
        of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>). They are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of outcasts employed to
        perform the originally <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">taboo‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> still <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">disdained‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇtrades</ENAMEX> of
        butchery, leatherwork, garbage collection, and the handling of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX>.
        They live in separate hamlets or on city outskirts: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400,000</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 3 million</NUMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. You‚Äôre most likely
        to come across them cleaning up garbage in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and temple grounds, or
        shining shoes at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">railway stations</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kobe</ENAMEX> earthquake
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, mounds of garbage lay uncollected despite the quick resumption
        of other basic services. Why? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the worst-hit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> was
        Nada-ku, a burakumin stronghold that suffered a high casualty and death
        toll.
        For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">national spirit</ENAMEX> (called yamato
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">damashii</ENAMEX>), embodied in its best sense the honor, endurance, and loyalty
        expected of every good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>. The militarist regime of the 1930s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">blatantly</ENAMEX> manipulated the concept to prepare the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for war and
        regional domination and to convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of their innate
        superiority over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>.
        The subsequent disillusionment has diluted yamato damashii
        as an ideal in the eyes of today‚Äôs younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>. Despite the
        renowned management methods and worker efficiency that drove the
        country‚Äôs spectacular postwar recovery, many wonder whether traditional
        Japan‚Äôs collectivist values can appeal to new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> seeking
        greater individualism and a more prominent role in the running of
        family, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and society.
        The constant clash between modern and traditional values
        leads to the numerous fascinating contradictions you will encounter in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. A long history of absorbing outside influences has resulted in a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> expect to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shinto</ENAMEX> baptism, a
        pseudo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> wedding (usually held in a hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">‚Äúchapel‚Äù</ENAMEX> and
        officiated by an unordained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigner</ENAMEX> in a robe), and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX>
        funeral. As in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries past</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go on mass pilgrimages to witness
        the spring blossoming of the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cherry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> or the flaming <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">golds</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reds</ENAMEX>, and ochres of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX> maples.
        But they also don‚Äôt seem to mind when the tranquillity of a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> rock garden is shattered by recorded announcements blaring
        from loudspeakers parroting the information already contained in the
        leaflets provided at the ticket <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>; when heavy-metal pop music
        loudly emanates from the radio of the middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of a corner
        grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>; and when <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, gardens, and hallowed temples are ringed
        by garish souvenir <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> whose shelves display both the tastefully
        understated and the hideously kitsch.
        If you think fanatical following accorded <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> suggests
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> society is hopelessly Americanized, you should see what
        happens when a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-day</TIMEX> sumo wrestling tournament is held in cities
        around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The centuries-old ceremony and ritual are more than
        a match for the razzmatazz of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> import. The slow-motion
        instant replay of a pair of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">150-kg</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">330-pound</NUMEX>) sumo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champions</ENAMEX> hurling
        each other across the ring with an utchari backward-pivot throw can be
        sheer poetry in motion.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Businessmen</ENAMEX> who by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> rule their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">still‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇdespite</ENAMEX> a recession that has hit the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late-night</TIMEX> entertainment
        industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hard‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbe seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclubs</ENAMEX> being pampered by fawning
        hostesses, giggling over countless glasses of whisky or sake and
        singing karaoke versions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúI Did It My Way</ENAMEX>,‚Äù only to
        collapse in a disheveled heap on the last train <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who might
        have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their day</TIMEX> controlling precision systems to turn out <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>,
        cameras, or computer chips sit glassy-eyed and transfixed in front of a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pachinko pinball</ENAMEX> machine, doing nothing but watching <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of little
        metal balls going nowhere. Back home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> who at first seem passive
        and subservient are formidably powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and homemakers, driving
        their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to scholastic success through ‚Äúexamination hell. ‚Äù
        Over this amazing cornucopia presides <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akihito</ENAMEX>. His
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hirohito</ENAMEX>, was until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX> considered a divinity, the living
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendant</ENAMEX> of the gods that created <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> (or ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yamato</ENAMEX>, as it is
        more evocatively known). The emperor‚Äôs role today is mainly symbolic,
        not unlike that of a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European monarch</ENAMEX>. But the imperial family
        remains largely out of sight, never giving an opinion, wholly removed
        from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life of their increasingly beleaguered subjects. This is
        a far cry from the assertive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meiji</ENAMEX>, whose radical social and
        political policies in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late-19th century</TIMEX> launched <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> into the
        modern era.
        So instead of trying to understand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇforget the
        bizarre theories of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúJapaneseness‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇjust</ENAMEX> open your eyes, your ears,
        and of course your mind. Savor the delicacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX>, which, at
        its finest, is truly a feast for a ll the senses. Take in the formal
        beauties of kabuki <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zen</ENAMEX> rock gardens, and ikebana flower
        arrangements; struggle to stay awake through an entire noh performance.
        Participate in the graceful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> ceremony or watch the dazzling display
        of skill in kendo (stick fighting), with its impressively fierce battle
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cries</ENAMEX>.
        Wherever you go, you will have the chance to admire or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criticize</ENAMEX>, to confirm stereotypes or to note exceptions. This book has
        been specifically designed to guide the curious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> to the myriad
        aspects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äúreal Japan‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwhatever</ENAMEX> that might be. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where the intriguing, the exotic, and the utterly baffling are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commonplace</ENAMEX>, where little can be taken at face value. Yet few people
        are so warmly welcoming of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>. Ultimately,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> who remain open-minded and ready for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> will be
        rewarded by unexpected and unforgettable experiences available nowhere
        else on the planet.
        Welcome to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>!
      
    
  
