
  
  
    
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> and Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
        It is hard to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Las Vegas‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of mythic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">proportion‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇstarted</ENAMEX> out as little more than a dusty railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stop</ENAMEX> in
        the middle of a barren and unforgiving desert valley. It is harder
        still to understand the dramatic changes that would occur in the valley
        over the course of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX>, which created the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> known today
        as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúEntertainment Capital of the World</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        Though initially settled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid 1800s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>
        struggled as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mormon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outpost</ENAMEX> for much of its early existence. It was
        not recognized as an official <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1905</TIMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 May of that year</TIMEX>,
        railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX>
        Railroad stood at the intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fremont</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> (where
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plaza Hotel</ENAMEX> now stands) and auctioned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1200</TIMEX> lots of railroad land
        mapped from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 square</NUMEX> blocks of desert dust. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, the city‚Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> had grown to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1500</TIMEX> brave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX>, though the only visitors
        were train <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> on their way to a real <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nine decades later</TIMEX>, today‚Äôs cascade of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> is
        surrounded by the fastest growing, most rapidly changing metropolis the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American West</ENAMEX> has ever known. They stroll wide-eyed in the shadows of
        the landmarks of the world‚Äôs greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>; around them, within
        walking distance of one another, loom replicas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eiffel Tower</ENAMEX>, a
        massive pyramid of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>.
        In a testament to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Las Vegas‚</ENAMEX>Äôs relentless pursuit of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">illusion</ENAMEX>,its modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> never recognize the landmarks that
        originally offered the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> its shot at history: its natural springs,
        most of which have long since run empty. Though water flows freely
        through the city‚Äôs multitude of artificial lakes, lush resort swimming
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>, and sprinklers quenching the famous golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, it now arrives
        via a giant pipeline connected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado River</ENAMEX>. Without that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pipeline</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> would most certainly dry up and crumble back into
        the desert.
        Notable as the only major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> built in the
        twentieth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> is particularly unfettered by any burden
        of history or preservation. As <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">old‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsome</ENAMEX> would say historically
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">significant‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbuildings</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> succumb to the pressures of age,
        design, or simple decline of attendance (and therefore value), the law
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> takes over. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are completely remodeled, or, at
        the extreme, reinvented as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grand implosions</ENAMEX> accompanied by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fireworks</ENAMEX>, parties, and general street-wide celebration. Few will
        remember, or perhaps even care, thatthe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>-themed Venetian
        (complete with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>-fed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canals</ENAMEX>) is built upon the site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rat</ENAMEX>
        Pack‚Äôs most famous haunt, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sands Hotel-Casino</ENAMEX>. Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>;
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, who knows?
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, like every good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gambler</ENAMEX>, has worked hard to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reinvent</ENAMEX> and renegotiate its future. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a decade</TIMEX> of
        conversion from an insider <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mob</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to a family-friendly attraction for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> is again on the verge of its next phase‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇtop
        notch resort <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Today‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> reigns as one of the world‚Äôs most
        popular travel and vacation destinations. World class accommodations,
        five-star dining, and shopping opportunities that rival every major
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> have added immeasurably to the city‚Äôs reputation for all-night
        gambling, drinking, and adult-oriented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temptations</ENAMEX>. Hotel-casinos have
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">repositioned</ENAMEX> themselves as complete <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX>, offering full-service day
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spas</ENAMEX>, huge shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>, and attraction-filled theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇall</ENAMEX> in
        addition to the gambling, golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">showrooms</ENAMEX> of the past.
        New <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bellagio</ENAMEX>, are aimed at travelers
        attempting to recapture the glamour of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Rat Pack</ENAMEX> era, while many
        others are following the lead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesars Palace</ENAMEX>, which offers
        world-class shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. This trend toward building complete
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resorts</ENAMEX> is perhaps the best approach attempted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, since
        it offers something for everyone. Always betting on the side of growth,
        expansion, and the power of positive cash flow, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> has again
        transformed itself and emerged as much more than a water <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stop</ENAMEX> for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thirsty pioneers</ENAMEX>.
        Such rapid change and reinvention results in what many call
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> without a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>. But for its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over one million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
        million annual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, it is this very characteristic‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇnamely the
        city‚Äôs uncanny ability to sense the next big thing, or failing that, to
        create one‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthat makes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of their dreams. In fact,
        many of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> visitors choose to stay. For nearly a
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>, new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> have numbered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost four</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousand</NUMEX> per month,
        pushing the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of the valley up near <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.3 million‚ÄÇ‚</NUMEX>Äî‚ÄÇa
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 1000 percent</NUMEX> increase since that fateful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroad</ENAMEX> auction of
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1905</TIMEX>.
        Outside the resort <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corridors</ENAMEX>, new suburban residential
        developments have swallowed the surrounding desert, eagerly edging to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> of the easterly and westerly mountain ranges. Unlike the
        original <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> suburbs, new master-planned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> like
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summerlin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Valley</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> within themselves; in fact, they
        boast <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more square miles</NUMEX> and more amenities than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> itself. New
        businesses spring up almost immediately, built into the plan and ready
        to serve an already-waiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. Driving through these
        areas feels like traversing a movie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">set‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe homes</ENAMEX> sparkling and new,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roadways</ENAMEX> smooth and wide, the landscaping young and fragile.
        There are those who leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> as well. For the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
        thousand a month who come to stay, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately two thousand</NUMEX> others
        pack up their belongings and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> elsewhere, still searching for what
        brought them to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Dream</ENAMEX> is
        alive and well here, but it has little patience for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>. This is
        part of the unrelenting psyche of the place. Although the motto of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> is that everyone is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>, for the most part, it is a city
        unforgiving of failure.
        Still, despite all this rapid growth, incessant change, and
        unsettling population turnover, there certainly is a core <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, and
        there certainly are long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, many who proudly call
        themselves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX>.
        Driving in the central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few miles</NUMEX> of
        Downtown, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> passes the neighborhoods of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston Heights</ENAMEX> and the
        Huntridge, where <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plaster</ENAMEX>-walled and wood-floored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> reign, often
        still occupied by the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>. Not far from these modest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> are the city‚Äôs first upscale developments, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rancho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Circle</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Scotch 80s.</ENAMEX> Here, just a short mile or so from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fremont</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Street</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glitter Gulch</ENAMEX>, are quiet, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch-style homes</ENAMEX> spread out over parcels of
        an acre (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 1‚ÅÑ2 hectare</NUMEX>) or more, complete with swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX>,
        tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corrals</ENAMEX>, and lush, mature landscaping. These
        neighborhoods, often overlooked as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äútoo Downtown‚</ENAMEX>Äù by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX>, are
        what longer established <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> would consider treasures.
        It is here, in neighborhoods like these, that a sense of
        the need for continuity and community is emerging. In many core
        neighborhoods of all income classes, voices are being raised about the
        necessity of neighborhood preservation, about community service, and
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> offering broad-based opportunities and experiences for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
        growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">‚ÄúSin City</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> are not really new to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>; they had
        simply been overshadowed by growth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>. Today, many
        long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> are seeking to regain a sense
        of security in the rapidly changing landscape, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in which one
        could leave the doors unlocked at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years ago</TIMEX>. Through
        civic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and neighborhood preservation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, they are
        working hard toward a renewal of that sense of community lost in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hustle</ENAMEX>.
        Also beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX> and Downtown lie other signs of a
        real living and breathing metropolis. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Nevada-Las</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> boasts a student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">23,000</NUMEX> (though, like most of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commuters</ENAMEX>). Before its recent rapid
        expansion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> claimed to have more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> per capita than any
        other in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. (Apparently spiritual guidance was a
        necessity for those who dwelt among an excess of temptation. )
        And though today‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> is still dominated by the
        gambling industry, non-gaming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> has flourished here as well,
        thanks to the county‚Äôs and state‚Äôs favorable tax structure. Much of the
        non-gaming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> resides in suburban business <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and
        master-planned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, part of the city‚Äôs effort to reinvent the
        nature of urban and suburban existence by offering multiple industrial
        and retail <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> throughout the valley. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Credit</ENAMEX> card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, mail order <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, health care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiaries</ENAMEX>, and high-tech
        software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> all contribute to a healthy local economy, helping
        to diversify <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> in the face of an ever-changing national
        gambling landscape.
        Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> has recently started to show signs of
        maturity in its cultural status as well. Long dismissed as a gaudy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">playground</ENAMEX> of excess, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> has seen recent spurts of cultural
        growth. Local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> is healthy, a first-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>
        recently opened, and there are encouraging signs that a centrally
        located arts and retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district</ENAMEX> known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Gateway</ENAMEX> will soon erupt
        from its upstart beginnings into a major draw for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> alike.
        Likewise, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> remains one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> competing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. There are also dozens of
        smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> serving a variety of specific interests, including
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dueling alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weeklies</ENAMEX>.
        As <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> embarks on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new millennium</TIMEX>, one can sense
        an attempt by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to accept its disparities, to come to grips with
        the nature of its own existence and place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, and to
        thoughtfully wrestle with the challenges of its future. While it
        confronts the issues that all growing cities <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">face‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇcrime</ENAMEX>, growth,
        challenges to its industry‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇLas <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> seems to know that it has within
        its grasp the chance to rank among the world‚Äôs great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, to show
        what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">America‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 20th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">metropolis</ENAMEX> can accomplish.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Las Vegas‚Äôs</ENAMEX> transformation from a lowly watering hole to a
        gambling and prostitution stop, to a desert retreat for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heavyweights</ENAMEX>, and finally to an international <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">resort city</ENAMEX> is part of an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">eternal metamorphosis.</ENAMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> living with one eye open to the future
        prevents life here from ever being boring, and also attracts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>
        by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the millions</NUMEX> to experience the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> life, if only for a few
        glittering moments.
      
    
  
