
  
  
    
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> and Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every day</TIMEX> except <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> o‚Äôclock in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX>, a
        loud boom splits the air, shattering the calm of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> yet prompting
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> merely to glance at their wristwatches. A <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> pound gun
        set on a battery of the imposing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> above the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> has fired a
        single <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shell</ENAMEX>. The sound fades into the distance as the smoke from its
        muzzle dissipates into the clear air. This is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> which,
        since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1846</TIMEX>, has marked time in its own distinctive style and to which,
        in return, time has bequeathed a rich legacy of monuments, myths,
        martyrs, and memories that make it a magnet for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>. It sits in the east of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5-km</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3-miles</NUMEX>) south of
        the estuary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">River Forth</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">605-km</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">378-miles</NUMEX>) north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>. It was founded in an amazing
        geological area on hills created by ancient volcanic activity‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇideal
        vantage points for building strong defenses and spying an approaching
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>.
        The allure of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> is its complexity: It‚Äôs like a jewel
        with several facets. Look at it from different angles and you will
        discover something new each time.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> became the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúprincipal burgh‚Äù</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> during
        the reign of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James III</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1460¬≠‚Äì1488</ENAMEX>), and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following years</TIMEX> it
        blossomed. Complete <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that time</TIMEX> are still in place,
        replete with multi-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> (called tenements or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äúlands‚Äù</ENAMEX>),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">churches</ENAMEX>, taverns, and tollhouses. These are crisscrossed by numerous
        narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúwynds‚Äù</ENAMEX> and separated by open spaces where markets
        were held, royal decrees were heard, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> were hanged in front
        of large and enthusiastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX>.
        Take a stroll through these wynds <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, especially at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dusk</TIMEX>
        when the pale glow of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">streetlamps</ENAMEX> softens the shadows. It is
        possible to imagine the activities of the population <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> centuries
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> going about the king‚Äôs business or off to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tavern</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> playing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">noisy street</ENAMEX> games, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúfishwives‚Äù on the street
        corners selling shucked oysters from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leith</ENAMEX> (on the coast
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> miles away). Fortunately, it is less easy to conjure up the
        smells of that time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewage</ENAMEX> was thrown into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> from upstairs
        windows, accompanied by shouts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">‚ÄúGardeyloo</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> (derived from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúGuarde de</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">l‚Äôeau</ENAMEX>! ‚Äù or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúBeware of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX> ). Strolling
        would not have been as pleasant an experience as it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three hundred years later</TIMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1760s</TIMEX>, this medieval city
        spawned a sibling. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚ÄúNew Town</ENAMEX>,‚Äù which was planned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX> and embellished by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Adam</ENAMEX>, became one of the most beautiful
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> of the world. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it is still very much complete,
        rivaled only in size and grandeur by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia‚Äôs St. Petersburg</ENAMEX>. One can
        easily imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> in crinolines and bonnets walking along the
        thoroughfares, with carriages riding noisily over the cobbled
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> engendered by the creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Town</ENAMEX>
        brought about the new ‚ÄúAge of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enlightenment‚</ENAMEX>Äù for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>. Although it
        ceased to be a political <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1707</TIMEX> (when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> joined with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> to create the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> was at the forefront
        of intellectual debate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> arts were in the ascendant, with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Scott</ENAMEX> creating such works as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Roy</ENAMEX> and Ivanhoe
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Burns</ENAMEX> composing his epic poetry.
        In modern times the handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Georgian New Town</ENAMEX> and noble
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">medieval Old Town</ENAMEX> live happily side by side. Their very different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> ‚Äútwo <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> for the price of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. ‚Äù
        Edinburgh watches over many of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotland‚Äôs</ENAMEX> national
        treasures with great pride. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edinburgh Castle</ENAMEX> is a treasure in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">itself‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> also
        Scotland‚Äôs most popular attraction. Its strong walls guard not only
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jewels</ENAMEX> and royal artifacts but also the memories of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
        historic events. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> national art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> featuring the
        work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> from around the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Palace</ENAMEX>
        dating back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 15th century</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, one left
        powerless in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1707</TIMEX> and the other newly empowered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> major
        museums illustrate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edinburgh‚</ENAMEX>Äôs fascinating history, with one holding a
        collection revealing the annals of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Scotland‚Äôs</ENAMEX> past and the lives of her
        most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">illustrious sons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>.
        Yet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the delights of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is that it is not
        simply a collection of heartless historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fa√ßades</ENAMEX>. It is instead a
        living, thriving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. The tenements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Town</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Town</ENAMEX> are still in residential use, with a range of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> sustaining the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> is compact, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where you can walk to appointments or to
        your <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> entertainment. It has few tall <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. With its
        proximity to the countryside‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇonly <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> in any direction to the
        seashore or unbroken green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hills‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit</ENAMEX> comes as no surprise to learn
        that it has been confirmed as one of the most congenial places to live
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> are often accused by their fellow
        Scots of lacking passion and have been labeled ‚Äúprim and proper. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù One</ENAMEX>
        reason for this could be that they have traditionally pursued such
        conservative, respectable vocations as banking, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, law, and
        academia. But this wealth of earnest achievement doesn‚Äôt mean that the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lack verve or the ability to enjoy themselves. It is simply that
        the serious aspects of life are given their proper due before the fun
        can begin.
        Edinburgh‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are some of the most friendly and
        welcoming you could hope to meet: they are quite genuine and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unaffected</ENAMEX>. The city‚Äôs urbane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> enjoy their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theaters</ENAMEX>, and exhibitions as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> do. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
        feature internationally renowned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chefs</ENAMEX> who create dishes using some of
        the finest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>, game, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> in the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> here love to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">socialize</ENAMEX>, and they get together in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX>, each with its own
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX> hark back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>, with
        small, smoky <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and low lighting. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Town</ENAMEX>, chic wine bars
        welcome the banking and insurance set for after-office rendezvous.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> the opera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">impresario</ENAMEX> Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolf Bing</ENAMEX> undertook the
        task of organizing the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> arts festival, which aimed to
        attract major names in the fields of music, drama, and dance. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Edinburgh International Festival</ENAMEX> had grown into the largest annual
        arts event in the world, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> performances in numerous
        venues across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early September</TIMEX>. Today,
        however, the main arts festival is only part of a veritable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circus</ENAMEX> of
        summer activities that seem to turn the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> upside down.
        Regiments of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in full dress regalia march precisely
        to the sound of pipe and drum in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Military Tattoo</ENAMEX>, and connoisseurs
        of the silver screen gather for an extravaganza of offerings on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">celluloid</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Festival Fringe</ENAMEX>, perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dr. Jekyll</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Festival‚Äôs Mr. Hyde</ENAMEX>, is an umbrella title given to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
        performances ranging from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde</ENAMEX> to the downright irreverent.
        And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> at festival time, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> willingly gives its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>
        over to stilt walkers, automatons, satirists, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">barbershop</ENAMEX> quartets
        along with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500,000 visitors‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</NUMEX>ÄÇbelying its reputation for being sober
        and staid.
        Another wonderful time to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> is at the turn of
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> hosts the ‚Äúbiggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Year‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world,‚Äù</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hogmanay</ENAMEX>. The whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> comes out into the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> to watch a huge display of fireworks illuminate the historic
        skyline. Where better to sing your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX> rendition of ‚ÄúAuld <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lang</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Syne‚Äù</ENAMEX>?
        At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the start of the new millennium</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> is once again
        wielding true political power on behalf of its fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX>: The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúScotland Act</ENAMEX>,‚Äù passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1998</TIMEX>, transferred control of
        domestic policy from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1707</TIMEX>. The sense of an impending new era can be discerned in the pride,
        confidence, and energy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. It is also taking
        concrete form in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Parliament</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> at the bottom of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Mile</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm foundations</ENAMEX> in the past,
        but it also has designs on the future.
      
    
  
