
  
  
    
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">INDIA</ENAMEX> AND ITS‚ÄàPEOPLE
        This land is a constant challenge to mind and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, a
        glorious shock to the system. It is no place for the faint-hearted.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> is exhilarating, exhausting, and infuriating‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa land where,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">you‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find, the practicalities of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life overlay the mysteries
        that popular myth attaches to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. In place of the much-publicized,
        and much-misunderstood, mysticism of its ancient religions, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> in
        reality has quite another miracle to offer in the sheer profusion of
        its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> and landscapes.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> comprises a diamond-shaped subcontinent that stretches
        over <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,000 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,800 miles</NUMEX>) from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kashmir</ENAMEX> mountains in the north
        right down to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kanyakumari</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cape Comorin</ENAMEX>, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indian Ocean</ENAMEX>. From
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> to west <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> also covers <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 3,000 km</NUMEX>, from Arunachal Pradesh
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assam</ENAMEX> on the border with its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burma</ENAMEX> to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gujarat</ENAMEX> coast on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arabian Sea</ENAMEX>. Only in more recent post-colonial
        times did its natural geography exclude the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bangladesh</ENAMEX>. Even there, for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostilities</ENAMEX>, there‚Äôs an undeniable
        cultural affinity with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">India‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇfeuding</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> rather than unrelated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strangers</ENAMEX>. In fact, when you look at its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4,000 years</TIMEX> of history‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇor
        any of today‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, for that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">matter‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇits countless feuds</ENAMEX> seem
        to be a perpetual but necessary dynamic of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> civilization.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> is a massive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, with a lot of different and
        inevitably conflicting regional and sectarian interests. Rupee
        banknotes are printed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> languages: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi, Urdu</ENAMEX>,
        Sanskrit, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sindhi, Bengali, Marathi, Gujurati, Oriya, Punjabi, Assamese</ENAMEX>,
        Kashmiri, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malayalam</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kannada, Tamil</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telugu</ENAMEX>. A count
        of the languages spoken all over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, leaving out the dialects, comes
        to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,652</NUMEX>, written in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> different alphabets.
        The national language of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> is spoken by less than the
        majority, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, for which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has a permanent program
        of modernization, is spoken by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 3 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, mostly in
        the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. Everybody <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">‚Äúspeaks‚Äù cricket</ENAMEX>, though, with its
        innings, wickets, and boundaries present in every dialect.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> impressions you‚Äôll get at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mumbai</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bombay</ENAMEX>) is the diversity of ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX>. From
        blue-eyed and sometimes red-haired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kashmiris</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetans</ENAMEX>
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sikkim</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darjeeling</ENAMEX>, through all the shades of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heartland</ENAMEX>, right down to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dark-skinned</TIMEX>, often curly-haired, Dravidians
        from southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, you soon realize there‚Äôs no such thing as a
        ‚Äútypical‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>.
        India‚Äôs prehistoric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> were probably what
        anthropologists call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Proto-Australoids</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">They‚Äôve</ENAMEX> since been joined by
        Mongols, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aryans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Persians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghans</ENAMEX>, while
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> have also left their traces.
        The landscape is alternately rich and arid, lush and
        desolate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">majestic Himalayas</ENAMEX> in the north make an appropriate home
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva</ENAMEX>, one of the most-revered <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hindu gods</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kashmir</ENAMEX> is a serenely
        beautiful and coveted land of green forest, alpine meadows, and lakes,
        while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab</ENAMEX> in the northwest is the fertile center of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">country‚Äôs Green Revolution</ENAMEX>, supporting the nation‚Äôs self-sufficiency in
        wheat, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">barley</ENAMEX>, and millet. On the doorstep of this wealth, the Thar
        Desert of noble <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rajasthan</ENAMEX> heralds the vast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Deccan</ENAMEX> plateau of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">parched</TIMEX>,
        ruddy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">granite</ENAMEX> that dominates the peninsula of southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delhi</ENAMEX> stands at the western end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ganga</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ganges</ENAMEX>) river
        basin in which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> grows much of its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX>. Flanked with patches of
        forest leading up into the foothills of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayas</ENAMEX>, the flat plain
        stretches right across to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay of Bengal</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,600 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,000 miles</NUMEX>)
        away, but some areas are kept as nature reserves for the country‚Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wildlife</ENAMEX>, notably its tigers, leopards, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX>. Bengal‚Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">greenery</ENAMEX> is the threshold to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darjeeling</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assam</ENAMEX>.
        The rugged southern peninsula is hemmed in by low-lying
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mountains‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe Vindhya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satpura</ENAMEX> to the north and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Ghats</ENAMEX> running parallel to the coasts. The forested Malabar
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coast</ENAMEX> in the west is sown with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coconut</ENAMEX>, betel-nut, pepper,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rubber</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cashew nut</ENAMEX>, which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> still tempt <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> across the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arabian Sea</ENAMEX>. Some of the palm <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> in the area provide shade for beach
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resorts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Goa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerala</ENAMEX>.
        India‚Äôs landscape also features man-made architectural
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">treasures</ENAMEX>, bearing witness to the many great religions and
        civilizations which have enriched the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">country‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇmonuments</ENAMEX> now, after
        centuries of neglect, preserved by the restoration program started by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archaeological Survey of India</ENAMEX>. The sights are endless: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX>
        gopuram <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>-gates of the south, the temples of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Varanasi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benares</ENAMEX>),
        the cave monasteries of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ajanta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellora</ENAMEX>, the beautiful and erotic
        sculptures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khajuraho</ENAMEX>, the splendid marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>, fortresses, and
        mausoleums of the emperors and maharajas in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Agra</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rajasthan</ENAMEX>,
        the colonial government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX>, or the unusual style of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic-Oriental</ENAMEX> railway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mumbai</ENAMEX> (known until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bombay</ENAMEX>).
        The cities‚Äô shanty-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town districts</ENAMEX> are often directly in the
        shadow of the shining skyscrapers, built by the shanty-town <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>
        themselves. Here <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> carry bricks on their heads as gracefully as a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are also responsible for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other
        characteristic of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúarchitecture‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇcow-dung patties</ENAMEX> which are
        preserved and kept for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">artfully</ENAMEX> shaped into mounds with shapes
        that differ from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX>, some of them resembling a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX>
        stupa, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gopuram</ENAMEX>, or even a Moslem <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">minaret</ENAMEX>.
        The only constant in this huge landscape is the people
        themselves. Even in the vast open spaces of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rajasthan</ENAMEX> desert or the
        Deccan plateau of central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> appear everywhere, a tribesman
        on camel-back or lone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> holding her headdress in her teeth to keep
        out the dust as she carries a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> or a bundle of
        firewood on her head. If, as the road stretches before you empty and
        clear right up to the horizon, and you can see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> tree, it‚Äôs a
        pretty safe bet you‚Äôll find <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> sadhu (holy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>) resting in
        its shade.
        The teeming <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calcutta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mumbai</ENAMEX> have
        become legendary. They crowd each other into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roadway</ENAMEX>, bulge out of
        tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">auto</ENAMEX>-rickshaws, and perch on top of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX>; a family of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> clings onto a motor-scooter, and a whole school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> on
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullock-cart</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs hazardous; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> do topple over, rooftop
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> do occasionally get swept off the top by an
        overhanging steel rod, but they accept the risk for the free
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ride‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇrooftoppers aren‚Äôt</ENAMEX> in the habit of buying tickets.
        It‚Äôs important to remember not to apply Western values to
        everything you see here. The poverty, for instance, does not create the
        sense of shame as it does for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who live in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. In
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> poverty is borne with considerable dignity and even with a
        cheerfulness that some may find difficult to understand. The same form
        applies to jostling, which is a whole way of life in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
        Everyone makes way for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX>, sacred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cow</ENAMEX> has right of way everywhere, whether walking nonchalantly through
        the center of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, or reclining across a new expressway. After a
        while you may begin to detect something a bit uncanny in the way a cow
        seems to look around and beyond her immediate surroundings‚<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">ÄÇ‚Äî‚Äàit‚Äôs</ENAMEX> as if
        she knows that she‚Äôs sacred.
        You can‚Äôt get around it: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where religion
        is ever-present. Although the constitution of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> as
        a secular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, religion still plays a vital part in everyday
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">life‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇin</ENAMEX> its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> as well as in the architecture, sculpture, and
        painting of its great monuments. A little background information on the
        major forms of faith may help.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religions of India</ENAMEX>
        Hinduism
        If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hinduism</ENAMEX> is more or less <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">India‚</ENAMEX>Äôs national belief system,
        this may be because it offers something for everyone: mysticism and
        metaphysics for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>, ceremony for ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, austerity,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensuality</ENAMEX>, tranquillity, and frenzy.
        Building on the ancient cults and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vedic</ENAMEX> teachings of the
        Indo-Aryans dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1300</TIMEX> b.c. , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hinduism</ENAMEX> began to take its present
        form in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth century</TIMEX> a.d. , under considerable pressure for a
        more ‚Äúaccessible‚Äù religion. Popular devotional worship, with its appeal
        to the common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, replaced the sacrifices practiced exclusively by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brahmins</ENAMEX>.
        It is said there are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">330 million gods</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pantheon</ENAMEX>, but they might be seen as <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">330 million facets</NUMEX> of a single
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">divinity</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> most important manifestations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brahman</ENAMEX>, or
        godhead, are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vishnu, Brahma</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shiva</ENAMEX>, which are often presented to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Westerners</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trinity</ENAMEX>, though this is not really comparable to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> concept.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúbig three‚Äù</ENAMEX> are by no means accorded equal status.
        Vishnu, the preserver, is regarded by his worshippers as a god from
        whose navel a lotus grew bearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brahma</ENAMEX> whose task it was to create the
        world. Vishnu, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-armed god with mace, conch, discus, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lotus</ENAMEX>,
        has many incarnations, of which the most famous is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krishna</ENAMEX>, who appears
        as conquering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, flute-playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>, or mischievous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>. Vishnu‚Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wife Lakshmi</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> of good fortune.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva</ENAMEX> is the dancing destroyer-god, wearing a garland of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skulls</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX> around both neck and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>. As the god of time and
        ascetics, he decides the fate of the world. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX> and king
        of dance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva</ENAMEX> is as passionate as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vishnu</ENAMEX> is serene. Just in case you
        think you have got it all clear in your mind, remember that Vishnu
        destroys by not preserving and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva</ENAMEX> preserves through the renewal
        arising from destruction.
        Hindu ethics say that the path to salvation has three
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">principles</ENAMEX>: righteousness, prosperity honestly achieved, and, not
        least, pleasure. At the center of the confrontation with the harsh
        reality of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life is the concept of karma; that is ‚Äúwork‚Äù or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúdeed</ENAMEX>,‚Äù and the implication that the sum total of one‚Äôs acts in a
        previous life will determine one‚Äôs present <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in life. A better
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reincarnation</ENAMEX> is promised those whose deeds and actions are good in
        this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>. The ultimate goal is spiritual salvation, or moksha, a
        freeing from the cycle of rebirth.
        While this teaching has served to sustain the rigid
        hierarchy of the caste system, it is not so ‚Äúfatalistic‚Äù as some would
        have it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX> say we cannot escape our karma, but that with good
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgment</ENAMEX> and foresight we can use it to our advantage.
        By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bengali</ENAMEX> Brahman
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ram Mohan Roy</ENAMEX> tried to rid <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinduism</ENAMEX> of primitive idolatry. The
        self-immolation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widows</ENAMEX>, known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sati‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa widow</ENAMEX> becomes sati, a
        ‚Äúvirtuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>,‚Äù by climbing onto her husband‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral pyre‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇhas
        disappeared, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>-god <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanuman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>-headed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ganesh</ENAMEX> are
        still idolized, and nobody will dare to deny the sanctity of the cow
        and all her products: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>, curd, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX>, and dung, the last of which
        is used for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">More than 83 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> embraces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinduism</ENAMEX>,
        which is more a way of life than a religion; its sacred rituals and
        observances are only a small part of what good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hindus</ENAMEX> believe makes
        them good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX>. Much more than the mystical elements which fascinate
        and draw so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Westerners</ENAMEX> here, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hinduism</ENAMEX> is concerned with the basics
        of everyday life: birth, work, health, relationships, and death, all of
        this helped along by regular consultations with a local astrologer.
        Even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the intricate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> caste system can play a
        role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians‚</ENAMEX>Äô choice of job, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>, and political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>,
        despite the numerous anti-discrimination statutes passed since
        Independence. Brahmins, the priestly caste, fill many of the top posts
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>; many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> can
        trace their ancestry to the proud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kshatriya warrior caste</ENAMEX>; business is
        dominated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Vaishya caste</NUMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shudras</ENAMEX> till the land.
        The so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Untouchables</ENAMEX> have greater opportunities now to rise on
        the social scale, a few of them becoming captains of industry or
        cabinet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>, but it‚Äôs still their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brethren</ENAMEX> who sweep the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>.
        Most marriages in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> are still arranged traditionally
        with carefully negotiated dowries. While ever more matrimonial
        advertisements in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> editions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Times of India</ENAMEX> and other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> mention ‚Äúcaste no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>,‚Äù just as many specify the required
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caste</ENAMEX> or insist on a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚Äúfair-complexioned‚</NUMEX>Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> while touting a
        university diploma or an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> work permit.
        Islam
        Following a conflict in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> almost as old as Islam
        itself, a peaceful coexistence between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hinduism</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> seems hard to
        achieve. It‚Äôs hard to imagine a faith more hostile to all idolatry,
        fierce in its uncompromising monotheism, and opposed to the caste
        system as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> When sufi mystics or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akbar</ENAMEX> tried to create
        a synthesis between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> faiths, the orthodox on both sides
        resisted.
        Hindu conversions to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> faith were more often
        performed out of hope of social advancement under a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> government
        than out of conviction. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> today, as fervent as their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brethren</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, are mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of
        those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">converts</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Over 80 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> form the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest religious
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">India‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇalmost</ENAMEX> as many as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pakistan‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇmost</ENAMEX> of
        them descendants from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">converts</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughals‚</ENAMEX>Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>, who bore
        the brunt of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> retaliation for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long years</TIMEX> full of subjection and an
        often unfair identification with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> rule. Left behind by the
        exodus to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> partition, they make up the peasantry in
        the north. While they mostly keep a low profile, you may hear of
        ‚Äúcommunal incidents‚Äù in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Followers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islam</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> are divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> primary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunnis</ENAMEX> (adherents of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunna</ENAMEX> law expounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mohammed‚</ENAMEX>Äôs own
        words and deeds) and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shiites</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> of those interpretations
        proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mohammed‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every day</TIMEX>, the devout face <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mecca</ENAMEX>,
        bow their foreheads to the ground, and proclaim: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúThere is no god but
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allah</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed</ENAMEX> is His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prophet</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sikhs</ENAMEX>
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> attempt to merge the principles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hinduism</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> is that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sikhs (‚Äúdisciples‚Äù</ENAMEX>). Nanak, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>),
        was born a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1469</TIMEX> and reared on the egalitarian principles of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>. He opposed idolatry and the caste system (which was subsequently
        too strong to resist). From Islam he took the idea of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> God, but
        refused any such specific conception as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allah</ENAMEX>. He saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">God‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manifestation</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinduism</ENAMEX>, as being everywhere in the world He
        created. Nanak‚Äôs teachings were written in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adi Granth</ENAMEX>, which
        acquired for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sikhs</ENAMEX> the sanctity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koran</ENAMEX>. According to this faith,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> are forbidden.
        The militancy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sikhs</ENAMEX> came about only as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nanak‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">successors</ENAMEX> got embroiled in politics‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwith dire results for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sikhs‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇwhen their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> challenged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughals</ENAMEX>. After the execution
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guru Tegh Bahadur</ENAMEX>, his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guru Gobind Singh</ENAMEX>, exalted the faithful
        to be ever ready for armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX>. They all took the surname <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singh</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">meaning ‚ÄúLion‚Äù</ENAMEX> (all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sikhs</ENAMEX> are named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singh</ENAMEX>, but not all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Singhs</ENAMEX> are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sikhs</ENAMEX>), and wore a turban and kept the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">K‚Äôs</ENAMEX>: kesha (uncut hair and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beard</ENAMEX>), kanga (comb for their hair), kara (steel bracelet), kachha
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">soldier‚</NUMEX>Äôs shorts), and kirpan (dagger). Their distinctive appearance
        made them highly visible and so inspired an unflinching courage.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sikhs</ENAMEX> make up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 2 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. With the
        consistent militant need to defend their faith, they make up a fiercely
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">competent √©lite</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>, but they are also skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>
        at the spearhead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Revolution in the Punjab</ENAMEX>, where most of
        them live. Their rights have been the source of conflicts in the
        central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
        Buddhism
        Bu ddhism was founded over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,500 years ago</TIMEX> in reaction to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brahmanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX>, but it practically vanished as an organized
        religion from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> scene by persecution and absorption into the
        Hindu mainstream. It continues, however, to exert influence on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spiritual</ENAMEX> and artistic life to the present day.
        Buddha‚Äôs own life explains his teachings, but the truth is
        buried in both legend and historical fact. He was born Siddhartha
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gautama</ENAMEX> in a grove of sal <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lumbini</ENAMEX> (just across the Nepalese
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">border</ENAMEX>) around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 566</TIMEX> b.c. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, who was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> of the
        Sakyas, is said to have conceived him after dreaming that a magnificent
        white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX> holding a lotus flower in his trunk had entered her
        side.
        Siddhartha grew up in princely luxury, but when he was
        taken out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> to the edge of the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, he saw the poor, the
        sick, and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged</TIMEX>. Then he saw a religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beggar</ENAMEX> who seemed serene,
        and he realized the path his life must take.
        Abandoning his riches, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siddhartha</ENAMEX> went off into the
        kingdoms of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ganga valley</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> he begged for his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>,
        learned to meditate, and practiced severe self-mortification, but still
        felt no <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearer</NUMEX> to understanding life‚Äôs suffering. Then, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 35</TIMEX>,
        sitting under a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> at the place now known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bodh Gaya</ENAMEX> (south of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patna</ENAMEX>), he vowed to stay there until his goal was achieved.
        For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49 days</TIMEX> he resisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX> and temptresses, and became
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">truly Enlightened‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇBuddha</ENAMEX> as he is called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. He preached his new
        wisdom at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarnath</ENAMEX> (near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Varanasi</ENAMEX>) and with ever more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX> went out
        to spread his word. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> himself converted ruthless bandits and whole
        armies from the path of violence. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kushinagar</ENAMEX>, between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bodh Gaya</ENAMEX> and
        his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX>, he died at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 80</TIMEX> of dysentery, it is said, from eating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>.
        Preaching that suffering came from the pursuit of personal
        desire, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> had advocated <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Middle Way of the Eightfold Path:</ENAMEX>
        right views, right resolve, right speech, right conduct, right
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">livelihood</ENAMEX>, right effort, right recollection, and right meditation.
        Only thus could the enlightenment of Nirvana be achieved.
        This original doctrine, without any sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddha‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        divinity, was embraced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hinayana</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lesser Vehicle</ENAMEX>) school which
        spread to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sri Lanka</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burma</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laos</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mahayana</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Vehicle</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> added the concept of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bodhisattva</ENAMEX> as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divine savior</ENAMEX>, and was then the most dominant form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX>,
        spreading to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.
        After centuries of almost total eclipse, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buddhism</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> has
        been able to achieve a revival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, in part by offering its
        egalitarian philosophy to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu Untouchables</ENAMEX> as an escape from
        discrimination. There are now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 5 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>,
        many of them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maharashtra</ENAMEX>.
        Jainism
        As old as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism, Jainism</ENAMEX> has made its mark with its
        concept of ahimsa (non-violence) and is much more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pacifist</ENAMEX> than its
        name, which means religion of the conquerors.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vardhamana Mahavira</ENAMEX> was its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>. He was born in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">540</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">b.c.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bihar</ENAMEX> and, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>, was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>. He, too,
        abandoned riches to become an ascetic. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahavira</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Great Hero</ENAMEX>)
        pursued self-mortification to the end of his life, stripping off his
        clothes to take his word from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>. He died of
        self-inflicted starvation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 72</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Para</ENAMEX>, near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rajgir</ENAMEX>. His
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> were later to divide into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digambaras</ENAMEX> (‚Äúspace-clad,‚Äù i.e.
        , naked) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Svetambaras</ENAMEX> (‚<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Äúwhite-clad‚Äù</NUMEX>) you see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
        The religion, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mahavira</ENAMEX> is seen as the
        manifestation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tirthankaras</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>), attributes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> to all
        living <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX>, as well as other natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> was
        therefore abandoned for its destruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> and animal life. The
        doctrines survive in vegetarianism, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">monks</ENAMEX> carrying dusters to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sweep insects</ENAMEX> away from where they tread and wearing a gauze veil over
        their mouth to avoid breathing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flies</ENAMEX>.
        Jainism, which never spread beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, claims <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 million</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>, including many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gujarat</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deccan</ENAMEX>, with a
        few in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bengal</ENAMEX>. It had considerable influence on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahatma Gandhi‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">non-violence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>; he used its fasting-unto-death as a potent moral
        and political <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jains‚</ENAMEX>Äô non-violent religion excludes them
        from agriculture as a profession, but they dominate the electronics
        industry in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangalore</ENAMEX>.
        Parsis, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>
        The tiny but powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parsis</ENAMEX> brought
        Zoroastrianism from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> shine in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">business today</TIMEX>. The
        Parsis, as their name suggests, originate from ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persia</ENAMEX> and today
        form only a minute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in the world of religions, with barely
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, mostly in and around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mumbai</ENAMEX>. They
        have been and are still enormously influential in this country‚Äôs
        economic life, often serving as all-important go-betweens in the
        sometimes immensely difficult relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, and
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>.
        Their religion dates as far back as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the seventh century</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">b.c.</ENAMEX> , when their prophet Zoroaster contrasted his peaceful and
        sedentary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Righteousness</ENAMEX> with the polytheistic nomadic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>. His was an attitude that probably determined not only their
        general ethics, but also their occupational destiny as highly
        sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Parsis</ENAMEX> base their elaborate code of ethics on the
        concept of a constant struggle existing between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creation‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthat</ENAMEX> is, light and good‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand those of darkness and evil.
        Its teachings puts great emphasis on the very purity of the world‚Äôs
        natural elements, fire, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. For instance, to avoid
        polluting the elements, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parsis</ENAMEX> do not bury or cremate their dead, but
        lay them exposed and naked on their famous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Towers of Silence</ENAMEX> for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vultures</ENAMEX> to devour.
        India‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is ancient indeed. Some texts
        claim that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> at the time of the
        Babylonian exile, in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">587 b.c.</TIMEX> ; others bring them to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cranganur</ENAMEX>, on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malabar</ENAMEX> coast, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 72</TIMEX>, about the time that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> is
        thought to have brought his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX> mission to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. The oldest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> still in existence is situated down the coast at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cochin</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">182</NUMEX>), dating back at least to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth century</TIMEX> a.d.
        Some others, less orthodox, can be found in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mumbai</ENAMEX>, but most emigrated
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> when it was founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1948</TIMEX>.
        The earliest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> other than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> (see page
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">197</NUMEX>), were the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Nestorian ‚Äúheretics‚Äù</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian Orthodox</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>, also living on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Malabar coast</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first centuries</TIMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> era. Modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian Christians</ENAMEX>, some descended from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Syrians</ENAMEX>, others from those converted by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Portuguese</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX>, number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 19 million</NUMEX>. They are mainly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>,
        living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Goa</ENAMEX>, and elsewhere you will find all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> variations
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestantism</ENAMEX>, all with a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tinge</ENAMEX> to them.
        The new religion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> is of course modernization, and
        young, upwardly mobile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> are everywhere. Growing
        involvement in electronics, telecommunications, nuclear power, and
        space satellites is intended to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, as one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> said,
        ‚Äúdirectly from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th</TIMEX> into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX>. ‚Äù To achieve this
        transition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is cutting through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> to break with
        political corruption and find some kind of peaceful modus vivendi for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">communal</ENAMEX> and regional interests. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kenneth</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> called it a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúfunctioning anarchy</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù The miracle of how it
        functions is well worth observing.
      
    
  
