
  
  
    
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢‚Ä¢</ENAMEX>
        ‚Ä¢
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢‚Ä¢</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢Ibiza</ENAMEX> and Formentera
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢ Ibiza</ENAMEX> offers a healthy slice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>
        lifestyle infused with some of the spirit and architecture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>. Although it is strictly a part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archipelago</ENAMEX> known
        as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islas Pitiusas</ENAMEX>, or pine-covered isles, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibiza</ENAMEX> in fact displays
        many of the characteristics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islas Baleares</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Balearic Islands</ENAMEX>,
        of neighbouring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mallorca</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menorca</ENAMEX>, with which it is commonly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grouped</ENAMEX>. In terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, it is part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baleares</ENAMEX>. Here you‚Äôll find all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">discos</ENAMEX> you could
        wish for, but there are also traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>, deserted beaches,
        secret coves, and quiet walks for when all you want to do is escape the
        fray.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢Formentera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibiza‚</ENAMEX>Äôs diminutive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">neighbour</ENAMEX> just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hour‚Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ferry-boat</ENAMEX> ride (or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25 minutes</TIMEX> by hydrofoil) to the south, is an island
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">apart‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇin some ways more like a desert <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> than a satellite or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outpost of Ibiza</ENAMEX>. During the supremacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Barbary Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th and 17th centuries</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Formentera</ENAMEX> was so vulnerable it had to be
        abandoned, and it wasn‚Äôt resettled until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX>. Now it
        offers the perfect antidote to the stress of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">modern-day</TIMEX> living, and is
        the ideal place to recharge yourself before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">another evening</TIMEX> of
        exuberant nightlife back on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúmainland‚Äù Ibiza</ENAMEX>. Alternatively, if you
        prefer to find an even quieter stretch of beach, the waters around
        Ibiza are dotted with a host of minor islets, most uninhabited but all
        eminently explorable.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢One</ENAMEX> thing you‚Äôll quickly realize about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ibiza</ENAMEX> is its
        laissez-faire attitude towards life. On this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> paradise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expatriates</ENAMEX> coexist side by side with movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, the
        young and trendy, ageing hippies, and, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>, the total
        residential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> being over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80,000</NUMEX>. Despite the onset of tourism,
        in many parts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">islanders</ENAMEX> still adhere to old traditions, living off
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruits</ENAMEX> (literally! ) of land and sea. Ibiza, small as it is, is not
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those barren <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> rocks with an allure that begins and
        ends at the beach, and although it‚Äôs a part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, it is not the
        usual bullfight-and-flamenco scene. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are a distinct race:
        they have a unique, ancient heritage and a passionate folklore all
        their own. They also have their own language, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ibicenco</ENAMEX>, a dialect
        related to the mallorqu√≠ (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Majorcan</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Catalan</ENAMEX> language,
        though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castilian</ENAMEX> is spoken as well.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢Ibiza</ENAMEX> lies <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearer</NUMEX> to the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Africa</ENAMEX> than to the
        Catalonian <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barcelona.</ENAMEX> With an area of just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">541 sq km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">209 sq</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX>), it is slightly smaller than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Isle of Man</ENAMEX> or twice Martha‚Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>. It may not be much of a speck on the globe,
        but it is big enough to contain a modest mountain, verdant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">and‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇthat real <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">novelty‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa river</ENAMEX>. Likewise, the island‚Äôs
        highest peak, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Sa Talaia</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atalaya</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">475 meters/1,558 feet</NUMEX>),
        hardly ranks among the world‚Äôs most dramatic, but you can see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>
        from the top.
        ‚Ä¢The climate here is distinctly <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>: temperature
        extremes are uncommon and days are warm throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, with the
        heat of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> usually tempered by sea breezes. This, combined with
        the island‚Äôs extraordinary underground water resources, assures the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success of Ibiza‚</ENAMEX>Äôs agriculture. For the tourist, the olive, fig, and
        almond <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> are objects of beauty and colour; for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>, they‚Äôre
        cash <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX>. So is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX>, drying in the huge, square pans at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinas</ENAMEX> in the south.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢The</ENAMEX> capital of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibiza</ENAMEX>, called simply <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ibiza, or Ibiza Town</ENAMEX>,
        has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 35,000</NUMEX>. This is the island‚Äôs main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and
        financial, governmental, and administrative centre, and its charms
        match those of other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean ‚Äújewels</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù It is also a major
        entertainment spot with its own appeal, from the whitewashed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> of
        the ancient walled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> clambering up the hillside to the hustle and
        bustle of the harbour area, with its bistros and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX>. Its
        popularity is such that it has gained a reputation for being something
        of a trend-setters‚Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">haven‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇpost</ENAMEX>-modern or New Age, this is the place
        to be.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢The</ENAMEX> busiest tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> lies <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15 km</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX>) west of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romans</ENAMEX> called it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Portus Magnus</ENAMEX> (great
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">port</ENAMEX>), which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibicencos</ENAMEX> adapted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portmany</ENAMEX>. You might still come
        across both versions, but the official name of the boom <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is Sant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antoni Abad</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Castilian</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbot St. Anthony</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>).
        Skirting the bay, which has been transformed into a variation on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rio de</ENAMEX>
        Janeiro‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Copacabana Beach</ENAMEX>, are high-rise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and apartment
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> is a centre not only for beach activities but for
        lively nightlife as well.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Ä¢The</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">largest‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇas</ENAMEX> opposed to busiest‚<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇtown</ENAMEX> on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Eul√†ria del Riu</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R√≠o</ENAMEX>) on the east coast. Originally
        this was merely a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hamlet</ENAMEX> on a hilltop crowned by a picturesque
        fortress-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. Now the tourist imperative has extended the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> all
        the way down to the sea and far along the coast.
        ‚Ä¢Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> are much less developed, and therein lies
        the essence of many delights. If you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> inland to the less populous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centre</ENAMEX> of the island, you‚Äôll find hamlets consisting of little more
        than a whitewashed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, a general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>. This is the time
        to relax over a glass of the locally made hierbas (an alcoholic drink
        made from herbs), listen to the crickets, and watch the world go
        by.
      
    
  
