
  
  
    
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is many things to many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>: a land of hope,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wonder</ENAMEX>, faith, salvation, contradiction, and sometimes despair.
        Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is only now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years old</TIMEX>, the roots of its three prime
        religious faiths (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juda¬≠ism</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>, and Christianity) stretch back over
        many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millennia</ENAMEX>, and some of its ancient settlements are amongst the
        oldest on earth.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patriarch</ENAMEX>, led his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here in
        search of ‚Äúthe land of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> and honey‚Äù; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX> was born, lived,
        ministered, and died here; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>, visited
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> during his heavenly <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúNight Journey</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù Each religion and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sect‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇJews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> (including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Druse</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> (including <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Armenian</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eastern Orthodox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Samaritans</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Copts</ENAMEX>),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baha‚Äôi</ENAMEX>, and several more‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇclaims some piece of this sacred <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>. Each
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX> worships a single god and recognizes elements of the others‚Äô
        beliefs. Sometimes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> denomination shares one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> may then be marked out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designate</ENAMEX> where worshippers of the
        various denominations take their place.
        This giddying confluence of distinct religions is matched
        only by the diversity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. As a largely immigrant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">State of Israel</ENAMEX> provides home to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 80</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> around the world. Nearly half the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> hail
        from overseas, and they have brought with them many of the accumulated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">customs</ENAMEX> and cultural traditions of their former <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>.
        In the face of such plurality it‚Äôs hard to characterize
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. This is a land where different and sometimes conflicting
        traditions continue to matter despite heavy odds. Not so much a
        melting-pot as a ‚Äúland of unlimited impossibilities,<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">‚Äù Israel</ENAMEX> compresses
        a host of sights and lifestyles into a small area, offering a
        cornucopia of experiences for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.
        Preeminent among the attractions is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount</ENAMEX> area is the geographical heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has drawn
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, sometimes heavily armed, ever since the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">proclamation of the ‚ÄúHoly Land‚</ENAMEX>Äù and development of the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
        sites for pilgrims in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fifth century</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find that the Old
        City‚Äôs myriad colours, sounds, smells, and tastes stir the senses; the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Mount‚</ENAMEX>Äôs architecture can take your breath away; pilgrims tracing
        Christ‚Äôs journey to Calvary along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Dolorosa</ENAMEX> remain a deeply
        moving sight; and the views from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount of Olives</ENAMEX> are stunning. For
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> seeking spiritual refreshment, there are countless churches
        to visit, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of the Holy Sepulchre, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basilica of</ENAMEX>
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annunciation</ENAMEX> (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazareth</ENAMEX>), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of the Nativity</ENAMEX> (in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX>), just to mention the most famous. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> revere the sites
        on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome of the Rock and El-Aksa Mosque</ENAMEX>. Even when
        these sights are bustling with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> you‚Äôre likely to find them
        compelling.
        However, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> is only a starting point‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbeyond the
        capital lie more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> attractions <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">per square mile than</NUMEX> in any other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the world, beckoning not only pilgrims, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, and
        archaeologists, but also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hikers</ENAMEX>, ornithologists, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scuba-divers</ENAMEX>,
        windsurfers, and many others. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is so compact you can cram enough
        variety of activities into a week to satisfy almost every taste.
        Indeed, should you decide to go slow on culture, you‚Äôll find
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> a splendid place for leisurely sun-worshipping. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has begun to realise its considerable potential for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">beach</ENAMEX>-style tourism. The fast-paced metropolis of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> boasts
        beautiful white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sands</ENAMEX>, while other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> have their own
        unique features. It is perfectly feasible to spend a fortnight in
        Eilat, exploring the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Sea</ENAMEX>, lying on the beaches, journeying into the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Negev Desert‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> never see a religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> or an archaeological
        site.
        After an exhausting day on the go or at the beach, you can
        rest assured that you‚Äôll be able to relax in comfortable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>,
        hospices, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> are delighted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from
        everywhere visit their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and welcome you with genuine warmth.
        Nor are you likely to encounter a language problem, as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> is
        taught in all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and is widely spoken.
        It has been suggested that it‚Äôs impossible for any
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigner</ENAMEX> to understand the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> psyche. Possibly no other country
        has had such a turbulent history. Visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masada</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yad Vashem</ENAMEX> (the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holocaust Museum</ENAMEX>) may give you an inkling of the capacity for tragedy
        and heroism embodied in both that history and the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">State of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. Yet, despite all the displacement and suffering, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>
        of this land continue to be friendly and welcoming.
      
    
  
