
  
  
    
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jungle</ENAMEX>
        To go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> without setting foot in the jungle would
        be to miss an essential beauty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. A walk in the jungle can
        be a rare sensual pleasure. Sounds flood in from all sides: the buzz
        and whine of crickets, the chatter of squirrels, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poop-poop-poop</ENAMEX> of
        hornbills, the cries of gibbon apes. You are likely to see everything
        from the deep gloom of the densest forest to the sudden brilliant burst
        of sun in a clearing, playing endless variations on the textures and
        myriad shades of green in the surrounding vegetation.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kinds</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jungle</ENAMEX>
        Variations in soil, slope, and altitude give rise to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
        different types of forest:
        Mangrove forest. Mangrove <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">shrubs</ENAMEX> grow on coastal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marshland</ENAMEX> in the brackish zone between the sea and fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. The
        dense undergrowth of their aerial prop roots perform natural land
        reclamation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> and leaves feed crabs whose waste products in
        turn feed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, prawns, and mollusks. The mangrove‚Äôs distinctive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companion</ENAMEX> is the low, trunkless nipa palm, whose curtain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fronds</ENAMEX> has
        traditionally provided roofing material for coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">huts</ENAMEX>.
        Freshwater swamp. Abundant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> in the fertile
        alluvium of river plains attract prolific <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wildlife</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peat</ENAMEX> swamp, found
        in the southern <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the peninsula and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarawak</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borneo</ENAMEX>, is less
        fertile but rich in hardwood <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">timber</ENAMEX>. Where swamp gives way to dry land,
        you will see the fascinating, monstrous strangler-figs.
        Dipterocarp forest. The botanical term refers to the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-winged <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> (similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúkey‚Äù</ENAMEX> of the common sycamore) borne by
        a large number of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">forest‚Äôs tallest trees</ENAMEX>. This dry-land rainforest
        is what you will see most frequently from just above sea level up to an
        altitude of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">900 m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,000 ft</NUMEX>). Its wealth of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> is remarkable,
        including the tualang, found both in the northern <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the peninsula
        and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sabah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarawak</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borneo</ENAMEX> ironwood or belian produces the
        world‚Äôs densest, hardest timber after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ironwood</ENAMEX>. But
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabah</ENAMEX> boasts the fastest-growing <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> in the world: an acacia-like
        Albizzia falcataria, which was ‚Äúclocked‚Äù from germinated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX> to almost
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 m</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 35</NUMEX> ft) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just 13 months</TIMEX>.
        Heath forest. Poor soil on the flat terrain leading to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foothills</ENAMEX> or on sandy mountain-ridges produces only low, stunted trees
        with thick leaves. The heath forest is remarkable for its profound
        silence compared with the jungle‚Äôs incessant din.
        Montane forest. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4,000 ft</NUMEX>) and above in large
        mountain ranges, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as low as 600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,000 ft</NUMEX>) on small isolated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mountains</ENAMEX>, the large <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and liana creepers give way to myrtle,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">laurel</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oak trees</ENAMEX>. Wild raspberries appear along with magnolias,
        rhododendrons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">orchids</ENAMEX>, and other epiphytes (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> that grow on other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> but are not parasites, since they procure their own food
        supply). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most intriguing specimens of montane <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flora</ENAMEX> (also
        found in the heath forest) is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pitcher plant</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animal Life</ENAMEX>
        Unlike the wildlife of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> plain, most of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> jungle are not very conspicuous. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tigers</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leopards</ENAMEX> remain rare. Plus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX>, rhinos, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bears</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> are the smallest of their kind.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Elephant</ENAMEX>. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> on the peninsula,
        and twice that number in eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sabah</ENAMEX>. A few have been domesticated
        for plantation work. They are daintier <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX> than their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhinoceros</ENAMEX>. Scarcely <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sumatran Rhino</ENAMEX> remain; the
        best place to see them is at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sepilok</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX>, where controlled
        breeding may combat the ravages of poaching. To see it in its wild or
        semi-wild <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, try the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sungai Dusun Wildlife Reserve</ENAMEX> northwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX>,
        or in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tabin</ENAMEX> reserve in eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sabah</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tapir</ENAMEX>. This animal is remarkable for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> features: its
        short, overlapping snout that resembles the sawed-off trunk of an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>, and its unique <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">body coloring‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇblack</ENAMEX> up front, white in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">middle</ENAMEX> and back, black rear legs. It is found only on the peninsula.
        Your best chance to see it is at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ampang</ENAMEX> reserve near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX>
        or at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taman Negara</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Deer</ENAMEX>. Most common are the tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse-deer</ENAMEX>. These timid
        nocturnal <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX> sport a brown coat speckled with white. The largest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Malaysian deer</ENAMEX> is the brown antlered sambar. Another shy <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX>, you
        might spot it at the edge of the forest or on river <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. The barking
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX>, so-called because it bays like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> when threatened by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predators</ENAMEX>, wears a shiny reddish-brown coat.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX>. The few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX> left roaming the peninsula
        are the smallest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX>, weighing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only 200 kg</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">440 lb</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 kg</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">220 lb</NUMEX>) less than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tiger</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leopard</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúclassic‚Äù</ENAMEX> spotted yellow or black coat of the
        leopard may be seen not only in the jungle but also around plantations
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX>. The smaller clouded leopard hunts up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, enjoying
        a varied diet of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby orang-utans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>, and squirrels. The
        leopard-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> is not a lot bigger than a domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and may nip in and
        out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>.
        Proboscis <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>. Unique to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borneo</ENAMEX>, the male sports the
        splendid pendulous nose that gives this species its name. It is also
        the male who emits a formidable honk through its nose at times of great
        excitement or alarm. The female‚Äôs nose is an unremarkable little snub,
        but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zoologists</ENAMEX> say that she appreciates, and is even aroused by, the
        male‚Äôs proboscis. They can best be seen on the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kinabatangan</ENAMEX> river
        in eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sabah</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bako</ENAMEX> and Samunsan nature reserves in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarawak</ENAMEX>.
        Orang-utan. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>, orang-utan means <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúforest person‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇan
        appropriate mark of respect for the mammal biologically closest to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
        These highly intelligent, russet-colored apes live in the swamp forests
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sabah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarawak</ENAMEX>, and are best seen in eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sabah‚</ENAMEX>Äôs Sepilok
        wildlife reserve. They are very individualistic nomads, meeting
        occasionally to share a fruit supper before going their own way. Some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sepilok</ENAMEX> confuse them with the similarly colored red-leaf
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbut unlike monkeys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orang-utans</ENAMEX> have no tails.
      
    
  
