
  
  
    
      
        What to Do
        Entertainment
        Sound and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Light Shows</ENAMEX>: All the most impressive ancient sites
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> have a sound and light show, and it adds an extra theatrical
        dimension to your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> experience. Stirring music and dramatic
        soundtrack accompany the dance of lights over the monuments. At Giza
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX> have a show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nightly</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luxor</ENAMEX> the show is held
        at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Karnak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> (though <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Luxor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> is floodlit) where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> spend
        half the show seated and the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> wandering among the obelisks
        and columns as the story unfolds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aswan</ENAMEX> sound and light show takes
        place at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philae Temple</ENAMEX> some <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX> away. Remember to take a warm
        layer if you intend to see a show during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter months</TIMEX>, as the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evenings</ENAMEX> can be chilly.
        For information on all <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sound and Light</ENAMEX> shows <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) 386
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3469</TIMEX>; fax (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">02</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">385 2880</TIMEX>; web site
        <www.sound-light.egypt.com>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Folkloric Events: The Bedouin</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX> have a
        fascinating lifestyle. Though many have now traded their wandering ways
        for permanent settlements, they still prefer to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX> rather
        than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and treasure their traditional social habits. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
        have opened up their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> and you can have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening meal</TIMEX>
        with them and discover more about their world.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper Egypt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nubian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">floorshows</ENAMEX> have a different
        atmosphere and flavor. They are performed in all the large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, and
        feature traditional music and dancing from this most ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX>
        culture.
        Most large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> will have a floorshow featuring music and
        dance, including a voluptuous belly-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancer</ENAMEX>, who will introduce the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> to the art of gyrating <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> style. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> probably be
        invited to join in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">as the evening</TIMEX> progresses!
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clubs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Discos: Belly</ENAMEX>-dancing is not just a tourist show,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">it‚Äôs</ENAMEX> also popular with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptians</ENAMEX> and you can take in a serious and
        perhaps more earthy show at several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Discos</ENAMEX>
        are also popular‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsome of the most popular can be found at the major
        international hotels‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand have a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clientele</ENAMEX> in
        addition to attracting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Casinos</ENAMEX>: There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>,
        mostly in the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, and they attract a number of serious ‚Äúhigh
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rollers</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationals</ENAMEX> are not allowed to gamble so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> are
        only open to foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 21</TIMEX> (you will be asked for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ID</ENAMEX>). Stakes are priced in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US Dollars</ENAMEX> and you can usually play
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blackjack</ENAMEX>, roulette, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>, and baccarat. Slot machines are also
        available.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cairo Opera House</ENAMEX> opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, a gift from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Performances are staged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between October</TIMEX> and
        May. Formal dress may be required.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian National Circus</ENAMEX>: The national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circus</ENAMEX> started with
        the help of skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, and it has a
        permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">base</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azouga</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> for most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> the
        whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troupe</ENAMEX> moves to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX> to escape the heat and humidity of the
        capital.
        Sports
        Beaches and watersports: You‚Äôll find wonderful fine sand
        beaches all along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Sea</ENAMEX> coast, the west coast of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peninsula</ENAMEX> and its southern tip, and also along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> coast.
        In general, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> areas are more organized for foreign
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> caters to a much more domestic market.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharm El Sheikh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hurghada</ENAMEX> are the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX>, well-equipped
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and eateries, with a full range of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> such as
        windsurfing, water-skiing, and water rides: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dahab</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nuweiba</ENAMEX> on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">west</ENAMEX> coast of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX> are smaller, with a hardened diving or
        windsurfing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">crowd‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇgreat</ENAMEX> for a low key vacation. Because <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>
        temperatures rarely drop below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 70s</TIMEX>, this area is a good year-round
        option for a fun-filled and a sun-filled vacation.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snorkeling</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diving</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> is a great place for both
        diving and snorkeling ‚Äî the southern tip of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai Peninsula</ENAMEX> is one
        of the world‚Äôs prime dive sites. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ras Mohammed National Park</ENAMEX> has over
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,500</NUMEX> species of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> types of coral along with an offshore
        vertical sea wall. These offer a variety of habitats and diving for all
        abilities. The reefs run all the way up the eastern coast of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peninsula making Dahab</ENAMEX> and Naweiba good <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bases‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthough quieter</ENAMEX> then
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sharm El Sheikh‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇfor</ENAMEX> diving excursions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurghada</ENAMEX> sits across a small
        strait from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ras Mohammed National Park</ENAMEX> and the sea and coral life is
        excellent.
        If you wish to learn to dive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> there is an excellent
        network of dive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> that offer training, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ab</ENAMEX>-initio to professional
        levels. All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> are affiliated with one of the major certifying
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PADI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professional Association of Diving Instructors</ENAMEX>) is the
        most common. The basic qualification, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open Water</ENAMEX> certificate, takes
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> to complete. On completion this will allow you to dive with
        an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> to a depth of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> ft), which opens many dive sites
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> to you.
        Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> also offer an introductory session commonly
        known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúDiscover Scuba Programme</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù This involves a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> or
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> of theory and swimming pool work, which will give you the
        chance to try out the basic techniques. Many large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> offer this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äútaster‚Äù</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emperor Divers</ENAMEX> is a long-established operation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>
        at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hurghada, Na‚Äôam Bay</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nuweiba</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> details can be found at their
        web site <www.emperordivers.com>.
        If you don‚Äôt want to dive then you can snorkel just
        offshore along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Sea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX> coasts to see excellent tropical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marine</ENAMEX> life. If you don‚Äôt have your own equipment it is easy to buy at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX>.
        Other water-based activities include a glass-bottomed
        boat-ride or a trip under the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Aquascope</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">submarine</ENAMEX> to see
        the excellent underwater environment. This is situated in the main
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">harbor at Sharm El Sheikh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">069 662252</NUMEX>.
        Fishing: All the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Sea</ENAMEX> coast, in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinai</ENAMEX> and along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> have marinas where you will be able
        to rent <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> for a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> or day‚Äôs fishing. The fishing is excellent,
        and some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will even set up a barbeque so that you can enjoy
        your catch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safaris</ENAMEX> and desert adventures: Over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egypt‚</ENAMEX>Äôs land is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">desert</ENAMEX>, making it only a matter of time before it became a tourist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resource</ENAMEX>. With so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to get away from it all, it is the
        perfect contrast to our urban existence. You can take safaris lasting
        from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one to three days</TIMEX> on camel, or by four-wheel-drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> where
        all supplies are included, or simply head off on quad <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> for an
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> of fun in the sand dunes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX> region is best organized
        for these activities, though the western desert is developing. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hurghada Adventures Club</ENAMEX> offers professional and multilingual fully
        insured quad safaris; contact them at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Friendship Village</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">010 156</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7571</TIMEX>; web site <www.geocities.com/hurghada_adventures>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camel</ENAMEX> and horseback-riding: Motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> are only recent
        arrivals in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> and traditional forms of transport are still popular
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptians</ENAMEX> and make great vacation activities. Camel rides and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treks</ENAMEX> can be taken around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luxor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aswan</ENAMEX>; at every
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resort</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX> and on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Sea</ENAMEX> coast. Horseback-riding is also
        well organized in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Sea</ENAMEX>, less so along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.
        Other sports: If you feel the need to work up a sweat while
        you are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> then you can become a temporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the Gazira
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Club‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇonce the domain of the upper classes. Situated on Zamelek
        Island the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> features an amazing array of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> including
        tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, squash <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">handball courts</ENAMEX>, and several swimming
        pools. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oberoi Mena House Hotel</ENAMEX> operates an 18-hole golf club in the
        shadow of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giza</ENAMEX>, and you don‚Äôt need to be a guest to
        enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
        There‚Äôs something for all budgets in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>. The skills of
        carvers, weavers, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> have been passed down through the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> and you can really have fun for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> browsing at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wares</ENAMEX>. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptians</ENAMEX> are tenacious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopkeepers</ENAMEX> and you will
        have to have a will of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX> and sense of humor to ignore their sales
        pitches.
        Where to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shop</ENAMEX>
        Bazaars: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Khan El Khalili</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> is one of the oldest and
        most renowned bazaars in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> world, and it is a veritable
        treasure-trove of shopping opportunities. The labyrinth of narrow
        alleys constitutes several different ‚Äúquarters,‚Äù each specializing in a
        particular skill or merchandise. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most fascinating is the
        tent-making area, where large ceremonial marquis style tents are
        fashioned by hand from brightly dyed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton</ENAMEX>. Stroll around and
        mingle with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptians</ENAMEX> doing their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shopping‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇKhan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Khalili</ENAMEX> is not
        just a tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bazaar‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇto find handicrafts and artifacts from around
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luxor</ENAMEX> has a smaller but no less atmospheric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bazaar</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aswan</ENAMEX> has a great shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> running one block parallel to the
        river.
        Archaeological sites: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mini</ENAMEX>-tourist markets have sprung up
        around most of the major archaeological sites, and they all sell much
        the same items but prices are likely to be higher than at the larger
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bazaars</ENAMEX>.
        When shopping, be aware that quality does vary greatly and
        some bargains may not be what they appear‚<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇinferior stone</ENAMEX> painted to
        look like marble or alabaster is a favorite ploy around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Upper Egypt</ENAMEX>. Always study any item carefully before purchase.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find prices begin to drop at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX>,
        after the tour <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> leave, especially out of season.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Tips</ENAMEX>
        If you take a guide or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interpreter</ENAMEX> with you, it is
        customary for them to receive a percentage on every purchase you
        make.
        At reputable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> you will be able to arrange for the
        shipping of items that are too large to carry or too fragile to check
        on the return flight home.
        Haggling
        Few prices are fixed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> and thus a protracted
        discussion will begin, the purpose of which is to agree to a price that
        satisfies both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> and seller‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇin other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúhaggling</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        Remember that negotiations should be undertaken with good
        humor; this is not a battle, it‚Äôs more a form of verbal gymnastics
        meant to achieve a win/win situation. Cups of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> are
        traditionally offered to oil the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deal‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇalthough</ENAMEX> today
        you may be offered the ubiquitous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">coke instead‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> if you are serious
        about buying don‚Äôt turn this down as it‚Äôs a symbolic stepping-stone
        marking you apart from the mere browser. The starting price is always
        high. Don‚Äôt accept it but don‚Äôt insult the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX> with a ludicrously
        low counter-offer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> probably end up with a price that‚Äôs around
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50‚Äì70%</NUMEX> of this initial price so if the goods are genuinely more
        expensive than you want to pay, better to walk away now with a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">handshake</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> ‚Äúno thank you. ‚Äù If you want to proceed, make your
        lower offer but have a higher final price in mind; you‚Äôll reach it
        gradually while your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> takes great pains to explain how good the
        quality of their product is as against those of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. One
        good tip is to agree on a strategy with any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">beforehand‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇfeigned</ENAMEX> nonchalance by your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> can work in your
        favor.
        And at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX> have fun; once the deal is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sealed</ENAMEX>, you‚Äôll definitely come home having bought something exciting
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>!
        What to Buy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabaster</ENAMEX> and marble: Carving skills have been passed down
        through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the centuries</TIMEX>, particularly in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> near the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kings</ENAMEX> and around the marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarries</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aswan</ENAMEX>. You can find myriad
        copies of ancient pieces‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇfrom obelisks to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids ‚Äî</ENAMEX> and incredibly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kitsch</ENAMEX> and tacky copies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient Egyptian</ENAMEX> artifacts such as
        Tutankhamun‚Äôs mask, but also wonderful hand-carved vases, bowls, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urns</ENAMEX>. Small items, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">scarab beetles‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇconsidered</ENAMEX> a lucky amulet
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Egypt‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇare</ENAMEX> sold in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, but also by young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and street
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawkers</ENAMEX> around the archaeological sites.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Copper</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX>: These <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metals</ENAMEX> have long been used for
        practical items such as water <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>, samovars, or cooking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pots</ENAMEX> and
        they make excellent souvenirs. Older <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> have the patina of age
        where new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pieces‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇusually</ENAMEX> made on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">site‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇare</ENAMEX> bright and shiny. Trays
        can be found in all sizes and those with a wooden stand make wonderful
        portable tables for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cotton</ENAMEX> and woolen goods: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> has been famed for its fine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cotton</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousands of hectares</NUMEX> under cultivation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nile Delta</ENAMEX>
        are one of the country‚Äôs most lucrative export <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earners</ENAMEX>. For the
        domestic market you‚Äôll find practical items such as the gellabiya‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe
        long shirt-like garment worn by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">men‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> T-shirts, normally featuring
        images of camels and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, gellabiyas are usually plain,
        perhaps with a little collar detail, but for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> you can find
        brightly decorated versions, often bedecked with sequins. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> also
        find skimpy belly-dancing outfits if you want to be daring.
        Other natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> are made into beautiful scarves,
        shawls, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blankets‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇoften</ENAMEX> used as wraps by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptians</ENAMEX> to keep the
        winter chills at bay and woven with rich patterns in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> tones or
        deep <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">reds</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Sheep wool</ENAMEX> is the most common and therefore the cheapest,
        followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">camel hair</ENAMEX>, which is exceptionally soft. Most expensive are
        silk or silk blend items.
        Jewelry: It‚Äôs not surprising, given the amount of gold
        thought to have been buried in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tombs‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇlike the riches found
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tutankhamun‚</ENAMEX>Äôs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">1920s‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthat gold</ENAMEX> and jewelry is a good buy in
        modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>. Precious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metals</ENAMEX> are sold by weight, with very little
        added to the price for workmanship. Precious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> and semi-precious
        stones including <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">topaz</ENAMEX>, lapis lazuli, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aquamarine</ENAMEX>, can be bought
        loose or set in rings, necklaces, bracelets, or brooches. Hieroglyphic
        cartouches are also popular remembrances‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jeweler</ENAMEX> can have your name
        made up into a cartouche of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> letters in just a couple of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">days‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇchoose</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>.
        Woodwork: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> frowns on the use of precious metals in its
        religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, so artisans working more basic raw materials have
        always been highly regarded in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Egypt‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇparticularly</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cairo‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇis</ENAMEX> famed for its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood carvers</ENAMEX>, who still produce beautiful
        hand-worked pieces in small workshops in the old part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. From
        the smallest box to large coffee tables, the intricate detail is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exquisite</ENAMEX>. The finest and most authentic work is mashrabiya, the
        lattice screens that covered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX> windows allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to watch
        the world go by without being seen. This is now reproduced in small
        scale for picture frames or as room screens, which make an excellent
        statement in a modern living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>. Look also for boxed chess
        and backgammon sets made from wood inlaid with pieces fashioned from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pearl</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ivory</ENAMEX>. Don‚Äôt worry about the risk to endangered
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal species‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇmost <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ivory</ENAMEX> is camel or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">donkey bone</ENAMEX>, not
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant tusk</ENAMEX>.
        Papyrus: The leaves of the papyrus were dried and used by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ancient Egyptians</ENAMEX> as a form of paper. The art of papyrus-making was
        lost in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> when it was reintroduced using native
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it is possible to buy cheap papyrus printed with gaudy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> scenes in almost every souvenir shop in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, but some
        of the most authentic are sold at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">The Pharaonic Village</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> where
        the papyrus is grown, processed, and hand-painted on site.
        Perfume: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ancient Egypt</ENAMEX> enjoyed a leisurely
        life surrounding themselves with incense, unguents, and perfumes made
        from petals and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oils</ENAMEX>. Perfumes are still popular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and you will see
        the perfume blender at the bazaar surrounded by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of glass
        bottles containing the numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oils</ENAMEX> that combine to make a single
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scent</ENAMEX>. They will copy your favorite brand of western perfume, or will
        suggest a blend to suit your skin <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">type</ENAMEX> and you can purchase an ornate
        glass perfume bottle to put it i n. If you don‚Äôt want the perfume, the
        bottles are on sale in many souvenir <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and make pretty decorative
        pieces.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Spices</ENAMEX>: The long trade <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> north and east that came
        together in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> made it a marketplace for many <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX>.
        You can still find interesting flavorings and colorings on sale, along
        with the dried hibiscus <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> used to make sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>.
        Things to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children</ENAMEX>
        Long hot days touring <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ancient Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">temples</ENAMEX>, tombs, and
        museums are not going to be at the top of most children‚Äôs lists of
        great things to do on vacation, but there are lots of ways to make
        their trip fun.
        When visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX>, let them enjoy a camel or horse
        ride out across the site. You‚Äôll be able to hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luxor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aswan</ENAMEX> and at numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Sea</ENAMEX> and in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinai</ENAMEX>.
        Don‚Äôt miss the mummy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> will
        love the slightly gory-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pharaohs</ENAMEX> and will be fascinated by the
        process of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mummification‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthough it‚</ENAMEX>Äôs not for the faint-hearted.
        Take a felucca ride on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nile‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit‚Äôs</ENAMEX> fun being out on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> alike.
        Visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pharaonic Village</ENAMEX> and let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life rather than just imagining it.
        Ride in a horse-drawn <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriage</ENAMEX> along the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Corniche</ENAMEX> next to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luxor</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Aswan‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthis</ENAMEX> high vantage point gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> a
        great view of what‚Äôs happening.
        Book a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> with a pool, so that after a day sightseeing,
        you can have a relaxing swim and some ‚Äúkid‚Äù fun. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> too young
        to dive or snorkel, take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>-bottom boat rides or the Aquascope
        submarine to get an excellent view of the marine life.
        Calendar of Events
        Many of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egypt‚</ENAMEX>Äôs primary holidays are based on the Moslem
        calendar, which is calculated on the changing lunar cycle. Please check
        with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian Tourist Board</ENAMEX> (see page tk) for exact festival dates
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> that you are traveling.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January - Coptic Christmas</TIMEX> with presents and partying for
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
        Coptic Good <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Friday‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇ2002/ 3</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> ; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003/ 25 April</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2004/</NUMEX> 9
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005/ 29 April</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006/ 21 April</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2007/</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 April</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2008/ 25</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coptic Easter</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sham En Nessim</ENAMEX> ‚Äî the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">National Spring Festival</ENAMEX>, held the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coptic Easter</ENAMEX>, when the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> comes out
        to celebrate.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan Bairam</ENAMEX> is a month long celebration when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Moslems</ENAMEX>
        fast during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hours</TIMEX> of daylight. There are nightly iftah <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sundown</ENAMEX> (special <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan</ENAMEX> dishes) with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> gathering to celebrate.
        Gifts and celebrations on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three days</TIMEX> of the festival, called
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eid El-Fitr</ENAMEX>. Approximate dates <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-2002/</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 November</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003/ 27 October</TIMEX>;
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2008/</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 September</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mulid En Nabi</ENAMEX> is another major holiday‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit celebrates the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prophet‚Äôs</ENAMEX> Birthday.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qurban Bairam</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eid El-Adha</ENAMEX>) is a time when many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>
        travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mecca</ENAMEX> (their holy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>) to commemorate the slaying of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham</ENAMEX>. Just as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>, when a ram was substituted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX>,
        lambs are slaughtered, cooked, and shared by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> or local
        neighborhoods.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Film Festival</ENAMEX> is held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each December</TIMEX> with screenings
        of major international films taking place at various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> all across
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
