
  
  
    
      
        What to Do
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dublin</ENAMEX> is rapidly becoming a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-hour</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, so there is
        plenty to enjoy when your sightseeing is done. The city‚Äôs many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX> are
        the center of social life, offering conversation and a quiet pint,
        food, music, and song. There are also lots of late-night <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>. And
        with first-class <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and a profusion of booksellers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antiques</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>, you can browse or buy contentedly. If you‚Äôre feeling
        active, there are excellent opportunities for sports. For at-a-glance
        information on the city‚Äôs entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, refer to the map on
        the cover of this guide.
        Going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pubs</ENAMEX>
        As you walk through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> it will sometimes seem
        that there‚Äôs a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX> on every corner. Pubs are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Ireland‚Äôs</ENAMEX> living
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rooms‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthey</ENAMEX> provide not only <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX> and food, but atmosphere,
        entertainment, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">craic‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇfriendly</ENAMEX>, lively, amusing talk. You may not
        fall into conversation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> quite as readily as in a country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX>,
        but you‚Äôll find that here, as everywhere, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> are welcoming
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX> also serve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthey</ENAMEX> are good places to have
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lunch‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇand some have dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>. Be warned that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX> around
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">O‚ÄôConnell Street</ENAMEX> can be rough, and at times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> Bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX> can be
        rowdy. Pubs open <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">around 11am and closing hours</TIMEX> have been extended to
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:30am</TIMEX>.
        Reputedly the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brazen Head</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bridge Street Lower</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe Tone</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Irishmen</ENAMEX> supposedly
        met here. With its cobblestone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>, it looks like a picturesque
        country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX>, and seems to be a must for every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Redcap‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tavern</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back Lane</ENAMEX>, off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">High Street</ENAMEX>) is a big, relaxed place with live
        music. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O‚ÄôDonoghue‚Äôs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slattery‚Äôs</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> famous music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX>, are still
        among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dublin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs best. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O‚ÄôDonoghue‚Äôs</ENAMEX> (Merrion Row) was formerly the haunt
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dubliners</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slattery‚Äôs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capel Street</ENAMEX>) is a bit scruffy, but has
        perhaps the city‚Äôs best traditional music. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Nealon‚Äôs</ENAMEX> (also in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capel</ENAMEX>
        Street) has jazz on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and eclectic music the rest of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>.
        If you like traditional dancing, go to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">O‚ÄôShea‚Äôs Merchant</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bridge Street Lower</ENAMEX>).
        Stag‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dame Court</ENAMEX>) is known for its good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. Ryan‚Äôs
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Parkgate Street</ENAMEX>) is a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toner‚Äôs</ENAMEX> (Baggot
        Street Lower) is an old, authentic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long Hall</ENAMEX> (South
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great George‚Äôs Street</ENAMEX>) is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> time machine with (reputedly) the
        city‚Äôs longest bar counter.
        Off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grafton Street</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kehoe‚Äôs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Anne Street</ENAMEX>), a
        favorite watering spot; and on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke Street</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX> with with
        Ulysses <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">connections‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇDavy Byrne‚Äôs</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leopold Bloom</ENAMEX> ate a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gorgonzola</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwich</ENAMEX> and drank a glass of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailey‚Äôs</ENAMEX>, a busy,
        trendy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX> on the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leopold Bloom‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. Back of the Gaiety
        Theater you‚Äôll probably encounter a theatrical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Neary‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chatham Street</ENAMEX>). Microbreweries have also appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>, and sell
        their excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin Brewing Company</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North King Street</ENAMEX>)
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porterhouse Brewing Company</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament Street</ENAMEX>).
        There are many old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Temple Bar</ENAMEX>, but they are often
        very tourist-oriented. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver St. John Gogarty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fleet Street</ENAMEX>), named
        for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-of-letters who was the model for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ulysses</ENAMEX>,
        has good traditional and other music and a dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. There‚Äôs music
        upstairs in the small, quaint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha‚Äôpenny Bridge Inn</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wellington Quay</ENAMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Temple Bar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Bar</ENAMEX>) attracts a busy, lively <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>; the Norseman
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East Essex Street</ENAMEX>) is favored by the art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Auld</ENAMEX> Dubliner
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Anglesea Street</ENAMEX>) is a pleasant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX> that caters a lot to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>.
        Whether you drink <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> or not, a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>
        isn‚Äôt complete without a visit to some of its <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pubs‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇdon‚Äôt</ENAMEX> miss this
        experience.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
        Open <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX>) vary considerably, with news
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwich bars</ENAMEX> open well before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9am</TIMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30</TIMEX>
        or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:45am</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Shopping hours</TIMEX> have expanded; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> in tourist areas like
        Grafton <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> stay open extended <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. Outside the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> may close by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:30 or 6pm</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day Sunday</TIMEX>, with
        late-night shopping until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8pm</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Stores</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shops</ENAMEX>
        The main shopping areas are in and around <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grafton Street</ENAMEX>,
        along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau Street</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Temple Bar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">O‚ÄôConnell Street</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Henry Street</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pedestrian Grafton Street</ENAMEX> is lined with well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marks</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spencer, the Body Shop</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMV</ENAMEX> records, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Ashley</ENAMEX>. The
        excellent, upscale department store <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown Thomas</ENAMEX> is also on Grafton
        Street. O‚ÄôConnell Street is lined with more downscale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, but two
        landmarks are still here: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eason‚Äôs</ENAMEX> books and art supplies, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        largest department store, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clerys</ENAMEX>, with its famous clock.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malls</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> include the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Stephen‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        Green <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Centre</ENAMEX>, where you can buy just about anything and also
        have a meal (it can be very crowded, especially in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>). The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powerscourt Townhouse</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Clarendon Street</ENAMEX> (follow the sign from Grafton
        Street) is more upscale, and specializes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and caf√©s, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antiques</ENAMEX>, jewelry, and clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. Also on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Clarendon Street</ENAMEX> is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Westbury Mall</ENAMEX>, with caf√©s and fine jewelry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>.
        On the other side of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grafton Street</ENAMEX>, leading into Dawson
        Street, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Royal Hibernian Way</ENAMEX> is a small shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> with some
        exclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>. Dawson Street is lined with bookshops and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX>.
        Finally, there is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILAC Center</ENAMEX>, which is second only to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Stephen‚Äôs Green</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. Here you‚Äôll find many clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> for all
        ages and a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunnes Stores</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> clothes- and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">food-shop</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>.
        Markets: The oldest is on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moore Street</ENAMEX>, famous for the
        cries of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fruit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>, electronics, and a little bit
        of everything else is on sale here.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Georges Street Arcade</ENAMEX> is a sheltered market between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, a good place for second-hand books, music,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clothing</ENAMEX>, and ethnic ware.
        Best known, perhaps is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Redcap‚</ENAMEX>Äôs in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back Lane</ENAMEX>
        (opposite <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Christ Church Cathedral</ENAMEX>). Stalls here sell books, used
        clothes, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> and jams, and a variety of flea-market stuff.
        What to Buy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiques</ENAMEX>: There are antiques fairs in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Newman House</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Stephen‚Äôs Green South</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every second Sunday year</TIMEX> round. And don‚Äôt miss a
        stroll down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Francis Street</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> 7), <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dublin‚Äôs ‚Äúantiques</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>,‚Äù
        lined with antiques and art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. Also check out the lovely antiques
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> floor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powerscourt Townhouse</ENAMEX>.
        Art: For contemporary art, especially the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, you should try the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerlin Gallery</ENAMEX> (off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Anne Street</ENAMEX>), the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor Galleries</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kildare Street</ENAMEX>), or the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Solomon Gallery</ENAMEX> (Powerscourt
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Townhouse</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Bar Gallery</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Bar</ENAMEX>) exhibits the work of up
        to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident artists</ENAMEX>.
        Books: Eason‚Äôs in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">O‚ÄôConnell Street</ENAMEX>, is a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> with
        mainstream books, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, and art-supplies. Waterstone‚Äôs
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hodges Figgis</ENAMEX> (of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulysses</ENAMEX> fame), are across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from each
        other in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dawson Street</ENAMEX>. Both carry an excellent selection of
        literature, general books, books on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, and the works of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Hanna‚</ENAMEX>Äôs in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau Street</ENAMEX> sells new and secondhand books,
        posters and old postcards, and has a good children‚Äôs section.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Books</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Frederick Street</ENAMEX> specializes in languages.
        For antiquarian books, go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathach Books</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke Street</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Temple</ENAMEX>
        Bar, the bookshop at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallery of Photography</ENAMEX> carries a large
        selection of photographic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flying Pig</ENAMEX> is a
        secondhand bookshop. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Winding Stair</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ormond Quay</ENAMEX> is an
        interesting, labyrinthine secondhand bookshop with a caf√©.
        Chocolates: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> handmade chocolates are on sale at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Butler‚Äôs Irish Chocolates in Grafton Street</ENAMEX>.
        Crafts: The most distinguished place for modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crafts</ENAMEX> and jewelry is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DesignYard</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Essex Street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Temple</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bar‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇeverything</ENAMEX> here is of high quality. For traditional crafts, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, on the corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau and Dawson</ENAMEX> carries a fine
        selection of jewelry, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crystal</ENAMEX>, and knitwear. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tower Craft Design</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pearse Street</ENAMEX>, off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Canal Quay</ENAMEX>, has a range of crafts
        made and sold on the premises.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waterford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cavan, Galway, Tipperary</ENAMEX>, and Tyrone
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal</ENAMEX> is sold everywhere, and prices do not vary. Try the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> (see above), or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Crystal Store</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wicklow Street</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Food</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunnes Stores</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILAC Center</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau Street</ENAMEX>) sells
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Irish smoked salmon</ENAMEX> (ask for the wild, not farmed, variety). For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
        country <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheeses</ENAMEX>, go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheridan‚Äôs Cheesemongers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Anne Street</ENAMEX>,
        or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Cheese Company</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity Street</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knitwear</ENAMEX>: There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds of knits for sale, expensive
        traditional knit-by-hand sweaters and sweaters ‚Äúhandknit‚Äù on a machine.
        For the former, be sure to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau Street</ENAMEX>.
        For the latter, bargains can be found at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blarney Woolen Mills</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>
        Street) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin Woolen Mills</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lower Ormond Quay</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kilkenny Shop</ENAMEX>
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau street</ENAMEX> carries a large variety of knitwear and handwoven
        goods. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T√°in</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Bar Square</ENAMEX>) has stylish handknits. Monaghan‚Äôs
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grafton Arcade</ENAMEX>) specializes in cashmere.
        Linens: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown Thomas</ENAMEX> has a great linen department <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX>.
        On the south end of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dawson Street</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Needle¬≠craft</ENAMEX>, specializing in fine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> linens.
        Music: If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">you‚Äôre</ENAMEX> looking for indigenous music, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtic</ENAMEX> Note
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau Street</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Claddagh Records</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Bar</ENAMEX>) carry a good
        selection of traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> recordings. You can‚Äôt
        miss <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMV</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grafton Street</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pottery and Porcelain: In Nassau Street the Kilkenny Shop</ENAMEX>
        has a fine selection.
        Souvenirs: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of Kells</ENAMEX> exhibition and
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viking Adventure</ENAMEX> carry large, comprehensive collections, and there
        are a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau Street</ENAMEX> that carry affordable reminders
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VAT Refunds</ENAMEX>
        Non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationals</ENAMEX> are entitled to a refund of the value
        added tax (VAT) charged on items that are purchased to be taken out of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Ask the shop for a validated receipt; the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cashback</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dublin Airport</ENAMEX> will give you an instant refund as you depart. Some
        tourist-oriented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VAT</ENAMEX> off credit-card purchases before
        they charge you. In that case, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX> must stamp the receipt, and you
        must return it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> by mail upon arriving home. Purchases
        shipped directly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> to a non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are not subject to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VAT</ENAMEX> (though you may incur import taxes). If you are traveling on to
        another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, you should collect your VAT refunds at your final
        point of departure for home.
        Entertainment
        Theater
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dublin</ENAMEX> has a proud tradition in theater which is still very
        much alive, so advance booking is advisable. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Abbey Theatre</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lower</ENAMEX>
        Abbey Street is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ireland‚Äôs</ENAMEX> national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>. Once on the cutting edge,
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> its more experimental repertoire is presented on its second
        stage, the intimate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peacock</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate Theatre</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Parnell Square</ENAMEX>, has a
        similar tradition, and stages a cosmopolitan mix of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> and
        international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs known for showcasing important new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">playwrights</ENAMEX>. In both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> you‚Äôll find the very highest standards of
        acting and production.
        The Victorian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympia</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dame Street</ENAMEX> is the venue for all
        sorts of popular theater, concerts, and variety shows. The Gaiety
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South King Street</ENAMEX> is worth visiting for its ornate d√©cor. It
        presents everything from legitimate plays to variety acts.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project Arts Centre in East Essex Street</ENAMEX> has a lively
        program of dance, drama, and performance arts. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews Lane</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">River¬≠bank Theatre</ENAMEX> (at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mer¬≠chant‚Äôs Quay</ENAMEX>) show
        inter¬≠na¬≠tional contemporary work. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Samuel Beckett Theatre</ENAMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity College</ENAMEX> is mainly for drama <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, it brings in some
        interesting shows in from outside.
        The most important event of the theater season is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dublin Theater Festival</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">festival</ENAMEX> is a showcase for
        international productions and new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> plays.
        Music
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Classical Concerts</ENAMEX>: If you are in search of a romantic
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> of live classical music, seek out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Symphony</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orchestra</ENAMEX>, which can be heard in a year-round program of concerts at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Concert Hall</ENAMEX> (NCH) in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Earlsfort Terrace</ENAMEX>. The RIT¬¥Concert
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orchestra</ENAMEX> also performs there. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> music concerts and recitals are
        given at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin‚Äôs Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX> in the beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surroundings</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Hospital</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Anne‚Äôs Church</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dawson Street</ENAMEX> has
        lunchtime concerts and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of Ireland Arts Centre</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foster</ENAMEX> Place
        off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Green</ENAMEX> has both a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunchtime and evening</TIMEX> concert series. See
        the Calendar of Events for music festivals. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCH</ENAMEX> also hosts jazz and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> evenings.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Opera Ireland</ENAMEX> (formerly the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dublin Grand Opera</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>) offers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">short spring</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter seasons</TIMEX> based on the standard
        repertoire at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gaiety Theatre</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King Street</ENAMEX>. The small but more
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enterprising Opera Theatre Company</ENAMEX> does <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> performances a
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> of short operas by contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> or baroque <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> at
        various venues.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX>, Folk, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz: The Royal Dublin Society</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballsbridge</ENAMEX> holds huge open-air concerts, including <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX>, and
        jazz. Another large venue is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Point</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East Link Bridge</ENAMEX>, which hosts
        major pop and rock acts (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riverdance</ENAMEX> was staged here). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX>
        carries listings for all such events, and In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> has
        up<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-to-the-minute</TIMEX> information. Some of the best music is heard at the
        mid-size venues: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympia Theatre</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Bar Music Centre</ENAMEX> in
        Curved Street, where you can hear everything from local acts to
        international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúDubcore‚Äù</ENAMEX> (alternative bands). The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Music Hall of Fame</ENAMEX> (IMHF), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">57 Middle Abbey Street</ENAMEX>, presents concerts
        and other events, along with its exhibits and audio-visual tour through
        the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> pop music.
        Dance
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dublin</ENAMEX> has a number of modern dance and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ballet companies</ENAMEX>
        that perform at various venues. For traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> dancing, go to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O‚ÄôShea‚Äôs Merchant</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pubs</ENAMEX>). Cult√∫rlann na h√âireann holds a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">c√©il√≠</ENAMEX> (an
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> of traditional song and dance), on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> in Monkstown
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">280 0295</ENAMEX>).
        Film
        O‚ÄôConnell Street is the main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>-center location for the
        big new-release cinemas. Art-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and international films are shown at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Film Centre</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eustace Street</ENAMEX>. The center contains the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Film Archive</ENAMEX>, an information <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, a bookshop, and a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">library</ENAMEX>. Its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cinemas</ENAMEX> present a varied program of new international
        and archival films. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Light House Cinema</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle Abbey Street</ENAMEX>, and
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Screen</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">D‚ÄôOlier Street</ENAMEX> also show international films. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">open-air</ENAMEX> movies are screened in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Meeting House Square</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Temple Bar</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nightclubs</ENAMEX>
        Quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> can be found along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Leeson Street</ENAMEX>,
        although some say ‚Äúthe strip‚Äù has faded a bit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>.
        Annabel‚Äôs is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> and disco located beneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burlington Hotel</ENAMEX> in
        Leeson Street. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry‚Äôs</ENAMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Henry Grattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Baggot Street</ENAMEX>,
        serves good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Temple Bar</ENAMEX> look for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club M</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloom‚Äôs Hotel</ENAMEX> in
        Anglesea Street, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bob‚Äôs Backstage Bar</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East Essex Street</ENAMEX>; the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Kitchen</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clarence Hotel</ENAMEX> is owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bono</ENAMEX> and the
        Edge of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U2</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ri Ra</ENAMEX> is a friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> located in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dame Street</ENAMEX>.
        Busloads flock nightly to hear middle-of-the-road <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
        cabaret at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jury‚Äôs Hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ballsbridge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doyle‚Äôs Irish Cabaret</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burlington Hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Leeson Street</ENAMEX>.
        As in every other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclubs</ENAMEX> quickly come and go, so
        it is essential to check the listings in local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> like In
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> or Events.
        Sports
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jogging</ENAMEX>: The best place is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix Park</ENAMEX>, where you can also
        relax and watch sports, especially on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf</ENAMEX> is very popular, and there are many superb
        courses in and around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Golf Club</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dollymount</ENAMEX> and
        many other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> welcome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>; advance booking is rarely required.
        Contact <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin Tourism</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golfing Union</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tel</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">269</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4111</TIMEX>, fax <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">269</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5368</TIMEX>, for information.
        Fishing: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea</ENAMEX> angling is permitted year rou nd, but river
        fishing requires a license. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin Tourism</ENAMEX> and any fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> can
        supply information.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator Sports</ENAMEX>: Ireland‚Äôs most famous sport, horse
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">racing</ENAMEX>, takes place at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leopardstown; The Curragh</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of
        flat racing, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hunt</ENAMEX> racing is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punchestown</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kildare</ENAMEX>. The premiere show jumping event is the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Kerrygold Horse Show</ENAMEX> at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RDS</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Greyhound racing</ENAMEX> is on at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shelbourne Park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ringsend</ENAMEX>, and at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Harold‚Äôs Cross Stadium</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rugby</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> (soccer) are played at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lansdowne Road</ENAMEX> venue in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ballsbridge</ENAMEX>, and traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> game of
        hurling at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Croke Park</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watersports/Beaches</ENAMEX>: There are beaches at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malahide</ENAMEX> and
        Dollymount, but the best are in the south at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bray</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Killiney</ENAMEX>. At
        Sandycove, below the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joyce Museum</ENAMEX>, is the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forty Foot</ENAMEX> bathing
        spot, once a men‚Äôs nude beach, but now open to everyone. It is not
        advisable to swim within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 miles</NUMEX>) of the city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> because of
        pollution.
        Children‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>
        There are plenty of things for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to enjoy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>.
        Note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> tickets are available for rail and bus services and
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 16</TIMEX> travel at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-fare on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DART</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eustace Street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Temple Bar</ENAMEX>, is a children‚Äôs
        cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> that offers a changing program of plays, workshops,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">readings</ENAMEX>, and performances, all geared toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs best to
        book in advance for the activities, as The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark</ENAMEX> has become quite
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">popular</ENAMEX>, and activities sometimes fill up in advance; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">670 7788</TIMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">fax 670 7758</ENAMEX>.
        Older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dublinia</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX>) and The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viking Adventure</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX>), a re-creation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> of Viking
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúDiflin.</ENAMEX> ‚Äù
        The self-guided <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock ‚Äôn‚Äô Stroll Trail</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>, which
        follows in the footsteps of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> rock legends, will appeal to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teenagers</ENAMEX>, as will the interactive displays and shows at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMHF</ENAMEX> (see page
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX>).
        Museums that will appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fry Model</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Railway Museum</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malahide Castle Estate</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX>), while the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Wax Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Granby Row</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">872 6340</ENAMEX>) has a special
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúChildren‚Äôs World‚</ENAMEX>Äù tableau depicting well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">fairy-tale</ENAMEX> characters
        and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of the Megastars</ENAMEX> devoted to pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX>. Older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX>
        should enjoy the tour of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin Castle</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Museum</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zoos</ENAMEX>: there are nature <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix Park</ENAMEX> and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin Zoo</ENAMEX> has a pet corner and zoo train especially designed for
        younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restaurants</ENAMEX>: Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and caf√©s welcome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
        Some suggestions are <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chompy‚Äôs in the Powerscourt Townhouse Centre, The</ENAMEX>
        Bistro for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pasta</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Market</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fitzer‚</ENAMEX>Äôs caf√©s, and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coffee Dock Grill</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jury‚Äôs Hotel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ballsbridge</ENAMEX>, which provides a
        special menu just for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
