
  
  
    
      
        Where to Go
        The island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> offers a wealth of activities, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>,
        and attractions. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> choose to remain in a single <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> area
        and enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature comforts</ENAMEX> of beach, restaurant, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclub</ENAMEX>.
        Others are eager to explore <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">nature‚Äôs wildlife</ENAMEX> at the bottom of a coral
        reef or at the top of a mountain peak. Wherever you go in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamaica‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇfrom the tropical coasts to the rugged interior to the
        secluded eastern tip of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">island‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇyou‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find fascinating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">landscapes</ENAMEX>. In this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, we journey clockwise around the island,
        starting at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montego Bay</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northwest</ENAMEX> coast. Along the way, you‚Äôre
        sure to discover places you never knew existed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>, worth an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hour‚Äôs</ENAMEX> visit or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> of exploration.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montego Bay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ocho Rios</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Coast</ENAMEX>
        The northern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">coast</ENAMEX> has been the major focus of tourist
        development on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. Much of the new development has
        occurred here, and in some places this has changed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the
        landscape. However, there‚Äôs no denying that this area has just about
        everything needed for a perfect holiday, whether you want to do nothing
        but sit on a beach, dive and snorkel along the coral reefs, enjoy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sports</ENAMEX>, or explore the history and culture of the island.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montego Bay</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äú MoBay‚Äù</ENAMEX> (as it‚Äôs called by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>) is probably the most
        complete <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> area in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>, with its beaches, sports, and shopping
        along with a large number of fine hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX>. It is almost nonstop
        fun, and because it is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only minutes</TIMEX> from the international <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>,
        there is no lengthy transfer to your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is also surrounded
        by a host of different attractions. Its disadvantage, if it matters, is
        a lack of attractiveness: it is a rather soulless hodgepodge of
        development with no real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. But if you are here simply to have
        fun, you might not even notice.
        This tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">heartland</ENAMEX> is also home to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jamaicans</ENAMEX> who
        live in the hills surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. Originally named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Villa</ENAMEX> Manteca
        by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> (‚<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ÄúFat City</ENAMEX>,‚Äù because they used to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butcher</ENAMEX> wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX> in
        the area), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montego Bay</ENAMEX> developed into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar cane</ENAMEX> and
        became a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana port</ENAMEX> under colonial rule. During <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
        built an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> here that later became the international
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">airport</ENAMEX>. This and the harbor, which attracts modern cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>,
        guaranteed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Montego Bay</ENAMEX> a large slice of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica‚Äôs</ENAMEX> tourist action.
        Downtown
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> sits on the east side of the wide bay, with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cruise port</ENAMEX> on the west. Downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montego Bay</ENAMEX> is located between the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. It is a jumble of loud and boisterous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX> breathing the fumes of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of makeshift shacks sell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> or cigarettes, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of</NUMEX>
        oil-barrel barbecues cook jerk <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">burgers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Roads</ENAMEX> meet at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sam</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sharpe Square</ENAMEX>, originally <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Square</ENAMEX> but renamed after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1831</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> rebellion who was hung for his part in the uprising. In
        one corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX>, an old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison lockup</ENAMEX> built in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1806</TIMEX> to house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drunken sailors</ENAMEX> or runaway <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ring</ENAMEX>, the site
        of the once-regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> auction. However, this isn‚Äôt the place to be
        after dark.
        Nearby, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fustic Street Craft Market</ENAMEX> is a constant buzz of
        activity. This is the place to come to check out the full range of
        local handicrafts and souvenirs. The windows and doors of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 100</NUMEX>
        wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cabins</ENAMEX> are bedecked with printed sarongs, T-shirts, and carved
        masks. Try your hand at haggling and you are guaranteed to get a better
        price than you thought.
        Just on the outskirts of downtown are a couple of shopping
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> that carry international duty-free goods. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montego Bay</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Centre</ENAMEX> is air-conditioned and under cover, but the newer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Centre</ENAMEX> has the added attraction of well-known fast food
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outlets‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇfor</ENAMEX> that little touch of home.
        Beaches and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resorts</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> east to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gloucester Avenue ‚Äústrip‚Äù</ENAMEX> for the beaches
        and resort life. This is the place to be for all the action, with some
        of the busiest bars, loudest music, and wildest water sports on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island</ENAMEX>. As you reach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gloucester Avenue</ENAMEX>, you‚Äôll pass the remains of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Fort</ENAMEX>, with its small sturdy walls and heavy cannon that guarded the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bay</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>.
        Most beaches in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MoBay</ENAMEX> are private, which means you pay a
        small fee to enter. They are kept neat and tidy, with water-sports
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> and areas for changing and showering. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one along
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Fletcher Beach</ENAMEX>, which on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> is popular with
        the town <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwellers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montego Bay</ENAMEX>. You can almost feel the beat of the
        music booming across the sand from all the portable radios and tape
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>.
        Farther along the strip is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doctor‚Äôs Cave Beach</ENAMEX>, the
        original <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montego Bay</ENAMEX> beach developed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Edwardian</ENAMEX> era when sea
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bathing</ENAMEX> became a popular pastime throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Empire</ENAMEX>. It
        became a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for wealthy and upper-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> and was donated to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1906</TIMEX> by the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>. It is still as popular as ever
        and the sand is sublime, but the cave after which the beach was
        originally named was destroyed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1930s</TIMEX> during a hurricane.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cornwall Beach</ENAMEX>, another private beach with perfect sand and sheltered
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">waters</ENAMEX>, can be found behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica Tourist Office</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, a
        short distance east along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gloucester Avenue</ENAMEX>.
        West of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX>
        The cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montego Bay Freeport</ENAMEX>, sits on an
        outcrop on the west side of the bay. It is a popular stop on cruise
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">itineraries</ENAMEX>. There is a small shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> on site, but the main
        duty-free <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> and the beaches are <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only minutes</TIMEX> away. This area is
        also home to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montego Bay Yacht Club</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> a number of
        yachting regattas through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. You can hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> here to take a
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full day</TIMEX> out at sea for sport fishing or just a relaxing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jaunt</ENAMEX>.
        A little way off the coast is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montego Bay Marine Park</ENAMEX>,
        established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">26 sq km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 sq miles</NUMEX>) of reef,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sea</ENAMEX>-grass, and mangrove swamps and covers an area west of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to
        the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Montego Bay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>. A number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> offer underwater
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tours</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>-bottomed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> or submersible <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>, or you can rent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">snorkel</ENAMEX> or scuba gear to get a closer look yourself. These can be
        booked from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pier 1</ENAMEX>, a small marina with caf√©s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>
        that sits in the middle of the bay between the beaches and the cruise
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">port</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South of the Bay</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South of Montego Bay</ENAMEX> there are a number of attractions that
        make enjoyable excursions, if you want to tear yourself away from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">beach</ENAMEX> or book an outing from your cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barnett Estate</ENAMEX>, with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its 18th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">great house</ENAMEX>, has
        been owned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerr-Jarrett</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 250 years</TIMEX>. Their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ancestor Nicholas Jarrett</ENAMEX> arrived on the island in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1655</TIMEX>, and the family
        was at the forefront of economic and political activities on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX>
        for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>. They once owned almost all the land on which
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montego Bay</ENAMEX> now stands. You‚Äôll be able to tour the still-operating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">plantation</ENAMEX> and wander around the great <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, which has been restored
        with many original touches.
        Near the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anchovy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocklands Bird Sanctuary</ENAMEX> offers a
        fascinating close-up encounter with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX>
        began almost by accident in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1950s</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Salmon</ENAMEX>
        moved onto a plot of land high in the hills above <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montego Bay</ENAMEX>. She
        loved the hummingbirds that inhabited the garden and began to befriend
        them so that they came regularly for feeding. Now you, too, can come
        eye-to-eye with these beautiful tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX> provides
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar water</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX> so that you can feed them. The buzzing sound of
        the wings signals their approach and, if you are lucky, they will fly
        up and perch on your finger to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.
        High in the hills <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">27 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">17 miles</NUMEX>) south of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montego Bay</ENAMEX> is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belvedere Estate</ENAMEX>. It is a working <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX> producing a mixed crop of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruits</ENAMEX>, but it also opens a fascinating window on plantation
        life during colonial times. The current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> have created an
        agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> to demonstrate the traditional methods of crop
        production as well as everyday life on the plantation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> wear
        traditional clothing and work with the tools of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forefathers</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> even be able to consult a traditional herbalist to cure your
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ailments</ENAMEX>. Swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> add a modern dimension to the
        trip.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Road</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX> along the main <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montego Bay area</ENAMEX>,
        there is a string of luxurious resort <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> like golf
        courses and equestrian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ironshore</ENAMEX> and
        Half <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon Resort</ENAMEX> have duty-free shopping and fast food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>. A
        number of sightseeing attractions lie along this route, which leads to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falmouth</ENAMEX> and, eventually, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocho Rios</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rose Hall Great House</ENAMEX> is, perhaps, the most infamous house
        in the whole of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. Set high on a hill above the coast with
        commanding views, it was built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Palmer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 18th century</TIMEX>
        and named after his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose</ENAMEX>. It later became the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annie Palmer</ENAMEX>
        when she married into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>; it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annie</ENAMEX> who has given the house
        its fame and reputation. She was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who struck fear into the heart
        of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. They said that she was a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witch</ENAMEX> with
        potent magical powers who had murdered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> and an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">unidentified</ENAMEX> number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> before she herself died under mysterious
        circumstances. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locals</ENAMEX>, who believed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was haunted by her
        spirit, buried her nearby so that she could be reunited with her body
        and rest in peace.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> fell into ruin after emancipation, when fear of
        the witch‚Äôs influence drove the plantation‚Äôs slaves away. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX> it
        was bought by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rollins</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, who began the difficult and
        time-consuming job of totally renovating the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX> mahogany
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wood</ENAMEX> cut from <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> from the surrounding estate has been use to great
        effect in the refurbished <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> where new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> and ceilings had to be
        built. The interior has been redecorated with fabrics and furniture
        dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1700s</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> times. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballroom</ENAMEX> has a woven
        wall-covering that is a reproduction of an original by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philipe de la</ENAMEX>
        Salle, which he created for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marie Antoinette</ENAMEX>. Be sure to experience the
        beautiful views from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annie Palmer‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs sitting room</ENAMEX>, where you
        can see along the coast and catch a cooling sea breeze. Here, it is
        said, she plotted the death of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>.
        Farther east, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenwood Great House</ENAMEX> was once the property
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the wealthiest and most powerful colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. The first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barrett</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">invading English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> were major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landowners</ENAMEX> from the
        middle of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX> and played an important role throughout the
        colonial history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>, holding positions of great influence in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX> and administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>. Another (and perhaps more
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">famous</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Barrett</ENAMEX>, who married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Browning</ENAMEX>. She was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> but never came to the island:
        the responsibility for working the plantation lands fell to her male
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>.
        This <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, begun in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1780</TIMEX>, was only one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barrett</ENAMEX>
        properties in the area and was built for entertaining rather than for
        use as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> (the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barrett</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cinnamon Hills</ENAMEX>, is now owned
        by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Cash</ENAMEX>). It is now home to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bettin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, who
        are custodians of its treasures. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> has many original features
        and authentic touches. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furniture</ENAMEX> and art collected over the generations
        fills the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, but perhaps most fascinating is the collection of
        original musical instruments and machines used for entertainment before
        the advent of electricity. A fine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX> piano, a polyphone
        machine with disks, and a pianola were all used for dancing or recitals
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballroom</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> is the largest of any <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 300</NUMEX> volumes, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> first editions; the
        books would have been used to while away the long <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">humid days</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1826</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Barrett</ENAMEX> won <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">¬£800</NUMEX> in a competition when the house‚Äôs entryway was
        selected as the best mile of macadam <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. The approach to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> must have been truly spectacular at that time, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you
        must drive with a little care, as its condition is a bit rough.
        Just before reaching the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falmouth</ENAMEX> you‚Äôll find
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica Safari Village</ENAMEX>, home of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jamaican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crocodile</ENAMEX> and other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tropical creatures</ENAMEX>. This wetland area covers a vast amount of mangrove
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">swamp</ENAMEX> and has been turned into a nature theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. You can travel by
        boat into the very heart of the swamp to get a close-up look at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">secretive creatures</ENAMEX>. Scenes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX> film <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live and Let Die</ENAMEX>
        were filmed here.
        Falmouth
        Once an important <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> for the shipment of molasses and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falmouth</ENAMEX> has many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1800s</TIMEX>. But
        despite its colonial heritage, most visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Falmouth</ENAMEX> because it is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> for rafting on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Martha Brae River</ENAMEX>. It is one of the most
        popular activities on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">river</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">48 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX>) long, and the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11‚ÅÑ2-hour</TIMEX> raft ride covers <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 miles</NUMEX>) of
        navigable river that meanders through the lush countryside, where you
        can take in the verdant river <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and the peace and quiet. It‚Äôs a
        cool and relaxing way to be pushed along, almost like a tropical
        gondola ride. Each raft is hand-built by the raft captains to carry <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. The rafts are made of bamboo from the surrounding countryside
        and can be used for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only four months</TIMEX> before they have to be
        replaced.
        Just to the east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is a small scruffy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bay</ENAMEX> that comes
        to life at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. Called by several names (including <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúGlistening
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Waters‚Äù and ‚ÄúLuminous Lagoon‚Äù</ENAMEX>), it is officially known as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oyster Bay</ENAMEX>.
        Once darkness falls, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in the bay is filled with luminescent
        micro-organisms that glow when agitated. It is almost as if someone has
        immersed a neon light in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. You can take <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> cruise to
        watch this fascinating phenomenon and dip a hand in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to make
        it happen yourself.
        From Cockpit Country to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Ann‚Äôs Bay</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South of Falmouth</ENAMEX> you‚Äôll find Cockpit Country, an amazing
        and almost impenetrable landscape of limestone plateau (or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äúkarst‚Äù</ENAMEX>)
        pitted with holes and fissures that have created many fantastic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">formations</ENAMEX>. Deep <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depressions</ENAMEX> and high outcrops are blanketed by layers
        of green vegetation and topped by a lush canopy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, making travel
        difficult and sometimes dangerous. It is here that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maroon</ENAMEX> people
        chose to live after they had been freed by their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1655</TIMEX>.
        Even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> there are few <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">roads‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇthis really is one of the
        last true vestiges of wilderness in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. Because much of the area
        is inhospitable to human activity, it is a lush area for birdlife and
        rare <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">plant species</ENAMEX> that have disappeared from other parts of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island</ENAMEX>. You can find <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of caves in the limestone fissures, and
        some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intrepid visitors</ENAMEX> go ‚Äúspelunking,‚Äù exploring their watery
        interiors. If you want to see the area or investigate the caves, do
        take a guide and go well prepared.
        Scattered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Maroon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> remain, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> still
        making a meager living out of the poor soil. Tours of the village of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accompong</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Arawak</ENAMEX> cave drawings nearby can be arranged
        through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica Tourist Board</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the best times to visit is in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early January</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Maroon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hold a major festival.
        Farther east along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">coast</ENAMEX> lies <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Discovery Bay</ENAMEX>, said to be
        the place where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> landed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1494</TIMEX> on his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> journey from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>. The precise location is still disputed, as some say that he
        landed farther along the coastline. Nevertheless, a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> on the
        roadside at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discovery Bay</ENAMEX> stands as a tribute to his achievement.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus Park</ENAMEX> is built on land donated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser Bauxite Company</ENAMEX>,
        whose industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">site</ENAMEX> now dominates the bay. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Park</ENAMEX> includes an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eclectic</ENAMEX> collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> from the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX>: old railway
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">memorabilia</ENAMEX>, artifacts from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar cane</ENAMEX> processing <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX>, and a
        banana-tallying machine can all be found here.
        Just outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Discovery Bay</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Runaway Caves</ENAMEX>, which are
        easily accessible and safe to explore. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> stretches <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up to 16 km</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 miles</NUMEX>) inland and includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green Grotto</ENAMEX>, a vast cavern with an
        underground lake where stalactites are clearly reflected in the glassy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arawak</ENAMEX> paintings, though fading, can still be seen on the walls
        of the caves. Guided tours are well organized and include a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> trip
        on the lake.
        The main polo season in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> sees match after match on
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pristine grass</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chukka Cove</ENAMEX>. For those who like other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>-riding activities, there is also an equestrian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> that
        organizes exhilarating rides on the beach and trips along guided trails
        through the surrounding hills.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Runaway Bay</ENAMEX> is the appropriately named area of coastline
        where slaves were said to have escaped the island to try to find a
        better life; often they traveled the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">145 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">90 miles</NUMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. Today
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Runaway Bay</ENAMEX> is one of the newest and fastest developing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northern</ENAMEX> coast. A series of hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> has sprung up to take
        advantage of the fine beaches. The diving and snorkeling opportunities
        along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">reef wall</ENAMEX> here are said to be the best in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. Most
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotels</ENAMEX> offer instruction and organized dives out to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ricky‚Äôs Reef</ENAMEX> or the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canyon</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major reef areas. There are also a couple of small aircraft
        lying offshore (relics of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runners</ENAMEX> who ran out of luck) that make
        fascinating artificial dive sites.
        In the hills south of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Runaway Bay</ENAMEX> is the village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nine</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mile</ENAMEX>. This is where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> and social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Marley</ENAMEX> was
        born and spent the early part of his life. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> is tiny and a
        total contrast to the bustle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trenchtown</ENAMEX> ghetto in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingston</ENAMEX>,
        where he lived as a recording <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX>. Marley‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> was brought here
        after his death and lies in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum</ENAMEX>, where he is buried with his
        prized guitar. The surrounding land and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> under which he sat as
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> have been turned into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>, but the ambiance
        is spoiled by the numerous ‚Äúguides‚Äù and souvenir <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> who crowd your
        path to the entrance. Inside the compound you‚Äôll find genuine
        Rastafarian guides. The whole site is painted in the bright green, red,
        and yellow colors that represent nature, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, and sunshine. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marley Mausoleum</ENAMEX> lies in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> with other symbols of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rastafarian</ENAMEX> faith, including a photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haile Selassie</ENAMEX> (their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spiritual</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judah</ENAMEX> depicted on a stained glass
        window.
        To the east is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Ann‚Äôs Bay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX> of the black
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">activist Marcus Garvey</ENAMEX>. His statue can be found on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main Street</ENAMEX>, outside
        the town <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>. It is also the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sevilla la Nueva</ENAMEX>, the original
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> settlement on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>, founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1509</TIMEX>, which sits just to the
        west of the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbus</ENAMEX> is said to have landed here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1503</TIMEX>
        when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> was in a desperate state of repair. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>
        were abandoned in the harbor but, despite many attempts by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archaeologists</ENAMEX> to locate them, they have never been found. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbus</ENAMEX>
        spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some months</TIMEX> at an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arawak</ENAMEX> settlement here before assistance
        arrived and he made his way back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> built a sugar <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1515</TIMEX> and
        attempted to develop the site, but the persistent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fevers</ENAMEX> contracted
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mosquitoes</ENAMEX> in the swamps forced them to move and create a new
        capital at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Spanish Town</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1538</TIMEX>. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sevilla la Nueva</ENAMEX> was not
        completely abandoned, continuing as a working <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum</ENAMEX>
        distillery that were later developed and expanded under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> rule.
        The most obvious remains at the site <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX> from this time. There are
        vestiges of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">distillery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle pens</ENAMEX>, and a large pimento
        barbecue for roasting allspice <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">berries</ENAMEX>. Older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">remains</ENAMEX> lie scattered
        along the shoreline and in shallow <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> beyond the tidal reach. Many
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> are being actively excavated and look a little ramshackle. A
        small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> great <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> displays finds from the
        site.
        Ocho Rios
        Jamaica‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is a relatively recent
        creation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ocho Rios</ENAMEX> began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> when the site of a fishing
        village was systematically developed with the express aim of turning it
        into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX>. There are several large hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> here, and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> is a popular destination for cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, with several ships
        calling at the port <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ocho Rios</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> for ‚Äúeight rivers,‚Äù but this name is
        not descriptive of the area. It is thought that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> was named
        following an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> mistranslation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> phrase las
        chorreros, meaning <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúriver rapids</ENAMEX>,‚Äù as there are a number of these near
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. There is very little left of old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocho Rios</ENAMEX>: the scant remains
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ocho Rios Fort</ENAMEX> are probably the oldest and now lie in an industrial
        area, almost forgotten as the tide of progress has swept over the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX>.
        The main waterfront area, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turtle Beach</ENAMEX>, sits in front of
        the town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. It is a wide arc of sand, shallow and sheltered. You
        must pay a small fee to enter, but the sand is kept clean and there are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> and refreshments available. You‚Äôll be able to hire a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> to
        take you out to the reef that runs all along the coast here, easily
        seen just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few hundred meters</NUMEX> from the shore; snorkeling offers the
        opportunity to observe a wealth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and other sea creatures.
        Jamaica‚Äôs largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radisson Renaissance Grande Hotel</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overlooks Turtle Beach</ENAMEX>.
        The main activity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is shopping. In fact, Ocho
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rios</ENAMEX> is a virtual shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> for the cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> who arrive in
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most days of the week</TIMEX>. There are a number of expensive
        jewelry and other duty-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, all with goods priced in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">US dollars</NUMEX>
        (duty-free goods must always be paid for in foreign currency). It‚Äôs a
        veritable treasure-trove of quality gems, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, and cigars. Take a look
        around the incongruous pink <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj Mahal</ENAMEX> shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soni‚</ENAMEX>Äôs in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> of town. The latter complex, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, probably has
        the widest choice. There is also a thriving craft market behind the
        main beach, where you will be able to haggle for locally produced
        goods, from a T-shirt to a necklace of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">semiprecious stones</ENAMEX>. Once the
        business day stops, there are few bars and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>;
        evening activity tends to focus on the large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ocho Rios</ENAMEX>, though not the prettiest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> on the island, has
        a number of advantages as a destination choice. It has beautiful
        natural attractions nearby, and it makes a good base for other, longer
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journeys</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>, being within relatively easy reach of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kingston</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Mountains</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> that leads to both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montego Bay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Antonio</ENAMEX>.
        Dunn‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">River Falls</ENAMEX>
        If you visit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> place on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> outside your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>,
        then this should be it: a place of fantastic natural beauty and flowing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> that epitomizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arawak</ENAMEX> name for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xaymaca</ENAMEX> (‚Äúland of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wood</ENAMEX> and water‚Äù). Only <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 miles</NUMEX>) west of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocho Rios, Dunn‚Äôs River</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falls</ENAMEX> is a series of limestone cascades that carry the water of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunn‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        River almost to the sea. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cascades</ENAMEX> fill with clear water and are
        surrounded by overhanging vegetation. Modern tradition demands that you
        climb up through the bubbling cascades as part of a human <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>. Lines
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, all holding hands, do a slightly wobbly ‚Äúconga‚Äù to the top,
        where everyone forgets decorum and gets very wet in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs fun
        and totally tropical, but you‚Äôll be very lucky if you have the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> to
        yourself to enjoy the kind of romantic experience advertised in the
        tourist brochures.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guides</ENAMEX> are optional, but they are sure-footed and will take
        care of your camera until you reach the top. Don‚Äôt forget to take a
        change of clothing and a towel. There are wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">walkways</ENAMEX> at the side
        of the falls for those who don‚Äôt want to get quite so wet.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plantations</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> leading south from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocho Rios</ENAMEX> climbs out of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> and twists and turns through a narrow valley of tropical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vegetation</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fern Gully</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Five km</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 miles</NUMEX>) of giant cottonwood
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, with their tangle of thick roots, frame varieties of giant fern
        to create a canopy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fronds</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leafy branches</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Insects</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">frogs</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> call together in a cacophony of sound. It feels so
        humid in the midst of the vegetation‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwith sunlight streaming through
        the upper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> and steam rising from the damp ground‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthat you can
        imagine being on the set of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">prehistoric dinosaur</ENAMEX> film.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ocho Rios</ENAMEX> is surrounded by not only areas of natural beauty
        but also by landscaped tropical splendor. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> gardens in
        the area, all admired among gardening connoisseurs and all with
        different specialties to explore. Choose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, or visit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> to get
        a comprehensive overview of tropical environments, not to mention some
        pointers for caring for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> that can be purchased back home.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Coyaba River Garden</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coyaba</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arawak</ENAMEX> word
        for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúparadise,‚Äù and this garden, set high above <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocho Rios</ENAMEX>, lives up to
        its name. <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Plants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, and native <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> are complemented by rivers
        and streams teaming with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX>. The small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> at the site
        traces the history of the island from the time of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arawak</ENAMEX>.
        The gardens of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carinosa</ENAMEX> (owned by ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seaga</ENAMEX>) are famed for their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Orchid House</ENAMEX>, which propagates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>.
        The gardens also have collections of caged <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> and small <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw Park Gardens</ENAMEX> has perhaps the best panoramic views of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>,
        with distant views over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocho Rios</ENAMEX>. Set on the hillside above the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>,
        it comprises <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">14 hectares</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35 acres</NUMEX>) of tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and natural
        waterfalls that once formed the grounds of the now-closed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw Park</ENAMEX>
        Hotel.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">White River</ENAMEX> runs east from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocho Rios</ENAMEX> and marks the
        boundary between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Mary Parish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Ann Parish</ENAMEX>. River rafting
        takes place here, and although the journey is not as long as at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brae</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX>), it is possible to enjoy a swim at a natural pool as
        part of the trip, so bring along some swimwear. You can also enjoy an
        evening river cruise, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are lit with torches. Turn off the
        main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> just before the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">White River Bridge</ENAMEX> to find the Calypso
        rafting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>.
        On the main <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> east out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocho Rios</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prospect</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plantation</ENAMEX>, which offers tours by jitney and horse <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> through crops
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX>, plantains, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar cane</ENAMEX>. The well-informed guides
        will give you plenty of information about the natural and introduced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flora</ENAMEX> of the island. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> settled the land and grew <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> here
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX>, but the fine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúgreat house‚Äù</ENAMEX> was built by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX> was bought in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX> by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industrialist</ENAMEX> Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Mitchell</ENAMEX> and became an important focus
        for diplomatic, political, and social activities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. Many
        important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dignitaries</ENAMEX> have visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and it has become a
        tradition for <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> to be planted to mark each special occasion. The
        tour passes <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> planted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Royal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luxembourg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
        Young, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>, among many others. You can also plant
        your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> at the plantation, which can grow next to those planted
        by the ‚Äúgreat and good. ‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX> also houses a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX>
        for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the brainchild of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Mitchell</ENAMEX>. It promotes the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ideal</ENAMEX> of good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> through hard work and community service. Many
        former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academy students</ENAMEX> have gone on to high rank in the diplomatic and
        civil services.
        A little farther east is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harmony Hall</ENAMEX>, a beautiful
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methodist</ENAMEX> minister‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1886</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, which has been
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art gallery</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, has been elegantly preserved with
        pretty painted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood fretwork</ENAMEX> and stained shutters. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> on the
        upper floor boasts a collection of some the best art and crafts in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. Original paintings from local and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest artists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ceramics</ENAMEX>, and
        a collection of imported <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crafts</ENAMEX> make it a good place to find a souvenir
        of high quality. Beneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>. During
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> there are many exhibitions and performances in the gardens
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>; ask at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> for information.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Firefly</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annotto Bay</ENAMEX>
        The coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> continues east through the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of
        Oracabessa, with its decaying iron <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fretwork</ENAMEX>, and on to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Galina Point</ENAMEX>,
        the most northerly part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. Set high on a bluff overlooking the
        coastline at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galina Point</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Firefly</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel Coward</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dean</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> theater and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> and the archetypal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coward</ENAMEX> had the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> and lived here until his death,
        creating a haven where he could be out of the public eye. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is
        surprisingly small and simple, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>, a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>, and a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of social <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>. What makes it special is its position, with
        magnificent views of the coastline east toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Antonio</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">southeast</ENAMEX> to the peaks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Mountain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">range</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">song ‚ÄúA Room</ENAMEX>
        with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">View</ENAMEX>,‚Äù which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coward</ENAMEX> wrote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>, inspired him to build the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> on this spot.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties Coward</ENAMEX> held here were legendary. Film stars
        such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Taylor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophia Loren</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Chaplin</ENAMEX> were
        entertained with songs at the grand pianos that still sit in the main
        room. Coward valued his private life, however, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> were never
        allowed to stay overnight at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Firefly</ENAMEX>. In fact, there was no room for
        them. They were given guest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Harbour</ENAMEX>, another house
        farther down the hill that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coward</ENAMEX> also owned; it can clearly be seen
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Firefly‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garden</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coward</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> and is buried in the garden, at his
        favorite spot overlooking the coastline. His simple gravestone is
        decorated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> with a small vase of fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>. A short video
        presentation in the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> gives a fascinating background to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and his prodigious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>.
        Also on the grounds is a small, sturdy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, much older
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Coward‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Morgan</ENAMEX> and his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of cut-throats used the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> to plan their dastardly deeds.
        With tiny windows and thick walls, it made a perfect secret hideaway
        for counting stolen ‚Äúpieces of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>. ‚Äù
        Nearby is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of another famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, an author
        whose fictitious main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> has taken on an almost-real persona.
        Goldeneye was home to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Fleming</ENAMEX> when he wrote all the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúJames Bond‚</ENAMEX>Äù
        novels. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fleming</ENAMEX> came to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX> while serving in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>, decided to settle here, and bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>.
        Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bond</ENAMEX> was noted for his bravery and prowess, he was in fact
        named after a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of very different talents: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleming</ENAMEX> took the name of
        his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚Äú007‚</NUMEX>Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the book <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Birds</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Indies</ENAMEX>,
        which had been researched and written <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years earlier</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is
        not open to the public.
        Inland from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Firefly</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brimmer Hall Plantation</ENAMEX>, a working
        plantation of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">809 hectares</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,000 acres</NUMEX>) that produces a variety of
        crops including <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coconuts</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">citrus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>. It has a beautiful
        great <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, made (unusually) of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> and filled with an eclectic
        collection of furniture from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Empire</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tour</ENAMEX>, by jitney, shows how the plantation works, with knowledgeable
        staff to answer questions and give demonstrations of such skills as the
        correct technique for climbing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>.
        The main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> continues to hug the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">north coast</ENAMEX>, but just
        before reaching <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Annotto Bay</ENAMEX> there is a turn south in the direction of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingston</ENAMEX>. Take this route to reach <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Castleton Botanical Gardens</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 18</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">km</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11 miles</NUMEX>) inland. The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">37 hectares</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">91 acres</NUMEX>) of garden are set on
        lands above the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wag Wag River</ENAMEX>, which twists through a steep and narrow
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">valley</ENAMEX>. They were landscaped in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1862</TIMEX> with a large consignment of plants
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kew Gardens</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. Exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> from every corner of the
        British <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> were subsequently brought here before being transplanted
        to other gardens on the island. It might not be the oldest, but
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castleton</ENAMEX> is regarded by many as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúfather‚Äù</ENAMEX> of tropical gardens in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> because of its work in the propagation and distribution of new
        plant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genera</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Antonio</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Mountains</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">eastern</ENAMEX> area of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> is the most tropical and
        (according to many) most beautiful part of the island. The high peaks
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Mountains</ENAMEX> dominate the landscape. This is where swathes of
        lush virgin rainforest mix with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> on the high
        mountain slopes and meet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">verdant banana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> that
        blanket the coastal plains. The mountains attract moisture sweeping
        across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic Ocean</ENAMEX> and are thus often swathed in heavy rain
        clouds that feed the forests and fill numerous streams and rivers.
        There are few major <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> in this area. The main route follows the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coastline</ENAMEX>, circumventing the mountains and leading to some of the
        least-visited areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> that are totally off the tourist
        track.
        The western approach to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Antonio</ENAMEX> is characterized by
        huge groves of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX>, which in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> times made the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> one
        of the richest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>. All along the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">coast</ENAMEX> here you
        will see remains of the old railway line, which once linked the
        plantations to the port but now mostly provides a place for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to
        play or <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> to graze. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station houses</ENAMEX>, however, still give an
        impression of the grandeur of the recent past. The line was just closed
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, but with the speed at which the native <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> have reclaimed
        the land, it might have been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred years ago</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Antonio</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Antonio</ENAMEX> dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1723</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> was called
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúTitchfield‚Äù</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">estate</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>, who was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> at the time. Expansion began after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1739</TIMEX> peace
        treaty with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maroons</ENAMEX>, who lived inland south of the site. The area
        proved unsuitable for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar cane</ENAMEX> production, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1871</TIMEX> fruit shippers
        began to take locally grown <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX> back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, and the trade was an immediate success.
        In its heyday <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Antonio</ENAMEX> was the undisputed ‚Äúbanana
        capital of the world,‚Äù with an additional benefit: the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>
        brought the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> traveled out on the
        empty <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and stayed in the area after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> took their ripening
        cargo back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. Only the rich could afford to travel
        in this style, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Antonio</ENAMEX> developed into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for high-class
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tourism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fine hotels</ENAMEX> catered to the visitors‚Äô every need, and the town
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reveled</ENAMEX> in the money brought in from abroad.
        Those days are long gone, as is the booming <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX> market:
        exports from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> broke the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> monopoly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>.
        However, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Antonio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX> still has a buzz of activity, especially
        in the harvesting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, as all of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Jamaica‚Äôs banana</ENAMEX> exports
        leave from here. The manual counting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúhands‚Äù and ‚Äúbunches‚Äù</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bananas</ENAMEX> (recounted in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Harry Belafonte‚Äôs famous ‚ÄúBanana Boat Song‚Äù</ENAMEX>) was
        mechanized in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, but the work of loading the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> is still
        labor intensive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Antonio Yacht Club</ENAMEX> can also be found in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">harbor</ENAMEX>. This is the center for sport <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fishing‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇespecially</ENAMEX> for blue
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marlin</ENAMEX>, which are found in the surrounding waters. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Port Antonio</ENAMEX> plays
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">International Blue Marlin Tournament</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>,
        when the harbor is filled with large and expensive sport-fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>
        from around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nestled</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Mountains</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> has a
        beautiful setting. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> wide bays offer natural harbors, and tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Island</ENAMEX> sits just offshore. This was the island bought by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Errol Flynn</ENAMEX>
        when he settled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Antonio</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>; he used it merely as a garden
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">extension</ENAMEX> for the large <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">yacht</ENAMEX> he moored there. His drinking parties
        were legendary, and he is fondly remembered by older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in the town
        as a charming rogue. Take the small ferry from the harbor to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX>, where you can walk through the woodland or sunbathe on the
        small beaches. The once-private <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is now a hotel and
        restaurant.
        The headland between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main bays is called ‚ÄúThe
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill‚Äù</ENAMEX>; here you will find the oldest part of town. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> of
        wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Antonio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> sat away from the bustle of the busy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">port</ENAMEX> in a grid of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> has fallen into
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decay</ENAMEX>, but there are still vestiges of its fine history to be seen.
        Ornate ironwork now rusts, wooden fretwork <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">molds</ENAMEX>, and paint <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">peels</ENAMEX>, yet
        there remains a beauty about this aging finery. Nearby on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. George‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        Street is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. George‚Äôs Village</ENAMEX>, an area of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> and caf√©s designed
        as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quirky ‚ÄúAmsterdam street</ENAMEX> meets <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">piazza‚Äù mall</ENAMEX>. The whole
        idea is the brainchild of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baroness</ENAMEX> who also owns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palace</ENAMEX>
        Hotel, one of the smartest in town.
        On the eastern peninsula tip is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Folly</ENAMEX>, the remains of a
        large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> surrounded by legend and mystery. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Locals</ENAMEX> will tell you
        that it was built for a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> who brought his new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. As he carried her over the threshold, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> began to
        collapse and she fled, leaving him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">forever</TIMEX>; his business subsequently
        failed and he became a broken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. There are few <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grains</ENAMEX> of truth in
        this story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>, a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Neo-Classical Italian villa</ENAMEX>, was
        actually built for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Mitchell</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> who lived here with his
        family for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX>. Unfortunately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cement</ENAMEX> used for its
        construction contained sea sand, which caused the iron reinforcing rods
        to corrode. This eventually weakened the structure and it collapsed.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> now lies covered in undergrowth and makes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> pen for a
        local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, but remnants of the pretty arches and columns can still
        be seen.
        For a wonderful view of the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, take the road up to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnie View Hotel</ENAMEX>, which is set on a hill just to the south. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bays</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy Island</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> can all easily be seen. Don‚Äôt forget
        your camera.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rio Grande</ENAMEX>, just west of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Antonio</ENAMEX>, is the largest
        river complex on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>, combining a number of tributaries from the
        Blue <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mountains</ENAMEX>. Rafts have long been a method of transport for local
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, who use them to carry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX> down from the upper slopes to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">port</ENAMEX>. Rafting on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rio Grande</ENAMEX> was popularized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Errol Flynn</ENAMEX>, who
        loved the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX>, and became a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúmust‚Äù</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> in the late
        1940s‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit is still just as popular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The lush river valley cuts
        deep into the heart of the mountains, with sheltered habitats for many
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX>. A raft trip here is a much more tropical
        experience than on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martha Brae River</ENAMEX> (farther west, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falmouth</ENAMEX>).
        Rafters start at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berridale</ENAMEX> and complete their cruise at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rafters‚</ENAMEX>Äô Rest
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Margaret‚Äôs Bay</ENAMEX>), where there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>. There are even
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moonlight</ENAMEX> cruises for those who are romantically inclined.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tropical Peace and Splendor</ENAMEX>
        The drive east from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Antonio</ENAMEX> offers some of the
        prettiest views in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. A series of coral headlands covered in
        tropical vegetation reach out into the ocean. Beautiful private villas
        and a small number of fine resort <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> sit proudly on the headlands
        or nestle in the small bays. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San San</ENAMEX> gained a reputation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Errol Flynn</ENAMEX> for its elegant social scene; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it is an exclusive
        hideaway with a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX>. A small faded sign points the way to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Lagoon</ENAMEX>, a tiny coastal inlet with a freshwater spring just
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">offshore</ENAMEX>. The clear fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> mixes with the briny sea water just a
        few <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meters</NUMEX> away and creates a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> hues of green and blue. The
        freshwater hole is said to be bottomless, although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Cousteau</ENAMEX>
        dived here and measured the depth at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">61 m</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 ft</ENAMEX>). You can swim and
        scuba-dive among a wealth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and other sea life; also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and
        restaurant provide refreshment ranging from a drink to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-course
        meal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frenchman‚Äôs Cove</ENAMEX>, a little farther east, is also beautiful. Tiny
        bays of soft <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX> sheltered by cliffs and cooling vegetation provide a
        completely different experience from the beaches of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montego Bay</ENAMEX>. This
        is the area for romantic private getaways.
        To the south of the coastal area, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Athenry Gardens</ENAMEX> (formerly
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX>) has wonderful views of the surrounding mountains, but
        these botanical gardens are renowned much more for what is under the
        ground than what is above it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonsuch Caves</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX> with
        dramatic formations of stalactites and stalagmites. The largest cave is
        called the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cathedral</ENAMEX> because of its size and scale. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find fossils
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and other marine <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> that were deposited in sediment
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, when this area lay on the ocean floor. The paths
        are well lit and offer amazing views of the interior.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica‚Äôs Eastern</ENAMEX> Tip
        If you continue along the main coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, you‚Äôll reach
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Bay</ENAMEX>. This small fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> at the easternmost end of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island</ENAMEX> is the traditional center of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äújerk,‚Äù Jamaica‚</ENAMEX>Äôs national dish
        that is now gaining a worldwide following. The jerk marinating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">technique</ENAMEX> was first developed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Maroon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as a method of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tenderizing</ENAMEX> and cooking their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>. You will smell the roasting meat
        and aromatic wood fires as you arrive in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>. The fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> is
        cut into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äúbellies‚Äù</ENAMEX> and scored to make it easier to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and serve. It
        is then covered in the paste that gives jerk its name, placed on a rack
        over the pit fire, and turned every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">few minutes</TIMEX> until it is ready. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marinade</ENAMEX> is a good deal spicier than you would find in a tourist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurant</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> is wonderfully tender; ask for a bite-sized
        sample before you buy. You‚Äôll be offered a serving of roasted
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">breadfruit</ENAMEX> along with the jerk to provide the perfect bland antidote to
        the spice. Share the dining table in a simple shack with a few local
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and you‚Äôll have one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">‚Äúreal‚Äù Jamaican</ENAMEX> experiences.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Maroon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of proud and tenacious
        slaves, still live in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> isolated pockets on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore Town</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornwall Barracks</ENAMEX>, both inland from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boston Bay</ENAMEX>, make up the nucleus of
        the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (the western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maroon</ENAMEX> area is in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cockpit Country</ENAMEX>, south
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falmouth</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">settlements</ENAMEX> here were founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1739</TIMEX> after the peace
        treaty with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>. Maroon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are very private, still running
        their own affairs and paying no land taxes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Although
        their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> don‚Äôt look very different from the other rural
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> on the island, it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maroon</ENAMEX> attitude to life which make
        these societies interesting to visit. If you wish to get to know the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, you can arrange to visit them with a guide (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">121</NUMEX>).
        The coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> makes its way around the eastern tip of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. The few attractions here are natural, very beautiful, and
        unspoiled, but the difficult and long journey from the major resorts
        means that few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> venture this far. Long <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX> is one of the
        longest and most magnificent beaches on the island, with not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sight‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇjust nature at its best. There is no development here for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
        main reasons. First, this sector of coastline is most at risk from the
        threat of hurricanes as they whip across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic Ocean</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,
        the coastal swells here are extremely dangerous, preventing the
        swimming activities and water sports so beloved by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. You‚Äôll
        find wooden fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> pulled up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sands</ENAMEX> and nets hanging out
        to dry. The beach has fine pink sand; powerful breakers throw sea spray
        into the air. At the southern end of the beach there is a small bar
        where you can sit and admire the dramatic view.
        Farther south, near the fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchioneal</ENAMEX>, are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reach Falls</ENAMEX> (also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich Falls</ENAMEX>), perhaps the last
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uncommercialized</ENAMEX> falls on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. The surrounding vegetation is truly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tropical</ENAMEX>, with no landscaped <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX> and no sign of a shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>.
        The fresh clear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> comes directly down from the mountains of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Crow National Park</ENAMEX> and fall into a deep azure pool. Scenes in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film Cocktail</ENAMEX> (starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX>) were filmed in the cascades.
        On the easternmost tip of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> stands <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morant Point</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lighthouse</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1841</TIMEX>. With pristine mangrove swamps and the
        deserted sandy beaches of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holland Bay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mammee Bay</ENAMEX>, the landscape is
        truly magnificent. Here are the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles and miles</NUMEX> of landscape that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> conjures up in your dreams. Unfortunately, there is nobody here
        to hand you a cooling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX> at the end of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">exploration‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇand the
        difficult journey from the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> to the lighthouse makes it thirsty
        work indeed.
        From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morant Point</ENAMEX>, the road turns west back toward
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingston</ENAMEX>. There is little to hold the attention here although the area
        has seen important historical incidents which have had a bearing on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modern Jamaica</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Port Morant</ENAMEX>, a little way west, was the place where
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Bligh</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúThe Bounty‚</ENAMEX>Äù fame <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> landed breadfruit on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>.
        The famous mutiny occurred during the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> journey, when he refused
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> much-needed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, keeping it instead for the precious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>.
        Even after all his effort, however, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> survived, and he had
        to return with a second cargo. It proved to be worth the effort for
        Bligh, who received a reward of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,500 guineas</NUMEX> for his effort.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morant Bay</ENAMEX> is the major settlement in southeast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>; it
        played a major part in one of the turning points in the history of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Morant Bay</ENAMEX> rebellion of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865</TIMEX> was led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Bogle</ENAMEX> and
        supported by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George William Gordon</ENAMEX> (after whom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gordon House</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaican</ENAMEX> seat of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>, is named). The uprising and the violent
        reaction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> forces resulted in the destruction of many of
        the historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, which never really recovered. The
        most interesting attraction in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Morant Bay</ENAMEX> is a statue that commemorates
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogle</ENAMEX>, located outside the tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX>. This strong, powerful
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">depiction</ENAMEX> was designed and sculpted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edna Manley</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Mountains</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Mountains</ENAMEX> are the highest on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> and cover
        much of the interior of the eastern part of the island. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
        major peaks: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Mountain Peak</ENAMEX> is the highest at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,256</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7,402 ft</NUMEX>),
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Crow Mountain</ENAMEX> is the lowest at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,753</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5,750 ft</NUMEX>). The
        mountains are blanketed with thick, verdant <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">forests watered</ENAMEX> by regular
        tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">downpours</ENAMEX> from the heavy clouds that surround the high peaks.
        The blue heat haze that surrounds the mountains and gives them their
        name can best be seen on warm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX>, when it is possible to see
        peak after peak stretching into the distance.
        A number of slopes and valleys have remained untouched by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and offer a habitat for rare hummingbirds and swallowtail
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX>. The richness of the environment around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Mountains</ENAMEX>
        has long been recognized; protecting the areas of virgin forest is now
        a priority. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Mountain National Park</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Crow</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Park</ENAMEX>, which together cover <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">78,200 hectares</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">193</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 acres</NUMEX>),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservationists</ENAMEX> are attempting to halt the encroachment of local
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> and loggers.
        The best way to view the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Mountains</ENAMEX> is to drive from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buff Bay</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">north</ENAMEX> coast down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingston</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">B1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>,
        although the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> can be impassable after a heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> due to
        landslides. Always check with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> and hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to determine
        if road conditions are good before you depart. But the interior of the
        mountain range and the most beautiful parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> are not
        accessible to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>: the best way to experience them is to take a
        guided walk. There are a variety of routes, which can last from a
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX>. The hike to the summit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Mountain</ENAMEX> itself
        is not for the inexperienced and will take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full day</TIMEX>; if you want to
        see the sunrise, start out at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2am</NUMEX> to reach the summit in time to greet
        another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX>). Whichever option you choose,
        remember to take some warm clothing, because temperatures here are a
        few degrees lower than on the coast, even on a sunny <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>. When the
        clouds come in, it can feel quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">chilly</TIMEX>.
        In addition to their tropical splendor, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Mountains</ENAMEX>
        have another important attraction: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slopes</ENAMEX> at an altitude above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> m
        (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9,840 ft</NUMEX>) are perfect for growing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Mountain</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> is said by aficionados to be the best in the world. The coffee
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX> lie in the humid heights, where soil conditions and the
        slow growing process (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> from germination to harvesting)
        produce a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> with a high yield. This natural affinity between
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Mountains</ENAMEX> and the coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bean</ENAMEX> is amazing, because the first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> are said to have arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> by accident. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1723</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XV</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> ordered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> arabica <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> to be sent from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martinique</ENAMEX>, which lies farther south. Two
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> died on the long journey and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> one found its way to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamaica‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇexactly</ENAMEX> how is still shrouded in mystery. This <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> was
        the start of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jamaican</ENAMEX> coffee industry, the most important business
        in this part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 250 years</TIMEX>. Many of the working
        practices of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> would still be recognized by those first plantation
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>. Because of the topography and the delicate nature of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX>, much of the work is still done by hand. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jablum Coffee</ENAMEX>
        Factory near <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavis Bank</ENAMEX> offers guided tours where you can see <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX>
        being roasted and ground; you can also buy supplies of coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> to
        take home.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingston</ENAMEX> and Environs
        With one of the largest natural harbors in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">world‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇlying</ENAMEX> between lush green hills and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean Sea‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇKingston
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX> became the perfect site for one of the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>. Commercial success made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingston</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1872</TIMEX>.
        Now home to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 700,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>), it is a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with many facets. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Modern ‚ÄúNew</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kingston</ENAMEX>,‚Äù with its office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and high rise blocks, is the
        administrative heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>, with government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, consulates,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX>. To the northeast lie the foothills of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Mountain</ENAMEX>
        range, where wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingstonians</ENAMEX> have traditionally built <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> to
        take advantage of the cooling breezes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> live on the flat, dusty
        plains below, where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> life has simply been transplanted to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Goats wander the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live in tiny tin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shacks</ENAMEX> with
        few amenities. They sit up against several other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shacks</ENAMEX> that make up
        blocks of properties (or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äúyards‚Äù</ENAMEX>). The violence and crime that have
        been a very public feature of life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingston</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> center
        on political and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> rivalries within these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yards</ENAMEX>. The young
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> are brought up knowing nothing else.
        As in any capital <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kingston‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> and attractions
        show the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> how the island evolved both as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> and as an
        independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. They also provide insight into how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jamaicans</ENAMEX> view
        themselves and their culture with national pride.
        Downtown
        Downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingston</ENAMEX>, once a model of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> colonial ‚Äúpomp
        and circumstance,‚Äù is now surrounded by some of the poorest and most
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">densely</ENAMEX> populated neighborhoods in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. It is not a place to
        wander around without a guide. The risk of petty crime is high and the
        atmosphere is a little too oppressive for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> to feel
        comfortable walking the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> alone (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">116</NUMEX>).
        The downtown area developed around the waterfront. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fruit</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rum</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX> were once transported from the old docks, but in recent
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> the harbor area has been transformed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica Conference</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, is a good example of how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> is striving to make its mark as a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
        There are also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> and historical collections that celebrate the
        culture of the island. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ocean Boulevard</ENAMEX>, has a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jamaican</ENAMEX> paintings, sculpture, and other
