
  
  
    
      
        What To Do
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outdoor Activities</ENAMEX>
        For information about lessons and/or guided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> excursions
        involving some of the activities listed below (climbing, walking,
        mountain biking, canoeing, and sailing), contact one of the following
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summitreks</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yewdale Road</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cumbria</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LA21 8DU</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">015394</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41212</NUMEX>, fax (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">015394</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41055</NUMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Adventure</ENAMEX>, Holehird
        Farm, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patterdale Road, Windermere</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LA23 1NP</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">015394</ENAMEX>) 47302.
        Walking
        A paradise for ramblers, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> has a wealth of
        choices for any level of ability. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novice</ENAMEX> or those not in peak
        condition there are walks or gentle strolls in the valley bottoms and
        around the lake shores. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">paths</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Derwent Water</ENAMEX> and Buttermere
        are particularly relaxing: They often take in areas of forest, such as
        at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizedale</ENAMEX>, or grassland and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> land, as at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirehouse</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lingholm</ENAMEX>.
        Short walks to panoramic viewpoints should be a part of everyone‚Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">itinerary</ENAMEX>. Try <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loughrigg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Loughrigg Terrace</ENAMEX>, easily reached from
        Grasmere <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>, for superb views of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windermere</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grasmere</ENAMEX> lakes. On
        these walks you‚Äôll never be far from a caf√© or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX>, so it‚Äôs always
        possible to break for lunch or refreshments.
        For those who want a slightly more challenging walk, but
        without a lot of hills to walk up and down, there are a number of
        routes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> with little or no gradient. Paths along the
        windswept bracken fells are for the most part flat and offer
        spectacular views of surrounding peaks. Examples include routes along
        Wrynose bottom, around <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wast Water</ENAMEX>, the path along the stream bed at
        Watendlath, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blea Tarn</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Langdale Fells</ENAMEX>; the
        latter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> routes are especially beautiful. These walks are a little
        more off the beaten track and require advance planning in terms of
        parking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and obtaining refreshment, but they‚Äôre rewarding
        because of the rich variety of landscapes they cover.
        Very fit, experienced walkers enjoy the peak walks, which
        involve steeper climbs and lead to the very highest points of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX>
        District. These require a little more thought, good equipment, and some
        form of refreshment such as a packed lunch (these can often be prepared
        by your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>) as they often take an entire day to complete. The
        easiest walks in this category are the ones up the popular peaks of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helvellyn</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Skiddaw‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇhere you‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find well marked paths and, most
        times of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. The most challenging area of all
        is high above <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wasdale</ENAMEX>. Scafell, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Gable</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pillar</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk Fell</ENAMEX>
        offer challenge and excitement even to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>.
        Once you assess your own capabilities and make your choice,
        the options are almost limitless. The tourist information centres
        throughout the region all have a vast amount of information on routes
        for all abilities, as well as maps and charts to help you plan an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outing</ENAMEX>. All footpaths are clearly marked. If you intend to head out
        onto the fells, though, you should take the appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ordnance Survey</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">map along‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇthey provide the most detailed guides to the terrain.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> who want to do some walking but don‚Äôt have suitable
        footwear or equipment should head for one of the larger sporting goods
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in one of the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowness, Keswick</ENAMEX>, or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambleside</ENAMEX>. Many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> rent boots, outerwear, rain gear, and
        such at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> rates.
        Cycling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cycling</ENAMEX> has become extremely popular in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX>, even
        taking into account the fact that some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> in the National
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> are incredibly steep. For those who would prefer to cycle
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">off-road</ENAMEX>, there are tracks through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">forests</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizedale</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whinlatter</ENAMEX> and some well marked cross-country routes. All the major
        towns have bike-rental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>; ask at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotels</ENAMEX> or tourist information
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centers</ENAMEX> for the location of the nearest ‚Äúhire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        Climbing
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wasdale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scafell</ENAMEX> offers challenging
        climbing. If you would like to scale the ‚Äúhighest heights,‚Äù you‚Äôll need
        expert guidance. For further information contact The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountaineering Council</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">177‚Äì179</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burton Road</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Didsbury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manchester</ENAMEX>,
        M20 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2BB</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0161</TIMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">445-4747</TIMEX>; fax (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0161</TIMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">445-4500</ENAMEX>.
        Fishing
        Fishing is an extremely popular sport in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>; with so
        many lakes to choose from and so much breathtaking countryside all
        around, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> is an ideal place to try your hand. The
        region‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> abound in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">char</ENAMEX>, perch, pike, vendace, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trout</ENAMEX>. Permits are required, and you will need to buy one separately
        for each lake. You can get information about rental equipment and
        permits at the following places: for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ullswater</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pooley Bridge</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glenridding</ENAMEX> tourist information centres; for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bassenthwaite Lake</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Park Information Centre</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Keswick</ENAMEX>; for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston Water</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston Gifts and Sports</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston</ENAMEX>; and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Derwent Water</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keswick Anglers Association</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canoeing</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boating</ENAMEX>
        If you want to get out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> under your own steam
        rather than on a lake ferry or steamer, there are a number of ways to
        do it. At <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Windermere</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Derwent Water</ENAMEX>, and Ullswater you can rent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rowboats</ENAMEX> (most are big enough for a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>). At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowness</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waterhead</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Windermere</ENAMEX>) you will find them lined up next to the
        ferry <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">piers</ENAMEX>; at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Derwent Water</ENAMEX> they are found at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeside</ENAMEX>. For
        Ullswater, travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glenridding</ENAMEX> in the south or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pooley Bridge</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">north‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇin</ENAMEX> either place you‚Äôll find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that rent canoes and
        other water-sports equipment. The local tourist information centres at
        Windermere, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Derwent Water</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ullswater</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston Water</ENAMEX> have
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> information. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Trust</ENAMEX> produces a
        free <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúLake User‚Äôs Guide‚</ENAMEX>Äù for the following lakes: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ullswater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston</ENAMEX>,
        Windermere, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bassenthwaite</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Derwent Water</ENAMEX>; these booklets have all
        the information you need to enjoy the water safely. Many lakes or
        sections of lakes are also wildlife conservation areas; these guides
        list the regulations that are in effect to protect water <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> and
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. Some of these regulations and restrictions change with
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf</ENAMEX>
        There are golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> in the following <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cockermouth</ENAMEX>,
        Kendal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keswick, Penrith</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windermere</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf courses</ENAMEX> here tend to
        be much more hilly than most in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>. The opening
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and rules regarding access vary, so contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cumbria Tourist</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Windermere</ENAMEX> or one of the local tourist information centers
        (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX>) before setting out with your golf bag.
        Riding and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pony Trekking</ENAMEX>
        Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">equestrian centers</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> offer
        guided rides, which range from easy to challenging. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the largest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centers</ENAMEX> is near <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston</ENAMEX>, and there are several around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ullswater</ENAMEX>.
        Public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridle paths</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> lead through
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Board</ENAMEX> or local tourist information <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> for full details
        (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX>).
        For information about lessons and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> excursions, try
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armathwaite Hall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equestrian Centre, Coalbeck Farm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bassenthwaite</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keswick</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">017687</ENAMEX>) 76949 (open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-round</TIMEX>), or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park Foot Trekking</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pooley Bridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ullswater</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">017684</ENAMEX>) 86696 (open
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">March‚ÄìOctober</ENAMEX>).
        Photography
        With its variety of landscapes and ever-changing light, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake District</ENAMEX> offers never-ending opportunities for outdoor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photographers</ENAMEX>. Standard print film is available in many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> in the
        major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>, but serious shutterbugs will want to seek out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
        following photography <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> for a full range of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> film and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey Photographic</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stramongate, Kendal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LA9 4BH</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">01539</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">720-085</ENAMEX>, or The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photo Shop</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Road, Ambleside, Cumbria</ENAMEX> LA22
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT; Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">015394</ENAMEX>) 34375.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeland Social Events</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agricultural</ENAMEX> shows
        Every farming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> when it comes together to celebrate its way of life and
        compete at various events. These are a traditional part of country
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">life‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthey‚Äôre</ENAMEX> not staged as tourist attractions, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> are
        always welcome. Local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> bring their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">livestock</ENAMEX> and engage in
        serious rivalry for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> rosettes. The prizes are often mere
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trinkets‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇthe real payoff is when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> comes to market, since a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prize ram</ENAMEX>, for example, can make a lot of money at market later in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. Family pride mixes with economics at these events. Farming can be
        a lonely life, and even in modern times it is rare for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> to
        take time off from the hard work and socialize. These agricultural
        shows offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> the opportunity to get together and have fun, and
        they offer visitors a rare chance to chat with the local farming
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheepdog</ENAMEX> trials
        The way sheepdogs do their job is a source of fascination
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> and of pride to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> who breed and train them. Each
        summer local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> get together for a friendly
        competition; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> maneuver sheep around a set course.
        Both speed and accuracy are assessed to decide the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>. Remember as
        you watch these skillful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> that they cheerfully perform the
        same tasks in snowdrifts and the thickest fog and cloud in the depths
        of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeland Sports Days</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX>, hard working and abstemious, have
        always found ways to enjoy themselves, and this more often than not
        involved means physical competition. A number of sporting contests have
        become part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeland</ENAMEX> tradition. Before the advent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> it was
        common to see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> walking towards the show-grounds, and
        often the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sportsmen</ENAMEX> from neighboring valleys came over the fells
        to compete.
        The sports days are still taken as seriously by competitors
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one hundred years ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Winners</ENAMEX> still become local
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> and their reputation reaches to the very corners of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lakes</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the sports that developed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> is a
        unique form of wrestling. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> stand face to face with their arms
        wrapped around each other‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, hands clasped tightly together behind
        the other‚Äôs back. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> then try to unbalance their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>. The
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to hit the ground with a part of the body other than the feet
        loses the contest.
        Fell running also tests the mettle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Competitors</ENAMEX> simply run
        up and down the side of a fell, taking obstacles like bogs, streams,
        and rocks in their stride. The fastest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> wins.
        Hound trailing, also once a part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life, remains a
        popular sport. This is how it works in today‚Äôs competitions: an
        aniseed-scented <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX> is laid on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> of the race, and the dogs
        are sent off across the fells to follow it, disappearing out of sight
        through the bracken. Although the prize money is negligible, you would
        not think so when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs reappear</ENAMEX> and the enthusiastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> call,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">whistle</ENAMEX>, and wave them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
        Hunting for live <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">prey</ENAMEX> is still an important part of country
        life, but less popular than in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Peel‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX>
        District <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> follow the pack on foot rather than using horses
        because the incline of the fells is too difficult for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summer Festivals</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>, not to be outdone by the agricultural shows,
        also hold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> festivals such as the popular Victorian <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Festival</ENAMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keswick</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Medieval Festival</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kendal</ENAMEX>; both are in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late May</TIMEX> and
        both feature crafts, food <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entertainers</ENAMEX> in
        period costumes. Many of the country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> also hold special events,
        such as antiques or crafts fairs or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúfun days‚Äù with fair rides,
        throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer months</TIMEX>. Check with the tourist information
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centers</ENAMEX> for details about these and similar events at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalemain</ENAMEX>, Holker
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muncaster Castle</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Bearing</ENAMEX>
        Rushes taken from the lakes were traditionally used to
        carpet church <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX>, and once a year, to refresh
        this floor covering, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> would ceremonially carry
        a new batch of rushes into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. This tradition has survived,
        though <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in many places the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> bear <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> rather
        than rushes. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> good places to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> the rush-bearing ceremony are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Mary‚Äôs Parish Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ambleside</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grasmere Parish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grasmere</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
        Natural raw materials found in the area have been used for
        centuries to make beautiful decorative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, horn, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wood</ENAMEX> were always used to make tools and implements, but these materials
        are now also being used in the production of interesting souvenirs.
        Favorite items that will help preserve your memories of the rugged
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeland</ENAMEX> countryside are clothing or blankets made from the local
        Herdwick <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX>, coasters of polished slate, or walking sticks with
        ram‚Äôs-horn handles.
        Crafts such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ceramics</ENAMEX> and pottery-making, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>-turning,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>-blowing are also popular. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> craftspeople work
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX>, and as you wander you‚Äôll find signs leading you
        to their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> in converted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barns</ENAMEX> and other outbuildings. The prices
        are not necessarily low, but the quality of these hand-crafted objects
        is high. Although every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> that sell these items, a good
        place to start would be the Made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cumbria</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> situated in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Information Centre</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Windermere</ENAMEX>; they stock a wide range of
        locally produced handicrafts.
        Visual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> find the natural beauty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> District
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inspiring</ENAMEX>, and their paintings or photographs make fitting souvenirs.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> in all the major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> and in some of the smaller
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>. If you find yourself in the village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boot</ENAMEX>, go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fold</ENAMEX>
        End <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallery</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">019467</ENAMEX>) 23316 (open <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter‚ÄìChristmas</ENAMEX> daily
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30‚Äì5:30</TIMEX>, longer in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heaton Cooper</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> are among the
        most prestigious landscape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>; visit their studio
        opposite the village green in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grasmere</ENAMEX> (open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">015394</ENAMEX>)
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35280</NUMEX>. Throughout the region you‚Äôll come across limited-edition prints
        signed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>; these make good mementos. Just pick your favorite
        view and it will bring you years of pleasure.
        Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> is so popular for outdoor
        activities, it‚Äôs a good place to shop for outdoor clothing and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX>. All the major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> have several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> with jackets, hats,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boots</ENAMEX>, rain gear, etc. There are good bargains to be found at the end
        of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each season</TIMEX>, particularly just after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> of
        towns like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambleside</ENAMEX> have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> sales.
        If <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">it‚Äôs foodstuffs you‚Äôre</ENAMEX> after, there are some unusual
        offerings in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX>. Cumberland sausage is the local specialty.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Award</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Woodall</ENAMEX>, who has a royal warrant to supply
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sausages</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth II</ENAMEX>, is one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to look
        for. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodall‚Äôs</ENAMEX> also prepares <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">delicious hams</ENAMEX> from home-reared <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.
        The family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> is at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waberthwaite</ENAMEX> just south of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ravensglass</ENAMEX>, but you
        will find his produce in food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kendal Mint Cake</ENAMEX> is packaged in fancy gift boxes but you
        don‚Äôt need to be going on an expedition to enjoy it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Nelson‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        Gingerbread, made and sold at their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grasmere</ENAMEX>, can be bought in
        pretty tins to take home.
        Markets are a good way to get a feel for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday</TIMEX> life. In
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the gentleman</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> come into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shop</ENAMEX> on market day. Particularly busy, colorful markets include those
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kendal</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keswick</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>), and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penrith</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> markets are not tourist attractions as
        such. However, for those who want to get a behind-the-scenes view of
        real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeland</ENAMEX> life, these events are hard to beat. Just be discreet,
        and don‚Äôt wear your best shoes. Try <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cockermouth</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>)
        or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penrith</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children</ENAMEX>
        There are so many things for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to do in the great
        outdoors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX>. They can paddle in the streams, go
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bird</ENAMEX>-wat ching, or cycle on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grizedale</ENAMEX> or Whinlatter
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">forests</ENAMEX>. Afternoon hikes and picnics are also pleasant diversions.
        Trying their hand at fishing or rowing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> on a lake can be a
        challenge. More organized activities include joining a horseback-riding
        or canoeing expedition. Particularly good family <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">outings‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇif the
        weather is fine‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇare trips to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trotters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX>
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bassenthwaite</ENAMEX> or at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Owl Sanctuary</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muncaster Castle</ENAMEX>, or taking
        steam-railway rides at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeside</ENAMEX> or on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">La‚Äôal Ratty</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eskdale</ENAMEX>. And a
        trip on a lake ferry can be run in any sort of weather.
        Rainy days are the most challenging for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, but there
        are still plenty of attractions to fill the time. Try the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aquarium of</ENAMEX>
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeside</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pencil Museum</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keswick</ENAMEX>, or the World of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beatrix Potter Exhibition</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowness</ENAMEX>.
        Nightlife
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> is not the place to come if you want lots
        of action into the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early morning hours</TIMEX>. Don‚Äôt expect to be swinging
        much after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>, even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>.
        Theater
        There is a lively theater scene in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> during
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, but many performances can be fully booked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ahead</TIMEX>. The
        tourist information <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> will have details of the programs. You can
        also obtain information directly from the following venues: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX>
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forest</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizedale</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">01229</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">860291</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brewery Arts Centre</ENAMEX>,
        122a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highgate, Kendal</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">01539</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">725133</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Theatre</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Keswick</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">017687</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74411</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Old Laundry Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crag Brow</ENAMEX>,
        Bowness-on-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Windermere</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">01539</ENAMEX>) 88444.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinema</ENAMEX>
        There are a number of cinemas in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> that
        show the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> releases and sometimes schedule retrospectives.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Zeffirelli‚Äôs on Compston Road in Ambleside</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> and restaurant
        complex where you can make a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> of it with a movie and a meal.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pubs</ENAMEX>
        Every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public House</ENAMEX>, or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pub</ENAMEX>, where alcoholic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> are served to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> (the drinking age is
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pubs</ENAMEX> were once where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> went to escape from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, but times have
        changed. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX> now serve meals and have entertainment; chalkboards
        outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX> will let you know when they‚Äôre having live music or
        other events. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX> have pool tables and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">darts</ENAMEX> or TV sets, which
        are usually tuned to sports events, more likely than not a football
        (soccer) game. Family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> have been introduced in many spots, making
        it easier for younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to enjoy meals with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> (and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX> versa). Many outside <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer gardens‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇvery popular when the weather
        is fine‚<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇalso</ENAMEX> now have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>-friendly areas. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX> has its own
        unique atmosphere, created by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> and the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clientele</ENAMEX>. If
        you stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a few days</TIMEX> you‚Äôre sure to
        find a favorite.
        Last call at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX> is at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> sharp, to ensure that guests
        don‚Äôt linger much beyond <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:15</TIMEX>. Local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> with drink licenses can
        serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> later than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>, often until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> themselves decide to
        call it a night.
      
    
  
