
  
  
    
      
        What to Do
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sightseeing</ENAMEX> is, of course, only a part of your visit to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>. You will probably want to take time to shop for traditional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arts</ENAMEX> and crafts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuching</ENAMEX>, or check out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> markets of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lumpur</ENAMEX>, drop by a few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">antiques shops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penang</ENAMEX>. A stopover in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> is also an opportunity to find the latest bargains for
        cameras and computers. Those who wish to can have a quite active
        vacation just sampling the local shopping scene. And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> offers a
        showcase of festivals of events and festivities throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> as
        well.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
        A variety of goods are available throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>. Large
        department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> are to be found in most major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, with
        night markets adding color while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antiques</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> brim with traditional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">handicrafts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antiques</ENAMEX>. Batik fabric designs, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> and
        pewter ware, and silk brocaded songket cloth are popular items.
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">The night</TIMEX> markets often offer items not likely to be found
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>, especially if you are in pursuit of bootleg CDs. In
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabah</ENAMEX>, you may even be able to buy a buffalo, though shipping is not
        included in the purchase price. Bargaining, away from the major
        department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, is required etiquette; but make sure on big-ticket
        items that you have a good idea of retail prices before you begin.
        Malaysia‚Äôs tax <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">havens</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pulau Langkawi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Labuan</ENAMEX>.
        Duty-free areas are also found at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rantau Panjang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pengkalan Kubur</ENAMEX>,
        both in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kelantan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Padang Besar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bukit Kayu Hitam</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kedah</ENAMEX>. A
        sampling of duty-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> can also be found at city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johor Bahru</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penang</ENAMEX>.
        Craftwork
        Most major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> have handicraft <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL‚</ENAMEX>Äôs Karyaneka
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jalan Raja Chulan</ENAMEX>, which act as a showcase for products from all
        over the peninsula and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Malaysia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL‚Äôs Central Market</ENAMEX> gives you a
        wider selection. As far as quality is concerned, some of the best
        traditional products are to be found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum shops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lumpur</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka, Kuching</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kota Kinabalu</ENAMEX>. The selection is more
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> in the markets and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelantan, Terengganu</ENAMEX>,
        Sarawak, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sabah</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kota Bharu</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Terengganu</ENAMEX>, take a guided
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kampung</ENAMEX> tour to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craftsmen</ENAMEX> at work‚<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇyou‚Äôll</ENAMEX> often find that you
        can get their products at a better price than in town.
        Batik
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bright</ENAMEX> and enticing, these colorfully patterned fabrics are
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> both hand- and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>-made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kelantan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terengganu</ENAMEX>, but had
        their origins in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> kingdoms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1,000 years ago</TIMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">technique</ENAMEX> remains the same, although it was adopted on the peninsula
        only in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX>. A design of melted wax is applied to cotton
        or silk using a metal stencil. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX> is then dipped in cool
        vegetable or synthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dye</ENAMEX>, which colors the cloth around the wax
        pattern. The piece is then dipped in hot water to remove the wax,
        leaving a lighter design behind. The process may be repeated for
        multiple coloring. Traditionally, certain designs were reserved for
        royalty, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> elegant geometric or exuberant, stylized floral
        patterns are available to all. You can either buy the cloth and have it
        tailored back home or buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sarong‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇuseful</ENAMEX> at the beach over a bikini.
        Other items include hats, scarves, ties, purses, kaftan shirts, and
        wall-hangings. Do note that the quality of batik can vary greatly.
        Kain Songket
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kain Songket</ENAMEX> (silk brocade) is a speciality of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terengganu</ENAMEX>.
        On a hardwood frame, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> and gold threads are woven into fine silk,
        usually of emerald green, dark red, purple, or royal blue. Besides
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">geometric</ENAMEX> and floral patterns, you will also find handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and
        dagger motifs. Songket was originally reserved for royalty, but is
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> also used for bridal dresses, other ceremonial robes,
        cushion-covers, and handbags.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silverwork</ENAMEX> and Pewter
        The silversmith‚Äôs centuries-old skills, originally
        developed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perak</ENAMEX>, are continued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kelantan</ENAMEX>.
        As Islam prohibits the representation of human or animal figures, the
        work done here is the happy result of imposing much simpler patterns
        than the often elaborate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">silverware</ENAMEX> across the border in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>. The
        work remains exquisite despite this perceived limitation. Besides
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">earrings</ENAMEX>, brooches, necklaces, and bracelets, you will find plaques and
        filigree jewelry, perfume bottles, snuff boxes (originally designed for
        betel nuts), belt buckles, caskets, lacquered trays, and magnificent
        bowls.
        Pewter-work, in the form of goblets, clocks, tankards, wine
        carafes, trays, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX>- and pepper-shakers, is a luxury side-product
        of the tin industry. It is actually <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> tin, hardened with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> alloy
        of antimony and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX>. The major names to look out for are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selangor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tumasek Pewter</ENAMEX>, both available throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Selangor</ENAMEX> is on sale in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX> at several major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> as well as
        department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. It is also made and sold in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>. The Tumasek
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pewter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> is on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jalan Kanan</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taman Kepong</ENAMEX>.
        Other Craftwork
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most attractive products of the traditional arts
        is the highly decorative puppet used in the wayang kulit shadow theater
        (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">154</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clowns</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> that you can watch being
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">made in a Kelantan</ENAMEX> rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workshop</ENAMEX> can make splendid ornaments.
        More practical but quite decorative are bamboo and rattan
        Baskets and mats woven from nipa palm <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX>.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuching</ENAMEX> look for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iban</ENAMEX> pua kumbu (hand-woven rugs),
        wooden hornbill carvings used in rituals, and silver jewelry, woven
        Bidayuh baskets, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orang Ulu</ENAMEX> beadwork and woodcarving, and Punan
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blowpipes</ENAMEX> and mats. Most antiques and curio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> are around the main
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bazaar</ENAMEX> just behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Esplanade</ENAMEX>, with a few in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Padungan</ENAMEX> area.
        An authentic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">blowpipe</ENAMEX> is one of the most accomplished
        pieces of indigenous workmanship in all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>. Really good ones
        are now increasingly rare and quite expensive, and their length, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 m</ENAMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 6 ft</NUMEX>), makes them difficult to carry around. Failing a real
        hardwood blowpipe, you can buy the handsome quiver of stout
        rattan-bound bamboo with the poison <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">darts</ENAMEX> (minus the poison), both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">authentic</ENAMEX>, and a shorter pipe of bamboo that does a perfectly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serviceable</ENAMEX> job of blowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">darts</ENAMEX> into your cork dartboard at home.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sarawak</ENAMEX> pottery is ochre-colored with bold geometric
        designs. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sayong</ENAMEX> pottery, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perak</ENAMEX>, has a glossy black color. There is
        even pottery from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johor</ENAMEX>, decorated with batik and gold thread, giving
        it a distinctive look.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Antiques</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka‚Äôs Baba Nyonya Chinese</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX>) is a
        great place to hunt and bargain for old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porcelain</ENAMEX> imported from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern China</ENAMEX>, antique <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> or jade bracelets, and, if you can find
        a way of shipping it home, a piece of furniture from the colonial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penang</ENAMEX> is also popular for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antiques-lovers</ENAMEX> along <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jalan</ENAMEX> Pintal Tali
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rope Walk</ENAMEX>), offering porcelain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ware</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>, coins, old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>, ceiling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lamps</ENAMEX>, and antique clocks. Occasionally treasures can be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unearthed‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇnotably</ENAMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> theatrical costumes and fake
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jewelry‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇas you rummage among the piles of junk in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown‚</ENAMEX>Äôs famous
        flea market at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lorong Kulit</ENAMEX>.
        Discount and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duty-Free Goods</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> is generally viewed as a better location for
        bargain prices on computers, tape-recorders, video cameras, and other
        electronic equipment. Computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX> say that the deals on computer
        software, pirated or otherwise, are better in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penang</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johor</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahru</ENAMEX>. If you cannot be bothered looking for discounts, you will find
        several good-quality modern shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX> on and around Jalan
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bukit Bintang</ENAMEX>, near the bigger tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>.
        You can get good deals in watches, jewelry, major brand
        sports clothes, and jeans in the street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">markets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lumpur‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇespecially</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chinatown‚Äôs Jalan Petaling‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> along <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jalan Penang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lebuh Campbell</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lebuh Chulia</ENAMEX>.
        Bargaining is not just recommended here, it is almost compulsory. The
        fakes are best distinguished from the genuine articles by how low a
        price you can get. If you find you are acquiring an incredible bargain,
        start asking yourself whether that is what you want to pay for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">an‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇalbeit brilliant‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇpiece</ENAMEX> of counterfeit merchandise.
        Shopping in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>
        The discount shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> here rival those of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
        without subjecting you to the latter‚Äôs aggressive style of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">salesmanship</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> that, except at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, no ‚Äútax-free‚Äù or
        ‚Äúduty-free‚Äù signs are allowed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, since this advantage
        applies all over the island.
        Those for whom bargain-shopping is the main reason for
        visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> should make some simple advance preparations. Bring
        along an extra bag to hold your purchases; compare prices at home to
        make sure you find actual bargains; find out beforehand the names of
        local authorized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>, especially if you want to buy high-priced
        electronic equipment and wish to reduce the risk of purchasing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counterfeit</ENAMEX> merchandise; and give yourself plenty of time to shop so
        you can compare prices.
        Everyone has his or her own technique for getting the best
        price, but a couple of general rules apply: decide in advance your
        spending limit and stick to it; and do it with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">smile‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthese</ENAMEX> people
        have seen it all and will not be brow-beaten.
        Best Buys
        For electronic equipment, watches, and cameras, the major
        shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> are on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Orchard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanglin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">River Valley</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penang</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Roads</ENAMEX>. Computers are best found at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funan Centre</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Bridge</ENAMEX>
        Road. But look out for the following:
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antiques</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jade</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ceramics</ENAMEX>, bronzes, gowns,
        incense <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">burners</ENAMEX>, and perfume bottles; <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> ceramics and bronzes; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
        brass; <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> wooden masks and carvings.
        Carpets from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> itself.
        Jewelry of jade, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, and silver at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Bridge Road</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">People‚Äôs Park</ENAMEX> shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Orchids</ENAMEX> in mixed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sprays</ENAMEX>, which can be boxed and
        air-freighted abroad or carried with you.
        Entertainment
        To cater to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> tastes, the major <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cities‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇKL</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melaka</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johor Bahru</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuantan, Kuching</ENAMEX>, and Kota
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinabalu‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇand the beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclubs</ENAMEX> and cocktail lounges
        with live music. The jazz and popular music scene is dominated by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Filipino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> of very high quality. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> deliver stunning
        carbon-copy renderings of current and past hits, while the musicians
        are quite brilliant in their set pieces or improvisations.
        Traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance and Theater</ENAMEX>
        Malaysia‚Äôs traditional entertainment is more often than not
        a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> affair. Tourist information <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kota Bharu</ENAMEX> and Kota
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terengganu</ENAMEX> can inform you about times and reservations. This
        information can also be found at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Information</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mak Yong Dance Drama</ENAMEX>
        This elegant art form evolved over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">400 years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>
        state of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patani</ENAMEX>, now part of southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, and is in the present
        performed across the border in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kelantan</ENAMEX>. It consists of a play on one
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> set romantic themes, accompanied by dance, operatic singing,
        and knockabout comic routines. The latter is accomplished by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>,
        while all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> are beautifully costumed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orchestra</ENAMEX> of rebab (bowed flute), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">tawak-tawk</ENAMEX> (gongs), and gunang
        (double-headed drums) plays music with a distinctly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX>
        flavor.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wayang Kulit Shadow Theater</ENAMEX>
        The most popular form of shadow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> is known as Wayang
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siam</ENAMEX>. It does not come, however, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Siam</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> was once known,
        but is of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> origin, drawing on themes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu epic Ramayana</ENAMEX>.
        It dates back over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1,000 years</TIMEX> to when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> first brought
        their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> culture to the peninsula. The stories surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rama</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sita</ENAMEX> involve ogres, demon-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey warriors</ENAMEX>,
        all represented on stage by puppets. With its customary cheerfulness,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> culture has added a comic element absent from the high drama of
        the original.
        The small <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">timber</ENAMEX> and bamboo <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> is mounted on stilts,
        and the puppets are seen as sharply etched shadows cast on a white
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cotton</ENAMEX> screen by a lamp hanging from the roof of the theater. One
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dalang</ENAMEX> (puppeteer), accompanied by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> playing oboe,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drums</ENAMEX>, gongs, and cymbals, acts out all the parts and produces all the
        different voices. He peeps from behind the screen to assess the age and
        sophistication of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> and varies the play accordingly.
        Originally, all the brightly colored puppets were made from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">buffalo</ENAMEX>, or goat hides, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the minor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are turned out
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> and celluloid. The bright colors are said to vary the
        intensity of the shadows and help differentiate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>.
        Festivals
        Malaysians love celebrating, and with so many different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">religions‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇIslam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hinduism, Buddhism</ENAMEX>, Christianity, and aboriginal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">animism‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthey</ENAMEX> give themselves plenty of opportunities. They often join
        in each other‚Äôs festivities, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> inviting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hari Raya</ENAMEX> feasts to end the fast of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of all the
        communities turning up for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Melaka‚Äôs Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">processions</ENAMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX>.
        It is difficult to fix precisely the dates of the various
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">festivals</ENAMEX>, as most of them are determined by lunar calendars which vary
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from year to year</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This month</TIMEX>-by<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-month</TIMEX> listing can therefore only be
        approximate.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January/February</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Year‚Äôs Day</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> is a national
        public holiday.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX> begins with a family dinner, and explodes
        with red banners and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>-dragon dances in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinatown</ENAMEX>.
        Traditionally the festivities end on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 15th day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chap Goh Meh</ENAMEX>, but
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber of commerce</ENAMEX> usually likes to extend this highly profitable
        season by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or two</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hari Raya Puasa</ENAMEX> or Aidil-Fitri celebrations mark the end of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan</ENAMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> of fasting. A delicacy served during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX> is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lemang</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glutinous rice</ENAMEX> cooked in bamboo stems).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thaipusam</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hindu festival</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murugan</ENAMEX>,
        celebrated with a procession of penitents seeking absolution at his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shrine</ENAMEX>. The biggest is from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Batu Caves</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX>).
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March/April</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peninsular Eurasians</ENAMEX> and indigenous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">converts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarawak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sabah</ENAMEX> celebrate with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Friday</ENAMEX>
        processions, the most famous being organized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Portuguese</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community of Melaka</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Peter‚Äôs Church</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelantan Kite Festival</ENAMEX> takes advantage of favorable winds
        to stage state-wide kite-flying contests (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">159</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chithirai Vishu</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>) is a more religious affair
        than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, with worship and prayers.
        May. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tadau Keamatan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sabah Rice Harvest Festival</ENAMEX>) is
        celebrated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kadazan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sabah</ENAMEX> with lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice wine</ENAMEX> and buffalo
        races.
        Kota <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Belud Market Festival</ENAMEX> includes, among the local
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">folklore</ENAMEX>, some spectacular high-jinks by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bajau</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX> on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">horseback</ENAMEX>.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gawai</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sarawak Rice Harvest Festival</ENAMEX>): Enlivened by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rice</ENAMEX> wine, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Iban</ENAMEX> stage cockfighting and blowpipe contests.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayak Day</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bidayuh</ENAMEX> and Iban get together for round after
        round of palm <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">toddy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice wine</ENAMEX>, and other jollities.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Festa de San Pedoa</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29 June</TIMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Boisterous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> tribute
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron saint</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melaka</ENAMEX>, where the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> has its fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> blessed.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July/August</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hari Raya Haji‚ÄÇ</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> celebrate the
        return of pilgrims from their journey to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mecca</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Festival of Hungry Ghosts</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> honor ancestors with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prayers</ENAMEX>, banquets, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> opera.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hari Merdeka</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">National Day</TIMEX>), which takes place on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, is a national public holiday.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>. Kelantan Top-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Spinning Festival</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> contest
        for top top-spinners (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">159</NUMEX>).
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October/November</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deepavali</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hindu Festival of Lights</ENAMEX>) is
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community‚</ENAMEX>Äôs major celebration, signaled by candles lit in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, family feasts, and prayers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prophet Mohammed‚Äôs</ENAMEX> Birthday is commemorated by processions
        and public readings from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koran</ENAMEX>.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penang Carnival</ENAMEX>: Month-long merriment takes place
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX>.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Day</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebrated</ENAMEX> throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> as a national
        public holiday.
        Sports
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water Sports</ENAMEX>
        Most large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> have their own swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coolest</ENAMEX> and most exhilarating swim is to be had in the natural pools of
        the waterfalls of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taman Negara</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Kinabalu</ENAMEX>, national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, and
        forest reserves.
        But if you prefer good sandy beaches, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> for the East
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast</ENAMEX>. The beaches of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelantan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terengganu</ENAMEX>, especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beach of Rantau Abang</ENAMEX>, and farther south at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johor‚Äôs Desaru</ENAMEX>, haven‚Äôt yet
        suffered too much from the industrialization polluting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX>.
        But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tioman Island</ENAMEX> has the best of the peninsula‚Äôs beaches, particularly
        if you like secluded coves. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX> itself, your best bets
        are the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penang Pangkor</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Langkawi</ENAMEX> islands. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarawak</ENAMEX>, the
        best beaches are northwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuching</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Damai, Santubong</ENAMEX>, or Bako
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Park</ENAMEX>; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sabah</ENAMEX>, either at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kota Kinabalu‚Äôs</ENAMEX> offshore islands of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tunku Abdul Rahman National Park</ENAMEX> or up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kudah</ENAMEX> on the northernmost
        tip of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Borneo</ENAMEX>; over on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sabah‚Äôs east</ENAMEX> coast try the islands in and around
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sandakan Bay</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> offer excellent amenities for all types of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">water</ENAMEX> sports: snorkeling, scuba diving, windsurfing, sailing, and
        water-skiing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scuba</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divers</ENAMEX> should remember that the coral and other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marine</ENAMEX> life are protected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> and are not to be picked or
        damaged.
        Other <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Sports‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> have left their mark; the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 250</NUMEX>
        golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, with a choice of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>-, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>-, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX>-hole. When the
        local <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> is private, as at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Perak Golf Club</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ipoh</ENAMEX>, your
        hotel may be able to get you temporary membership if you are a member
        of a golf club back home. Take your card along. The most comfortable
        courses are in the cooler hill <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Highlands</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraser‚Äôs Hill</ENAMEX>. The best of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> is at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saujana Golf and Country</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX>, but there are pleasant 18-hole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Langkawi</ENAMEX> island
        as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Golfers</ENAMEX> say that the best resort <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bukit</ENAMEX> Jambul
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf Club</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penang</ENAMEX>.
        The national sport, badminton, and is played wherever a
        net, real or makeshift, can be set up for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> to thwack the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shuttlecock</ENAMEX> across to each other. Resort <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> provide proper
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>.
        Tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> are also widely available, but the
        climate makes it a sport best reserved for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early morning</TIMEX>, or evenings
        when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are floodlit. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Squash</ENAMEX> has become a popular racket game
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> are widely available.
        Freshwater fishing is a delight in the mountain streams of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taman Negara</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Kinabalu</ENAMEX> national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> or on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lakes Chini</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenyir</ENAMEX>. Off the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>, try deep-sea fishing for barracuda or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shark</ENAMEX>. In all cases, inquire <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> at tourist information <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> about
        the necessary fishing permits. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunting</ENAMEX> licenses are so restricted that
        it is scarcely worth the trouble for the ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourist</ENAMEX>. )
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traditional Malay Sports</ENAMEX>
        Like the arts and crafts, ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> sports and pastimes
        are practiced almost exclusively on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>, though you may also
        see demonstrations elsewhere at cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarawak</ENAMEX>. The
        best time to see them is in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weeks</TIMEX> following the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> harvest and
        during the special festivals that stage statewide contests (see page
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">155</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelantan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terengganu</ENAMEX> preserve a centuries-old tradition
        of flying ornamental kites measuring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 6 ft</NUMEX>) across and again
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> to tail. In kampung workshops you can watch fantastic birds
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX> being made of paper (and increasingly, nowadays, of
        plastic, too) drawn over strong, flexible bamboo frames. Village
        contests judge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> on their most spectacular flying
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">skills‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇheight</ENAMEX>, dexterity, and the humming sound produced by the wind
        through the kite-head.
        Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">kite</ENAMEX> flying, top-spinning is no mere child‚Äôs game.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adults</ENAMEX> can keep a top in motion for over <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 minutes</TIMEX>. The top looks
        somewhat like a discus, made of hardwood with a steel knob of spike in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and a lead rim. The standard size is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 23 cm</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX> in) in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diameter</ENAMEX>. It takes some <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> to complete the construction of what
        is considered to be a precision instrument. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Villages</ENAMEX> stage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> games
        with the objective of keeping a top spinning for the longest time.
        Another derivative of the game, using a different kind of top, has for
        its objective to knock the opponent‚Äôs top out of the spinning area.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sepak Takraw</ENAMEX> is a kind of volleyball played with a ball
        made of rattan, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> can hit with every part of their body
        except hands and forearms. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> has to get over the net to the
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, without contacting the ball <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than three</NUMEX> times on their
        side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-man <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> scores points each time the ball
        hits the ground on the opponent‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> or if the ball is hit out of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> martial art <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silat</ENAMEX> came from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumatra</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 400</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>. It is performed with elegant stylized gestures, either as a
        form of wrestling, or as fencing with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> or a traditional kris,
        known as pencak silat.
      
    
  
