
  
  
    
      
        Festivals
        This is a far-from-exhaustive list of both traditional and
        new cultural festivals.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avoriaz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savoie</ENAMEX>), science-fiction film festival;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Champagne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burgundy</ENAMEX>, village processions for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>-growers’ patron
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saint Vincent</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> (or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early March</TIMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nice Mardi Gras</ENAMEX> carnival
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cluny</ENAMEX>, chamber music
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bourges</ENAMEX>, rock music; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Strasbourg</ENAMEX>, choral music; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arles</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Easter bullfights in Roman</ENAMEX> amphitheater
        May: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes, International Film Festival</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint-Tropez</ENAMEX>,
        “Bravade” religious procession; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amiens</ENAMEX>, jazz
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Versailles</ENAMEX>, chamber music; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Strasbourg</ENAMEX>, music;
        Honfleur, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitsun­tide Fête des Marins; Nîmes, Whitsuntide</ENAMEX> bullfights
        in amphi­theater; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Festival du Marais</ENAMEX> (music and theater); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dijon</ENAMEX>,
        music and theater, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street theater</ENAMEX> (until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>)
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avignon</ENAMEX>, international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, music, opera, dance,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>; Aix-en-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Provence</ENAMEX>, opera; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arles</ENAMEX>, photography seminars,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exhibitions</ENAMEX>, and audiovisual shows in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">amphitheater</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montpellier</ENAMEX>, music,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">opera</ENAMEX>, and dance (starts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange</ENAMEX>, opera in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amphitheater</ENAMEX>; Nice jazz; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bayonne</ENAMEX>, folklore; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Festival</ENAMEX> Estival
        (music and theater; till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Rochelle, Francopholies</ENAMEX> (music
        festival); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prades Festival Pablo Casals</ENAMEX> (chamber music; until
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mid-August</ENAMEX>)
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annecy</ENAMEX>, fireworks by the lake; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chartres</ENAMEX>, organ
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">recitals in cathedral, Assumption Day procession</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX>;
        Aix-en-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Provence</ENAMEX>, jazz; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colmar</ENAMEX>, wine fair; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Touquet</ENAMEX>, chamber music
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lyon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dance Biennale; Deauville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> film
        festival; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Festival</ENAMEX> d’Automne (music and theater; till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>);
        Dijon, wine festival; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mont</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saint-Michel</ENAMEX>, procession and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>: Angers <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde</ENAMEX> music; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>, jazz; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perpignan</ENAMEX>,
        jazz.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burgundy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beaune, Nuits-Saint-Georges, Meursault</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chablis</ENAMEX>), wine festivals; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dijon</ENAMEX>, gastronomy fair; <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX>, dance
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Baux-de-Provence</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fête des</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shepherds</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Midnight Mass</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Strasbourg</ENAMEX> and Alsatian
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> fairs
      
    
  
