
  
  
    
      
        What To Do
        To say that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> is a non-traditional city barely
        begins to hint at what a trip here will foretell. To say that gambling
        is the number one revenue source for business and taxes, and therefore
        has an immeasurable impact on the nature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, would be stating
        the obvious. Yet gambling is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> the story.
        The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> is where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX> come from, how they
        arrive here, and how they are served once they arrive. Gambling and
        entertainment may be the attractions, but tourism and service is the
        industry.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> reaps the rewards and suffers the losses of a
        metropolis of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over one million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> whose primary industry is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tourism</ENAMEX>. This existence makes the traditional travelers‚Äô definitions of
        ‚Äúwhat to do‚Äù and ‚Äúwhere to go‚Äù difficult to delineate. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>,
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> overlap, often to the point of indistinctness. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Casinos</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resorts</ENAMEX> and gambling and entertainment: where does one stop and the
        other begin? The answer is that they are interrelated and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interdependent</ENAMEX>.
        Until relatively recently, entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> were aimed primarily at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>. For the most part, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>
        wanted to experience any kind of entertainment or leisure time, they
        would likely visit one of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>.
        With the overwhelming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> explosion that started in
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1980s</TIMEX> came an unspoken demand from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> for more
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">traditional</ENAMEX>, off-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX> experiences, thus sparking a growth in local
        culture and amenities. Today, that process is still young but steadily
        evolving. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Locals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> are each feeling their way along a new
        path for experiencing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, one that combines the expected
        attractions of the gaming and tourism industry with those types of
        independent cultural amenities found in a more traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of its
        size. The happy result is a combination of the expected and the
        unexpected.
        Gambling
        Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX>, when gambling was officially legalized in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>
        after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22 years</TIMEX> of prohibition, it has been used to promote the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">travelers</ENAMEX>. Without question, the primary allure of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Las Vegas‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇdespite
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">showrooms</ENAMEX>, and shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇis the fact
        that one can legally place bets on games of chance and sporting events.
        Make no mistake: the times may be changing, but without gambling, there
        would be no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum Shops</ENAMEX>, no pirate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>, no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bellagio Gallery of Fine</ENAMEX>
        Art.
        Most of the gambling in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> is concentrated along the
        Strip, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly twenty</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> in excess of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100,000 sq ft</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9300 sq m</NUMEX>) beckon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passers-by</ENAMEX> to lighten their pockets a little and
        take the chance that they may be among the few who will win the ‚ÄúBig
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>. ‚Äù
        At most gaming tables along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX>, action is fast and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">furious</ENAMEX>, with generally inflexible house rules. Downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> are a
        bit more flexible when it comes to house rules, offering lower minimums
        and higher (sometimes no) limits. This attracts the unlikely
        combination of serious career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX> and novices without much to
        spend. Still, the atmosphere is generally more relaxed and amiable,
        probably due to the fact that Downtown is a concentrated area similar
        to a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">town‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇone</ENAMEX> that has not changed much in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 years</TIMEX>.
        It is important to keep in mind that before you venture
        into any live gaming area, you should familiarize yourself with the
        basics of the games you intend to play. Despite the exceptions pointed
        out above, most experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX> have little patience for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">novice</ENAMEX>, as they see them as a bad omen in the already frustrating
        situation of having to beat odds that are set against them. Also, there
        are strict rules as to what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> can do with his cards and chips,
        and where he can place his hands. Not knowing these rules can cost you
        a bet on the low end; repeated violations can lead to expulsion from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX>.
        If you are completely inexperienced, there are several ways
        to overcome your lack of knowledge. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> would be to read about
        the games. Below is a very brief guide to the most popular games, while
        many books are sold locally that go to great lengths to explain each
        game.
        Another method would be to practice on the electronic video
        version of the games before moving to the live tables. With minimum
        wagers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as low as 5¬¢</NUMEX> and a distinct lack of potentially impatient
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> waiting for you to decide your next move, electronic gaming is
        an alternative that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novice gamblers</ENAMEX> never move beyond. Most
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> offer a variety of video game slot machines. Try <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bally‚</ENAMEX>Äôs for
        the latest selection; after all, they manufacture them.
        Despite the potentially intimidating aspects of live
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gaming</ENAMEX>, it makes little sense to spend your vacation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> and
        not play at least a few hands of blackjack or craps, especially when
        there are free gaming lessons offered nearly everywhere. Gambling
        lessons are taught by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of novices, so no one feels
        pressured or out of place. This hands-on method is the best way to
        learn a game and its rules without risking your money or your
        pride.
        Baccarat
        Typically assumed to be a high-roller card game, baccarat
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">bah-cah-rah</ENAMEX>) is similar to blackjack, though it‚Äôs played with stricter
        rules, higher limits, and less player interaction. The object of the
        game is to come as close as possible to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>; the only real skill involved
        is deciding whether to bet on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> (i.e. , the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>). Most baccarat tables are located in quiet, sequestered
        sections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX>. Gambling lessons are highly recommended for
        this game.
        Big 6 (or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money Wheel</ENAMEX>)
        This spin-and-win (or more often lose) game looks strangely
        like the prize games offered in carnivals of old. Its ease of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">learning‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsimply</ENAMEX> bet on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the numbered wheel slots‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇattracts
        novices, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> edge makes them walk away very quickly.
        Bingo
        Nearly everyone knows the game of bingo, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>lottery
        in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> try to line up a horizontal or vertical row of
        randomly drawn numbers. The numbers are drawn until someone wins, and
        some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 10</NUMEX> cards playing at once. No lessons are
        required.
        Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> (or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">21</NUMEX>)
        This is the most popular live table game played in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegas‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇand the easiest card game to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">learn‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇowing</ENAMEX> to its relative
        simplicity. The object is to play against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>) to get as
        close to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> as possible without <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">‚Äúbusting‚Äù</ENAMEX> (going over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>). There are
        several optional bets‚<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsplitting</ENAMEX>, doubling down, insurance‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand
        variations that include single-deck vs. multi-deck card shoes and hands
        dealt face-up (as opposed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> down). The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> advantage is
        that if you bust, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> takes your money even if he busts as
        well.
        Craps
        This is the fabled game of cheering (and cursing) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX>,
        where everyone at the table has a stake in what one hapless gambler
        does with the dice. Loud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, dramatically placed chips, and flying
        dice all revolve around a set of complex betting rules and the fact
        that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> is more likely to be rolled than any other number. Money
        quickly changes hands at the craps table, making it another good
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for lessons. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don‚Äôt</ENAMEX> even lean against a busy craps table
        unless you know what you‚Äôre doing and have plenty of money to lose.
        Keno
        Another game very similar to a lottery, keno is usually
        played while sitting in a hotel coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>. Unlike bingo, however, the
        odds are shifted in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> circle random numbers on a purchased
        ticket and wait for a fixed set of numbers to be drawn. It‚Äôs easy to
        play: pick up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> numbers on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX>-number slip, then hand it and
        your money (usually a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar</NUMEX> per game) to the keno <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runner</ENAMEX>, and she‚Äôll
        return a computerized ticket. Watch the illuminated keno <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> above
        you to see if enough of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">numbers</ENAMEX> come up to win. The odds of
        winning are very low‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇin fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> advantage is greater than
        that of any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> game‚<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbut it‚</ENAMEX>Äôs an inexpensive way to pass the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> while you‚Äôre dining.
        Poker
        A high-stakes card game played in a high-pressure
        atmosphere. Unlike most other card games, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX> here play against
        each other; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> merely operates the game for a fixed percentage
        of the bets. There are many variations offered, from the standard
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>-card stud to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Hold ‚ÄòEm.</ENAMEX> This is another game in which lessons
        and lots of spare money are recommended. (As the old saying goes, ‚ÄúIf
        you can‚Äôt figure out who the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fool</ENAMEX> is at the poker table, it‚Äôs probably
        you. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX> )
        Pai Gow
        If you enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>, playing at mild pace, and playing
        against no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> advantage, you‚Äôll love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pai Gow</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> is dealt
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> cards, which are then arranged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> piles: one
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-card hand and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one two</NUMEX>-card hand. Standard poker rules apply; that
        is, pairs, straights, flushes, full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, etc. are ranked in a
        hierarchy of hands to determine the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card hand</ENAMEX> must
        beat the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card hand</ENAMEX>, and both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hands</ENAMEX> must beat the dealer‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> hands
        in order to win. If only one of the dealer‚Äôs hands wins, the game is a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúpush‚Äù</ENAMEX> (tie), and no money changes hands (this happens more often than
        not). If both the dealer‚Äôs hands win, you lose. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> also perfectly
        acceptable to ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> for advice on how to play your hand (and a
        great way to learn). The caveat is that since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> has no
        advantage, it takes <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> of your winnings.
        Roulette
        Another subdued game of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> fame, roulette does not
        enjoy much popularity in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs a relatively simple game,
        where bets are placed by laying chips on a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of
        numbers, colors, or odd/even. Different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> are given different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">colored</ENAMEX> chips to avoid confusion. The wheel is spun, the ball drops,
        and where it lands determines the outcome. Odds are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as high as 35 to 1</NUMEX>,
        which means a single <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> chip on the right number wins you <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$175</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hint</ENAMEX>:
        avoid playing a double-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> wheel and search for those with only one
        zero. ) Winning numbers are illuminated at each table to attract
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passers-by</ENAMEX> into thinking ‚ÄúIt‚Äôs hitting my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX>! ‚Äù
        Slots
        Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX>, slot machines have become the most
        popular form of gaming in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇso much so that they supersede
        the play at table games in many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>. Though all modern slot
        machines are computerized, the rules are still the same: get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> matching icons in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX> (or some combination thereof) and you win.
        The difference is that the computer decides when you win, not pure
        chance. And even though the payback increases the more you bet on a
        single pull, the computer will decrease your odds of winning. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">skill</ENAMEX>, they say, is to find a slot machine that‚<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Äôs ‚Äúhitting‚Äù</ENAMEX>; that is, a
        computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">that‚</ENAMEX>Äôs programmed to pay out big money. But what do you think
        the chances are of that happening very often?
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Video Poker</ENAMEX>
        Video <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> has become increasingly popular, so much so
        that there‚Äôs hardly a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">laundromat</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>
        that doesn‚Äôt have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two or three</NUMEX> machines. It‚Äôs the same as
        regular <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-card stud, with the machine acting as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>. Unlike
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slots</ENAMEX>, interaction and a semblance of skill are required; that is, you
        are offered a choice on how to play the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">hand you‚Äôre</ENAMEX> dealt. A chart on
        the screen lists the payoff of your winning hand and, as with slots,
        the more you bet, the better the payoff. Versions of video poker range
        from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúJacks or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better‚Äù</ENAMEX> (the standard game) to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúDeuces Wild‚Äù</ENAMEX> and ‚ÄúDouble
        Bonus,‚Äù though the more wild cards involved the lower the payoff.
        The Big Shows
        Once, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">showrooms</ENAMEX> were filled with top
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entertainment‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇheadliners</ENAMEX>, comedians, production shows, and dancing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">girls‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthat</ENAMEX> could be enjoyed at a very low price. In that bygone era,
        elaborate dinner shows were considered a loss <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, a way to keep
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> happily dropping money at the tables or the slot machines. As
        long as the bottom line shined, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>, especially those in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> era, were happy to continue providing low-cost or even free
        entertainment and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.
        When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> moved in with more stringent departmental
        accounting procedures, every sector of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel-casino</ENAMEX> had to show
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>. Not satisfied with a simple overall profit, corporate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> began to both raise prices and cut corners, resulting in an
        era of frustrating mediocrity from which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> has only recently
        emerged.
        Most <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">showrooms</ENAMEX> are again offering quality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and
        elaborate productions, sans the accompanying dinner service. The prices
        have certainly risen, but so has the benchmark of quality. Some of the
        bigger shows and headliner appearances (especially during major events
        like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Year‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>) exceed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> per ticket‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇtypical for New York
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>, but previously unheard of in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>. What this means is that,
        in the case of showroom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entertainers</ENAMEX>, the old adage of getting what you
        pay for now applies equally to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>.
        Although the runs for the shows listed here are considered
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">open-ended</ENAMEX>, remember that nothing is static in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>. Entire
        resorts open and close, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">showrooms</ENAMEX> sometimes change show times,
        prices, or entire featured productions. Also, there are numerous
        headlining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entertainers</ENAMEX> that change from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week to week</TIMEX>. For current
        listings of all resort entertainment, pick up a free copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showbiz</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">What‚</ENAMEX>Äôs On In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most comprehensive visitor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guides</ENAMEX>. Below, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúdark‚Äù</ENAMEX> refers to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> when the show does not play at
        all. Be advised that it is traditional for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">showgirls</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>
        production shows to be topless, and that tradition continues; many
        shows are not appropriate for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Superstars</ENAMEX>: Of the cavalcade of impersonator
        shows, this one is skewed heavily toward the modern era. Talented
        performers provide energetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renditions</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Estefan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Daniels</ENAMEX>, among others. And, yes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Girls impersonators</ENAMEX> still have Ginger. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stratosphere Hotel and Casino</ENAMEX>,
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas Boulevard South</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">380-7777</TIMEX>. Shows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 and 10pm</TIMEX>,
        no <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late</TIMEX> show <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunday‚ÄìTuesday</ENAMEX>; dark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$38</NUMEX> or less (special rate
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4‚Äì12</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesars Magical Empire</ENAMEX>: A particularly unusual interactive
        dinner and show experience set in a series of elaborately themed
        underground <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX> rather than a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">showroom</ENAMEX> proper. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Entertainers</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illusionists</ENAMEX> perform while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diners</ENAMEX> eat various <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> and then move to
        another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>. Fun for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesars Palace Hotel</ENAMEX> and
        Casino, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3570</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas Boulevard South</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">731-7110</TIMEX>. Multiple
        seatings start at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5pm</TIMEX>; dark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $75</NUMEX> (special rate
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5‚Äì10</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cirque du Soleil‚Äôs Myst√®re</ENAMEX>: The internationally famed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cirque</ENAMEX> takes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circus</ENAMEX> to new levels of sophistication in an amazing
        state-of-the art <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>. No <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are used in this circus, just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> of amazing physical and emotive skill and grace. A most
        unique <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> experience that borders on performance art. This
        popular show spawned the aquatic show at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bellagio</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Treasure Island,</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3300</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas Boulevard South</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">894-7111</TIMEX>. Shows <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30</TIMEX> and
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30pm</TIMEX>; dark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $60</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cirque du Soleil‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>: The latest from the acclaimed
        international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troupe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> dazzles in an aquatic environment that utilizes
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.5 million gallons</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.8 million liters)‚</NUMEX>Äàof <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. True to the Cirque
        tradition, there are no <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX>. Bellagio
        Hotel and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casino</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3600</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas Boulevard South</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">693-7111</ENAMEX>.
        Shows <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11pm</TIMEX>; dark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $100</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Gans</ENAMEX> ‚Äì <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Man of Many Voices: What</ENAMEX> started as a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">short-lived Las Vegas</ENAMEX> stint at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Stratosphere Tower</ENAMEX> has evolved into
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most popular shows in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gans</ENAMEX> is an amazing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impersonator</ENAMEX> and an energetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">showman</ENAMEX> who has mastered the art of
        entertainment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirage Hotel and Casino</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7900</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas Boulevard South</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">791-7111</TIMEX>. Shows 8pm; dark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frida y</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $60</NUMEX>.
        EFX: A grand <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$45 million</NUMEX> production show in a classic but
        updated style. Featuring a host of original music sung by the main star
        (at writing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Tune</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of other singing and dancing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">talents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EFX</ENAMEX> is a special-effects laden science-fiction tale suitable
        for all ages. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM Grand Hotel and Casino</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3799</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las Vegas Boulevard</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">891-7777</TIMEX>. Shows <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 and 10:30pm</TIMEX>; dark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $50</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Newton</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Las Vegas‚</ENAMEX>Äôs copnsummate entertainer, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayne</ENAMEX>
        Newton croons to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six nights a week</TIMEX> in an elaborate new
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theater</ENAMEX> named for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúMr</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegas‚Äù</ENAMEX> himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stardust Resort</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casino</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3000</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas Boulevard South</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">732-6111</TIMEX>. Shows 9pm
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday‚ÄìThursday</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8 and 11pm Saturday</TIMEX>; dark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX> or less.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Man Group</ENAMEX>: This award-winning (albeit unusual) show
        features three bald, blue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. The one-of-a-kind showroom
        experience has been called innovative, hilarious, and musically
        powerful. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luxor Hotel and Casino</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3900</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas Boulevard South</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">262-4100</TIMEX>. Shows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 and 10pm</TIMEX> (no late show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>); dark
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $50</NUMEX>.
        Jubilee! : <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long</ENAMEX> before the blockbuster movie, Jubilee! was
        sinking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX> in what is the show‚Äôs signature
        amazing special effect. The show also features <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk Arthur</ENAMEX> and
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of topless and costumed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">showgirls</ENAMEX>, making this an event for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> only. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bally‚Äôs Hotel and Casino</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3645</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas Boulevard South</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">967-4111</TIMEX>. Shows <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 and 10:30pm</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wednesday‚ÄìMonday</ENAMEX>; dark
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$45‚Äì60</NUMEX>.
        King <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Arthur‚Äôs Tournament</ENAMEX>: A radical departure from modern
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> stage shows, this one features two unusual elements: live
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> and dinner‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">latter</ENAMEX> of which is eaten without utensils. A
        re-creation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">medieval knights‚</ENAMEX>Äô jousting tournament, it‚Äôs great fun
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excalibur Hotel and Casino</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3850</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las Vegas Boulevard</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">597-7777</TIMEX>. Shows <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 and 8:30pm</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$45</NUMEX> or less.
        Legends In Concert: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> of many return <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>,
        this classic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> impersonation show features all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greats</ENAMEX> from
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Impersonators render uncanny performances of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tops</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>, as well as modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Turner</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial Palace Hotel and Casino</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3535</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las Vegas Boulevard</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">731-3311</TIMEX>. Shows <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 and 10:30pm</TIMEX>; dark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX> or
        less.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Master Magician Lance Burton:‚ÄàSet</ENAMEX> in perhaps the most
        magnificent environment in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Las Vegas‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇan impeccably gilded</ENAMEX> theater
        that somehow maintains intimacy‚<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇmagician Lance Burton</ENAMEX> pulls off
        extraordinary illusions with the assistance of a talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dancers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monte Carlo Hotel and Casino</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3770</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas Boulevard South</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">730-7777</TIMEX>. Shows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 and 10pm</TIMEX>; dark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX> or
        less.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Flatley‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance</ENAMEX>: From the heralded
        choreographer of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Riverdance</ENAMEX> comes this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> production, an
        internationally recognized hit featuring over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> in an
        amazing show of traditional and modern dance. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Hotel</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casino</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3790</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas Boulevard South</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">740-6969</TIMEX>. Shows
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 and 10:30pm</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>; 9pm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>;
        dark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50‚Äì80</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegfried</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX>: These world-famous illusionists and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> have risen from a small-time specialty act to stardom.
        Their famous white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX> are an integral part of the show, set in a
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1500</TIMEX>-seat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">showroom</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirage Hotel and Casino</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3400</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las Vegas Boulevard</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">791-7444</TIMEX>. Shows <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11pm</TIMEX>; dark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> and
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $60</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Splash:‚ÄàOne</ENAMEX> of the few remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">‚Äútraditional‚Äù Vegas</ENAMEX>
        production shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Splash</ENAMEX> features a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX>
        who perform around variety acts. There are numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">set</ENAMEX> and theme
        changes, plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> use, and a number in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX>
        (topless at the late show) come into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riviera Hotel</ENAMEX> and
        Casino, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2901</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas Boulevard South</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">734-5110</TIMEX>. Shows <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30</TIMEX>
        and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30pm</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36‚Äì60</NUMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best of the Folies Berg√®res‚Ä¶Sexier Than Ever: The home</ENAMEX>
        of the topless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folies Berg√®res</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tropicana‚Äôs</ENAMEX> show was recently revamped and updated. Nothing says ‚ÄúLas
        Vegas‚Äù quite like this; the glittering costumes and chorus line of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">showgirls</ENAMEX> is what the myth was based on. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tropicana Resort</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casino</ENAMEX>,
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3801</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas Boulevard South</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">739-2222</TIMEX>. Shows <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30</TIMEX> and
        10pm; dark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40‚Äì60</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
        Where there is money, there is shopping‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇor so it should
        seem. As with everything else in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> have
        always been around, but when compared with other major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, they did
        not live up to expectation. Hotel shopping areas consisted of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>
        selling primarily expensive and tacky (or sometimes cheap and tacky)
        merchandise, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> were utilitarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> of typical retail
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. This scenario has changed dramatically in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>.
        As the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> expands, so do the shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. Upscale
        department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> have arrived at suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>,
        challenging the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stalwarts</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dillard‚Äôs.</ENAMEX> Additionally, top
        name <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> now have retail locations in several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> shopping
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>. The development of new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum Shops</ENAMEX> (at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesars Palace</ENAMEX>) has in some cases single-handedly elevated the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of
        shopping in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, with even more major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>-based shopping
        promenades having emerged at the recently opened <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aladdin</ENAMEX> and Venetian
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resorts</ENAMEX>.
        As if the explosion of retail shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> was not enough
        to quell the demand, there are outlet <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> in abundance within a short
        drive, and a handful of local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> that deserve attention.
        Retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Malls</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum Shops</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesars</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/893-4800</ENAMEX>), a themed
        indoor shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">promenade</ENAMEX> built to look and feel like an outdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
        street, surprised quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> by attracting not only
        the obvious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX>, but also more than a handful of
        shopping-starved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> eager to explore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> they once had to travel
        out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to visit. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> expansion then doubled the space. From
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DKNY</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAO Schwarz</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> have their only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>
        location here. The number of excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and entertainment
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outlets</ENAMEX> makes this a great place for an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all-day</TIMEX>, one-stop spending
        spree.
        Also on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX>, The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fashion Show Mall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/369-8382</ENAMEX>) was for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> the only high-fashion shopping source for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> with excess cash. Though it has since been
        eclipsed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum Shops</ENAMEX>, many big name department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> absent
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">area malls</ENAMEX> are located here (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saks Fifth Avenue</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neiman Marcus</ENAMEX> among them). A generous selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>,
        from fast food to fabulous, satiate the hunger brought on by walking
        the mall‚Äôs long wings.
        Stepping away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Boulevard Mall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/732-8949</ENAMEX>) was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of its type in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>. As with many
        places in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, it was recently remodeled and expanded, making it
        again one of the city‚Äôs most popular stops for standard mall shopping.
        Its proximity to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX> make it popular for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> as well.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galleria</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sunset</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/434-0202</ENAMEX>) is the most
        recent of the suburban shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>. Located in the upscale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX> area of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Henderson</ENAMEX>, across from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunset Station Hotel</ENAMEX> and
        Casino, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> houses interesting specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in addition to
        department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, as well as a huge food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.
        Despite a recent renovation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Meadows Mall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/878-4849</ENAMEX>) is the least appealing of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>. At
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point the crown jewel of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> shopping, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> now resides
        in a central and older region of the valley, sandwiched between
        middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and upper-crust long-timers. While the shopping
        selection is similar to the other suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>, sadly, the atmosphere
        is not.
        Factory <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Outlet Malls</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fashion Outlet Mall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/874-1400</ENAMEX>) at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primm</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> (on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX>) is the latest entry into the
        outlet mall roster, and the best. Though it requires a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-minute</TIMEX> drive
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tropicana</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-15</ENAMEX> (or the free shuttle from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-888-424-6898</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fashion Outlet‚Äôs</ENAMEX> selection of top names
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guess</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Cole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Hilfiger</ENAMEX>) and specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> (such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams Sonoma</ENAMEX>) make it worth the effort.
        Within the valley is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belz Factory Outlet World</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/896-5599</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Belz</ENAMEX>, an indoor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>, offers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">145</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> ranging from
        clothing to electronics.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selected Local Shopping</ENAMEX>
        Beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> lie <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of unique specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>.
        From ethnic food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and vintage clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> to electronics and
        book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, there are so many interesting shopping spots that it is
        hard to imagine their breadth and depth. The following are a few <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> highlights; for a more thorough listing of specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, pick
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up one</NUMEX> of the free alternative newsweeklies, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CityLife</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Attic</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/388-4088</ENAMEX>) is perhaps the most famous
        vintage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, owing to its feature in both a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX>
        commercial and on extreme sports network <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> II. A massive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story
        collection of vintage clothes, appliances and knickknacks, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Attic</ENAMEX>
        serves an international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> with its wide selection of period
        clothing. They are often called upon to provide items for movies being
        filmed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>.
        On the other end of the scale, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tower/WOW</ENAMEX>! Multimedia
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superstore</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/364-2500</ENAMEX>) sells nothing even remotely vintage,
        except perhaps within its vast CD selection. A combined effort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tower</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Records</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Guys Electronics, WOW</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overwhelms</ENAMEX> in every way. To
        the right is a huge electronics and computer selection featuring a home
        theater <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and a classical listening <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. To the left are
        innumerable aisles of records, books, software, CDs, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12-inch</NUMEX> vinyl, and
        the city‚Äôs largest selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äòzines</ENAMEX>. At the fulcrum
        is a coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and caf√© under a giant screen television flanked by CD
        listening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>.
        Those who wear glasses will appreciate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX> location
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Optica</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/735-8557</ENAMEX>), a full service optometry
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shop</ENAMEX> that can repair eyewear, provide exams, and set visitors up with a
        new set of prescription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glasses</ENAMEX> or contact lenses‚<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇall</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> or
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> frame selection is among the best in town.
        For souvenirs of the innately <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> kind, there is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gamblers‚Äô General Store</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/382-9903</ENAMEX>), a centrally located
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> of slot machines, gaming tables, and other gaming
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accoutrements</ENAMEX>. Most items can be shipped for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purchaser</ENAMEX> by
        request.
        For a taste of authentic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paiute Tribal</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smoke Shop</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/387-6433</ENAMEX>) sells tax-free tobacco products through
        its drive-through window, so you can cruise right back to the hotel and
        spend all that money you just saved.
        Sports
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> is a sporting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Whether you want to watch
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Tyson</ENAMEX> pulverize his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>, bet on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Giants</ENAMEX> at a
        sports book, or play <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> holes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>, all it takes is the right toys
        and/or plenty of cash. If you engage in outdoor sports, remember that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">valley</ENAMEX> temperatures can reach well above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100¬∫</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">38¬∫ C</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> and
        below freezing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> after the sun drops below the mountains. Take
        all necessary precautions when participating in any outdoor sport.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator Sports</ENAMEX>
        Boxing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> has a rich boxing history, having hosted enough
        championship matches to qualify as a capital of the sport. A big-time
        bout at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> that handle most of the action‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM Grand</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/891-7777</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesars Palace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/731-7110</ENAMEX>), or
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirage</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">702/791-7111)‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇinvariably</ENAMEX> draws a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> heavy with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Finals Rodeo</ENAMEX>
        Held every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, this is one of the largest‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">richest‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇrodeo</ENAMEX> events in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, featuring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 days</TIMEX> of the
        nation‚Äôs top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX> and cowgirls riding <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bulls</ENAMEX>, busting broncos, and
        roping <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">calves</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mack Center</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> goes western with
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">endless</TIMEX> satellite events: beauty pageants, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and dances at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX>,
        cowboy-themed art exhibits, musical events at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Downtown‚Äôs Fremont Street</ENAMEX>
        Experience, and golf tournaments. If you wish to attend, plan
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ahead‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇlast-minute</ENAMEX> tickets to the big rodeo events are hard to come
        by.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motor Sports</ENAMEX>
        Serious auto racing arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> with the
        opening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Motor Speedway</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">17 miles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">27 km</NUMEX>) north of
        Downtown on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Interstate 15</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,500-acre</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">607-hectare</ENAMEX>) site is a
        speed-freak‚Äôs dream: a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11‚ÅÑ2-mile</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">21‚ÅÑ2-km</TIMEX>) tri-oval super <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">speedway</ENAMEX>,
        smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay</ENAMEX> and paved <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ovals</ENAMEX>, a drag strip, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road track</ENAMEX>, and a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motocross</ENAMEX> course. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Race fans</ENAMEX> fill the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">107,000</NUMEX>-seat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASCAR</ENAMEX>
        events like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las Vegas 300</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston West</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Craftsman Truck</ENAMEX> races,
        as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRL Las Vegas</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf Tournaments</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las Vegas Invitational</ENAMEX> held every <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fall‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇfamed</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX>
        Woods‚Äô <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> professional tournament in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1996‚</NUMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇis considered the city‚Äôs
        top golf attraction. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> split the action: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX> at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canyons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Highlands</ENAMEX>, and the main course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summerlin</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPC</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canyons</ENAMEX> is home to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Senior Classic</ENAMEX>, a top
        draw for golf‚Äôs big names held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every spring</TIMEX>. Check the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PGA</ENAMEX> website at
        <www.pgatour.com> for complete information on tournaments and on
        other golf events.
        Bowling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> has always had an affinity for <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">bowling</ENAMEX>. The PBA
        holds both national and senior televised tournaments here at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showboat Bowling Center</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>.
        Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, while lacking a major sports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>, is home
        to a triple-A baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and a minor-league hockey <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vegas Stars‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> city‚Äôs longest-running professional sports
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">outfit‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇis</ENAMEX> a farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for baseball‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Diego Padres</ENAMEX>;tickets are
        usually available for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cashman Field</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> games. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>
        Thunder hockey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> (which is not affiliated with any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>)
        competes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mack Center</ENAMEX>. During <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and basketball
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">seasons</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Nevada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> fields <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sports</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNLV‚</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Äôs basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> has a storied history, winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Participatory Sports</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf</ENAMEX>
        For a desert <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> has more than enough grass
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fairways</ENAMEX> and water hazards to keep the most avid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duffer</ENAMEX> busy. For a
        locator map and a course-by-course description, go to
        <www.lasvegasfreedom.com>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rio Suites Hotel</ENAMEX> maintains a
        course <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several miles</NUMEX> away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX> for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> that offers
        spectacular views of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas Valley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Angel Park Golf Club</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/254-4653</ENAMEX>) is a municipal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> with a difference: it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        18-hole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Palmer</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-hole par-3 course
        featuring replicas of famous par-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> holes from around the world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vegas Paiute Resort</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/658-1400</ENAMEX>) is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 miles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">32 km</NUMEX>) north of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> but worth the mileage: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> courses‚<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇcalled Snow</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mountain‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwas</ENAMEX> designated the best public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Nevada</ENAMEX> by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf Digest</ENAMEX>. Also beyond city limits is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Legacy Golf Club</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/897-2200</ENAMEX>) in the nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Henderson</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock Climbing</ENAMEX>
        Red <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock Canyon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/363-1921</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just 20 minutes</TIMEX> from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX>, boasts some of the best rock climbing in the western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. There are literally <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of climbing challenges, from
        small bouldering routes to towering, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>-only cliffs. Spring and
        fall are optimum climbing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX>, but almost any <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> will find a
        cross-section of the international rock-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock community</ENAMEX> roping up in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">canyon</ENAMEX>. Sky‚Äôs the Limit guide service (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/363-4533</ENAMEX>) can arrange
        climbing trips of nearly any duration. For a more climate-controlled
        climb, try the indoor climbing mountain at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GameWorks</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX> (see
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">page 100</ENAMEX>). At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">75 ft</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX>) it is said to be among the world‚Äôs
        highest.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hiking</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas Valley</ENAMEX> is rimmed with quality hiking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the more scenic is the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five-mile</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">River Mountain Trail</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/293-2034</ENAMEX>), which offers fine views of both <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Mead</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas Valley</ENAMEX>. Red <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rock Canyon</ENAMEX> affords numerous routes, including a
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-mile Pine Creek Canyon trek</ENAMEX> and a slightly longer walk along the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keystone Thrust Trail</ENAMEX>. Likewise, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Charleston</ENAMEX> is webbed wit h many
        good hikes; the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranger station</ENAMEX> there can supply more information
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/873-8800</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley of Fire</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX>) is also a popular hiking
        spot.
        Bicycling
        Avoid putting your mettle to the peddle on the city‚Äôs
        busier <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>; bike <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">paths</ENAMEX> are few and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">courteous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> even fewer.
        The best places are local <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX>-friendly spots beyond city
        limits. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> favorite: the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">13-mile</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">21-km</NUMEX>) scenic loop at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Rock</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canyon</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX>), takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cyclists</ENAMEX> through some of the area‚Äôs more
        picturesque landscapes and is not overly taxing. Mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bikers</ENAMEX> can
        call Escape the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">City Streets</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/596-2953</ENAMEX>) to arrange a more
        rugged ride through the canyon‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cottonwood Valley</ENAMEX>. Another good bet:
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Lamb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">State Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/486-5413</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few miles</NUMEX> north on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">US 95</NUMEX>. The
        bike paths wind among ponds, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, and historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennis</ENAMEX>
        Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> have tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> only.
        Otherwise,the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las Vegas Sporting House</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/733-8999</ENAMEX>), a
        membership sporting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, makes its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> available to nonmembers as
        well, and several additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> can be found in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lorenzi Park</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snow Sports</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Charleston</ENAMEX> has a ski area, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las Vegas Ski</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snowboard Resort</ENAMEX>, also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Canyon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/872-5462</ENAMEX>). It has
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bunny</ENAMEX>, intermediate, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> routes, along with all the trappings:
        ski rental, ski <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX>. The natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snowfall</ENAMEX> is often
        augmented by snow-making equipment to ensure adequate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">powder</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vegas Ski</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Snowboard Resort</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> long runs on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 acres</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hectares</ENAMEX>); despite its name, snowboarding is allowed only at certain
        times.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adult Entertainment</ENAMEX>
        For all the hype about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Las Vegas‚</ENAMEX>Äôs conversion to a family
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX>, the unrelenting truth is that beyond all the shiny new big name
        properties lies a bevy of adult-oriented distractions. While in the
        recent past efforts were made to eliminate many of these attractions,
        the actual result was that most of the more seedy or disreputable
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> have disappeared while those operating within the law have
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flourished</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> now seems poised to accept the multiple layers of
        its existence as a tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
        Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX> have appeased family
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> by cleaning up their shows and covering up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">showgirls</ENAMEX>. But
        at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Riviera</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/734-5110</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> shows are adult-oriented
        (though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Splash</ENAMEX> is covered for the early show); for raucous fun, choose
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúCrazy Girls‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇa topless review that gets even more red-light
        during convention <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>.
        There are also dozens of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> that offer either nude or
        topless entertainment. Of the topless-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> (all of which have
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bars</ENAMEX>), the two best are <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cheetah‚Äôs Topless Lounge</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2112</TIMEX> Western
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenue</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/384-0074</ENAMEX>), an intimate, friendly place, and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garden Cabaret</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1531</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas Boulevard South</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/385-8987</ENAMEX>)
        which, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> full-size stages, is quite the opposite. For totally
        nude <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX>, the choices are just as varied, but only one‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">venerable Palomino Club</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1848</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas Boulevard North</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">702/642-2984)‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇserves</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>. Of the numerous others that do not, the
        best bet is the tastefully decorated but oddly named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spearmint Rhino</ENAMEX>,
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3340</TIMEX> S. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Highland Drive</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">796-3600</ENAMEX>.
        Nightlife
        For all there is to do and see in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, one may
        wonder if there is a nightlife at all outside of the obvious. The
        answer is a resounding yes. From local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> featuring live music and
        comedy, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclubs</ENAMEX>, caf√©s and coffeehouses, the city‚Äôs nightlife
        beyond gambling and shows is very healthy. For a detailed listing of
        local events beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX>, pick up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> free alternative
        newsweeklies, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CityLife</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las Vegas Weekly</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nightclubbing</ENAMEX> has come of age in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, thanks to a
        resurgence of dance music and the city‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> boom. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club Utopia</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/390-4650</ENAMEX>), on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX> but not in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, may be
        single-handedly responsible for reviving the dying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> nightclub
        scene by taking the metropolitan sounds of techno and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> out of the
        underground and into a commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> venue for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time.
        That, along with the success of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club Rio</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/252-7727</ENAMEX>) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rio</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suites Hotel</ENAMEX>, led to a deluge of new hotel-based high energy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>,
        including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ra</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luxor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/262-4000</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Studio 54</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/891-1111</ENAMEX>), and more scheduled to open soon. Each caters
        to a specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, so hunt around until you find the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right for
        you.
        Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclubs</ENAMEX> place as much emphasis on drinking as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dancing</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Drink Las Vegas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/796-5519</ENAMEX>), a fabulous
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclub</ENAMEX> with numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> serving every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX> known to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/731-1925</ENAMEX>) is also <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stories high, with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waiters</ENAMEX> and waitresses dressed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sunbathing‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthey</ENAMEX> often jump on the
        bar for a little bikini dancing.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lesbian</ENAMEX> and gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> will find integrated nightlife
        in the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúGay Triangle‚</ENAMEX>Äù area on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise Road</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gipsy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/731-1919</ENAMEX>) is small but wall-to-wall with energetic dancing (it‚Äôs
        mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> here, though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are welcome). Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, Lace
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/791-0100</ENAMEX>) is a tiny women‚Äôs disco in the back of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angles</ENAMEX> video
        bar.
        The caf√© scene is surprisingly strong for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with so
        many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Starbucks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caf√© Copioh</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/739-0305</ENAMEX>) is a well known
        haunt of university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a calendar</TIMEX> of
        events ranging from poetry readings to live music. Nearby is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">venerable Caf√© Espresso Roma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/369-1540)‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe oldest</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coffeehouse</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> and, according to some, still the best in all
        its Bohemian glory.
        For less caffeine and more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in the
        Downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gateway District</ENAMEX> is the egalitarian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Enigma Garden Caf√©</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/386-0999</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX>, poets, city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">councilmen</ENAMEX>, and starving musicians
        partake day and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> of its garden setting and large menu featuring
        items with names of historic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> importance. In the opposite
        direction you‚Äôll enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jazzed Cafe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vinoteca</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/798-5995</ENAMEX>), a
        charming bistro with a magnificent by-the-glass <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> list and a
        carefully crafted menu of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tuscan</ENAMEX> specialties accompanied by acid jazz,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tiramis√π</ENAMEX> and espresso. Best of all, it‚Äôs open until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 4am</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children</ENAMEX>
        Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> is better known as an adult <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, there
        are a surprising number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>-friendly activities. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> have
        at least some kind of arcade, but the true high-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scorer</ENAMEX> is GameWorks
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/895-7626</ENAMEX>), next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM Grand</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">47,000 sq ft</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4371 sq</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX>) of games (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than 250</NUMEX>) from traditional pin-ball outposts to
        high-tech diversions. If you play up an appetite, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GameWorks</ENAMEX> also has a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">full-service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, snack bar, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starbucks Coffee</ENAMEX> outlet. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adults</ENAMEX>
        may relax in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and shoot pool while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kiddies</ENAMEX> shoot each
        other.
        Add a little zoom to your kids‚Äô day with a stop at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sahara</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speedworld</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/737-2111</ENAMEX>), a huge (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40,000-sq-ft /3720-sq-m</NUMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">playground</ENAMEX> of virtual reality auto racing in life-size race <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of interactive rides, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> 3-D <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between May</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> can take tots and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>
        alike for a cool dip at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wet ‚ÄòN Wild</ENAMEX> water <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/737-3819</ENAMEX>).
        There are kiddie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> and knee-buckling water slides. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Der Stuka</ENAMEX> offers
        a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-story drop, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Black Hole</ENAMEX> shoots you through a dark
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tunnel</ENAMEX>. Or just float along in the slow-moving lazy river or drift in
        the large wave pool.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, as it sought to attract more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> has become a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX> is a grand example.
        At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM Grand Adventure Theme Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">702/891-7777</TIMEX>; open spring
        and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> only), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> can raft a small river, take a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>-ft (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">61-m</NUMEX>)
        freefall from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky Screamer</ENAMEX>, watch a colorful sea battle, or chat
        with strolling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Decades ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circus Circus</ENAMEX> inaugurated the era of family
        friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel-casino</ENAMEX>, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> has tried to up the ante
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Slam Canyon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/734-0410</ENAMEX>), a pink-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX>-covered,
        climate-controlled cluster of attractions: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canyon Blaster</ENAMEX> corkscrew
        roller coaster, a water ride, bumper <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, carnival games, and a laser
        tag arena. It‚Äôs located behind the venerable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel-casino</ENAMEX>, which itself
        features <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>-friendly free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circus</ENAMEX> acts from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11am</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Roller coaster aficionados</ENAMEX> will want to hop aboard the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">twisting</ENAMEX>, turning, looping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Express</ENAMEX> roller coaster at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. While insi¬≠de, stop at the extensive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coney Island</ENAMEX>-themed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arcade</ENAMEX>. Equal thrills can be had atop the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Stratosphere Tower</ENAMEX>, where you
        will find a slingshot ride called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Shot</ENAMEX>. Its sudden vertical
        acceleration is accentuated by its setting <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,100 ft</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">335 m</ENAMEX>) above the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. There is a roller coaster up there as well, but experienced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">riders</ENAMEX> consider it too slow and uneventful despite the altitude.
        Next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM Grand</ENAMEX> you will find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M&M World</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
        stories of merchandise and memorabilia dedicated to the candy that
        doesn‚Äôt melt in your hand. Inside is an <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8,500-sq-ft</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">791-sq-m</NUMEX>) store
        loaded with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M&M</ENAMEX> knickknacks.
        Want to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>? Try the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-course miniature <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>, bumper <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>, go-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carts</ENAMEX> and arcade games at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scandia Family Fun Center</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/364-0070</ENAMEX>).
        Even farther from the lights is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bonnie Springs</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Nevada</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/875-4191</ENAMEX>), a mock ghost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Rock Canyon</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">wild-West</ENAMEX> town comes complete with gunfights, a wax <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, an opera
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-train</ENAMEX>, horseback riding, and an extensive petting
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">zoo</ENAMEX>.
        For motorized thrills, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> grand
        prix go-cart course. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Mini Gran Prix</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/259-7000</ENAMEX>)
        boasts the west‚Äôs only banked-oval stock car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX>, bring your
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">driving gloves‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇalong</ENAMEX> with go-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carts</ENAMEX> and kiddie <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carts</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7-acre</NUMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3-hectare</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> has wheels for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> as well.
        For something a little more aggressive, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paintball</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/595-2555</ENAMEX>) puts paintball <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in the hands of budding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">warriors‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇover</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 10</TIMEX>, that is.
        Local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX>
        Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> isn‚Äôt known for its culture, that
        doesn‚Äôt mean it hasn‚Äôt any. Anchor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> in the local arts scene
        include the long-lived <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nevada Ballet Theatre</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/243-2623</ENAMEX>), which
        has toured the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and the world with its original productions. The
        visual and performing arts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Nevada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vegas</ENAMEX> also constitute a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of cultural activity. The Summerlin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library and Performing Arts Center</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/256-5111</ENAMEX>) features an art
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> (as do most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library branches</ENAMEX> in the area) and frequent music
        and theater performances. Activity information is available through the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nevada Arts Council</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">702/486-3700</ENAMEX>).
      
    
  
