
  
  
    
      
        Hawaii’s Other Islands
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> usually confine their travels to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> main
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">islands — Oahu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maui</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kauai</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Big Island</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>. Some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> add <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Molokai</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lanai</ENAMEX> to their itineraries. No discussion of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> would be complete, however, without mentioning some other
        islands in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niihau</ENAMEX>. Just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">17 miles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">27 km</NUMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kauai</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">73-sq mile</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">189-sq km</NUMEX>) island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niihau</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">nee-ee</ENAMEX>-how) is called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">“The Forbidden</ENAMEX>
        Island” because it is privately owned and cannot be visited without an
        invitation from one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">225</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX>. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pure-blooded Hawaiians</ENAMEX> who speak the language. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are engaged in
        ranching operations for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Robinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>; the women
        collect and string the tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niihau</ENAMEX> seashells into leis that fetch big
        prices. There are no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niihau —</ENAMEX> nor electricity or running
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Once they finish the lower grades, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niihau</ENAMEX> attend
        school on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kauai</ENAMEX>. Niihau’s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are free to leave the island, but once
        they move elsewhere, they may be refused permission to return.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kahoolawe</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barren Kahoolawe</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">kah-ho-oh-law-vay</ENAMEX>) is a tiny
        island just off the southwest coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maui</ENAMEX>. Once inhabited by ancient
        Hawaiians, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> has since served as an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alcatraz</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>, a
        cattle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX>, and — most recently — a bombing range for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Navy</ENAMEX>
        (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939 to 1990</TIMEX>). Now turned back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is littered
        with unexploded bombs. Cleanup is slow and expensive, but plans call
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kahoolawe</ENAMEX> to become a cultural reserve. Until then, it remains
        essentially off-limits to the public.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midway</ENAMEX>. Lying some <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,100 miles</NUMEX> northwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midway</ENAMEX>
        is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">atoll</ENAMEX> comprised of a few tiny islands. Best known as the site of
        a pivotal <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> battle in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midway</ENAMEX> is no longer a
        military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> but is open to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, managed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX> &
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wildlife Department</ENAMEX> as a refuge for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of Laysan Albatross
        (called <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gooney birds</ENAMEX> for their comical awkwardness at takeoff and
        landing) who nest there. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aloha Airlines</ENAMEX> offers scheduled flights to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midway</ENAMEX>. For more information, contact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midway</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">888</ENAMEX>)
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">643-9291</TIMEX>; fax (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">770</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">386-3053</TIMEX>; <www.midwayisland.com>).
      
    
  
