
  
  
    
      
        What To Do
        Entertainment
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edinburgh‚Äôs Festivals</ENAMEX>
        Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> has many year-round attractions, the city
        bursts into life in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early September</TIMEX> with a number of
        separate festivals running concurrently. The major festivals discussed
        below are joined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Film Festival</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz and Blues Festival</ENAMEX>, and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Book Festival</ENAMEX> (said to be the biggest public book fair in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> almost bursts at the seams as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 500,000</NUMEX> visitors
        arrive, vying for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street space</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clowns</ENAMEX>, face <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX>,
        and numerous small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX> markets. For additional information, you can
        access websites for all the festivals at
        <www.edinburghfestivals.co.uk> (see tickets, page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">127</NUMEX>, for
        contact information for the various festivals).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Edinburgh International Festival</ENAMEX>
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> hosted its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">International Festival</ENAMEX>.
        With the talent of impresario <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolf Bing</ENAMEX>, it was a great success and
        rapidly became one of the premier festivals of its kind in the world.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every year</TIMEX>, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, all eyes are on
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of performances and events in the many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> of the city
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>. Although the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">festival</ENAMEX> was biased toward orchestral music,
        the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">festival</ENAMEX> has a comprehensive program of dance, music, opera,
        and theater, with some of the finest exponents in every field gracing
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX>. Over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">years Trevor Howard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margot Fonteyn</ENAMEX>, and Marlene
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dietrich</ENAMEX> brought their own inimitable style to the festival. Details of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">International Festival</ENAMEX> program are available in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> each
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edinburgh Festival Fringe</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Festival Fringe</ENAMEX> was born at the same time as the
        official <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">festival</ENAMEX> and acts as a sometimes irreverent, loose collection
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">extra</NUMEX> performances held in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Initially the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fringe</ENAMEX> consisted
        of several small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater companies</ENAMEX> that were not included in the
        official festival program but nevertheless decided to hold performances
        on the same dates.
        Free from the confines of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Festival‚Äôs</ENAMEX> rules
        and regulations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fringe</ENAMEX> has become synonymous with art that ‚Äúpushes
        the envelope,‚Äù and it has grown to eclipse its more staid official
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>. It comprises over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1500</TIMEX> different shows, with literally dozens
        of performances taking place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> (at all times of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>).
        Venues have included the front seat of a car‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwhere the small audience
        sat in the back!
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Performers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Cook</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudley Moore</ENAMEX> made the
        Fringe their own, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Stoppard‚Äôs Rosencrantz</ENAMEX> and Guildenstern Are
        Dead was premiered here. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> of young artistic and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comedic</ENAMEX> talent makes its way to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fringe</ENAMEX> has grown
        into arguably the largest showcase for burgeoning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> in the
        world. A program is produced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June each year</TIMEX> covering the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
        Fringe performances, while a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> program is published during the
        festival itself.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edinburgh Military Tattoo</ENAMEX>
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> established a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Military Tattoo</ENAMEX> at the same
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Festival</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> have now become an inseparable
        combination. A tattoo is a highly polished show of military marching,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pageantry</ENAMEX>, mock battles, and horsemanship, accompanied by the sounds of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pipe</ENAMEX>-and-drum bands from around the world. All this happens nightly
        (except <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>) against the backdrop of the magnificently floodlit
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">castle</ENAMEX> in an arena erected in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Esplanade</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Military Tattoo</ENAMEX> has an office at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Market Street</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shop/</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33‚Äì34</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Market Street</ENAMEX> (behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waverley Station</ENAMEX>), where
        you can see photographs from past events as well as purchase souvenirs
        and tickets.
        Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX>
        Hogmanay
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX> have traditionally hosted <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äúthe best New Year</ENAMEX>
        celebrations in the world,‚Äù and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> has expanded the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX>
        into a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-night <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hogmanay Festival</ENAMEX> of torchlight parades, street
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theater</ENAMEX>, and food fair in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31 December</TIMEX> (website:
        <www.edinburghshogmanay.org>). For those who still have some
        energy left after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a night</TIMEX> of revels, there is also a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Year‚Äôs Day</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triathlon</ENAMEX>.
        Nightlife
        Of course you don‚Äôt need to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> during the
        summer festivals to see performances of the arts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is home to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Opera and Ballet</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish National Orchestra</ENAMEX>,
        among other resident <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. There are also several major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>
        with an ever-changing schedule of plays, ballets, and musical
        performances as well as popular shows featuring international bands and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> on the tour circuit. Although you will find venues scattered
        throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, the main theater district is found south of the
        west end of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Princes Street</ENAMEX>.
        Whichever month you decide to visit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lothians Tourist Board</ENAMEX> produces <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What‚Äôs On</ENAMEX>, a leaflet to help you make
        your plans. Also available locally is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> The List, with
        complete events for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Glasgow</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Nights</ENAMEX>
        A number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will offer an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish</ENAMEX>
        dancing along with an ‚Äúaddressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">haggis‚Äù ceremony‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇtraditionally
        performed on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Burns Night</ENAMEX>, the birthday of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> who wrote an ode to
        this favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX>. You will find all the paraphernalia of
        kilts, bagpipes, and ceremonial arms along with traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX>
        food, whisky, and dancing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caledonian Brewery</ENAMEX> holds regular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evenings</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">ceilidhs‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa Gaelic</ENAMEX> word for informal gatherings with
        music, dance, stories, and song (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slateford Road; Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">337 1286</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pubs</ENAMEX>
        Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can‚Äôt visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> without spending a little
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> enjoying a glass of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX>. There are many different
        establishments to choose from, each with its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clientele</ENAMEX> and style.
        Finding one that suits you is all part of the fun. Most will serve
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, and you may even be able to order a full lunch
        or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening meal</TIMEX> for a bargain price.
        For a traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX> where you can sit among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>,
        try the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guildford Arms</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Register Street</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> north of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">east</ENAMEX> end of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Princes Street</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX> beer taps and frosted-glass
        windows are the epitome of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub d√</ENAMEX>©cor. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Drop Pub</ENAMEX> (on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grassmarket</ENAMEX>) is another traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>, with low ceilings
        and low lighting. Its name stems not from a drinking phrase but from
        the fact that it was very close to the gallows that used to stand in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>: The ‚Äúlast drop‚Äù refers to the fall to the end of the rope.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deacon Brodies Tavern</ENAMEX> (on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawnmarket</ENAMEX>) is also a traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX>.
        Because of its position in the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, you will find just as
        many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> here, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trading travel stories.
        Sports
        Rugby
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Rugby Union</ENAMEX>, and the
        stadium can be found at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murrayfield</ENAMEX>, west of the city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. Matches
        are held only intermittently, however The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Calcutta Cup Match</ENAMEX>, in early
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, pits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX> against their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúauld‚Äù enemy‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe English‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> is
        a great spectacle. For tickets and information, contact Murrayfield
        Stadium (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">346 5000</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Football</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Football</ENAMEX> (soccer) is a passion in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, though the two
        most successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Glasgow</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Premier</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division</ENAMEX> (the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart of Midlothian</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hearts</ENAMEX>),
        playing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Tynecastle Park ground</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">McLeod Street</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 7201</ENAMEX>),
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hibernian</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hibs</ENAMEX>), who play at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Easter Road Stadium</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">661</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1875</TIMEX>). Games are scheduled on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesdays</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>
        through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Athletics</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Meadowbank Stadium</ENAMEX>, in the east of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, is a premier
        venue for athletics (track and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>). It hosted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonwealth Games</ENAMEX>
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> and has a schedule of events throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>.
        Walking and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hiking</ENAMEX>
        You can take one of the numerous guided walking tours
        through the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old and New Towns</ENAMEX>. Specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">walks‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇWriters‚</ENAMEX>Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ghostly ‚ÄúWynds,‚Äù</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub tour‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇenable you to tailor your strolling to
        your interests (see guides and tours, page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">118</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Holyrood Park</ENAMEX>, within the confines of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, provides an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ideal</ENAMEX> area for walking. For many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, the view of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur‚Äôs Seat</ENAMEX> is one of the highlights of a trip to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. The walk
        up this volcanic peak is steep but within the capability of a normally
        fit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. You can set your own pace, though most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> manage to
        reach the top in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">around an hour</TIMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most days of the year</TIMEX> you‚Äôll have
        lots of company‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to help if you get into difficulty. Take a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">picnic</ENAMEX> and enjoy an alfresco lunch at this spectacular spot.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> has a long affiliation with the game. Indeed, it
        is said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> gave golf to the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leith Links</ENAMEX> is considered
        the ‚Äúhome of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>,‚Äù and there are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another five</TIMEX> municipal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> in the
        area. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lothians Tourist Board</ENAMEX> offers the ‚ÄúLothians and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Edinburgh Golf Pass</ENAMEX>,‚Äù with discounted rates on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> in the
        Lothians region.
        Just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">88 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">55 miles</NUMEX>) north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Andrews</ENAMEX>, a
        hallowed destination for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">golfers</ENAMEX> from around the world and one of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premier</ENAMEX> professional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> on the international tour. It is quite
        possible to play a round on a day excursion from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>.
        Skiing
        To the west of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillend</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midlothian Ski</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre</ENAMEX>, the longest artificial ski slope in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillend</ENAMEX> is open
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round and has all the equipment you need for rent (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">445</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4433</TIMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
        Where to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shop</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> draws the best of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> products to its stores
        and provides a ready marketplace for goods from the northern Highlands
        and islands. The major shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Princes Street</ENAMEX>, considered
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford Street of Scotland</ENAMEX>. Here you‚Äôll <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">find‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇamong many major
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">names‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇEdinburgh‚</ENAMEX>Äôs traditional department store, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jenners</ENAMEX>,
        which has been a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> for generations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> has a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wonderful Art Deco</ENAMEX> interior to match its ornate exterior. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>
        running parallel to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Princes Street</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Town</ENAMEX> also have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boutiques</ENAMEX>, and there are several antique <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">north of Queen Street</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Town</ENAMEX> also has interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> to explore and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">browse</ENAMEX>. At the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Mile</ENAMEX> you‚Äôll see typical tourist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paraphernalia</ENAMEX> (postcards and T-shirts), but in the narrow surrounding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> there are many individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> selling antiques, books,
        curios, and collectibles.
        If it‚Äôs raining or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> where you
        can shop in comfort. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waverley Shopping Centre</ENAMEX> (where you will also
        find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Information Centre</ENAMEX>) is on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Princes Street</ENAMEX> next to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Waverley Street Station</ENAMEX>, and the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Centre</ENAMEX> (with the
        central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX>) is on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Leith Street</ENAMEX> at the eastern end of Princes
        Street.
        What to Buy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woven Goods¬∂</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tartan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tartan</ENAMEX> fabric is synonymous with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, with
        many items and patterns to choose from. The major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> had
        their own traditional tartan patterns that instantly identified their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX> and kinship. If you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> ancestry, you will be able
        to find the tartan for you; otherwise, it is a matter of finding a
        pattern that you like. All tartan patterns must be registered, and one
        of the most recent is the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britannia</ENAMEX> tartan, commissioned especially
        for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Yacht Britannia</ENAMEX> in its new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. You will be
        able to buy it at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">giftshop</ENAMEX> adjacent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> on your visit.
        Traditionally tartans were worn in the form of a kilt or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">traditional Highland</ENAMEX> dress, and these are certainly still available.
        Today, however, you can buy almost anything with a tartan pattern:
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scarves</ENAMEX>, hats, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen aprons</ENAMEX>, waistcoats (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vests</ENAMEX>), tote bags, teddy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bears‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> list is almost endless! The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Edinburgh Weaving Company</ENAMEX> (on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castlehill</ENAMEX>) has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 150</NUMEX> tartans for sale but will also custom make a
        kilt for you to take home.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolens</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> is world renowned for its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> and the
        quality of its finished products. The northern islands produce
        beautiful, heavy-knitted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fair Isle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arran</ENAMEX> sweaters, which are
        available in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. In more modern times (after
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Industrial Revolution</ENAMEX>), cashmere was introduced to the weavers; the
        softer garments produced from this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> make good souvenirs or
        presents. Pack lightly and buy a warm sweater when you arrive in town
        to keep off the summer chills or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> winds.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tweed</ENAMEX> is also produced from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX>, manufactured into
        jackets, coats, and suits. Tweed traditionally kept lairds and lords
        warm as they went out on grouse shoots on their northern
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">estates‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇbefore the invention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goretex</ENAMEX>.
        Synonymous with <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pringle</ENAMEX> clothing is made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>
        at its manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70‚Äì74</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bangor Road</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leith</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">553 5161</ENAMEX>).
        You can visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> or buy from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in the
        city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. The fine weave and pattern are typical of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish</ENAMEX>
        weaver‚Äôs attention to detail.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassware</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pottery</ENAMEX>
        Traditional skills extend wider than weaving. High-quality
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pottery</ENAMEX> and glassware are also produced here. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edinburgh Crystal</ENAMEX>, at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penicuik</ENAMEX> (a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty-minute</TIMEX> ride from the city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>), produces a
        beautiful range of cut glassware in the form of glasses, decanters, and
        bowls. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stuart Crystal</ENAMEX> and Caithness
        Glass, both of which have beautiful patterns and a wide range of
        goods.
        Bagpipes
        The mournful lament of the single <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipe</ENAMEX> is a sound that is
        always associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, and you will certainly hear it as you
        travel around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. You will find <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> pipes still being
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">handmade</ENAMEX> in the heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilberry Bagpipes</ENAMEX> (at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilmore</ENAMEX> Place,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tollcross</ENAMEX>) manufactures and sells traditional, professional instruments
        in a range of sizes.
        Books
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> has been at the forefront of publishing and
        printing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>. It supported the work of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>, which
        was a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of learning from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX>, particularly in
        law, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, and veterinary practice. Although publishing itself has
        declined in importance, one legacy of the industry is the number of
        bookstores selling second-hand, antiquarian, and new books. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Thin</ENAMEX> has the largest bookstore in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> (on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Street</ENAMEX>, opposite the university <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>
        Street).
        You might not find the signed first edition of your dreams.
        But with the wealth of writing talent that has graced the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, books
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX> (along with poetry by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramsey</ENAMEX>) make very
        suitable souvenirs of your trip.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiques and Clocks</ENAMEX>
        As a capital <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> has its own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> for the
        stamping of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>, with the city‚Äôs mark found on many antique
        pieces. If you find an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äútappit hen‚Äù</ENAMEX> (a traditional drinking
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tankard</ENAMEX>), look for the silver assay mark of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>, indicating an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">authentic Edinburgh</ENAMEX> piece.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clockmaking</ENAMEX> has been a strong tradition since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1500s</TIMEX>. A
        good piece commands a high price.
        Jewelry, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Silver</ENAMEX>, and Other Crafts
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From the days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stuart</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> jewelry was
        known for the high quality of its workmanship. Use of traditional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish</ENAMEX> materials such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand stones</ENAMEX> such as carnelian or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">agate‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇmake</ENAMEX> for unique pieces. Often local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtic</ENAMEX> patterns appear in
        bracelets, brooches (pins), and scarf rings.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX> and crafts are held in high regard in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>.
        Beautiful examples of enamelware, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ceramics</ENAMEX>, and pottery are produced in
        great abundance, often following a Celtic theme.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Food</ENAMEX> and Drink
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> produces a range of edible (and drinkable)
        souvenirs that can make great presents for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> back home.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Edinburgh rock</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confection</ENAMEX> found only here, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rock</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, and coloring mixture that is boiled and then
        cooled on stone slabs before being shaped. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúrock‚Äù</ENAMEX> has a soft
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">texture</ENAMEX> and can be bought in a variety of shapes.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haggis</ENAMEX>. This nutritious and tasty dish is at the heart of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish</ENAMEX> cuisine, and you‚Äôll be able to buy it in all sizes to take
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. For those who find the t raditional sheep‚Äôs stomach casing a
        little off-putting, haggis is now produced in a range of outer <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">casings</ENAMEX>,
        including <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heat-resistant plastic</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shortbread</ENAMEX> and oatcakes. Oatmeal was a staple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredient</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish</ENAMEX> cuisine from the very earliest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and is now available in
        the form of oatcakes. For those who prefer something sweeter,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shortbread</ENAMEX> (traditionally served at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yuletide</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hogmanay</ENAMEX>) is rich in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>. You will find pretty tins of both types of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">biscuits</ENAMEX>
        for sale in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, often decorated with city or highland scenes.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Salmon</ENAMEX> and kippers. The kippers you enjoy for breakfast or
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">smoked salmon</ENAMEX> served as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> appetizer can be bought
        prepacked for your journey home.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whisky</ENAMEX>. It is said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scots</ENAMEX> invented <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whisky</ENAMEX>, and the
        national <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX> is now one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotland‚</ENAMEX>Äôs major exports. The subtle blend
        of pure spring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, malt, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇaged</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oak barrels‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇis</ENAMEX> unique
        to each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">distillery</ENAMEX> of single malt whisky. The diverse range of flavors
        makes exploration of single malts a fascinating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Try a selection at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whisky Heritage Centre</ENAMEX> (they have over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100</TIMEX> for you to sample),
        where you can then buy a bottle or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of your personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shop</ENAMEX> or in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drambuie</ENAMEX>. Since receiving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie Prince Charlie‚</ENAMEX>Äôs recipe in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacKinnon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> still owns the secret recipe for
        this alcoholic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beverage</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glavya</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glavya</ENAMEX> is a blend of whisky, herbal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oils</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>.
        Activities for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> has a wealth of activities for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to enjoy.
        Take them to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh Castle</ENAMEX> for stories of heroism and great views of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Stay to hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">One O‚ÄôClock Gun‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbut</ENAMEX> note that it is very
        loud, so prepare little ones for the surprise! Nearby, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lookout</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tower and Camera Obscura</ENAMEX> offer a unique view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Just be
        prepared for several fights of stairs to reach the top of the
        building.
        Explore the story of our planet at Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynamic Earth</ENAMEX>. Here
        you can experience an earthquake, touch an iceberg, and listen to the
        sound of a rain forest all in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edinburgh Zoo</ENAMEX> has a penguin parade <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> during the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>. You can‚Äôt help falling in love with these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX>, who march
        along in their black and white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúuniforms</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May every year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish International Children‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        Festival holds arts, theater, and dance activities and performances
        especially for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 8 to 15</TIMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> festival
        season, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will be fascinated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street theater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clowns</ENAMEX>, face
        painting, and temporary tattooing.
        If your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are tired of trudging city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, take a
        ride to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Portobello</ENAMEX> (on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Firth of Forth</ENAMEX>), where the long sandy beach
        offers a perfect environment for long walks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">kite</ENAMEX> flying, or wading and
        swimming in the sea.
        Treat your little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúladies</ENAMEX> and gentlemen‚Äù to high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>. They
        are sure to rise to the occasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cucumber sandwiches</ENAMEX>, cakes, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scones</ENAMEX> served on fine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone china</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
