
  
  
    
      
        What to Do
        Sports
        One thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> enjoyed about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> was their
        enthusiasm for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sports‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇhockey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">cricket</ENAMEX> in particular. In return,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> learned the delights of polo (imported with the Mughals
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Persia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>) and a kind of game-hunting that made
        grouse-shooting seem tame.
        Today, with the exception of game-hunting, sporting life in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> is still very active. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> in particular has very modern
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>, many built for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Asian Games</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>. Just be careful to
        adapt your activities to the climate, and avoid going out in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midday</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sun</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Participant Sports</ENAMEX>
        Swimming is a natural first choice. Many first-class <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotels</ENAMEX>
        in leading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> have swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX>, but there are a few precautions
        you should take when swimming elsewhere. For health reasons, it is best
        to avoid swimming in rivers, ponds, lakes, and reservoirs‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇyour body
        is unlikely to be able to deal with some of the other things swimming
        around with you.
        Beach swimming is best at the recognized resorts rather than
        at the major port <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mumbai</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juhu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chowpatty</ENAMEX> beaches
        are, for instance, definitely a bad idea, and though the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Marina</ENAMEX> beaches
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chennai</ENAMEX> are cleaner, there may be <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX>. The best resort beaches
        are on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Malabar</ENAMEX> coast at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kovalam, Goa</ENAMEX>, and, smaller but charming,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cochin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kovalam</ENAMEX> also has surfing, but be careful of strong currents. On
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">east coast</ENAMEX>, try <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puri</ENAMEX>, south of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calcutta</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pondicherry</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sailing</ENAMEX> is possible at nearly all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX>. In
        Chennai, you can rent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">catamaran</ENAMEX> and, if you‚Äôre staying at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj</ENAMEX> in
        Mumbai, you should be able to obtain a guest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> at the nearby
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yacht Club</ENAMEX>.
        Fishing is very popular in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, and although it is almost
        entirely a freshwater proposition, you will find it very good. The
        indigenous mahseer, a distant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX> of the carp, which can weigh as
        much as <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 kg</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">44 pounds</NUMEX>), is considered by many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sportsmen</ENAMEX> to be as
        good a sporting challenge as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">salmon</ENAMEX>. You will find more information
        and fishing permits available at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directory of Fisheries</ENAMEX> in the
        tourist office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Srinagar</ENAMEX>. The tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> can
        provide information and permits for fishing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yamuna</ENAMEX> river and,
        similarly, the tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangalore</ENAMEX> can be consulted if you wish
        to fish in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cauvery</ENAMEX> river.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiking</ENAMEX>, or trekking, as it is most often called here, is a
        marvellous way of getting away from the often madding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>,
        and you will find it is well organized in the old hill-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>.
        Travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> happily provide a range of camping and
        cooking equipment, as well as the guides, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cooks</ENAMEX>, and porters you need,
        and a jeep for travelling to more remote and inaccessible areas. Try
        Simla, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darjeeling, Sikkim</ENAMEX>, and, much closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Naini</ENAMEX> Tal
        region. The necessary arrangements for this can easily be seen to on
        the spot, but a more ambitious <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six-‚</NUMEX>ÄÇor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-day</TIMEX> trek needs some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX>, so it would be best to book with your travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> and settle
        the details before you leave home.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Golf and tennis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> will find these activities available
        in the major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Golfers</ENAMEX> should apply for a guest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> from
        the many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> inherited from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Tennis lovers</ENAMEX>
        will find there are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> in the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> or in public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>.
        Many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> also have a health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> with a gym or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">yoga class‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇthe real thing.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator Sports</ENAMEX>
        The most beloved sport in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, by far, is <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">cricket</ENAMEX>.
        There‚Äôs something in the intricacy of its arcane rules and controlled
        passion that appeals to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs an astounding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obsession‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> all major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX>. The most fervent
        atmosphere of all is at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calcutta Cricket Club</ENAMEX>, founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1792</TIMEX>,
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Marylebone Cricket Club</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. The Brabourne
        Stadium in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mumbai</ENAMEX> is more relaxed. If you don‚Äôt catch a major match,
        you may come across a competition in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Calcutta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> or a meadow in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hockey</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> import, in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> have
        surpassed their former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> they often share the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX>
        finals with their old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch-rivals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polo</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rajasthani</ENAMEX> specialty, but tournaments are also
        held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mumbai</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter months</TIMEX>. This is a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        sport.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Horse</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">racing</ENAMEX> is popular, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> such as the Calcutta
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Derby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Leger</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oaks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mumbai</ENAMEX>. The highest course in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darjeeling</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Camel racing</ENAMEX> is a big event at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaisalmer</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> and also in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX> festival at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pushkar</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209</NUMEX>).
        Entertainment
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the many pleasant surprises in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> is the way that
        its classical music‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇheard perhaps in snatches back in the West and
        often dismissed as something hopelessly beyond an ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westerner‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">appreciation‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇgrows</ENAMEX> on you when you hear it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of its
        creation.
        A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> encounter with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> music is most likely to be in
        the pleasant surroundings of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in one of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>
        (rather than in what might be the intimidating atmosphere of a large
        recital <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>) where it may be performed as an accompaniment to an
        elegant dinner, with first-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX>. The music consists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        basic elements: the raga, the melody of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or more notes, and the
        tala, the rhythm or tempo. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Improvisation</ENAMEX> is of the essence. In a
        prelude or alap, which in full-length recitals can <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last half an hour</TIMEX>,
        the lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> seems to grope around until he reaches the main theme
        and its many variations take hold and patterns emerge from the apparent
        confusion. In its own way, it establishes a hold over <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">you‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsoothing</ENAMEX>,
        lulling, and always fascinating‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand before you know it, you‚Äôre
        hooked.
        Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> themselves, give yourself up to the
        hypnotic effect of the notes, rhythms, and melodies, or even the
        silences. A fully realized performance could go on for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> (shorter in restaurant recitals). It is perfectly normal at a
        concert for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to walk around, fidget, and talk at the beginning of
        the recital until the music asserts itself.
        Apart from the music played in the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and the
        sophisticated music of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brahmanic</ENAMEX> tradition, you can listen to the
        folk music of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajasthan</ENAMEX>, rousing or plaintive, in the desert around
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaisalmer</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Song</ENAMEX>, using rhythm and melody in the same way as
        instrumental music, is religious and romantic in content. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Indian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">song</ENAMEX> is both joyful and sad. In the north, where song was subject to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arabian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> influences, it varies from dhrupad, meaning austere
        and without embellishment, to the more florid khyal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India‚Äôs</ENAMEX> version of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bel</ENAMEX> canto, or thumri, the style of light-hearted, tender love
        songs.
        In addition to this dinner music, the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> organize
        full-scale recitals of music, song, and dance, and so if you do acquire
        a taste for it, look out for concerts in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">town‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇDelhi</ENAMEX> has recitals
        around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic Day</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of January</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> dance is marvelously expressive, with every gesture
        and movement signifying a vocabulary of emotions. Like the sculptures
        on the temples, the eloquence of dance is a means of transmitting the
        messages of the holy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">scriptures</ENAMEX> and adventures of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> epics
        to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX>.
        Classical sacred dance, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bharatanatyam</ENAMEX>, has a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">108</NUMEX>
        different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">consecrated forms‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇyou</ENAMEX> can see them performed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shiva</ENAMEX> in
        the sculpted frieze of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thanjavur‚Äôs Brihadisvara Temple</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">191</NUMEX>).
        Originally, these holy dances were performed by devadasis, the sacred
        dancing-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, who were in fact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple prostitutes‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthat is, until
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> reform movement during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX> made it acceptable
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> of respectable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> to perform the dances, too.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kerala</ENAMEX>, try to see the lively kathakali dances, in which
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> play both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> and female parts to enact both divine and heroic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> legends in the most gorgeous costumes and elaborate makeup.
        Performances of musical works are regularly held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cochin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ernakulam</ENAMEX>. The more sophisticated dance found in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eastern India</ENAMEX> is known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odissi</ENAMEX>.
        Film in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, produced mainly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chennai</ENAMEX>,
        Mumbai, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calcutta</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bangalore</ENAMEX>, is a major industry. The large scale
        production of entertainment films is a phenomenon well worth seeing
        several times. You may well be more baffled by the appeal of the
        colorful musical comedies and violent shoot-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">em</NUMEX>-ups than you would be in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>, but the emotion of the melodramas and romantic adventure
        stories of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India‚</ENAMEX>Äôs cultural and historic past have considerable
        curiosity value for a rainy <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>. If you watch the action closely,
        you can learn a lot about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by what makes them cheer,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laugh</ENAMEX>, or weep. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calcutta</ENAMEX> seems to be the only other production center
        having any pretensions to artistic creativity at all, but ironically
        you‚Äôre actually more likely to see the works of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Satyajit Ray</ENAMEX> or Mrinal
        Sen shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> itself.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
        From the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mughals</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco Polo</ENAMEX>
        to Lord <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mountbatten</ENAMEX>, all have been seduced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India‚</ENAMEX>Äôs riches. It‚Äôs
        still a great place to shop.
        As in any ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India‚</ENAMEX>Äôs modernizing plunge into
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX> has produced its fair share of trinkets and tinsel,
        but its traditional craftwork continues at the highest level: silks,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">carpets</ENAMEX>, jewelry, perfumes, brassware, and wood-carving are first
        class, and you will have the added bonus of dealing with the most
        charming bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> in the world.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least half</NUMEX> the pleasure is in the bargaining. If you
        don‚Äôt want to be fleeced, don‚Äôt plunge in blindly. Go <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Cottage Industry Emporiums</ENAMEX>, which can be found in almost
        every major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. The selection here is not usually as wide as you‚Äôll
        find in the privately run <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and you can‚Äôt haggle, but it‚Äôll give
        you an idea of the range of goods, the quality, and, above all, the
        correct price.
        Then you‚Äôre ready for the fray, either in the bustling
        great bazaars such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Delhi‚Äôs Chandni Chowk</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mumbai‚Äôs Bhuleshwar</ENAMEX>, or
        the more sedate ambience of grander <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">showrooms</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> street
        market you shouldn‚Äôt miss is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mumbai‚Äôs Chor Bazaar</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thieves‚Äô Market</ENAMEX>,
        which is an extravagant flea market where, among other things, you‚Äôll
        see <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">motorists</ENAMEX> buying back spare parts stolen from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> the
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> before.
        If, during your tours of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, you come across
        products you like from places you will be visiting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, such as
        Rajasthan, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Varanasi</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>, wait until you get there‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe price
        and selection may be much better.
        Haggling with dapper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gujaratis</ENAMEX> and the bright-eyed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kashmiris</ENAMEX> can attain the level of high art. Even if you don‚Äôt land a
        bargain, there is real aesthetic pleasure in seeing, at the end of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">verbal ‚Äúcombat</ENAMEX>,‚Äù the disarray of silks thrown across a counter or a
        mound of carpets on the floor. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kashmiris‚</ENAMEX>Äô wizardry is at its best
        on the floating market of their shikaras, but you can also meet
        Kashmiris down in the plains, to which, like many other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wily birds</ENAMEX>,
        they migrate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX>.
        If there‚Äôs no magic formula for the perfect bargain‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇeach
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> will have his own psychological <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">approach‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇyou</ENAMEX> should avoid two
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extremes</ENAMEX>: Don‚Äôt be too eager, and don‚Äôt, on the other hand, assume
        everybody is out to cheat you. It spoils the sport.
        Carpets are one of the most attractive purchases you can
        make. Ever since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jahangir</ENAMEX> took <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian</ENAMEX>
        craftsmen up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> with him during his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long summer holidays</TIMEX>, the
        handwoven silk-and-woolen carpets of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Srinagar</ENAMEX> have been among the best
        in the world. The silk gives the carpets their unique <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheen</ENAMEX>. The prices
        will vary according to the proportions of silk and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> used and the
        density of the weave itself; naturally, none of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> are
        cheap.
        Look out for traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> and original Kashmiri
        motifs such as peacocks and fruit <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tiger hunts</ENAMEX>, and Mughal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>. Indeed many of the carpets seem just too lovely to walk on, but
        they make superb wall hangings, and even if you can‚Äôt remortgage your
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> to buy a big one, even a modest bedside rug can do wonders to
        warm and brighten a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cashmere</ENAMEX> is the one thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kashmiris</ENAMEX> are touchy about.
        That ‚<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Äú100%</NUMEX> cashmere‚Äù label you show them on your best sweater could
        provoke a loud snort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">‚ÄúScotland</ENAMEX>! ‚Äù or even <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúAustralia</ENAMEX>! ‚Äù But then,
        like an endearment to a beloved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, they will murmur <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúpashmina‚Äù</ENAMEX> and
        spread before you a shawl of soft, warm wool shorn, they tell you, from
        the underbelly of the wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Himalayan goats</ENAMEX>. Then, just when you think
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">you‚Äôve</ENAMEX> never touched anything finer, they turn around and whisper
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúshahtoosh</ENAMEX>,‚Äù laying out the finest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kashmir</ENAMEX> wool of all, taken from the
        throat of the ibex and woven so finely that one can pass a shawl right
        through a wedding ring. These, too, are expensive, but you can get
        shawls of good quality wool with distinctive embroidery at more
        reasonable prices.
        Silks have long been basic to a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady‚</ENAMEX>Äôs wardrobe
        and also make magnificent tunics, blouses, stoles, or long, trailing
        scarves for a Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX>. The costume more easily adapted to
        Western tastes than the sari, perhaps because it involves trousers, is
        a long tunic worn over baggy pantaloons with a soft stole around the
        shoulders; known as salwar kameez, it is most popular in the northwest,
        and very elegant.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> are famous for their silk: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bangalore</ENAMEX>, for its
        classic printed silk; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Varanasi</ENAMEX>, for its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and silver brocades; and
        Kanchipuram, for its heavy, brilliantly colored silk, favored for
        formal saris. Not forgetting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kanchipuram</ENAMEX> also
        produces superb silk ties.
        Cottons, either hand-printed or embroidered, are probably
        the best bargain of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> textiles, made into tablecloths,
        napkins, bed linens, spreads, pillowcases‚ÄÇ, and airy, light scarves
        that make life much more comfortable in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> heat. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian tailors</ENAMEX>
        are cheap, good, and fast, so you might consider having lightweight
        shirts and baggy pants made up for you during your stay.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton</ENAMEX> prints to look out for, particularly in
        Rajasthan, are: bagru, consisting of geometric or <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, almond, and
        vine patterns in blue, brown, and maroon; sanganeri, block printed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">floral</ENAMEX> and paisley patterns; and bandhani, tie-dye, which results in
        decorative color. The bright motifs with mirror-work stitched into
        them, much favored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajasthani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> of the desert for their long
        flowing skirts, are known as cutchhi or saurashtra. The dashing, rather
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">coarse cotton Punjabi phulkari shawls</ENAMEX> are made from fabric with
        patterns in orange, pink, green, red, and yellow.
        Jewelry is important here, whether made with precious or
        semi-precious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX>. The jewelry of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajasthan</ENAMEX> is much sought after.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> diamond <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> produced some of the world‚Äôs greatest gems,
        including the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kohi-nur</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountain of Light</ENAMEX>), now in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> crown
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jewels</ENAMEX>, having originally been set in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Peacock Throne</ENAMEX>. Although the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mines</ENAMEX> are superseded by those in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, the
        art of cutting and polishing is still extant in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gujarat</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mumbai</ENAMEX> is a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> for importing rough-cuts and selling the finished product. Don‚Äôt
        buy any unless you are an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> or have one with you. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Diamonds</ENAMEX> are
        graded from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>, with only D, E, and F considered good, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> being
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">colorless</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúriver white,<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äù J ‚Äúslightly tinted,‚Äù Q ‚Äúlight yellow,‚Äù and</ENAMEX>
        S to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X ‚Äúyellow</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        The essential piece of jewelry in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, however, is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bangle</ENAMEX>. Whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX> are devoted to them, made from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>,
        metal, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX>, and‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbest bargain of all‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇcolorful
        varnished papier m√¢ch√© from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">brass‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇeach</ENAMEX> has its own bazaar
        in the big neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">markets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mumbai</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calcutta</ENAMEX>. Of
        these, the most well known is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jains‚Äô Zaveri Bazaar</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mumbai</ENAMEX>, where
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antique gold</ENAMEX> is sold.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wood</ENAMEX> carvings vary from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ro sewood elephants</ENAMEX> or sandalwood
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camels</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Kashmiris‚Äô finely fretted walnut</ENAMEX>, created in the style of
        the screens on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Srinagar</ENAMEX> houseboats.
        For modern painting, try the art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connaught</ENAMEX>
        Place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mumbai‚Äôs Pundole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chemould Galleries</ENAMEX>, not to
        forget the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy of Fine Arts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calcutta</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cooks</ENAMEX> should be on the lookout for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">spices‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇchili</ENAMEX>,
        turmeric, cardamom, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ginger</ENAMEX>, nutmeg, and cumin‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwhich we advise you not
        to buy until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your last day</TIMEX>. The best places to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX> are
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khadi Bhandars</ENAMEX>, because they are government supervised, thus
        offering a product of assured quality.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tea gourmets</ENAMEX> will make a beeline for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darjeeling</ENAMEX>, to buy
        directly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX> or at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> bazaar. When you buy a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of kilos, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">they‚Äôll ship</ENAMEX> it for you in air-tight packages.
      
    
  
