
  
  
    
      
        What to Do
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
        Shopping in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is as exotic or as straightforward as you
        want to make it. If you want to take home memories as well as souvenirs
        try the souqs (traditional covered markets), where bargaining is the
        name of the game. Alternatively, there are a number of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>
        with international names as well as many excellent local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> selling
        goods at fixed prices.
        Traditional shop <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00 or</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30 a.m. to 1:00 p.m.</TIMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:00 to 7:00 p.m.</TIMEX> , and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00 or 8:30</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a.m. to 2:00 or 3:00 p.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shops</ENAMEX> close for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabbath</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>) and
        re-open on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, which is a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">normal business day</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> day of rest
        is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, so most souqs will be closed then. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malls</ENAMEX> and
        tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> tend to open <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all hours</TIMEX> to suit the local trade.
        Where to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shop</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> has the widest range of goods and types of shop
        that you‚Äôll find anywhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX> souqs offer all
        manner of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX> wares (as well as much of less interest), whereas in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yoel Salomon Street</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rivlin Street</ENAMEX> are good for arts
        and crafts, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Yehuda</ENAMEX> and surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> can supply most
        other items.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> has lots of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> on and around Dizengoff
        Street, but if you are treasure hunting you should visit the flea
        market in neighbouring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Jaffa</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX>), which is also generally
        good for arts and crafts. Other places with interesting souqs are the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akko</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazareth</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Druse</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> near
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haifa</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX>).
        Bargaining
        If you are in search of a particular item, look in
        ‚Äúfixed-price‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> first to get some idea of what you are likely to
        have to pay. However, even some of these will prove remarkably flexible
        if you try bargaining. To haggle successfully, pitch your opening price
        well below <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">target</ENAMEX> and don‚Äôt look too keen. Walking away is a good ploy
        if you have the time. Look elsewhere, and if you don‚Äôt find the same
        thing more cheaply, you can always come back later.
        What to Buy
        Art: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> art, and particularly modern art, is of a very
        high standard. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> has some excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
        Quality on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hebron Road</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Artists‚Äô House</ENAMEX> on Shmuel
        Hanagid Street are the most famous; also try the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New City</ENAMEX>. Safed,
        Jaffa, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ein Hod</ENAMEX> (near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haifa</ENAMEX>) are the main provincial centres. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel Museum</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Art</ENAMEX> are also
        good.
        Clothing: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leather</ENAMEX> is a popular item, though rarely cheap;
        try <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>. Sandals are a tradition in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jerusalem‚Äôs Old City</ENAMEX>, while an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> keffiyeh head-dress (as modelled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>) is useful for
        warding off desert dust and sun. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beware</ENAMEX>, however, as it may be taken to
        reflect a political opinion.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead Sea</ENAMEX> products: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bath</ENAMEX>-salts and mudpacks are the most
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">popular Dead Sea</ENAMEX> souvenirs, though there‚Äôs a huge range of other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">therapeutic</ENAMEX> and cosmetic goods for you to take home.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Diamonds</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Diamond Centres</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netanya</ENAMEX> (tel.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">09-862 4770</ENAMEX>) as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">02-673 3770</ENAMEX>) will pick you up
        from your hotel and give you a free tour of the workshops, where they
        will offer a wide choice of goods to select from and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> advice on
        what you may want to buy.
        Jewellery: This is a traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>, and the
        possibilities of what you can buy are almost endless. For something
        different, look for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> glass jewellery or fashionable filigreed
        Yemenite earrings and necklaces (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jaffa</ENAMEX>, and other places
        that are craft-oriented). In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eilat</ENAMEX> you should look for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilat</ENAMEX> stone, an
        attractive combination of malachite and azurite.
        Judaica: Traditionally-crafted ceremonial objects, such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">menorahs</ENAMEX> (a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-branched candelabra) and mezuzahs (inscribed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parchments/parchment</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX>), may not be to everyone‚Äôs taste, but they
        are undeniably <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>. Look out too for decorative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yarmulkes</ENAMEX> (skull
        caps) and some creative uses of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star of David</ENAMEX>.
        Oriental wares: In the souqs you will find all the
        favourite wares of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leather goods</ENAMEX>, brass and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX>, nargilas (hubble-bubble pipes), and of course carpets and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kilims</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Wood carvings</ENAMEX>: At any religious site you will find wooden
        religious statuettes being sold, either in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> or by itinerant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vendors</ENAMEX>.
        Sports
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> may not appear to be an obvious place to go for a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sporting</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX>, but this young and energetic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has dramatic
        open spaces, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> of accessible coastline, and a burgeoning range of
        sporting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and events, from white-water rafting in the Golan
        to world-class scuba diving in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Sea</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israelis‚</ENAMEX>Äô own sporting
        passions are <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball and football</ENAMEX> (soccer). Look in the local press
        (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX>) for details of upcoming matches.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land-based Activities</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf</ENAMEX>: It surprises many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> that there is only one
        18-hole course in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caesarea</ENAMEX> (tel. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">06-361174</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Horseback</ENAMEX> riding: The grassy valleys and gentle slopes of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea of Galilee</ENAMEX> provide classic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>-riding terrain. Riding centres
        are to be found near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tiberias</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vared Hagalil, Kfar Hitin</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6-693</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5785</TIMEX>).
        On the coast you can try the riding centre at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesarea</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herod‚Äôs Stables; tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">06-636 1260</ENAMEX>), while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artists Village Riding</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">04-984 1828</ENAMEX>) at picturesque <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ein Hod</ENAMEX>, near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haifa</ENAMEX>, offers
        the spectacular scenery of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carmel National Park, Haifa</ENAMEX>, and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coast</ENAMEX>.
        From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eilat</ENAMEX>, you can reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negev</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> in a few
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Texas Ranch</ENAMEX>; tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">07-637 6663</ENAMEX>). Finally, there are even
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stables</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">02-538 0296</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiking</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> are great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hikers</ENAMEX>, and almost everywhere
        you go you will find excellent walking-tour guides. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society for the</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection of Nature</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> (SPNI) offers environmental hiking tours
        nationwide in dramatic settings such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Samaria Desert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wadi Qelt</ENAMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead Sea, Galilee</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golan</ENAMEX>, and around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eilat</ENAMEX>. Call (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">03</NUMEX>) 638
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8677</TIMEX> for details.
        Similar tours are led by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature‚Äôs Way</ENAMEX>, an organization
        based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eilat</ENAMEX>. You can get their leaflet from the tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> or by
        calling (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">07</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">637 0648</TIMEX>. They also provide expert advice on independent
        hiking in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilat Mountains Reserve</ENAMEX> and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hikers</ENAMEX> should also consider the strange moon-like surface
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Makhtesh Ramon</ENAMEX> crater (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">73</NUMEX>). Ask at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visitor Centre</ENAMEX>
        for details.
        Watersports
        Windsurfing: The equipment you need for windsurfing can be
        hired from the beaches at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marina</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netanya</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haifa</ENAMEX> (at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bat</ENAMEX>
        Galim beach), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tiberias</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilat</ENAMEX>.
        Waterskiing: This is slightly less popular, but there are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>, which has a mechanical pull (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern Park</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">03-739 1168</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eilat</ENAMEX>, which offers the full range of motorized
        watersports, including jet skis, parasailing, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water bananas</ENAMEX>. All
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilat</ENAMEX> activities can be booked through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sea Sports</ENAMEX> (see Scuba
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diving</ENAMEX>, below).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sailing</ENAMEX>: Dinghies are available for hire from the marinas
        at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaffa, Akko</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netanya</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nahariya</ENAMEX>.
        On the other side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, sports are available on
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea of Galilee</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">River Jordan</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Golan</ENAMEX> region try
        white-water rafting through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kibbutz Kfar Hanassi</ENAMEX>, near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rosh Pinna</ENAMEX> (tel.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">06-06-691</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4992</TIMEX>), or at Activity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rafting & Recreation</ENAMEX> (tel. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">06</NUMEX>-693
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9377</TIMEX>); try a kayak or go inner-tubing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordan River</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hayarden</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abukayak; tel</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">06-06-922 245</NUMEX>) or at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kibbutz Kfar Blum</ENAMEX>, tel.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">06-694 8755</ENAMEX>.
        Scuba diving: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diving</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Sea</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilat</ENAMEX> is without
        doubt the sporting highlight of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. This is one of the richest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> in the world for tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and corals, and has excellent
        underwater visibility, ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 to 40 metres</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">130 feet</NUMEX>)
        and more. There are many diving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, all of which dive from Coral
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX>. The most experienced is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Aqua Sport</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">06-633 4404</ENAMEX>). Red <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea</ENAMEX>
        Sports are also recommended (tel. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">06-637</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6569</TIMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">633 3666</ENAMEX>).
        If you want to know what to expect before you dive, visit
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coral World</ENAMEX> underwater <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">observatory</ENAMEX> to see the brilliant, teeming
        underwater life that awaits you in the nature reserve. You can of
        course enjoy yourself by snorkelling on the surface, or you could try
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Eilat‚Äôs unique snorkelling</ENAMEX>/scuba hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">‚Äúsnuba‚Äù</ENAMEX> (see box below).
        Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilat</ENAMEX> highlight is the opportunity to dive with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dolphin Reef</ENAMEX>.
        An experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diver</ENAMEX> may prefer moving onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX>,
        where the diving is even better.
        There are several diving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coast</ENAMEX> (at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haifa, Akko, Rosh Hanikra</ENAMEX>, and other sites‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsee
        tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> for details). Conditions are good, with average
        visibility on calm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 metres</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">33 feet</NUMEX>).
        Swimming: You must be careful if swimming along the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean coast</ENAMEX>, as many lives are lost here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> to the
        vicious undertows. You should be safe as long as you obey the beach
        flags. A white flag tells you it‚Äôs safe and that a lifeguard is
        present. A red flag means that swimming is dangerous and a black flag
        means that no swimming is allowed. At <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>, there is a pleasant,
        though expensive, lido by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">marina</ENAMEX>.
        Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Activities</ENAMEX>
        Archaeological <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">digs</ENAMEX>: If you want to lend a hand to those
        delving into the past, contact either the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Youth Section Promotion</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ministry of Tourism</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">02-623 7311</ENAMEX>) or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiquities Authority</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">02-560 2627</ENAMEX>). Be warned that the work is
        often hard, the conditions spartan, and the financial reward
        nonexistent; but the satisfaction can be immense. You can also arrange
        archaeology-related expeditions through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel Archaeological</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>, based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> (toll-free in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.A.</ENAMEX>:
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ISRAEL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>).
        Birdwatching: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eilat</ENAMEX> enjoys a prime location on the
        migration path for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> flying from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. It is
        therefore one of the best spots in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> from where
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ornithologists</ENAMEX> can watch the massive flypast of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> bird
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migration</ENAMEX> takes place from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> and from
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March through May</TIMEX>. Contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Birdwatching Centre</ENAMEX> (tel.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">07-637 4276</ENAMEX>) for further information and details of tours and
        lectures.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camel</ENAMEX> treks: Several trekking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> offer the
        opportunity to explore the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Negev Bedouin</ENAMEX>-style, aboard a camel. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camel Riders company</ENAMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilat</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">07-637 3218</ENAMEX>) offers tours
        that range from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 to 15 days</TIMEX>. If this is too long, there are shorter
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tours</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Texas Ranch</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eilat</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">07-637 6663</ENAMEX>), for example,
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">organises half-day</TIMEX> desert tours <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camel contacts</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Breeze</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">07-633 7222</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep See</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">07-633 0130</ENAMEX>), and Tracks
        (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">03-691 6103</ENAMEX>).
        Desert safaris: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avi Desert Safari</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eilat</ENAMEX> (tel. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">07</NUMEX>-637
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8024</TIMEX>), has been leading off-road <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jeep safaris</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Negev</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judean</ENAMEX> deserts for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 20 years</TIMEX>.
        If you would like a more novel, self-drive way of exploring
        the desert, hire a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quad Runner</ENAMEX>. A cross between a motorbike and a small
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tractor</ENAMEX>, these fun <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> are available from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ostrich Farm</ENAMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilat</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">07-637 2405</ENAMEX>). You must be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">18 or</NUMEX> over and have a clean
        driving licence.
        Entertainment
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem Nightlife</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> has a staid reputation, but take a stroll in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New City</ENAMEX> in the area around <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ben Yehuda Street</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yoel Salomon Street</ENAMEX>
        and you‚Äôll find lots going on most evenings, including a handful of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">discos</ENAMEX>, several music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> and ‚Äúpubs,‚Äù and narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> congested
        with tables and thronging with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> venues regularly put on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> folklore shows. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA Auditorium</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King David Street</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">02-624 7281</ENAMEX>), produces an
        entertaining song-and-dance show on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evenings</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Khan Theatre</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Remez Square</ENAMEX>, near the railway station
        (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">02-671 8281</ENAMEX>), stages regular folklore shows in an old
        caravanserai, as well as hosting a theatre and the city‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and only
        nightclub; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiryat Anavim Kibbutz Hotel</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11km/7</NUMEX> miles out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">02-534 8999</ENAMEX>) hosts an enjoyable <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> of dance every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with
        music of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>. Other minor venues stage occasional ethnic
        folk-music concerts.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sultan‚Äôs Pool</ENAMEX>, a vast outdoor
        amphitheatre, stages rock concerts or other big-name events.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem theatre</ENAMEX> is varied and eclectic, but most
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">productions</ENAMEX> are in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Centre for the Performing Arts</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Theatre</ENAMEX>) at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus Street</ENAMEX> hosts local and foreign
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">productions</ENAMEX> of theatre, opera, and dance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre</ENAMEX> also houses a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bookstore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coffeehouse</ENAMEX>, restaurant, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>. The box office (tel.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">02-561 0011</ENAMEX>) is open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m. to 1:00</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. and one hour</TIMEX> before performances.
        Among the venues for classical music are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Givat Ram University</ENAMEX> campus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Theatre</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown Auditorium</ENAMEX>.
        There are several cinemas, showing films in their original
        language with subtitles in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinematheque</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hebron</ENAMEX> Avenue
        (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">02-672 4131</ENAMEX>), is the best venue for film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX>.
        For information about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">nightlife, look in Time Out</ENAMEX>, the
        listings pull-out section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX>, which is published
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Friday</TIMEX>. Also excellent is Your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, a free <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX>
        newspaper which you can pick up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and various tourist haunts.
        (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv Nightlife</ENAMEX>
        In contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> comes alive at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
        Crowds congregate along the promenade and along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dizengoff Street</ENAMEX>, but
        there‚Äôs much more to do than just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>-watch. If you‚Äôre after bars
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclubs</ENAMEX>, look in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> (a free listings
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>). There are over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclubs</ENAMEX> to choose from, some of them
        offering <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jamaican</ENAMEX> themes. In neighbouring Jaffa
        there are more nightspots offering touristy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX> folklore
        entertainment.
        If you are keen to learn <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> folk dancing, the Bicurei
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha‚Äôetim Cellar</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heftman Street</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">03-691 9510</ENAMEX>) will teach you.
        There is a good choice of cinemas, showing mainstream
        English-language films.
        Those with more highbrow tastes should make for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tel</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aviv Performing Arts Centre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo Da Vinci Street</ENAMEX> (tel. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">03</NUMEX>-692
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7777</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Opera</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> can enjoy the acclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Israel Opera company</ENAMEX>
        here or at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cameri Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dizengoff Street</ENAMEX> (tel. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">03-523 3335/527</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9888</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cameri</ENAMEX> is also the only theatre in town to regularly stage
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">productions</ENAMEX> with a simultaneous <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> translation (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Tuesday</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Habima Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Habima Square</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">03-526 6666</ENAMEX>), is
        claimed to be the country‚Äôs best <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">repertory theatre</ENAMEX>. It occasionally
        puts on English-language performances.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lovers</ENAMEX> of classical music should make for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX>
        Auditorium, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hubermann Street</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">03-528 9163</ENAMEX>), or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shaul Hamelech Boulevard</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">03-696 1297</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel Ballet</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Company</ENAMEX> is based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>. Dance is also staged at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZOA House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniel</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Frisch Street</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">03-695 9341</ENAMEX>).
        To find what‚Äôs on in general consult the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> Out
        supplement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fridays</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, a particularly good free <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>
        on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX>. )
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilat Nightlife</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>-style resort nightlife of this popular
        spot appeals most to the young and ‚Äúyoung-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-heart,‚Äù namely those who
        thrive on lively (and loud) international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">discos</ENAMEX>. If
        you want more serious entertainment, this is not the place for you.
        Much of the action is hotel-based, though the new
        commercial centres in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> are also very busy. There is nothing
        recognizably local in the tourist areas, except for the rather bland
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> folklore shows staged in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>. If you prefer a livelier
        and more authentic experience, try the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bedouin Evening</ENAMEX> at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ostrich Farm</ENAMEX>, which includes belly dancing and story-telling (tel.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">07-637 2405</ENAMEX>).
        Fringe films in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> are screened at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinematheque</ENAMEX> at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Murray Centre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ha‚ÄôTemarim Boulevard</ENAMEX>, and there is a Creat
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ive Arts Centre</ENAMEX> (opposite the port) where occasional musical events are
        staged. The highlight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilat‚</ENAMEX>Äôs musical year is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Red</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jazz Festival</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX>).
        For more information, pick up the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> listings leaflet,
        Events and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Places in Eilat</ENAMEX>, from the tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> on page
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX>. )
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children‚Äôs Israel</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> share a love of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and welcome them
        almost everywhere. Nevertheless, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Land</ENAMEX> is not the ideal place
        for a family holiday. Not many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will enjoy visiting more than
        the occasional holy or historical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>, especially if they have to keep
        silent. Careful planning and an imaginative approach to relating the
        story behind a site could, however, make a huge difference in
        stimulating a child‚Äôs interest.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> are usually modern, lively places. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diaspora Museum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Art</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel Museum</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> all have youth sections with exhibits and activities.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Israel‚Äôs west coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">don‚</ENAMEX>Äôt particularly cater
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilat</ENAMEX> is a typically <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>-style resort
        with numerous beach activities and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> designed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> very much in mind.
        At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, folklore shows are a good bet for older pre-teens
        and perhaps young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> (see opposite page). For something more
        ‚Äúhigh-tech,<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äù Eilat</ENAMEX> offers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leagues</ENAMEX> Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea</ENAMEX> aboard the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jules</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Verne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mobile underwater observatory boat</ENAMEX>. This is a spectacular
        laser-assisted special-effects underwater adventure. For entertainment
        on a more intimate scale, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilat</ENAMEX> stages a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bedouin Evening</ENAMEX> (see page
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilat</ENAMEX> is the place for water activities. Older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can
        learn to windsurf or try Eilat‚Äôs own snuba diving (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">87</NUMEX>). Coral
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World‚Äôs Yellow Submarine</ENAMEX> may well be the highlight of a child‚Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX>, but make sure you know the cost before you suggest it. Pedalos
        are a good starting point.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wildlife</ENAMEX>: There are no major zoos in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. Even so, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biblical Zoo</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolphinarium</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Llama</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpaca Farm</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitzpe Ramon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">alligator</ENAMEX> farm at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hammat Gader</ENAMEX> near
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea of Galilee</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hai Bar Biblical Nature Reserve</ENAMEX> near Eilat
        should all prove popular.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilat</ENAMEX> itself <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX> are the big attraction for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dolphin Reef</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX>) is an excellent family attraction,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can actually swim or even dive with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX> (at a
        cost). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> of all ages will also love the fabulous colours and
        shapes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> of the deep on display at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coral World</ENAMEX> (see page
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX>) or viewed from aboard one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilat‚</ENAMEX>Äôs special floating observatory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boats</ENAMEX>. To get the best from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coral World</ENAMEX>, pick up a copy of their
        excellent full-colour <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fish Guide</ENAMEX> and see how many of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">745</NUMEX> different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and corals your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can identify through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">observatory</ENAMEX>
        windows.
        Finding out what‚Äôs on: A children‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> appears in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> Out section in each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friday‚Äôs Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> and in Your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
        (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX>). There are story-telling sessions for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
        (from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> upwards), a puppet theatre, and other events for
        English-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. However, many activities are in
        Hebrew only.
      
    
  
