
  
  
    
      
        Where to Go
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pyramids</ENAMEX>
        Founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">641</TIMEX> and expanded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatimids</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ninth</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cairo‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇAl-Qahira</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">‚Äúthe City</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Victory‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇ</ENAMEX> became one of
        the most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in the world during the Medieval <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>,
        marking a rebirth in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt‚</ENAMEX>Äôs fortunes. Situated where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile</ENAMEX> valley
        widens to become the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nile Delta</ENAMEX>, it is now the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>
        noisy; its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> often at gridlock; its public transport system for the
        most part in chaos. However, once you accept these facts, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> has
        lots to offer the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>; its main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> is an essential part of your
        vacation experience and its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> life is a sure sign that you have
        come to a totally different culture.
        Central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>
        Central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> is based around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">River</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile</ENAMEX>, and several
        modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and squares where you‚Äôll find most of the international
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotels</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tahrir Square</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberation Square</ENAMEX>) on the east <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> is its
        heart, a mass of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> converging on the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> terminus in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, which is bounded by government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministries</ENAMEX> and office blocks
        housing airline <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Nearby on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of the
        river is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile Hilton Hotel‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa landmark</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cairenes</ENAMEX> (as the people
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> are known) as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. Leading east from the
        square is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kasr El-Nil Street</ENAMEX> lined with western-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX>. Nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ramses Square</ENAMEX> plays host to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Railway</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Station</ENAMEX>, designed in the heyday of colonialism and fronted by a
        monumental granite statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Ramses II</ENAMEX> transported from the ancient
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> capital of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>.
        Out in the river are several islands and the largest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>,
        Gezira, is home to one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cairo‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most chic neighborhoods, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zamalek</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find a number of things to do here. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gezira Sporting Club</ENAMEX> has
        a range of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> that you can enjoy as a temporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, but if
        you don‚Äôt feel sporty try <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">music‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> is here sharing a complex with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Art Museum</ENAMEX>. Finally,
        you can get an excellent view of the cityscape from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> Tower
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Borg</ENAMEX>), designed like a minaret, though it does stand significantly
        higher at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">182 m</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">600 ft</ENAMEX>) above the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South of Gezira</ENAMEX> is Roda
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX>, home to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manial Palace</ENAMEX>, now converted into an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art gallery</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nileometer</ENAMEX> is also situated here. Built in a.d. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">715</NUMEX> to help measure the
        peak and trough of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">the Nile</ENAMEX> flood. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> now no longer needed as the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Aswan High Dam</ENAMEX> in the far south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> completely controls the flow,
        keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> safe.
        The west <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">the Nile</ENAMEX> is home to the modern university
        and seemingly endless residential suburbs, but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> attractions lie on
        or close to the river. In the north, opposite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gezira Island</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian National Circus</ENAMEX>, a Soviet-trained <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troupe</ENAMEX>, performs nightly
        except in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>. Further south, set among verdant gardens, is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo Zoo</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian Museum</ENAMEX>
        Sitting on the north side of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tahrir Square</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1902</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>. Founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Auguste Mariette</ENAMEX> in an attempt to stop the flow of artifacts to museums
        around the world, it has grown into one of the major collections in the
        world, housing some of the finest treasures of the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX>
        civilization. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> is a little dated, confusing, and often
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">crowded‚ÄÇ‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇthe best time to visit is at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunchtime</TIMEX> when most large
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are having <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lunch‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbut</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 120,000</NUMEX> pieces on display, all
        between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000 and 1,400</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX>, it is a must-see attraction during
        your visit. The artifacts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> come from archaeological sites
        around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and they will add a great deal to your understanding
        and appreciation of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>. Allow at least <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">visit‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa</ENAMEX> comprehensive tour will take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX>. ‚ÄÇ‚ÄÇ The best
        strategy is to schedule <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> visits into your itinerary, both before and
        after your trips to the temples and other historical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> along the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile</ENAMEX>.
        The artifacts that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> put at the top of their
        lists are on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>, so you may want to head there first
        before you get worn out. Several recently refurbished <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> display
        over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,700</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> found at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tutankhamun</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Carter</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX>. The only undisturbed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX> tomb ever to be found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX>, it captured the public imagination and fired peoples‚Äô desire
        to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 19</NUMEX> when he died and there was little
        time to prepare a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> more suitable for royalty, but it was
        still filled with treasures for use when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> arrived at the Other
        World. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> following his interment, the tomb entrance became
        covered with debris when another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> was dug nearby, saving it from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tomb robbers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> coffins surrounding the king‚Äôs mummy are on display
        at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">museum‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> inner one is fashioned from pure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and weighs
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">170 kg</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">374 lbs</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King‚</ENAMEX>Äôs gold funerary mask can also be seen, a
        truly awe-inspiring find which still dazzles the eye even after over
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3,000 years</TIMEX>.
        Also upstairs is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mummy Room</ENAMEX> where you can find the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">preserved</ENAMEX> remains of some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egypt‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most illustrious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>. These
        mainly date from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th</TIMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">20th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynasties</ENAMEX> and include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramses IV</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tutmosis III</ENAMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tutankhamun</ENAMEX> could have been among
        them, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> made the decision to return him to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Valley</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX> and he now rests once again in the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX>
        of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> in a stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sarcophagus</ENAMEX>.
        The ground floor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> follow the chronological history of
        ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> starting on the left of the entrance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Kingdom</ENAMEX>
        Room. The finds are mainly tomb artifacts found at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> across the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and you can view the exact re-creation of a funerary chamber
        found at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dahshur</ENAMEX> to familiarize yourself with what you will see later
        in your vacation along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nile Valley</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper Egypt</ENAMEX>.
        Tomb artifacts give us a great deal of information about
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>. There are delightful wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> made as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> for the dead. These included <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craftsmen</ENAMEX> and boat
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>. Important <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foodstuffs</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> were
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re-created</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> to make sure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> would be provided for in
        his afterlife.
        Room <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> is devoted to the so-called heretic period of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> history when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ahkenaten</ENAMEX> established a religion based on only
        one god and founded a capital at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tell al Amarna</ENAMEX> in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>. The
        experiment lasted only until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ahkenaten‚</ENAMEX>Äôs death when almost all records
        relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> were destroyed. All the artifacts here were
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excavated at Tell al Amarna</ENAMEX> including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> giant statues of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pharaoh</ENAMEX>
        with his distinctive long chin and rounded belly.
        Among this amazing range of exquisite and colorful finds,
        there are also important artifacts that help confirm certain
        archaeological theories about the chronology of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> history such
        as the slate palate of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Narmer‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇone</ENAMEX> of the first documents scribed
        after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> became a unified <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statuary</ENAMEX> found all around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX> depicts both the
        important <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">deities‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇOsiris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hathor, Isis</ENAMEX> and others‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharaohs</ENAMEX>
        of the major dynasties. Huge representations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramses II</ENAMEX>
        illustrate the power held by the throne and by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>,
        though there are also tiny sculptures such as a bust of Queen
        Hatschepsut, which may have stood on a mantle or in a niche, showing
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptians</ENAMEX> were not just fixated by the epic and monumental.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamic Cairo</ENAMEX>
        Though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> has many modern and nondescript suburbs, the
        oldest districts of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Al-Qahira</ENAMEX> are well-preserved and exhibit some of
        the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">finest</TIMEX> period architecture in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> world. Founded to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">east</ENAMEX> of the river, it was protected from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">yearly Nile flood</ENAMEX> and
        surrounded by a high wall to guard against invaders.
        The famed marketplace of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cairo‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇKhan El-Khalili‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇstill
        buzzes with the atmosphere of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">medieval souk</ENAMEX> and it makes a good place
        to start your tour, though do return as the sun drops and the lights
        come on because the atmosphere is palpable. Narrow alleyways brim with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, leather, and alabaster, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> are replete with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">barrow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> touting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. It is the largest marketplace in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Near East</ENAMEX>, and it‚Äôs been so for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost one thousand years</TIMEX>. The
        market developed during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Fatimid</ENAMEX> period on the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>
        that connected the main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> gates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bab Zuweila</ENAMEX> in the south and Bab
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Futah</ENAMEX> in the north. A series of caravanserais (rooming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> for
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">camel caravans</ENAMEX> that were the main method of transporting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goods</ENAMEX>), or
        khans as they were known in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Fatimid</ENAMEX> era, were built
        here by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emir El-Khalili</ENAMEX>, giving the market its name. As you stroll
        along its various shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> look for significant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monuments</ENAMEX>. Exquisite stone carving, wood turning, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX>/brasswork, and
        ceramic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tiling</ENAMEX> are the main features of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> architecture and the
        period <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, mosques (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> of worship), madrasas
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>), khans and bayts (private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>) are very
        impressive.
        Major among these is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kalawun</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barquq Mosque</ENAMEX> on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">arterial Muizz lidina-Illah Street</ENAMEX>. Dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1293</TIMEX>, its long fa√ßade
        is rich in architectural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">detail</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Mansur Kalawan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">d.1290</ENAMEX>)
        is at the heart of the complex and is surrounded by beautiful screens
        of ornate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fretwork</ENAMEX>.
        If the striking portal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Nasir Mohammed</ENAMEX> madrasa
        next door strikes you as reminiscent of those in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> Gothic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">churches</ENAMEX>, you are not far from the truth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> was taken as booty
        from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crusader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Acre</ENAMEX> (now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>) when it was overrun by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barquq Mosque</ENAMEX> is the youngest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, completed in
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 14th century</TIMEX>.
        Continue north and then left on A-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darb al-Asfar Street</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">you‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bayt es-Suheimi</ENAMEX> on your right. This was the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> of
        the rector of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El-Ahzar Mosque</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">200 years ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> homes
        centered around a large central <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> called a qa‚Äôawith a fountain in
        the middle. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">qa‚Äôa</ENAMEX> led to the family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>. Light was supplied via a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dome</ENAMEX> (schukhsheikha) in the roof as the windows were covered by ornate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wooden</ENAMEX> covers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> has been fully restored and offers an
        excellent example of fine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cairene</ENAMEX> architecture.
        From here it‚Äôs only a short walk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mosque</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al-Hakim</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bab El-Futah</ENAMEX> set in a remaining section of the original city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mosque</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> oldest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>, dates from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">990</NUMEX> though it was
        renovated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. The symmetry of the large central <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> has
        a simple elegance. Plain outer walls give it the look of a fortress
        more than a place of worship. The huge square gates that flank it are
        more akin to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> since their primary function was to
        protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guards</ENAMEX> would regulate those who entered and departed.
        Look for the graffiti of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Napoleon‚Äôs French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> on the stone of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">towers</ENAMEX>; they spent some time garrisoned at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> and made sure
        they left their marks for posterity.
        The southern boundary of the market is marked by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Ghuri</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>, madrasa (Koranic
        school), and a wikala (an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Ottoman</ENAMEX> word for caravanserai or rooming
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX>). They were built at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the very beginning of the 16th century</TIMEX> by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sultan al-Ghuri</ENAMEX>, the last Mameluke <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum</ENAMEX> at the
        heart of the development is now a cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> hosting regular
        performances of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whirling Dervishes</ENAMEX> (who achieve religious ecstasy
        by circling around in continuous motion). The wikala, now fully
        restored, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> an arts <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> where you can view and buy pieces by
        local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>.
        Cairo‚Äôs oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> can be found just east of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Ghuri</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Azhar Mosque</ENAMEX> (meaning ‚ÄúThe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Splendid‚Äù</ENAMEX>) was finished
        in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">972</NUMEX> though it has been expanded many times over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>, and
        its remarkable inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX> now covers <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10,360 sq m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4,000 sq ft</NUMEX>).
        From the outset it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of culture and learning, arguably the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> in the world. It is still the foremost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> studies, attracting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 85,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>.
        You can walk south along the narrow alleyway cutting the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Ghuri</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> to reach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bab Zuweila Gate</ENAMEX>, once the lower entrance to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Huge round bastions topped by ornate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minarets</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Muayyad Mosque</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1420</TIMEX>) frame the tiny gate, which was used as a
        permanent scaffold to hang <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> gone by.
        A short stroll west (right) down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ahmed Maher Street</ENAMEX> from
        the gate leads to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Islamic Art</ENAMEX>, inaugurated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903</TIMEX> and
        featuring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> of beautifully crafted objects. Each room
        concentrates on a separate skill revealing excellent examples of carved
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ivory</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ceramics</ENAMEX>, and manuscripts. Elaborately decorated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> are
        also on display. If you intend to take home some souvenir <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Islamic</ENAMEX>
        crafts, this is a good place to learn about traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motifs</ENAMEX>, and patterns.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX> of the market region, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-minute</TIMEX> walk or
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten-minute</TIMEX> taxi ride, is The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citadel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Qal‚Äôa</ENAMEX>), a massive
        fortification built on high ground in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 13th century</TIMEX> to protect
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusaders</ENAMEX>. Later it became the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> of the Mamelukes
        and was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garrison</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWII</ENAMEX>. The size of a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>,
        the site now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> mosques, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, caf√©s, and is a place where
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> and local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> gather away from the noise and dust of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. The centerpiece of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citadel</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mosque</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Ali</ENAMEX>
        built <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1824 and 1857</TIMEX>. The largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, it has
        earned the name ‚Äúalabaster mosque‚Äù for its grand interior faced with
        the smooth pale <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>. The inner <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sanctuary hall</ENAMEX> is a truly monumental
        space in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> style, capped with a series of beautifully
        painted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">domes</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Ali</ENAMEX> sits under the colonnade. Its
        Carrera marble fa√ßade is incised with intricate carvings of traditional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> themes. Next to the elaborate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mosque</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Ali</ENAMEX> is the
        much simpler <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">el-Nasir Mosque</ENAMEX> with a small inner <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>.
        You‚Äôll be able to explore the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Military Museum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carriage</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your</TIMEX> tour, but do take time to visit the vantage points
        along the western <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> for wonderful views down onto vast areas of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citadel</ENAMEX>, left unused and now decaying, and panoramic views across
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>.
        The minarets that you see in the foreground belong to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        important <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. On the left is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madrasa of Sultan</ENAMEX>
        Hasan, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1362</TIMEX>. There are in fact <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> within
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> and each one has its own portal and inner <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>. The
        original minaret on the southwest corner is the tallest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265 ft</ENAMEX>). To the right of the madrasa is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Rafai Mosque</ENAMEX>
        completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1902</TIMEX> and the last greatest religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> to be built
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. It forms the resting places of many lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Ali</ENAMEX>, and is where the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Shah</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> was interred
        following his death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>.
        A short walk west from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citadel</ENAMEX> leads to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mosque</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ibn</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tulun</ENAMEX> founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">876</TIMEX> as the religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of a great military
        compound established by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ibn Tulun</ENAMEX> who was appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">868</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> is unusual in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> in that it has no <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">fa√ßade‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit</ENAMEX> is
        hidden behind a protective wall with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nineteen</ENAMEX> openings. It also has the
        only spiral minaret in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gayer-Anderson Museum</ENAMEX> beside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibn Tulun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> was
        built as a private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1540</TIMEX> and amalgamated with a neighboring
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cretan Woman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bayt al-Kritliya</ENAMEX>) dating
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1631</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> office <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Gayer-Anderson</ENAMEX> bought the latter
        between the two <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World Wars</ENAMEX>, and fully restored it with exquisite
        fretwork, wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">balconies</ENAMEX>, tiled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX>, and simple stucco walls. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">museum</ENAMEX> displays the outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> furniture, art,
        and handicrafts collected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gayer-Anderson</ENAMEX> during his time in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>.
        Old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early years</TIMEX> of Christianity a strong churc h‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coptic‚Äîwas</ENAMEX> established in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, and it flourished in this area,‚ÄÇnow
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">south</ENAMEX> of the city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> has survived to the present day.
        Almost <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nine percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptians</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>.
        To reach <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Cairo</ENAMEX> take the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nile River Bus</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jetty</ENAMEX>
        near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramses Hilton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>; it will drop you at the terminus of Masr
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Qadeema</ENAMEX>; or take the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> metro line <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mari Girgis Station</ENAMEX>.
        Enter <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Cairo</ENAMEX> by the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman Gate‚</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> Romans
        established a fort here following their annexation of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">country‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇwhere you will find a concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coptic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monasteries</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventh century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Moallaqah</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúThe Hanging Church‚</ENAMEX>Äù
        gets its name from its <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">location‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit</ENAMEX> was built <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> gate and claims to be the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> as its
        foundations date from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth century</TIMEX>. Nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Serga Church</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sergius</ENAMEX>) also claims this distinction. It is said to have been built at
        the site where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>, and the infant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> took shelter after
        they fled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Land</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of Saint Barbara</ENAMEX> is
        also worth visiting; it is typical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coptic</ENAMEX> in style. Next door is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">synagogue Ben-Ezra</ENAMEX>, now no longer used for regular services though the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guardian</ENAMEX> will allow you to look inside if he is available.
        The main attraction in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Cairo</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coptic Museum</ENAMEX>.
        Housed in an old byat, it is currently under renovation, but the work
        is mostly on the exterior leaving the wealth of artifacts inside
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">undisturbed</ENAMEX>. The collection covers all aspects of Coptic art and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">worship</ENAMEX>, from vestments, tapestries, early handwritten bibles, and
        painted icons, to ornate stone niches and wood-carved ceilings taken
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> all across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>. The guardians are particularly helpful
        and attentive.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pyramids</ENAMEX>
        Giza
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> have exerted a powerful hold on the
        world since explorers <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> began to explore this ancient land. Were
        they simply tombs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pharaohs</ENAMEX>, or astronomical markers to aid the
        quantifying of time; were they built to concentrate a natural energy
        source, or were they not built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> at all, a sign that an alien
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> visited the earth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>?
        Whatever the latest theory, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pyramids of Giza</ENAMEX> (the most
        well-known) are, without doubt, an amazing sight as you stand before
        them. Their sandstone fa√ßades reflect the sunlight, rose-colored in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, golden in the heat of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, and smoky purple as night
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">falls</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">can‚Äôt</ENAMEX> fail to marvel at the feat of design and organization
        that resulted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of individual stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">blocks</ENAMEX> being transported
        to the site and placed precisely one atop another with very little
        error in alignment, all without the aid of power tools or lifting
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX>.
        Archaeologists have concluded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Giza</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX> were
        built within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few hundred years</TIMEX> of each other by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of the
        same royal family c.<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2600</TIMEX> b.c. as elaborate tombs designed to foil
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">robbers</ENAMEX>. The largest of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Pyramid of Cheops</ENAMEX> is the
        only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúSeven Wonders of the World‚</ENAMEX>Äù described by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>. It stands <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">137 m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">450 ft</ENAMEX>) high and was the tallest
        structure in the world until the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eiffel Tower</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1898</TIMEX>. Originally capped with a smooth layer of limestone it would
        have reflected sunlight like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beacon across the Nile valley</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interior</ENAMEX> could not be more in contrast to the vast exterior. Steep,
        narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnels</ENAMEX> lead to a tiny funerary chamber furnished by a simple
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">granite sarcophagus</ENAMEX>. Look for the ventilation shafts that astronomers
        have proved aligned with major constellations in the skies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pyramid of Kephren</ENAMEX> is smaller than the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Pyramid</ENAMEX>,
        though its location on slightly higher ground makes it seem taller. Its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> was found to contain a red granite <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sarcophagus</ENAMEX>. The
        smallest pyramid, that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mykerinus</ENAMEX>, adds a wonderful perspective to
        the panorama, particularly when you align the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX> for that
        souvenir photograph. To the south of this are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> smaller, unfinished
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pyramids</ENAMEX> thought to be for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mykerinus</ENAMEX>.
        These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> now famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pharaohs</ENAMEX> were not the only ones laid
        to rest here however. Giza was the site of a royal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial ground</ENAMEX> from
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Early Empire</ENAMEX> and the desert landscape is dotted with
        numerous mud brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tombs</ENAMEX> and mastabas (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone tombs</ENAMEX> with flat roofs),
        though they are by no means as impressive as the pyramids
        themselves.
        Standing at the base of the sacred causeway that once
        linked the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nileisthe Sphinx</ENAMEX>, the enigmatic depiction of
        Khephren with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> attached to a lion‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. Sphinxes were
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guardian</ENAMEX> deitiesinEgyptianmythologyandthis was
        monumentalprotection,<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">standing73 m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">240 ft</ENAMEX>)longand20 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">66 feet</NUMEX>) high.
        Following <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Khephren‚</ENAMEX>Äôsdeaththe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> oftheSphinxwaslost under the desert
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sands</ENAMEX> that sweptthe areaandTutmosis
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IV</ENAMEX> believed that the statue spoke to him, telling him he
        would become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pharaoh</ENAMEX> if he cleared the sand away. Following this,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ancient Egyptians</ENAMEX> believed that the monument possessed prophetic powers
        and it still has a mysterious hold on the modern psyche.
        The most recent attraction at the pyramid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> is a
        small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> housing the remains of a solar barque (a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cedar longboat</ENAMEX>)
        which was found in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> was made to carry the spirit of
        Khephren into the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Other World</ENAMEX> after his death.
        You can tour the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX> on foot, or take a camel or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">horseback</ENAMEX> ride between the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> choose to embark on
        a longer journey on horseback to view the monuments without the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>
        cityscape behind them in the distance.
        Once you‚Äôve seen the real thing, maybe you want to visit
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pharaonic Village</ENAMEX>, a theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> recreating life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ancient Egypt</ENAMEX>.
        Colorful temples are presided over by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">reed boats</ENAMEX> ply the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">waterways</ENAMEX> in this interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> that will certainly help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
        understand how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may have lived‚<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit</ENAMEX> may also help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>.
        There‚Äôs a good re-creation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tutankhamun‚Äôs</ENAMEX> tomb at the time of
        its discovery so you can see just what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Carter</ENAMEX> saw in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">park</ENAMEX> also has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> and children‚Äôs play area.
        Saqqara
        Giza was not the only location where <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX> were
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">built‚ÄÇ‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthere</ENAMEX> are many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> scattered throughout the western
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">desert‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇand it was not the place where pyramid-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> started. To
        see the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and oldest pyramid you must make an hour‚Äôs journey south
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saqqara</ENAMEX> and, following this, on to the ancient capital of
        Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Egypt‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇMemphis</ENAMEX>.
        Saqqara was the final resting place for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> and constitutes the largest royal graveyard in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>. Pride of
        place at the site is taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Step Pyramid</ENAMEX> built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>
        Imhotep for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Djoser</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">c2670</TIMEX> b.c. The pyramid is made up of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tiers</ENAMEX>, reaching a height of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">196 ft</ENAMEX>). Inside the
        structure a shaft was dug <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">28 m</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX> ft) into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX> where the
        Djoser‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial chamber</ENAMEX> was situated. The pyramid is surrounded by a
        compound designed to mimic the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> at his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX>;
        with beams, columns, and bundles of reeds carved onto its fa√ßade.
        Several tombs surrounding the pyramid have extremely fine murals,
        particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mereruka‚Äôs</ENAMEX> tomb (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2300 b.c.</ENAMEX> ), the largest yet discovered
        at the site, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ti‚Äôs</ENAMEX> tomb with murals of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>. The mastaba
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idut</ENAMEX> has exceptional nautical scenes and you‚Äôll also catch
        sight of the name of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tomb robber‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇAhmed the Carpenter‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwho couldn‚</ENAMEX>Äôt
        resist letting the world know about his visit.
        Of the once white walls of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX>, little remains, but it
        was capital of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the sixth</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynasty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">c. 2200 b.c.</ENAMEX>
        ). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major relics are a monumental statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Ramses II</ENAMEX> lying
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prostrate</ENAMEX> after losing its feet, and an alabaster sphinx dating from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1400 b.c.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX> and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean Coast</ENAMEX>
        There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> leads
        through the fertile lands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nile Delta</ENAMEX>, past fields of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rice</ENAMEX>, and numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruits</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>. Life seems to have changed
        little in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>, though the mud-brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> now have the benefit
        of electricity. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> route leads out through the desert to the
        west of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> on a new four-lane <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> that leads to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wadi Natrun</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wadi Natrun</ENAMEX> was one of the most important areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> in
        ancient times, primarily because it was the main source of the mineral
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">natron</ENAMEX> used in the mummification and glassmaking processes. Coptic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christians</ENAMEX> founded an expansive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> for prayer and contemplation
        here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth century</TIMEX> a.d. when many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monks</ENAMEX> chose to live their
        lives as hermits. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> monasteries developed as a source of protection
        still remain, and each has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, monks‚Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX> and a sturdy high
        wall. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deir Abu Maker</ENAMEX> is the most important, having provided several
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coptic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>; nearby is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deir Anba-Baramos</ENAMEX>. Deir
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Es-Suryani</ENAMEX>, as the name suggests, was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monks</ENAMEX> and
        its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deir Anba Bishoi</ENAMEX>, is of typical design with a tiny
        round-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">domed fourth-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and inner defensive bastion dating
        from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>. Holy mass is said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Coptic</ENAMEX> language
        but an English-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> is available to give you a comprehensive
        guided tour.
        Founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander the Great</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> coast
        in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">322 b.c.</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX> was capital of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ptolemaic</ENAMEX> era.
        It was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> and temples, and a place of
        learning, with one of the most renowned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> in the known world.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Ships</ENAMEX> from around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> docked at the double harbor. The
        harbor‚Äôs entrances were protected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pharos Lighthouse</ENAMEX>, one of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonders of the World</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately all this was lost in a series
        of earthquakes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early centuries of the first millennium</TIMEX> and
        Ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX> now rests below the waters of today‚Äôs harbor. Recent
        underwater archaeological excavations have revealed a wealth of stone
        blocks and statuary lying <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only a few feet</NUMEX> below the surface.
        Although ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX> sank into the sea, the city
        continued to flourish as a trading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX>. It was the main entry point
        into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> until the advent of air travel in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 20th century</TIMEX> and
        its contact with a range of international influences made it the most
        cosmopolitan <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>. Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 19th</TIMEX> and early 20th
        centuries it was home to numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> ‚Äúex-pats,‚Äù one of whom, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Durrell</ENAMEX>, ‚ÄÇpainted a graphic picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> life
        here. However, the climate changed after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX> coup and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
        though you can still discern the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> feel of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX>, there is
        no doubt that it is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> sits on a wide bay with the colonial sandstone
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> on the waterside making a wonderful panorama as the sun
        begins to drop in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX>. Myriad fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats bob</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, their catches making the short journey across the wide Corniche
        (sea-front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>) to supply the day‚Äôs menus at local seafood
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX>. The western end of the bay sweeps round to a headland,
        which is thought to be the location for the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lighthouse</ENAMEX>. Today, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 15th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fort of Qait Bey</ENAMEX> watches over the
        harbor entrance. It houses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Museum</ENAMEX> with a collection of relics
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Naval</ENAMEX> sojourn here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1798</TIMEX>. Just west of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">fort</ENAMEX> is
        the former royal palace of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ras El-Tin</ENAMEX>, built for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Ali</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1834</TIMEX>.
        It was here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farouk</ENAMEX> signed his abdication before
        boarding his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">yacht</ENAMEX> for exile in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>.
        You can walk back to the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corniche</ENAMEX>.
        It takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">around 30 minutes</TIMEX> and is a very pleasant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strollthankstothecoolbreezesthatcomeoffthesea</ENAMEX>. Look for the elaborate
        oriental lines of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mosque</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu El Abbas</ENAMEX> on your right. Rebuilt in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX>, it holds the tombs of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheikh</ENAMEX> and other nobles.
        Take time to explore the exquisite Moorish stonework and the elegant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">domes</ENAMEX> and minaret.
        A small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> on the seafront marks the center of town.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Mini-buses</ENAMEX> dart in and out of the traffic to pick up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and
        there‚Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a frantic</TIMEX> rush at peak times as everyone tries to leave the
        city at once. Look for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cecil Hotel</ENAMEX> on the western end of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">square</ENAMEX>. Once the gathering place of the colonial ‚Äúglitterati,‚Äù it still
        draws <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> for a glimpse of a genteel past.
        Take a right at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> and walk away from the seafront
        past the tram terminus that links eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX> with the city
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>. Off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">El Hurriya Street</ENAMEX> you‚Äôll find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Neo-Classical</ENAMEX> fa√ßade of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greco-Roman Museum</ENAMEX> with a fine collection of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, and
        Ptolemaic artifacts found around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and under the waters of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">harbor</ENAMEX>, along with many ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> pieces. There is a marble
        statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius Caesar</ENAMEX>, consort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Cleopatra</ENAMEX>, who spent many
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> here, and a bust of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>, which was carved in his likeness
        after his death.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> and surrounded by modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">housing</ENAMEX> lie
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman Baths</ENAMEX>. Built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third century</TIMEX> a.d. they played host to
        the highly ranked of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX> who would come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX> to
        relax and exchange news while enjoying a soak or a massage. A little
        further southwest are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some second century</TIMEX> a.d. catacombs with tomb
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chambers</ENAMEX> painted to depict Greco-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> themes.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pompey‚Äôs Pillar</ENAMEX> sits only a few minutes‚Äô walk to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southwest</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>-m- (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">95-ft-</NUMEX>) high <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corinthian</ENAMEX> column hewn from red
        granite <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> on the site of the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple of Serapis</ENAMEX>. It was
        raised to honor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diocletian</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> general that now
        gives it its name.
        The ancient library of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX> founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ptolemy</ENAMEX> I was
        said to be the greatest collection of manuscripts in the ancient world
        comprising <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 70,000</NUMEX> items. Unfortunately it was damaged by fire
        several times and what remained was completely destroyed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">640</NUMEX> during
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> invasion. As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX> neared its end the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX>
        government sought to revive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of learning and
        recreate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria Library</ENAMEX>. With the help of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNESCO</ENAMEX> a new
        high-tech depository has been built on a site on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corniche</ENAMEX>, east of
        the central <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde</ENAMEX> circular design contrasts sharply
        with the dreary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> around it. Clad with gray Aswan <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">granite</ENAMEX>, it
        is engraved with letters and graphic inscriptions of cultures and
        societies around the world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> will house <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over four million</NUMEX>
        volumes composed of books, tapes, maps, videos, and discs.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX> has no proper beaches but <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 km</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX>) to the east is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montazah</ENAMEX>, a resort <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and sandy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bays</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montazah Palace</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX> as a hunting lodge,
        started the fashion. It is now a smart hotel and casino surrounded by
        beautiful gardens.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean Coast</ENAMEX>
        West of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX>, civilization gives way to empty desert
        except along the coast, where the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1990s</TIMEX> saw a building boom. Where
        only recently there were virgin beaches, now <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">mile upon mile</NUMEX> of concrete
        vacation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> line the strand until you reach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Alamein</ENAMEX>, a
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90-minute</TIMEX> drive along the coast. This tiny desert railway crossing was
        the scene of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the pivotal battles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWII</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>
        defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rommel‚Äôs German</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>. The military
        cemeteries of both sides engaged in the historical battle now stand as
        a poignant memorial to the death and destruction that took place in the
        heat of the desert. There is also a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> here with uniforms,
        military hardware, and maps illustrating the battle plans and tactics
        of this most grueling theater of war.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Upper Egypt</ENAMEX>
        The land of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper Egypt</ENAMEX> sits in the south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
        and it takes its name because it is up-river of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Delta</ENAMEX> area, which are known as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Egypt</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Upper Egypt</ENAMEX> was the
        heartland of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX> at the peak of its power and influence, and
        the remains of its ancient cities form one of the most important and
        breathtaking archaeological collections in the world.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luxor</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Valley of the Kings</ENAMEX>
        The modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luxor</ENAMEX> is one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> forming
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tourist</ENAMEX> bases on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nile Valley</ENAMEX>. Its name in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Arabic‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇEl-Uqsor‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇmeans
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúgods‚Äô palaces‚Äù</ENAMEX> and it indicates the supreme importance of this area to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient Egyptians</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luxor</ENAMEX> (known to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ancient Greeks</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thebes</ENAMEX>)
        was for many centuries the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital city</ENAMEX> and religious focal point of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>.
        The modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> sits on the east <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">the Nile</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 800</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">km</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500 miles</NUMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>. Thebes reached it peak in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Kingdom</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">era</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">c.1540‚Äì1100 b.c.</ENAMEX> ). By the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romans</ENAMEX> arrived it was already
        in decline, having lost influence when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assyrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">raiders</ENAMEX> seized control
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the seventh century</TIMEX> b.c. and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ptolemaic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> made their base
        at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth century</TIMEX> b.c. In the following centuries
        sand swept through the area burying many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> was erected atop this sandy layer and many treasures are still
        lost below the surface of the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last hundred years</TIMEX>
        Luxor‚Äôs major historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> have been cleared of sand allowing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to now view the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple structures</ENAMEX>. Across the river on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">west</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> are the remains of other temples, and more importantly, the
        burial places of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pharaohs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ancient Egypt</ENAMEX>, hidden in a
        slender valley beyond the narrow fertile river plain.
        In the heart of the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, set beside the waters of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luxor Temple</ENAMEX>, started by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amenophis III</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">18th Dynasty</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">c.1350 b.c.</ENAMEX> , and embellished by <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ramses II in the 19th Dynasty</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temple</ENAMEX> served a specific purpose, to host <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the New Year</TIMEX> celebration to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God Amun</ENAMEX> who would be represented in both his positive form, Amun
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Ra‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe sun god‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇand his negative form, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amun-Min‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa</ENAMEX> lustful, wanton
        and outrageous demon.
        The great pylon (grand entranceway with twin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>) of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temple</ENAMEX> is fronted by majestic statues of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramses</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> and a large granite
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obelisk</ENAMEX> once one of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pair‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> other was presented to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
        government by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Ali</ENAMEX> and now graces the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Place de la</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Concorde</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. Before heading into the inner sanctum of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, stride
        along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenue</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ram-Headed Sphinxesthatpointsinthe</ENAMEX> direction of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karnak Temple</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX>)to the north. These were erected by
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nectaneboduringthefourth century</TIMEX> b.c.
        Enteringthemaincourtyard of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, you will
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">findaperistylehall</ENAMEX>(with onerowofsupporting columns)decoratedwith
        flutedcolumns that werecommissioned by the Queen
        Hatshepsut,<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">andseveralimpressivestatuesofRamses II</ENAMEX> in black and red
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">granite</ENAMEX>.Perhapsthemostfascinating element of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mosque</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu El Haggag</ENAMEX> which was built within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> complex to protect the
        tomb of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mohammed‚</ENAMEX>Äôs brother-in-law. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mosque</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> were erected on the bed of sand that covered the temple
        and now sit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> ft) or so above the excavated floor level. The
        entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> is through a door at the east <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> above the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>.
        As you move further into the complex look for statues of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Tutankhamun</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, one of only a few depicting the young
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy Pharaoh</ENAMEX> to be found at his capital. From the hall, a colonnade
        leads to an immense hypostyle (with columns supporting the roof) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>,
        decorated with double rows of papyrus columns with beautifully
        preserved colors, and on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of Amenophis III</ENAMEX>. Elaborate
        carvings on the walls of both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> depict <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amenophis</ENAMEX> making
        offerings to the gods in thanks for his divine power.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Luxor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> does not have a sound and light show but it is
        open <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late each evening</TIMEX>, offering you a chance to enjoy the majestic
        remains under floodlights, a very romantic sight to behold.
        Between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luxor Temple</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">the Nile</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corniche</ENAMEX>, a
        tree-lined <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX> carrying traffic through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and officially
        called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">El-Nil Street</ENAMEX>. A wide walkway riverside allows you to stroll and
        benches allow for a shady seat. Here, the felucca (<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile sailboat</ENAMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> gather, trying to sell an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> or sunset trip on their
        graceful <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile Cruisers</ENAMEX> lie several abreast, disgorging their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> for tours or shopping trips. Horse-drawn carriages ply the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corniche</ENAMEX> offering trips to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Karnak</ENAMEX>, or a ride back to your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>.
        Also on the riverside of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">El-Nil Street</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mummy Museum</ENAMEX>,
        with an eclectic collection of artifacts and information about the art
        of mummification. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äúofficial‚Äù Archaeological Museum of Luxor</ENAMEX> lies a
        little way north. The modern air-conditioned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is well designed,
        with a small number of delightful pieces on display including a
        striking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">basalt</ENAMEX> statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pharaoh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tutmosis III</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North of Luxor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mosque</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu El Haggag</ENAMEX>, is the bustling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souk</ENAMEX> or market where you‚Äôll find a
        mixture of tourist souvenirs and local products such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">textiles</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Browsing</ENAMEX> is difficult as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> are attentive and can be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">insistent</ENAMEX>, but you‚Äôll have fun. If you want to buy pottery or
        alabaster, compare prices and quality with goods on sale at the artisan
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> on the west <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> (see page tk) before making a final
        decision.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Karnak</ENAMEX> sits in the northern <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the town
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thebes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No-Amun or ‚Äúthe City of Amun‚</ENAMEX>Äù in ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX>) now <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 km</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11/2 miles</NUMEX>) from modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luxor</ENAMEX>. Begun during the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Kingdom</ENAMEX>, it was
        the national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúSt</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter‚Äôs‚Äù</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> religion) from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 11th</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dynasty</ENAMEX> period, c.<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2134</TIMEX> b.c. The temple
        complex was expanded over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the subsequent centuries</TIMEX> with each generation
        adding their own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX> and monuments. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">excavations</TIMEX>, a cache of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17,000</NUMEX> items dating from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> era was found. It was finally
        abandoned towards <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth century</TIMEX> a.d. when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> looked to a
        new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of deities.
        The largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, the site extends <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 3 sq km</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 sq mile</NUMEX>). Standing at the heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of
        Amun, greatest of all <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theban gods</ENAMEX>. This monumental construction covers
        a140-<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">sq-m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,500-sq-ft</NUMEX>) area, with a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Hypostyle Hall of 122</ENAMEX>
        columns in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> rows, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">21 m</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> ft) high, and is considered one of the
        finest ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
        The avenue of the ram-headed sphinxes flanks the route from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> entrance. This was used for ceremonial purposes,
        allowing statues of the gods to be carried to the river for journeys to
        the west <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, or to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Luxor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karnak</ENAMEX> was linked to Luxor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> by a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 km-</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3/4-mile-</NUMEX>) long avenue decorated with smaller
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temples</ENAMEX> and flanked by sphinxes, most of which now lies below the
        modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>.
        From the ticket office you enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">temple complex</ENAMEX> through
        a colossal pylon, one of the most recent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> at the site and the
        largest constructed anywhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ptolemaic</ENAMEX> period.
        However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> was never finished and lacks the epic reliefs
        (carved images) found at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philae</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denderah</ENAMEX> (see pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 and 62</TIMEX>).
        Walk through the gateway and you‚Äôll find yourself in an
        immense open space‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe largest temple <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. To
        the left is the diminutive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Seti II</ENAMEX>, and further along on the
        right a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> dedicated to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramses III</ENAMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> smaller pylon,
        fronted by statues of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramses</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shields Karnak Temples</ENAMEX> greatest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">architectural masterpiece‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe Great Hypostyle Hall</ENAMEX>. Its immense
        columns (the top of each one could accommodate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> standing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>)
        recreate the papyrus <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">forests</ENAMEX> of the sacred <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> from which all life
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sprang</ENAMEX> (also representing the landscape of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Egypt</ENAMEX>), and they were
        highly decorated and brilliantly painted in their heyday.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> pylon leads on to the oldest parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>,
        past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">obelisks</ENAMEX> added at the behest of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pharaoh Seti I</ENAMEX> and Queen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hatshepsut</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Kingdom</ENAMEX> era. The pink <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">granite ‚Äúneedle‚Äù</ENAMEX> of the
        queen is the tallest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, pointing <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 m</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX> ft) toward the sky. It
        was originally topped by a cap of pure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, which reflected the bright
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sunlight</ENAMEX> and acted as a beacon for those who searched from afar for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temple</ENAMEX>. Look for a simple statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tutankhamun</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy king</ENAMEX>, below
        the needle. He consolidated power at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thebes</ENAMEX> during his short reign.
        Beyond the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">temple complex</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Karnak stretches</ENAMEX> out over
        the landscape as far as the eye can see, but many of the other remains
        are more difficult to identify. An interesting building towards the
        rear is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Festival Hall of Tutmoses III</ENAMEX>. It recreates in stone the
        field tent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pharaoh</ENAMEX> used when on military campaigns, with the
        central row of columns higher than the outer, meant to hold an
        imaginary canvas high above the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX> of the main temple complex you will find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sacred</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX>, used in ceremonial processions. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it forms the foreground for
        the seated part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sound and Light Show</ENAMEX>. Stop at the giant granite
        scarab on the northwest corner of the lake. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amunophis III</ENAMEX>
        originally commissioned the scarab it was placed at his temple on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">west</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Egyptians</ENAMEX> consider it lucky to walk <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times
        counter-clockwise around the scarab before touching it and making a
        wish.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TheTheban Necropolis</ENAMEX> and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kings</ENAMEX>
        Whilerulingfrompalaces ontheeastbankoftheNile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharaohs</ENAMEX>
        chose to be buriedonthewestbank,asthiswastherestingplaceoftheGodAmun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ra</ENAMEX>
        intheformof the setting sun. Tuthmosis I was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pharaoh</ENAMEX> to be
        entombed there c.<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1490</TIMEX> b.c. choosing a narrow valley out of site of the
        capital as a secret and supposedly safe location for his resting place,
        cut deep into the rock. Numerous other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> followed him, creating a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">veritable ‚Äúcity</ENAMEX> of the dead‚Äù with each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> more elaborate or brightly
        decorated than the last.
        Though the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Valley of the Kings</ENAMEX> has become popularly known,
        it is not the only ancient attraction on the west <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">the Nile</ENAMEX>.
        There are temples, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of other tombs of lesser though
        important mortals such as high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>, nobles and highly regarded
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artisans</ENAMEX> who worked on the royal tombs. The tombs are known
        collectively as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theban Necropolis</ENAMEX>.
        From the ferry docking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> on the west <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> to
        the nearby ticket <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> where you can purchase tickets for all the
        separate archaeological sites. From there the road leads directly
        toward the range of low hills that hide the tombs. You‚Äôll pass <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> huge
        sentinel statues <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">21 m</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX> ft) high on the river plain facing out
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">towards the Nile</ENAMEX>. These are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colossi of Memnon</ENAMEX>, statues of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pharaoh</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amenophis III</ENAMEX> that once guarded the entrance to his temple, which has
        now completely disappeared.
        At the split in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roadway</ENAMEX>, a left turn will lead you
        directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> complex of Medinet
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Habu</ENAMEX>. Often left out of the tour group itinerary, this part of the west
        bank can be much quieter than the better-known attractions, but they
        offer some interesting insights into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> life and some excellent
        remains. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX> and royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were buried in a valley separate
        from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>. The renowned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nefertari</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Ramses II</ENAMEX>, has the most ornate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> (number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX>) but it is not
        always accessible.
        Below the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX> are the remains of the town
        of the artisans, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deir el-Medina</ENAMEX>. This is the settlement where
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masons</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">builders</ENAMEX> who worked on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">royal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tombs</ENAMEX> lived. Simple brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> stand row upon row and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archaeologists</ENAMEX> found a wealth of everyday artifacts from cooking
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">utensils</ENAMEX> to work tools, painting a vivid picture of the ancients‚Äô
        activities. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archaeologists</ENAMEX> also discovered a number of simple tombs
        where the artisans buried their dead. Brightly decorated by their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">peers</ENAMEX>, they depict the incumbent in life, at work, or laboring in the
        fields. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomb of Sennedjem</ENAMEX> (number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Innerkhau</ENAMEX> (number
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">359</NUMEX>) are worth exploring.
        A right turn at the junction leads along the valley floor
        past the modern artisan <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheik Abd el-Gurnah</ENAMEX>, where you will
        be able to buy alabaster and onyx pieces. The simple brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>
        faced with ochre and blue stucco, though larger than those at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deir</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">el-Medina</ENAMEX> are little changed in style. There are a number of tombs and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temples</ENAMEX> scattered in farmland here; the most prominent is the mortuary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Ramses II</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramesseum</ENAMEX>. Built to hold festivities during
        his visits from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thebes</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramesseum</ENAMEX> was decorated with majestic
        statues of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pharaoh</ENAMEX>, and the pylon depicts him triumphant at the
        Battle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qadesh</ENAMEX> when he quashed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hittites</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately, much of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> lies in ruins.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tombs of the Nobles</ENAMEX> sit between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramesseum</ENAMEX> and the
        village. The best of these date back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">18th Dynasty</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX>
        art and creativity were at their peak. Take time to explore number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomb of Nacht</ENAMEX>, a temple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronomer</ENAMEX>. The paintings that cover the
        walls depict the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile</ENAMEX> at its most splendid with abundant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> and
        depictions of wine-making. The nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tomb of Mena</ENAMEX> (number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">69</NUMEX>) is also
        worth a visit for realistic scenes of harvesting and threshing. Tomb
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">57</TIMEX>, that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khaemhat</ENAMEX>, was decorated with statues of himself and his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">family‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇvery</ENAMEX> rare for tombs of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramose‚Äôs Tomb</ENAMEX> is also
        important. A high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amenophis IV</ENAMEX>, he began to
        prepare an elaborate resting place decorated with fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bas-reliefs</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tomb</ENAMEX> was abandoned when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amenophis</ENAMEX> abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thebes</ENAMEX> and made a new
        capital at Tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">el-Amarna</ENAMEX> to the north. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Ramose</ENAMEX> dutifully followed his
        master there to engage in an experimental new way of living.
        Before turning off the coastal plain into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX>, one of the most impressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theban</ENAMEX> temples comes into view on
        the left, that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen Hatshepsut</ENAMEX>. She was a remarkable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, gaining
        power as regent for the young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Tutmosis II‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇher stepson‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇbefore
        usurping it for herself by claiming divine right to rule. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of
        Hatshepsut, dedicated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hathor</ENAMEX>, is a vast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-tiered
        structure carved into the base of the rose-colored hillside facing out
        towards the river. Each level has a colonnaded fa√ßade, and as you
        approach on foot it gives you the opportunity to take in the monumental
        scale.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lower Terrace</ENAMEX> is cut by a wide ramp leading to a large
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courtyard</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Terrace</ENAMEX> level and a smaller ramp leading to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Upper Terrace</ENAMEX> (unfortunately closed to visitors).
        Behind the colonnades on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle Terrace</ENAMEX>, to the left
        of the ramp, are carved scenes depicting a trade mission bringing myrrh
        and incense from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egypt‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Punt</ENAMEX>, now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>. A small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hathor</ENAMEX> sitting to the left of the colonnade has columns carved with the
        cow‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> that depicted her. To the right the walls are carved with
        scenes from the life of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen Hatshepsut</ENAMEX> including her divine birth
        where her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is shown being attended by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heket</ENAMEX>, the frog-headed
        midwife god, watched over by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amun</ENAMEX> himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anubis</ENAMEX> (God of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mummification</ENAMEX>) has a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> here and you will clearly see his
        jackal-headed form on the walls.
        Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carvings</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hatshepsut</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> have been
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defaced</ENAMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tutmosis II</ENAMEX> tried to remove all traces of her at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luxor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Karnak</ENAMEX> when he finally became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pharaoh</ENAMEX> following her death,
        but this does not spoil the formidable architectural achievement of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temple</ENAMEX> itself.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Valley of the Kings</ENAMEX> lies out of view in the hills
        behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hatshepsut‚Äôs Temple</ENAMEX>. As you turn to head up into the valley,
        look for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on the left surrounded by shady <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>. This was the
        field <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Carter</ENAMEX> during the long search that finally
        resulted in the finding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tutankhamun‚</ENAMEX>Äôs treasure-filled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX>.
        Tickets for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Valley of the Kings</ENAMEX> allow you to visit
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> tombs, so if you want to visit more you must buy several tickets.
        There are over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX> tombs in the valley‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand some still yet to be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">discovered‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇdating c.1490‚Äì1100 b.c.</ENAMEX> , but not all will be open on your
        visit. The most impressive and important are listed below.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomb of Tutankhamun</ENAMEX> (number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX>) is without a doubt the
        most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX>, but the interior is disappointing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> died very
        young and artisans had only just begun to dig the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX>, so it‚Äôs
        small and sparsely decorated. Undoubtedly the discovery of an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">undisturbed</ENAMEX> tomb and its vast treasure trove in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX> is what maintains
        its popularity. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King‚</ENAMEX>Äôs mummy is the only one still in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">situ‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇ‚ÄÇmany</ENAMEX> others are on display in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian Museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> (see
        page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>). Extra fee to enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX>.
        Other tombs in the valley are much more instructive about
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> life, death, and the afterlife. They are also larger and more
        brilliantly decorated.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomb of Ramses VI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX>) reopened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> after major
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">renovations</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb shaft</ENAMEX> is decorated with excellent paintings
        depicting chapters of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of the Dead‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> rituals to be
        performed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptians</ENAMEX> to reach the afterlife.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tomb of Seti I</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">c.1279 b.c.</ENAMEX> , is one of the
        largest tombs in the valley boasting some of the finest decoration.
        There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> connecting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corridors</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pits</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> before
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial chamber</ENAMEX> is reached. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX> pays his respects to the
        deities including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ra</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kephri</ENAMEX> as he makes his symbolic journey.
        Masons dug a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">shaft 10 m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> ft) into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX> for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramses III‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11</NUMEX>) c.<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1151</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corridors</ENAMEX> then continue 125 m (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">410</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ft</ENAMEX>) to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial chamber</ENAMEX>. Look for scenes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> sailing on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nile</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of war including spears and shields. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> harpists
        sing the praises of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramses</ENAMEX> before the deities, giving rise to the
        temple‚Äôs alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">name‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇTemple</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harpists</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramses IV</ENAMEX> was responsible for saving many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mummies</ENAMEX>
        of his ancestors after tomb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">robbers</ENAMEX> desecrated their places of rest,
        stealing the treasures without thought for the reputation of the dead
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>. He organized the rewrapping of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mummies</ENAMEX> and devised a
        secret hiding place for them in a narrow valley behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hatshepsut</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> has good wall reliefs protected by glass
        screens.
        A splendid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red granite sarcophagus</ENAMEX> has pride of place in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomb of Horemheb</ENAMEX>. You‚Äôll need to walk down a long steep corridor to
