
  
  
    
      
        Where to Go
        To help you plan your itinerary, we divide <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
        regional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is devoted entirely to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, where you‚Äôre
        likely to begin your trip, get your bearings, and become acquainted
        with modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. We then present <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> tours spreading out from the
        capital to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> of historic and artistic interest as well as to
        sites of natural beauty. If you have sufficient time to explore <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>,
        you might want to begin and end your visit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX>, you
        can venture out to explore the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>
        Originally known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">meaning ‚Äúestuary‚Äù</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> was just
        a sleepy little village surrounded by marshland on the broad Kanto
        plain until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 16th century</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tokugawa Ieyasu</ENAMEX> moved
        here and made it the center of his vast domains. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ieyasu</ENAMEX> became
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shogun</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1603</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edo</ENAMEX> in turn became the seat of national
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">government‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> the largest in the world. Edo expanded
        rapidly to accommodate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ieyasu‚</ENAMEX>Äôs 80,000 retainers and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and
        the myriad common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who served their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> needs. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX> the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> had grown to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,368,000</NUMEX>.
        The ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> lived on the high ground, the Yamanote
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">(‚Äúbluffs‚Äù</ENAMEX>) west and south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>. The artisans, tradespeople,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> of entertainment (reputable and not so reputable) lived
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúdowntown‚Äù</ENAMEX> on the reclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">marshlands</ENAMEX> north and east, in the area
        still known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shitamachi</ENAMEX>. As these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations interacted</ENAMEX>, a
        unique new culture was born. Edo became the center of power and also
        the center of all that was vibrant and compelling in the arts.
        After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> grew even stronger, when the movement
        known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meiji Restoration</ENAMEX> overthrew the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> shogunate and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imperial</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was renamed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokyo (‚</ENAMEX>ÄúEastern
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital‚Äù</ENAMEX>), and from that moment on all <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">roads‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇpolitical</ENAMEX>, cultural, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">financial‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇled</ENAMEX> here.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice</NUMEX> suffered almost total
        destruction. First, the earthquake of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923</TIMEX> and subsequent fire razed
        nearly all vestiges of old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edo</ENAMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 140,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the
        process. Rebuilt without any comprehensive urban plan, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> remains a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of subcenters and neighborhoods, even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>, each with its own
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distinct</ENAMEX> personality.
        Unlike the great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital cities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, there is no
        prevailing style of architecture here, no ‚Äúmonumental‚Äù core for a new
        building to harmonize or clash with. Even after the collapse of the
        economic bubble in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, construction projects are everywhere. Whole
        blocks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> seem to disappear <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>, replaced in the blink
        of an eye by new office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">condominiums</ENAMEX>, cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX>,
        and shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of enormous creative and entrepreneurial
        energy, much of which goes into reinventing itself. If there‚Äôs a
        commodity in short supply here, it‚Äôs relaxation. Nobody ‚Äústrolls‚Äù in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, and there are few places to sit down outdoors and watch the
        world go by. The idea of a long, leisurely <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch hour</TIMEX> is utterly alien.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> are in a hurry to get <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">somewhere‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇeven</ENAMEX> if they don‚Äôt
        always know precisely where they‚Äôre going.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial Palace</ENAMEX>
        If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> can be said to have any <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> at all, this is it.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Today‚Äôs Imperial Palace</ENAMEX> is on the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>, where the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shogunate</ENAMEX> ruled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">265 years</TIMEX>; it was thereafter home to
        the emperors of the modern era. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> was almost totally destroyed
        in the air raids of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, then rebuilt in ferroconcrete. This
        is the least interesting part of what was once the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fortifications</ENAMEX> in the world, and in any case you can‚Äôt get in to see
        it. What you can see are the lovely grounds of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Garden</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moat</ENAMEX> and massive stone ramparts, and those few examples of classic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">architecture‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇgates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>, armories, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">watchtowers‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthat</ENAMEX> have survived since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX>.
        The imperial family still resides in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>, so the
        general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> is admitted to the grounds on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two days each year</TIMEX>:
        on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 January and 23 December</TIMEX>. On these occasions, you might find it
        hard to compete with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> who come
        to pay their respects.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Imperial Palace‚Äôs East Garden</ENAMEX> is open to the public
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> except <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Otemachi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway station</ENAMEX>, you
        enter the gardens at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Otemon Gate</ENAMEX> and wander through hedgerows of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">white</ENAMEX> and pink azaleas, around ponds and little waterfalls edged with
        pines, plum <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, canary <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">palms</ENAMEX>, and soft green cryptomeria japonica.
        Over the treetops you catch an occasional glimpse of the skyscrapers of
        modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>. Also on the grounds are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Imperial</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collections</ENAMEX>, an exhibition <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> for art treasures donated to the public
        by the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>; and the ‚ÄúHundred<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-Man</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guardhouse</ENAMEX>,‚Äù where
        the approach to the inner sanctum of the fortress was defended by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
        shifts of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> samurai <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX> each.
        A walk clockwise around the palace grounds will bring you
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to the picturesque <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nijubashi Bridge</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Seimon Gate</ENAMEX>, where
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> is allowed to enter the palace grounds. You then pass the
        most prominent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs modern government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, the National
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diet</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚Äôs parliament</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. A complete circuit
        would also include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Theater</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Museum of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Art</ENAMEX>. With a short detour, you can also take in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yasukuni Jinja</ENAMEX>.
        Founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1869</TIMEX>, this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúShrine of Peace for the Nation</ENAMEX>,‚Äù
        dedicated to the souls of those who have died for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> in battle.
        Besides the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> of worship, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine complex</ENAMEX>
        includes a noh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater stage</ENAMEX>, a sumo wrestling ring, several teahouses,
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yushukan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> of war memorabilia.
        Ginza
        Tokyo‚Äôs best-known district is named after a silver mint
        originally located here. Once the epitome of chic, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ginza</ENAMEX> has lost many
        of its smartest young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> to the fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX> of districts
        like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aoyama</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omote-sando</ENAMEX>, but the area is still fascinating.
        The windows of such department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wako</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitsukoshi</ENAMEX> are works of art. Inside, there‚Äôs more art: all the major
        department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> project themselves as bastions of culture,
        maintaining their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> and mounting frequent world-class
        exhibitions of prints, painting, pottery, and sculpture. Downstairs you
        can find still more <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúart‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇto</ENAMEX> Western eyes at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">least‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇin the
        astonishing basement gourmet food displays. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> is also a
        good place for cheaper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX> than you‚Äôll find in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>-level
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX>. )
        Running <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly north‚</NUMEX>Äìsouth through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ginza</ENAMEX> from the corner
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hibiya Park</ENAMEX> all the way to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokyo Bay</ENAMEX> is the broad avenue called
        Harumi-dori. Taking a stroll down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX> is such a national
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> that there‚Äôs even a colloquial expression for it: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gin</ENAMEX>-bura.
        Just south of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ginza</ENAMEX> itself, as you walk toward the bay, you see on your
        left the red lanterns and long banners of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kabuki-za</ENAMEX>, home base for
        that most thrilling and colorful form of traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> drama.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> kabuki theater was built in on this site in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1889</TIMEX>. Designed to
        invoke the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> architecture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> period, the theater was
        destroyed in an air raid in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> and rebuilt in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>.
        Still farther south is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tsukiji Central Wholesale</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Market‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe largest fish</ENAMEX> market in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Some 1,600</NUMEX> wholesale dealers
        do business here, supplying <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> consumed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. Get here very early (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5am</ENAMEX> is ideal) to see the tuna auctions
        and enjoy the orchestrated pandemonium of the market at its finest.
        From here, you could walk to the lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hama Rikyu Detached Palace</ENAMEX>
        Garden. Originally a Tokugawa family estate, the garden became a public
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">park</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>. The path to the left as you enter leads to the ferry
        landing, where the ‚Äúriver buses‚Äù depart for their journeys up the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sumida River</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asakusa</ENAMEX>.
        Asakusa
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asakusa</ENAMEX> is the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shitamachi</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the quarter</TIMEX>
        best-beloved of that fractious, gossipy, prodigal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> called the
        Edokko, who trace their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúdowntown‚Äù</ENAMEX> roots back at least three
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>. Edokko are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX> for sentimentality and for ninjo: the
        web of small favors and kindnesses that bind them together. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sneeze</ENAMEX> in
        the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">middle of the night</TIMEX> and your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edokko</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> will demand the next
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> that you take better care of yourself; stay home with a fever
        and she will be over by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> with a bowl of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Edokko</ENAMEX> craftsman
        would rather lose a commission than take any guff from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> who
        doesn‚Äôt know good work when he sees it. Edokko quarrel in a language
        all their own, an earthy local dialect as profane and expressive as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklynese</ENAMEX>. Ignore the proprieties‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇor offend the pride of an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Edokko‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> he will let you know about it, in no uncertain terms;
        respect his sense of values and you make a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> for life.
        The heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asakusa</ENAMEX>, in turn, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sensoji</ENAMEX> (also known as
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asakusa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kannon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>). According to legend, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple houses</ENAMEX> a
        small statue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> of mercy, found in the Sumida
        River by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 628‚ÄÇ‚</TIMEX>Äî‚ÄÇbut in fact not even the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> have ever seen it. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edo</ENAMEX> became the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of the
        Tokugawa shogunate, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asakusa</ENAMEX> began to flourish as an entertainment
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early-19th century</TIMEX> even the kabuki <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> were
        located here. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meiji Restoration</ENAMEX> and the opening of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to exotic
        new Western-style amusements further enhanced <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Asakusa‚</ENAMEX>Äôs reputation as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fun City</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to call itself a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúbar‚Äù</ENAMEX> opened in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asakusa</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1880</TIMEX> (and is still doing business); the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> movie theater
        opened here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903</TIMEX>. Before long, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> around the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temple</ENAMEX> were filled with music <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>, burlesque <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>, cabarets,
        gambling dens, and watering holes of every description.
        Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> was firebombed to ashes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>,
        but by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the area had raised enough money to rebuild
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sensoji</ENAMEX> and all of the important <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> around it. So what if the
        restorations were in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concrete</ENAMEX>? The original is still there in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spirit‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> should neglect it.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sensoji Temple</ENAMEX> and Surroundings
        Start your exploration from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asakusa Station</ENAMEX>, on the Ginza
        subway line (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokyo‚Äôs</ENAMEX> first subway). A few steps from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exit</ENAMEX> is
        Kaminarimon (‚ÄúThunder God <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gate‚Äù</ENAMEX>), the main entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, hung
        with a pair of enormous red paper lanterns. From here, the long, narrow
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arcade</ENAMEX> called Nakamise-dori is lined with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toasted rice</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crackers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX> in gourd-shaped wooden bottles, dolls, toys, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>,
        children‚Äôs kimono, and ornaments and souvenirs of all sorts. Some of
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> have been operated by the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
        The arcade ends at a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story gate called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hozomon</ENAMEX>. To
        the left is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX>-Story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pagoda</ENAMEX>, and across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> is the main
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hall of Sensoji</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> should be sure to stop at the huge bronze
        incense burner in front of the hall, to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúbathe‚Äù in the smoke‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇan
        observance believed to bestow a year‚Äôs worth of good health.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> to the right of the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> is the Asakusa
        Jinja, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shinto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> dedicated to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanja‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇof Sensoji</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX> and Shinto get along quite peacefully in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, sharing ground and even deities. ) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanja Matsuri</ENAMEX>, held here
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third weekend</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, is the biggest, most exuberant
        festival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>.
        Ueno
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX> of the city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ueno</ENAMEX> was chosen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1625</TIMEX> by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tokugawa Shogun Hidetaka</ENAMEX> as the site of a vast temple complex. Called
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kan‚Äôeiji</ENAMEX>, it was established on the area‚Äôs one prominent hill to
        protect the capital from evil spirits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kan‚Äôeiji</ENAMEX> was a seat of great
        power until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX>, when it became the battleground in the shogunate‚Äôs
        last stand against the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> and most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> were
        destroyed. Subsequently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ueno</ENAMEX> was turned into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokyo‚Äôs</ENAMEX> first public
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">park</ENAMEX>, endowed with all the preferred Western improvements: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>,
        concert <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>, a library, a university of fine arts, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX>. Ueno
        should be a stop on any visitor‚<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Äôs itinerary‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇespecially</ENAMEX> if you happen
        to be here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-April</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cherry blossoms</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> are
        glorious.
        No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> here should miss the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokyo National Museum</ENAMEX>, a
        complex of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> art and archaeology
        dating back to the prehistoric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jomon</ENAMEX> and Yayoi periods. Outstanding
        among the exhibits are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> sculpture of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX>- and
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heian</ENAMEX> era, illustrated narrative scrolls from the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kamakura</ENAMEX> period, paintings by the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muromachi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>
        Sesshu, and woodblock prints by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edo</ENAMEX>-period masters <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Utamaro</ENAMEX>,
        Hiroshige, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hokusai</ENAMEX>.
        Nor should you neglect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Museum of Western Art</ENAMEX>,
        on the east side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ueno Park</ENAMEX>: an outstanding collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
        Impressionist paintings, prints, and drawings, the gift of a wealthy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kojiro Matsukata</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> itself was designed by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Corbusier</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rodin</ENAMEX> sculptures in the courtyard‚<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe Gate of Hell</ENAMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thinker</ENAMEX>, and the magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Burghers of Calais‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇare</ENAMEX> authentic
        castings from the original <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">molds</ENAMEX>.
        Of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Edo-</ENAMEX>era <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that have survived or been
        restored, the most important are the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kan‚Äôeiji</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toshogu Shrine</ENAMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Tokugawa Shogun Ieyasu‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa</ENAMEX> lesser version
        of the great sanctum at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikko</ENAMEX>, in the mountains of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nagano Prefecture</ENAMEX>
        (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX>). Also of interest is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kiyomizu Kannon Hall</ENAMEX>, modeled
        after the larger and more famous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kiyomizu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX>; registered
        as a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Treasure</ENAMEX>, this is one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that survived
        the battle of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX> intact.
        At the south end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> is the statue of Saigo
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Takamori</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> that overthrew the shogunate in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saigo</ENAMEX> is a problematic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> history: in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1871</TIMEX> he was
        killed in an unsuccessful rebellion against the very government he
        helped to found. )
        From here, it‚Äôs a short walk west to the grounds of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shinobazu Pond</ENAMEX>. Just inside the entrance, on the right, is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shitamachi Customs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manners Museum</ENAMEX>. Budget some time here: it will
        give you a wonderfully concrete sense of the lifestyle that defined
        this part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for well over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">300 years</TIMEX>. The displays include a
        full-scale reproduction of a nagaya (one of the long, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">single</NUMEX>-story row
        houses typical of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Edo</ENAMEX> period). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> are welcome to take their
        shoes off and walk through the tatami-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mat rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harajuku</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yoyogi Park</ENAMEX>
        The venerable imperial traditions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and the frenetic
        celebration of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> culture are arrayed side by side in this
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. From <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Harajuku Station</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan Railways</ENAMEX>
        Yamanote loop line, it‚Äôs but a few steps to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meiji Jingu</ENAMEX>, the shrine
        dedicated to the spirits of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meiji</ENAMEX> (who died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>) and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress Shoken</ENAMEX>. The entrance is marked by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> huge torii gates,
        their pillars made from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1,700-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cypress trees</ENAMEX>.
        From here, broad gravel paths lead to the honden (the
        sanctum of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX>), destroyed in the air raids of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX> and restored
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial Treasure House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meiji</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>
        presided over the emergence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> as a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation state</ENAMEX>, and his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shrine</ENAMEX> is surely the most solemn, decorous place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>. During the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">festival</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31 October</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 November</TIMEX>) and on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Year‚Äôs Day</ENAMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will come to offer prayers and pay their
        respects. Spring and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> make better visits, when you can admire the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">irises</ENAMEX> and flowering <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">shrubs</ENAMEX> of the inner gardens.
        Adjacent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yoyogi Park</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> is
        remarkable chiefly for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Yoyogi Sports Center</ENAMEX>, comprising
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tange Kenzo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> itself was
        once a parade ground for the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>
        it was taken over by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Occupation</ENAMEX> for military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">housing</ENAMEX> and nicknamed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">‚ÄúWashington Heights</ENAMEX>,‚Äù then redeveloped as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympic Village</ENAMEX> site for
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tokyo Olympic Games</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, thanks to the broad avenues
        and new subway s tops built for the games, this had become one of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liveliest</ENAMEX>, trendiest, and demographically youngest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarters</TIMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
        On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> and holidays, part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX> through the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">park</ENAMEX> is closed to traffic. Rock bands that are not quite yet on a
        professional footing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> in their equipment and play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>, just
        for practice. The bands are loud‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthey have to be to compete with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> imitators in black leather jackets and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sideburns</ENAMEX> who
        also lay claim to some of this great free space, dancing in circles to
        the oldies on enormous boomboxes. Street <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, body paint, in-your-face
        fashion, photo ops: on a warm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yoyogi Park</ENAMEX> is more fun
        than any place in town.
        The opposite (west) end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> borders on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shibuya</ENAMEX>,
        where you can visit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHK Broadcasting Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        public television <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">network‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa</ENAMEX> must for anyone wishing to see how
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">samurai</ENAMEX> epics are made. Your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Information Center</ENAMEX>
        will have information on the ‚ÄúStudio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park‚Äù</ENAMEX> guided tour of the NHK
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soundstages</ENAMEX>.
        Shinjuku
        In the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Edo</ENAMEX> period <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shinjuku</ENAMEX> was where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the major roads
        from the west came together. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1900s</TIMEX> the area had become a
        sort of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">bohemian quarter</TIMEX>, beloved of the city‚Äôs cliques of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> it emerged as one of
        Tokyo‚Äôs major transportation hubs, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated three million</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pass through <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shinjuku Station</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> itself
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">divides Shinjuku</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> distinctly different areas, east and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">west</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Shinjuku</ENAMEX> rejoices in a special gift of nature. Its
        relatively stable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX> can support earthquake-safe
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skyscrapers‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇforemost</ENAMEX> among them is the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Government</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>, more familiarly known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokyo City Hall</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Hall</ENAMEX> complex
        was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tange Kenzo‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">magnum opus</ENAMEX>, arguably the last great work
        of his career. It was a staggeringly expensive project, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>
        have had an ongoing love-hate relationship with its postmodern
        monumental design since it was completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> consists
        of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX>-story main office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX>-story annex, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan</ENAMEX>
        Assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, and a huge central <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>. The main building
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">soars 243 m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">797 ft</ENAMEX>), splitting on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">33rd</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>.
        Weather permitting, the observation decks on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">45th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> of both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">towers</ENAMEX> offer views all the way to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Fuji</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Shinjuku</ENAMEX> is really <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX>: a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daytime quarter</TIMEX> of
        department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, vertical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>, and discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, and a nighttime
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bars</ENAMEX> (straight and gay), cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, strip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX>,
        game <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parlors</ENAMEX>, jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>-by<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-the-hour</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, raves, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">honky-tonks‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇmost of the latter in a seedy, neon-lit neighborhood
        called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kabuki-cho</ENAMEX>. The neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">isn‚</ENAMEX>Äôt really dangerous, but it‚Äôs
        all too easy for the unwary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> to wander into a rip-off; if you
        plan to explore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kabuki-cho</ENAMEX>, do so with a knowledgeable local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX>.
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">longish</ENAMEX> walk along <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shinjuku</ENAMEX>-dori from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> will
        bring you to the north end of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shinjuku Gyoen National Garden</ENAMEX>.
        Originally a feudal estate, this collection of gardens (in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> styles) became part of the imperial household after
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meiji Restoration</ENAMEX> and, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>, a public park‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe ultimate oasis
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this quarter</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shinjuku Gyoen</ENAMEX> is famous for its botanical
        greenhouse, for its flowering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cherry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, and for its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">chrysanthemum</ENAMEX> exhibition during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first two weeks of October</TIMEX>.
        Shinagawa
        Not otherwise rich in tourist attractions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shinagawa</ENAMEX> has
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gem</ENAMEX> that should not be missed: Sengakuji‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> that evokes
        what is surely the most popular story in all of premodern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
        history.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1701</TIMEX> a young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">provincial baron</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asano Takumi</ENAMEX> no
        Kami, morally insulted by a court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kira</ENAMEX>, attacked and
        wounded his tormentor. Asano was ordered to commit suicide for his
        offense; however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kira</ENAMEX> went free. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asano‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan steward</ENAMEX>, Oishi
        Kuranosuke, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of his loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retainers</ENAMEX> vowed revenge. On
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1702</TIMEX>, despite many obstacles, they attacked
        Kira‚Äôs heavily guarded villa on the east side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumida River</ENAMEX>, cut
        off his head, and brought it in triumph to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asano‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sengakuji</ENAMEX>,
        the family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>. This was a dilemma for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. On
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hand, their revenge was perfectly in accord with the samurai code
        of honor; on the other, they had murdered a high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>. Eventually,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oishi</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> were also ordered to commit suicide; this they did,
        and they were buried at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sengakuji</ENAMEX> with their lord. Celebrated in kabuki
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theater</ENAMEX>, film, and television, the story has had an abiding hold on the
        imagination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> come annually
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sengakuji</ENAMEX> to lay incense on the tombstones and walk through the
        small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of the Loyal Retainers</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>,
        personal effects, and other memorabilia are preserved.
        Kanto
        The once-marshy plain of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kanto</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokyo‚</ENAMEX>Äôs hinterland, the
        region where the feudal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warlords</ENAMEX> set up their military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">administrative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. Their tough-minded pragmatism survives
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> not only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> but also in the dynamic industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">zone</ENAMEX> that
        has burgeoned around it in such <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kawasaki</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yokohama</ENAMEX>. But
        monuments at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamakura</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikko</ENAMEX> still bear testimony to the region‚Äôs
        history. And reigning supreme over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kanto</ENAMEX> is a sublime spiritual comment
        on the vanity of all such human endeavors: sacred <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Fuji</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> easy-to-manage excursions from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> would make
        memorable additions to your stay. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of them‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇto <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yokohama</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Kamakura‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇare daytrips</ENAMEX>. Visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikko</ENAMEX> and to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Fuji</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hakone</ENAMEX> will be
        more enjoyable as overnighters.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikko</ENAMEX>
        ‚Äú Think nothing splendid,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says an old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">proverb</ENAMEX>,
        ‚Äúuntil you‚Äôve seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikko</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù In the mountains of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tochigi Prefecture</ENAMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 150 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">93 miles</NUMEX>) north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikko</ENAMEX> is the final
        resting place of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ieyasu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> shogunate, who died in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1616</TIMEX>. Upon his death he was declared a god by the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and
        subsequently known as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tosho Daigongen (‚ÄúThe Great Incarnation</ENAMEX> Who
        Illuminates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East‚Äù</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The following year</TIMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">remains</ENAMEX> were taken in a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> procession to be enshrined here, on the site of a religious
        center founded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some eight centuries</TIMEX> before. In life, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ieyasu</ENAMEX> had made
        himself the absolute monarch of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. His personal fief alone was
        worth enough to feed and support some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Toshogu, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum complex</ENAMEX> that he commanded for himself in his apotheosis, is
        extraordinary.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikko</ENAMEX> is best reached from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> (by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Railways Shinkansen</ENAMEX> line from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ueno</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, with a transfer
        at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Utsunomiya</ENAMEX>, or by the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tobu Line ‚ÄúLimited Express‚</ENAMEX>Äù from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asakusa</ENAMEX>). The journey takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about two hours</TIMEX>. The little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikko</ENAMEX>
        is essentially <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one long</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">railway station</ENAMEX> to the Toshogu
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shrine</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toshogu Shrine Complex</ENAMEX>
        A short bus ride from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station plaza</ENAMEX> brings you to the
        red-lacquer <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shinkyo (‚ÄúSacred Bridge‚Äù</ENAMEX>), a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">28-m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX>-ft) span over the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daiya River</ENAMEX>, where your exploration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toshogu</ENAMEX> begins. The bridge marks
        the spot where the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shodo</ENAMEX> is said to have crossed the
        river in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 766</TIMEX> on the backs of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> huge serpents, to found the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temple</ENAMEX> that would later become <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rinnoji</ENAMEX>. An entrance to the shrine
        complex is just across the road, opposite the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> and up a flight of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stone</ENAMEX> steps that brings you first to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shodo‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rinnoji</ENAMEX> belongs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tendai</ENAMEX> sect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX>. The main
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hall</ENAMEX>, called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanbutsudo</ENAMEX>, with its almost erotic color scheme of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black</ENAMEX> and green and vermilion, dates to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1648</TIMEX> and is the largest single
        building at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toshogu</ENAMEX>. Inside are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> huge gold-lacquered statues,
        representing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different manifestations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>. In the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amida Nyorai</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> who leads <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX>; on
        the right is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Senju (‚ÄúThousand-Armed‚Äù</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kannon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> of mercy; on
        the left is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bato-Kannon</ENAMEX>, depicted with a horse‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on its forehead,
        regarded as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protector</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX> of the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> is the
        Goho-tendo, a subtemple where worshippers inscribe their prayers for
        health and prosperity on slats of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> that are later burned to carry
        the prayers to heaven. To the south is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Abbot‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇby
        tradition an imperial prince‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwith a particularly fine garden in the
        style of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Edo</ENAMEX> period.
        Leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinnoji</ENAMEX> from the west side, you come to the broad
        Omote-sando <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX> that leads uphill to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> itself. Note the
        monument to the daimyo <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matsudaira Masatane, Ieyasu‚</ENAMEX>Äôs trusted retainer.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matsudaira</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some 20 years</TIMEX> planting the majestic cryptomeria cedars
        on the grounds of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> and along the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">64-km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40-mile</NUMEX>) avenue of
        approach. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX> has been destroyed; a few sections
        of it survive on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, where many of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,000</NUMEX> trees
        still standing are maintained by corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX>.
        At the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omote-sando</ENAMEX>, on the left, is the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pagoda</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX>, decorated with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> signs of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">zodiac</ENAMEX> and the hollyhock crest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. From here,
        a flight of stone steps leads to the first gate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toshogu</ENAMEX>: the
        Omotemon, guarded by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fierce red-painted Deva <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX>. In the first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courtyard</ENAMEX> is the stable, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> the shrine‚Äôs sacred white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>;
        the carved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> above the door is the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of three
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monkeys‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇ‚ÄúHear</ENAMEX> no evil, see no evil, speak no evil! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù‚ÄÇ ‚Äî‚ÄÇthat</ENAMEX> has
        become a symbol of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikko</ENAMEX>, the logo on virtually every souvenir. At the
        far end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyozo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sutra Library</ENAMEX>), which houses
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 7,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> scriptures in a huge revolving bookcase.
        As you approach a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> set of stone steps, you see on the
        right a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">belfry</ENAMEX> and a tall bronze candelabrum; on the left is a drum
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tower</ENAMEX> and a bronze revolving lantern. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bronzes</ENAMEX> were presented in
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-17th century</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, in gratitude for the
        special exemption that gave them exclusive trading privileges with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> during the period of national seclusion. Off to the left is the
        Yakushi-do, a temple honoring the manifestation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> as healer
        of illnesses.
        At the top of the steps is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yomeimon</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúGate of Sunlight‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> triumphal masterpiece of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toshogu</ENAMEX>, rightly
        declared a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Treasure</ENAMEX>. This is the ultimate expression of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opulent Momoyama</ENAMEX> style inspired by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX> sculpture and
        architecture. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX>-white and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> ft) high, its columns, beams,
        and cornices are carved with a menagerie of dragons, phoenixes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX> in a field of clouds, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">peonies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sages</ENAMEX>, and angels,
        all gilded and painted in red, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, blue, and green. To the right and
        left of the gate there are paneled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>, also carved and painted
        with a motifs from nature: pine and plum <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> of the field, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">waterfowl</ENAMEX>.
        Inside the gate to the left is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mikoshi-gura</ENAMEX>, a
        storeroom for the portable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX> that grace the semi-annual Toshogu
        Festival processions (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 May</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 October</TIMEX>). To the right is the
        Kaguraden, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> where ceremonial dances are performed to honor the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gods‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> where, for a modest fee, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> can have Shinto wedding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ceremonies</ENAMEX> performed, complete with flutes and drums and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> maidens
        to attend them.
        Opposite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yomeimon</ENAMEX>, across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>, is the Karamon
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">(‚ÄúChinese Gate‚Äù</ENAMEX>), the official entrance to the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX>. This
        structure, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yomeimon</ENAMEX>, is also a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Treasure</ENAMEX> and just as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ornately</ENAMEX> carved and painted. The walls on both sides of this gate
        enclose the honden (main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX>.
        The entrance is to the right. Here you remove your shoes
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lockers</ENAMEX> are provided) to visit the outer part of the hall, called the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">haiden</ENAMEX> (oratory). You may not proceed further than this, for at the far
        end of the oratory are the naijin (inner <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>) and nai-naijin
        (innermost chamber), where the spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ieyasu</ENAMEX> is enshrined. With him
        are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other worthy companions: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyotomi Hideyoshi, Ieyasu‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>,
        and the great <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minamoto no Yoritomo</ENAMEX>, who founded
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kamakura</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shogunate‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ieyasu</ENAMEX> claimed as an ancestor.
        The tour next takes you to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toshogu</ENAMEX> icon: the famous
        Gate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleeping Cat</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> itself, on a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> above the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entrance</ENAMEX>, is said to have been sculpted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hidari Jingoro</ENAMEX>, a legendary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master carver</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> period. From here a flight of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">207</NUMEX> stone
        steps takes you up through a wonderful forest of cedars to Ieyasu
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tokugawa‚Äôs</ENAMEX> tomb. The climb is worth making, if only for the view, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, and a cool, rushing stream. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> itself, a miniature bronze
        pagoda that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> the great shogun‚Äôs ashes, is nothing special.
        A short walk west from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toshogu</ENAMEX> itself is surely the oldest
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> on this holy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ground</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Futarasan Jinja</ENAMEX> is a Shinto
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shrine</ENAMEX> founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 8th century</TIMEX> to honor the deity
        Okuni-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nushi</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no</NUMEX>-Mikoto (‚ÄúGod of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ricefields‚Äù</ENAMEX>), his consort, and their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. In one corner of the enclosure is a bronze lantern <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">some 2.3 m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ft</ENAMEX>) high; the deep nicks in the bronze were made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> on duty at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX>, who believed that the lantern transformed itself into a
        goblin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. Such was the incredible cutting power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sword‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇembellished</ENAMEX> perhaps a bit by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> superstition.
        Iemitsu, who was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ieyasu‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> Tokugawa
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shogun</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1603‚Äì1651</ENAMEX>), undertook the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toshogu</ENAMEX>. He has his own
        resting place here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daiyu</ENAMEX>-in, to the west of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Futarasan</ENAMEX>. Smaller in
        scale, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daiyu</ENAMEX>-in is in fact the more impressive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum</ENAMEX>, set on a
        forested hillside and approached by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> flights of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone stairs</ENAMEX> and
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> decorative gates. The most impressive of these, at the top of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stairs</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Yashamon (‚ÄúShe-Demon Gate‚Äù</ENAMEX>), so named for the figures in
        its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> alcoves. The sanctum of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX>, designated a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Treasure</ENAMEX>, has a gilded and lacquered altar <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">some 3 m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">nearly 10 ft</NUMEX>)
        high, where a seated wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iemitsu</ENAMEX> looks down upon his
        mighty works.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX> Chuzenji
        The waterfalls and forested hills of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikko National</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> area are a welcome respite to the monumentality of Tokugawa
        architecture. Even if you are here only on a daytrip, you should take
        the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6.2-mile</NUMEX>) bus ride up the spectacular winding Irohazaka
        Highway to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chuzenji</ENAMEX>. Better yet, take a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> and tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> to stop
        at Akechi-daira, the halfway point. The view of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Nantai</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,484 m</NUMEX>;
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8,148 ft</NUMEX>) and the valley below is magnificent.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Chuzenji</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,270</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4,166 ft</NUMEX>) above sea level, was
        made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eons ago</TIMEX> when a now-dormant volcano erupted and blocked the river
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courses</ENAMEX>, creating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cataracts</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">96-m</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315-ft</ENAMEX>) Kegon-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no</NUMEX>-taki at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">south</ENAMEX> end is the country‚Äôs most famous waterfall. An elevator takes
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sightseers</ENAMEX> to an observation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> in the gorge below. The falls are
        especially impressive after a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> rain, when the sunshine produces a
        single or even double rainbow in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> the falls
        form a spectacular cascade of icicles. At the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gorge‚Äôs</NUMEX> north end,
        Ryuzu-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no</NUMEX>-taki <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">(‚ÄúDragon‚Äôs Head Falls‚Äù</ENAMEX>) is broader but not as high; it
        has the additional merit of a teahouse, where you can sit and watch the
        water tumble into the lake.
        Famous for its <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rainbow trout</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chuzenji</ENAMEX> is too cold for
        swimming most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> throng to this area for its
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spectacular spring</TIMEX> and fall scenery and for its numerous hot springs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resorts</ENAMEX>. The most impressive historical monument on the eastern shore
        of the lake is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuzenji</ENAMEX>, a subtemple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toshogu‚Äôs Rinnoji</ENAMEX>. The temple
        enshrines a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5-m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>-ft) standing figure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kannon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Goddess</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mercy</ENAMEX>, said to have been carved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> from the
        trunk of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Judas tree</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Yokohama</ENAMEX>
        Situated <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12.5 miles</NUMEX>) southwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yokohama</ENAMEX>
        was an unimportant little fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1854</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs long
        centuries of self-imposed isolation came to an end. Foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> were at last able to enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. But
        the unrest they inspired prompted the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to move them
        all here, to a guarded compound on the village <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flats‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇostensibly</ENAMEX> to
        guarantee their safety, but more importantly to contain the
        contamination of their uncouth ways and ideas.
        The ploy worked well enough until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meiji Restoration</ENAMEX>,
        when those Western ideas were needed to modernize the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1869</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> okohama became an international <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX>, and the burgeoning
        international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> quickly spread beyond its confinement to the
        high ground still known <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bluff</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1872</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Japan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">railway</ENAMEX> went into service between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yokohama</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, and the city
        began to flourish.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice</NUMEX> shared the same destructive fate.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">great Kanto earthquake of 1923</ENAMEX> destroyed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 60,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yokohama</ENAMEX> and took over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> lives. The next <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reconstruction</ENAMEX> and growth were wiped out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1945</TIMEX>, when
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> leveled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX> was hastily
        restored during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean War</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is one of the busiest and most
        important trading <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> in the world.
        With a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three million</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yokohama</ENAMEX> no longer
        sits in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo‚</ENAMEX>Äôs shadow. In many respects, in fact, it is the more
        cosmopolitan <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, preferred by many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of the greater
        metropolitan area as a place to live and work. If you are on a short
        visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, your excursion time might be better spent elsewhere.
        But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yokohama‚</ENAMEX>Äôs great waterfront, port redevelopment project, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> should still keep it high on your list.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan Railways Keihin-Tohoku</ENAMEX> line takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 40</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sakuragi-cho Station</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yokohama</ENAMEX>; the faster
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shinkansen</ENAMEX> leaves you off at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shin</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yokohama</ENAMEX>, on the outskirts of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sakuragi</ENAMEX>-cho it‚Äôs a short walk to the waterfront (which is
        still referred to by its old name, the Bund) and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pier</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yamashita Park</ENAMEX>. Here you can take a tour of the harbor on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sightseeing</ENAMEX> launches moored near the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hikawa-</ENAMEX>maru, now retired from
        service. It carried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yokohama</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> for some
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX>; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, it has a pleasant beer garden on the upper
        deck.
        At the entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pier</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>-story Silk
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Center Building</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silk Museum</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>, with its
        collection of kimono and exhibits of the silk-making process, evokes
        the period when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yokohama</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hub</ENAMEX> of that industry. On the first
        floor are the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yokohama International Tourist</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>.
        For a bird‚Äôs-eye view of the harbor, take the elevator to
        the observation deck of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">106-m</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">348-ft</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Tower</ENAMEX>. The beacon
        atop the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> gives it a claim of being the tallest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lighthouse</ENAMEX> in the
        world; it also has an interesting oceanographic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Minato Mirai 21</ENAMEX> project, launched in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>, was
        intended to turn a huge tract of neglected waterfront north and east of
        Sakuragi-cho into a model ‚Äúcity of the future,‚Äù integrating business,
        exhibition, and leisure <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. The centerpiece of the project is
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Landmark Tower</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yokohama‚</ENAMEX>Äôs tallest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>; its
        observation deck affords a spectacular view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX>
        Bridge, especially at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
        Nearby is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yokohama Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, designed by Tange
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenzo</ENAMEX> and housing works by both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, including
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picasso</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braque, Kandinsky, Kishida Ryusei</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yokoyama Taikan</ENAMEX>. On the
        waterfront itself is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nippon-maru Memorial Park</ENAMEX>, where pride of place
        goes to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-masted sailing ship popularly called the ‚ÄúSwan of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù Now a training <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX>, it is open to visitors on guided
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tours</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yokohama‚Äôs Chinatown</ENAMEX>, a few minutes‚Äô walk from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Railways‚Äô Kannai Station</ENAMEX> in the center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, is the largest in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. Its narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> are crowded with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foodstuffs</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spices</ENAMEX>, herbal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX>, cookware‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇin fact, anything that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
        exports. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, needless to say, are wonderful.
        Fashionable, upbeat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yokohama</ENAMEX> is centered in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> areas. One
        is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Basha-michi (‚ÄúHorse-Carriage Street‚Äù</ENAMEX>) running from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kannai Station</ENAMEX> to
        the waterfront. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> acquired its name in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>, when
        it was laid out for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> of the city‚Äôs Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>; a
        more recent redesign evokes that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> with red brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalks</ENAMEX> and
        imitation gas lamps‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbut the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX> along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> are
        up<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-to-the-minute</TIMEX>. The other area extends from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ishikawa-cho Station</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motomachi</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">International Cemetery</ENAMEX>. Motomachi was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> area
        developed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Meiji</ENAMEX> period to serve Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX>, and it has
        kept pace with the movements of fashion ever since.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">International Cemetery</ENAMEX>, established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1854</TIMEX>, is the
        last resting place of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 4,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> different
        nationalities who lived and died in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yokohama</ENAMEX>. Behind it is the Yamate
        Shiryokan, a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> of materials about the city‚Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. Just up the hill at this end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motomachi</ENAMEX> is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Harbor View Park</ENAMEX>, where the views at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">night‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwhen Yamashita Park</ENAMEX> and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX> are floodlit‚<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇare</ENAMEX> especially fine.
        The last must-see in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yokohama</ENAMEX> is Sankei-en, originally the
        estate of wealthy silk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX> and art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">connoisseur</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hara Tomitaro</ENAMEX>, who
        opened his garden to the public in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1906</TIMEX>. At great expense he
        transferred here a number of important <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that once
        belonged to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rinshunkaku villa</ENAMEX> and
        the charming <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Choshukaku</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX>, as well as a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> from
        Kyoto‚Äôs famed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daitokuji</ENAMEX>. Sankei-en is a special delight from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>
        though early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, when the plum and cherry <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> blossom.
        Kamakura
        Kamakura, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less than an hour</NUMEX> south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, was
        the seat of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan‚Äôs</ENAMEX> first military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamakura</ENAMEX> shogunate
        was founded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late in the 12th century</TIMEX> after a long and bloody rivalry
        between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">noble</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> over control of the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">victorious Minamoto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX> chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kamakura</ENAMEX> as its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> because
        this fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">village‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇgirded</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> by steep wooded
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">hills‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwas</ENAMEX> a natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fortress</ENAMEX>. Here they created what most of us
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">envision as the ‚ÄúWay</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samurai‚Äù</ENAMEX>: the values, codes, religion, and
        culture of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX> caste that would rule <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">700 years</TIMEX>.
        Much of that culture was inspired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rinzai</ENAMEX> sect of Zen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX> and its sense of discipline and self-control, its austere
        philosophy of art and life. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shogunate</ENAMEX> founded great numbers of Zen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temples</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kamakura</ENAMEX>. Many are still standing, and some are registered
        as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Treasures</ENAMEX>. From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan Railways</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kita</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX>)
        Kamakura, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Yokosuka</ENAMEX> line, you can easily
        reach <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of these temples.
        Engakuji, founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1282</TIMEX>, became the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> most important
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of monasteries called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gozan (‚ÄúFive Mountains‚Äù</ENAMEX>), a
        hierarchy established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 14th century</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zen</ENAMEX> temples under the
        official patronage of the shogunate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engakuji</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamakura‚</ENAMEX>Äôs largest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>; often wracked by fire and earthquake, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> of the
        original <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> have survived. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of these are registered as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Treasures</ENAMEX>: the shariden (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> of holy relics), built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1282</TIMEX>,
        and the huge <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">belfry</ENAMEX> on the hill above. The bell, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">some 2.5 m</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8 ft</ENAMEX>)
        tall, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1301</TIMEX>. The principle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> open to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engakuji</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">butsunichi-an ceremonial hall</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> can take
        part in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> ceremony.
        Nearby is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tokeiji</ENAMEX>, familiarly known as the ‚ÄúDivorce
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX>,‚Äù which was unique as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caste</ENAMEX> seeking an escape from unhappy marriages. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> managed
        to make her way here and stay for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX>, she could
        obtain a decree of divorce from the shogunate and go free. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homotsukan</ENAMEX> (treasure <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokeiji</ENAMEX> has a collection of
        Kamakura-period paintings, sculpture, and calligraphy, some of which
        are registered as <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Important Cultural Objects</ENAMEX>. Also on the grounds is
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matsugaoka Bunko</ENAMEX>, a research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> established in memory of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">D.T.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suzuki</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1870‚Äì1966</ENAMEX>), who pioneered the study of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zen Buddhism</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South of Tokeiji</ENAMEX>, on the way to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamakura‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Meigetsu</ENAMEX>-in and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jochiji, Zen</ENAMEX> temples with especially fine gardens.
        Still farther south is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenchoji</ENAMEX>, founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1249</TIMEX>, the foremost of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">‚ÄúFive Mountains</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù It was modeled on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>
        monasteries of the time and built for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk</ENAMEX> who was said to
        have interceded with the dreaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kublai Khan</ENAMEX> to stop the Mongol
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">invasion of Japan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenchoji</ENAMEX> is still an active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX>; like many of
        the temples in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kamakura</ENAMEX>, it offers <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> the opportunity to take
        part in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zen</ENAMEX> meditation training sessions. Nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ennoji</ENAMEX> boasts a
        remarkable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of sculptures representing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enma</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord of Hell</ENAMEX>) and
        his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>.
        Sightseeing in Kamakura
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kamakura</ENAMEX> proper, don‚Äôt miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tsuru-ga-oka Hachimangu</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine complex</ENAMEX> built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoritomo no Minamoto</ENAMEX>, the first Kamakura
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shogun</ENAMEX>. It was dedicated to the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ojin</ENAMEX>, from whom
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yoritomo</ENAMEX> claimed descent. As part of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-September</TIMEX> festival at this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shrine</ENAMEX>, there is a spectacular tournament of archery on horseback
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">yabusame</NUMEX>), in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contestants</ENAMEX> dressed in the costume of
        Kamakura-period huntsmen must hit a series of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> small wooden
        targets as they come down a narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> at full gallop. The spacing
        between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> gives the rider just barely enough time to drop the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reins</ENAMEX>, notch and fire an arrow, and regain control of his mount.
        On the grounds of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>. The Kamakura
        Municipal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX> houses a collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> oil
        paintings, watercolors, wood block prints, and sculpture.The Kokuhokan
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Treasure Museum</ENAMEX>) has a fine collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> from
        various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamakura</ENAMEX> temples and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX>, including some excellent
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13th-century</TIMEX> paintings.
        A short walk east from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hachimangu</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Yoritomo‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇan exceedingly</ENAMEX> plain and modest affair compared with the way
        a later dynasty of shoguns chose to immortalize themselves at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikko</ENAMEX>. In
        many ways <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoritomo</ENAMEX> was a less-than-admirable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Japanese</ENAMEX>
        history, but you still might want to stop at this little moss-covered
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stone</ENAMEX> pagoda to pay your respects.
        If for nothing else, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoritomo</ENAMEX> earns our admiration for his
        determination to create a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúSeated Buddha‚Äù</ENAMEX> for his capital to rival the
        huge bronze figure made in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">749</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Todaiji</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nara</ENAMEX>. That idea
        bore <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1292</TIMEX> with the casting of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">120-ton</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Daibutsu</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">courtyard of Kotoku-in temple‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇafter Mr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Fuji</ENAMEX>, probably the most
        photographed icon of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. The massive seated figure, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11.4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> ft)
        high, sits in the classical pose of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amida Buddha (‚</ENAMEX>ÄúCompassionate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One‚Äù</ENAMEX>), his hands resting in his lap, the thumbs touching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">palms</ENAMEX> and
        the eyes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-closed in an expression of profound serenity. The statue
        is hollow, and you can climb a staircase inside to look out through a
        window between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddha‚</ENAMEX>Äôs shoulders.A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> was originally built to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> the figure, but this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> was destroyed in a tidal wave in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1495</TIMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the five centuries</TIMEX> since then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> has been dispensing
        his benevolence to visitors in the open air.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daibutsu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kotoku</ENAMEX>-in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hase</ENAMEX>, the district
        in the western part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamakura</ENAMEX>. The other major attraction here is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hasedera</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kannon Hall</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> is the largest wooden
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">devotional</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>: a statue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚ÄúEleven-Faced Goddess</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercy</ENAMEX>,‚Äù <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> ft) high, carved from a single tree trunk and
        covered in gold leaf. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crown</ENAMEX> symbolize her
        ability to search in all directions for those in need of compassion. No
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> knows for certain when the figure was carved; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> legend dates it
        to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 8th century</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Amida Hall of Hasedera</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> the image
        of a seated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amida Buddha</ENAMEX>, endowed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minamoto no Yoritomo</ENAMEX> when he was
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42‚</NUMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa particularly unlucky age according to popular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> belief.
        Yoritomo‚Äôs piety bought him a little more time to enjoy his success; he
        was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX> when he was thrown by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> and died of his injuries.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryukoji Temple</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Enoshima Island</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamakura</ENAMEX> history was not shaped by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Minamoto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX> alone.
        No account of this area would be complete without the story of Nichiren
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1222‚Äì1282</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk</ENAMEX> who founded the only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native Japanese</ENAMEX> sect of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX>. Nichiren‚Äôs defiance of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jodo (‚ÄúPure Land‚Äù</ENAMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX> eventually persuaded the shogunate to order him beheaded on a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hill</ENAMEX> to the south of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hase</ENAMEX>. However, legend says that, just as the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">executioner</ENAMEX> raised his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX>, a lightning bolt struck and broke it in
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. Before he could try again, a messenger arrived with an order
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commuting Nichiren‚</ENAMEX>Äôs sentence to exile on the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sadogashima</ENAMEX>.
        Later, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1337</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nichiren</ENAMEX> sect built the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ryukoji</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> on the same
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hill</ENAMEX>.
        On the nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sagami</ENAMEX> bayshore are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yuigahama</ENAMEX> and
        Shichirigahama, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the beaches closest to the metropolitan area. In
        the hot, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">humid summer months</TIMEX> it can feel as if the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yokohama</ENAMEX> is here, searching in vain for a vacant patch of
        sand. Equally popular is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enoshima</ENAMEX>, the little island just offshore,
        with a hill in the middle that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">affords‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇon clear days‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa</ENAMEX> fine view of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Fuji</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Izu Peninsula</ENAMEX>.
        Hakone
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hakone</ENAMEX> is a national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> area southeast of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fuji</ENAMEX>, extremely popular with weekend trippers from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>. Just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, this area makes a very pleasant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">daytrip</ENAMEX>. But to enjoy more of the countryside, you can stay overnight
        and continue down the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Izu Peninsula</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>.
        Even if you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan Railpass</ENAMEX>, we suggest that you
        invest in the all-inclusive ‚ÄúHakone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Pass‚Äù</ENAMEX> offered by the Odakyu
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Railway</ENAMEX>. This entitles you to a roundtrip train ticket from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shinjuku</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gora</ENAMEX>, connecting with the funicular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">railway</ENAMEX> up into the mountains to a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. You then swing across the volcanic Owakudani valley and down
        the other side for a boat cruise across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Ashi</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hakone</ENAMEX>-machi. From
        there, you can take a bus (still on the same pass) along the Sumiko
        River to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Odawara</ENAMEX>, and then back by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>.
        Among the many attractions of this excursion is the Hakone
        Open <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chokoku</ENAMEX> no mori, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúForest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sculptures</ENAMEX>) at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyanoshita</ENAMEX>. Established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> rejoices in a wonderfully
        designed and landscaped mountain setting. Here the works of such
        Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sculptors</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calder</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giacometti</ENAMEX> share the
        garden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> with those of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimizu Takashi, Takamura Kotaro</ENAMEX>, and other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. The exhibits are chosen for their resistance to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> is as lovely in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> as it is in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> stop here on the way to the little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gora</ENAMEX>,
        to catch the cable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sozan</ENAMEX> and from there the gondola ride up into
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX> and across the smoking, sulfurous <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Owakudani valley</ENAMEX>.
        There‚Äôs a stop en route where you can visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Owakudani Natural</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Museum</ENAMEX>, which has some uninspiring audio-visual presentations
        of volcanic eruptions. Down in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> is the really interesting
        display: an array of seismographs busily recording the movement of the
        vast tectonic plates deep below.
        Ride the next cable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to the shore of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Ashi</ENAMEX>, where
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">excursion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cruisers</ENAMEX> leave from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">piers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Togendai</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20-minute</TIMEX>
        ride to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hakone</ENAMEX>-machi on the other side of the lake. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> the
        reflection of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Fuji</ENAMEX> in these clear blue <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> is breathtaking. In
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early August</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lakeshore</ENAMEX> sponsor the dramatic Torii
        Matsuri festival, when a great wooden arch is set alight and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a thousand</NUMEX>
        burning lanterns are sent floating out across the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.
        In the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> period Hakone-machi was an important town
        on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokaido</ENAMEX>, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> through this mountainous area between
        the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> and the shogunal capital in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edo</ENAMEX>. The
        shogunate, always suspicious of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the move, maintained a system
        of garrisons along the road, and no one went through without an
        official pass. The checkpoint here, called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hakone Sekisho</ENAMEX>, is an
        exact replica of the original, with a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> of period costumes
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. The surrounding area is well known for its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">inns</ENAMEX> and
        thermal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX> and for its Hakone-zaiku woodcrafts with inlaid mosaic
