
  
  
    
      
        Where to Go
        Finding the most suitable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> for your style of
        vacation is important, as each group of islands, as well as each
        individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>, is unique. Do you want sun-kissed beaches, nonstop
        nightlife, ancient sites to explore, or traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> life
        around you?
        Most islands will have a little of each of these elements,
        but some, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ios</ENAMEX>, have given themselves over to party tourism
        almost completely. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, there is little traditional activity for
        you to enjoy. Equally, islands such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lesvos</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chios</ENAMEX> have few
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nightclubs</ENAMEX>. Here you‚Äôll find much more evidence of the rural life, with
        olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">groves</ENAMEX> and livestock <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> in the hilly interiors.
        In this edition, we have divided the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aegean Islands</ENAMEX> into
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">odyssey</ENAMEX> starts with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyclades</ENAMEX> islands, the most
        accessible island <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>. Next,
        traveling counterclockwise, we reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodecanese</ENAMEX> islands in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southeastern Aegean</ENAMEX> (excluding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodes</ENAMEX>, which is covered in its own
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berlitz Pocket Guide</ENAMEX>). We then move on to the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aegean</ENAMEX> islands of
        Samos, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chios</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lesvos</ENAMEX>, which sit parallel to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> mainland,
        and the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aegean</ENAMEX> islands of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samothraki, Limnos</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thasos</ENAMEX>. We
        conclude with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sporades</ENAMEX> islands.
        We have concentrated on the major islands in each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
        However, you‚Äôll also find concise information about some of the smaller
        or more remote islands within the larger island <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, such as the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyclades</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodecanese</ENAMEX>, to help you plan any island-hopping you
        might want to undertake.
        Getting Around
        Connections among the island <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> are poor, with the
        exception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piraeus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafina</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> mainland,
        which serve as transportation hubs for those who wish to travel from
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of islands to another. However, within each chain
        (particularly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyclades</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodecanese</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sporades</ENAMEX>), ferry
        connections are regular and journey times are relatively short. Car
        ferries are the slowest of the transportation options, but their
        stately progress allows you to enjoy the sun and sea air from their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promenade</ENAMEX> and sun decks. Both hydrofoils and large, powerful catamarans
        will cut ferry journey times in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>; however you will sit in an
        air-conditioned interior <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> for the duration of your ride.
        Once on a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>, you can easily get around on
        foot or rent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for more in-depth exploring. Also, most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> on
        smaller islands are linked by a good bus system.
        Within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyclades, Dodecanese</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sporades</ENAMEX> island <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>,
        there are certain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> that serve as hubs for travel to and from other
        islands within each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Below is a list of the hubs and the islands
        that can be reached by ferry from them within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX>. From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mykonos</ENAMEX>,
        you can travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delos, Paros, Naxos, Tinos, Andros</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syros</ENAMEX>. From
        Skiathos, you can reach <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Skopelos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Allonissos</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skyros</ENAMEX>. From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kos</ENAMEX>, you
        can reach <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patmos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kalymnos, Nyssiros</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">medieval citadel</ENAMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodes</ENAMEX> (covered in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berlitz Pocket Guide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodes</ENAMEX>).
        The overseas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Tourist</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> (GNTO) carry current schedules for the major ferry
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. The web site (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gtpnet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>) also lists this information.
        Note that extra ferries always run during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">peak season</TIMEX>.
        When to Go
        When to go is a decision of equal importance. The Aegean
        has a short, wet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> when walking, hiking, and mountain biking are
        extremely enjoyable activities, because the weather is pleasant but not
        too hot. The air is bright and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clear‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇperfect</ENAMEX> for photography.
        However, travel arrangements can be difficult <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early in the season</TIMEX>.
        The traditional opening time for many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orthodox Easter</ENAMEX>, although some do not open until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of April</TIMEX>. The
        ferry timetable runs on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> (read curtailed) service until the
        first week in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summer</ENAMEX> is long and hot, but the heat is tempered (or
        disguised) by the sometimes blustery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meltemi</ENAMEX> winds, which blow from the
        heart of central <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, south through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aegean</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> season is
        also marked by an influx of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">backpackers</ENAMEX> and package <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vacationers</ENAMEX> from
        all across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. The islands are busy, but all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> are open, and extra ferries and small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">caiques</NUMEX>) mean more opportunity to travel between islands.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Autumn</ENAMEX> is warm and the pace less <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">frantic‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇperfect</ENAMEX> for such
        watching activities as the harvesting of the olives. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> is over and many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> will close
        for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX>. Most of the staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">you‚Äôll</ENAMEX> see in bars and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> during
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> return to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> on mainland <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> until the following
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.
        The Cyclades
        Lying closest to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Attic</ENAMEX> peninsula, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyclades</ENAMEX> is the island <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would think of as typically
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>. Its islands have small fishing harbors replete with azure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>,
        whitewashed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> with brightly colored trim, small domed chapels, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">donkeys</ENAMEX> in their fields.
        Originally named <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many centuries ago</TIMEX> because its islands
        formed a circle or cyclos around the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Delos‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇone</ENAMEX> of the most
        important sites in the ancient world‚<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe Cyclades</ENAMEX> was first composed
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> islands. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty</NUMEX> islands have since been added, making the
        Cyclades the largest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> island <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
        You will definitely be sharing the main islands with many
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, although this has not yet spoiled their charms. For
        those who look for solitude, there are still quiet islands to be
        explored, off the beaten track.
        Mykonos
        A tiny, treeless rocky island regularly swept by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">summer</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">winds</ENAMEX> has become one of the most popular vacation destinations in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>. Why? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mykonos</ENAMEX> is a state of mind as well as a place. It‚Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hedonistic</ENAMEX> and funky, and tolerant of alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lifestyles</ENAMEX>. A mecca
        for gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> and nude sunbathers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mykonos</ENAMEX> is also a trendy spot
        for the fabulous and well-connected, who come to shop in its designer
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boutiques</ENAMEX> (open almost around the clock) and go clubbing till
        sunrise.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amazingly</ENAMEX>, the island retains its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> character. The
        capital, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mykonos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX>, is one of the most beautiful in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aegean</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">island</ENAMEX> happily caters to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> in addition to single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">backpackers</ENAMEX> as well as the wealthy. It offers a stepping stone to the
        sacred island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delos</ENAMEX>, with all its archaeological treasures, yet has
        a variety of beaches for those who want to do little but soak in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sun</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mykonos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX> is the only large settlement on the island.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> built on undulating land that radiates out from a fishing harbor
        where a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> still moors and sells its catch. You will probably
        find the island mascot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petros</ENAMEX>, a pelican (the older <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petros</ENAMEX> now has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apprentices</ENAMEX>, both also called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petros</ENAMEX>) waddling among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>,
        hoping for a fishy tidbit. Beside the port sits the quaint, round-domed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paraportiani Church</ENAMEX>, a favorite backdrop for fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>.
        Behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> is a maze of narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> and whitewashed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> with overhanging balconies resplendent with potted <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> of bougainvillea. Art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jewelers</ENAMEX>, and fashionable
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eateries</ENAMEX> can be found on every corner; but <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the morning</TIMEX>, you‚Äôll
        have the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> to yourself, so enjoy every detail of the pretty
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cycladic</ENAMEX> architecture. Brightly painted doors hide cool courtyards and
        white paint outlines the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> pavements of the alleyways.
        A small bay bounding the north side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> has Venetian
        balconies overhanging the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alefkandra Quarter</ENAMEX> or
        ‚ÄúLittle <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>,‚Äù it is the place to come for a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sunset cocktail</ENAMEX> or
        dinner by the water‚Äôs edge. From here, you‚Äôll get a full view of the
        line of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> windmills that sit above the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.
        Walking from the fishing harbor north toward the commercial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">port</ENAMEX> will take you past the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folklore Museum</ENAMEX>, with exhibits of
        traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> household items. Nearby, next to the southern bus
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX>, is the archaeological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>. Among its many exhibits, there
        are funerary statues and other items from the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhenia</ENAMEX>, the
        burial ground for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delos</ENAMEX>.
        The interior of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mykonos</ENAMEX> is barren and dusty. The only
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that break the monotony are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 300</NUMEX> small white
        chapels that dot the hillsides. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> of worship on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is the
        red-roofed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourliani Monastery</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its 16th-century</TIMEX> bell <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>. It is
        situated at the center of the inland village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ano Mera</ENAMEX>, whose small
        square makes a peaceful place for a leisurely lunch.
        The beaches of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mykonos</ENAMEX> rival those of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Tropez</ENAMEX> in their
        reputation for bohemian activities; however, there are enough stretches
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX> and little coves that you can find somewhere that suits your
        own tastes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paradise Beach</ENAMEX>, a clothing-optional beach, is probably the
        most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX>, with nonstop music that lasts well into the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early hours</TIMEX> of
        the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Super-Paradise</ENAMEX>, in the next bay, is a gay,
        clothing-optional beach. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families head</ENAMEX> out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Platis Gialos</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Psarou</ENAMEX>,
        but they can be crowded. Farther east, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agia Anna</ENAMEX> offer the
        promise of a little more space.
        Delos
        It is difficult to overestimate the importance of the
        sacred island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delos</ENAMEX> during ancient times. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> myth,
        it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God of Light</ENAMEX>. It was believed to be
        free floating until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo‚</ENAMEX>Äôs birth, after which huge columns rose up
        from the sea bed to anchor the island. Perhaps because of its
        geographical location at the center of the islands in the surrounding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyclades</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>, it also inspired the name for the island <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>.
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyclades</ENAMEX>, you may remember, comes from cyclos, or circle. ) Delos was
        not only an important religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, but also a major meeting point
        for trade between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hellenistic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> eras.
        It was designated the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">treasury</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delian League</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">480</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">b.c.</ENAMEX> , an act which encouraged its growth as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for banking and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commerce</ENAMEX>. As a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delos</ENAMEX> is now one of the most important
        archaeological sites in the world. Its remains reflect its dual roles
        in ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> life, a holy place and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of trade.
        Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delos</ENAMEX> has no modern settlement or tourist
        infrastructure. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> must travel here, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>, as an excursion
        from a surrounding island, alighting at a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jetty</ENAMEX> beside the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ancient port</ENAMEX>, now silted up. From here, the vista of the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> can
        be seen, with a fine residential <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> to the right, and the remains
        of a series of magnificent temples to the left. The temples were the
        last stop on a long pilgrimage for ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX>. Here, you
        could make offerings to the god <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo</ENAMEX> at his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX>, or consult
        the powerful oracle in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>.
        From the ferry <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jetty</ENAMEX>, turn left and walk down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sacred</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX>. In the distance, you will see a fine palm <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>, a symbol of
        Apollo‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX>. Surrounding it are the remains of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sacred Lake</ENAMEX>,
        drained in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX> to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mosquitoes</ENAMEX> from breeding in the
        stagnant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Walking through the site toward the palm <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> will take
        you past the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sanctuary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo</ENAMEX>, comprising a series of once fine
        colonnaded stoas and temples, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artemis</ENAMEX>.
        A number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX> statues, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Terrace</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions</ENAMEX>, form a
        honor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> on the approach to the sacred lake. They are perhaps the
        most photographed symbol of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delos</ENAMEX>, and are believed to date from the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> b.c. Their numbers have dwindled over the centuries
        from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 5</NUMEX>. Today, an attempt is being made to recreate the
        statues in their prime, with modern <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX>. At present, only one is
        in its natural aged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
        On higher ground behind the lake is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Delos</ENAMEX>.
        Although it has the dour look of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks building</ENAMEX>, it houses many of
        the finest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statuary</ENAMEX> and artifacts found at the site, and they bring to
        life the bare bones of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">temple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. Fine pottery
        and exquisite jewelry show that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life was enhanced by quality
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">possessions</ENAMEX>, which were taken for granted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
        To the left of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> area is perhaps one of the most
        exciting parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delos</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Theater Quarter</ENAMEX>, although the theater
        itself (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third century</TIMEX> b.c. ) is not the highlight of the site. It is
        the labyrinth of family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shadow</ENAMEX> that brings the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to
        life. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Streets</ENAMEX> that have felt the footfalls of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> and Romans
        still lead to the front doors of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>. Some are meager
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">square</NUMEX> boxes, but behind a number of strong stone walls, magnificent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX> are revealed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">courtyards</ENAMEX> were beautified by some of the
        most ornate mosaic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall frescoes</ENAMEX> in the ancient world.
        Search out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Dionysos</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Trident</ENAMEX> with
        their simple floor patterns, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Dolphins</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
        Masks for more elaborate examples, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dionysos</ENAMEX> riding a panther,
        on the floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Masks</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleopatra</ENAMEX> is also
        worthy of note, named for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> who left behind
        headless statues of herself and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dioskourides</ENAMEX>. The statues
        in situ are reproductions‚<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe originals</ENAMEX> sit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delos Museum</ENAMEX>.
        Behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Theater Quarter</ENAMEX> is an area with a number of shrines
        dedicated to foreign gods, an indication of the numerous cultures that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">influenced Delos</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gods</ENAMEX> were worshipped here.
        Above the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, the slopes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Kynthos</ENAMEX> rise to a
        height of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">112 m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">367 ft</ENAMEX>), offering a view across the whole site. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">climb‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇalong</ENAMEX> a narrow and sometimes steep path‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwill lead to scant
        remains of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">b.c. temples</ENAMEX>, although the site was occupied
        as early as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone Age</ENAMEX>.
        Lying <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few hundred meters</NUMEX> to the west, the island of
        Rhenia was both a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delians</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial ground</ENAMEX>. Delos
        was a sacred <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> and its soil had to be kept pure; therefore, birth
        and death were prohibited human activities. Even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> this ancient
        code is still being kept by modern archaeologists. Funerary artifacts
        found here are displayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mykonos</ENAMEX>.
        Andros
        The nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cyclades</ENAMEX> island to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> mainland, Andros
        is a short ferry ride from the port of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rafina</ENAMEX>, and is therefore very
        popular with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Athenians</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> vacations. Wealthy
        shipping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> own large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> along the coast and in the hills,
        which are more verdant than those of other islands in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, and
        its red soil contrasts with the dull earth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mykonos</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paros</ENAMEX>.
        The major port of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gavrion</ENAMEX> on the west coast serves the
        whole island, but the main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chora</ENAMEX> (which simply means ‚Äútown,‚Äù
        and is often used on islands with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> main settlement). Off the
        tourist route, on the east coast of the island, it is also known as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX>. Much of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chora</ENAMEX> has remained unchanged for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Athenian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weekenders</ENAMEX> have refurbished the charming old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">townhouses</ENAMEX>, and
        it has a very genteel air.
        The cultural heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX> owes much to the generosity of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Goulandris</ENAMEX> shipping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. They funded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Art Museum</ENAMEX>, just
        to the north of the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>, which features the work of a selection
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> modernist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX>. They were also instrumental in the
        creation of the archaeological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hermes of Andros</ENAMEX>,
        a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> copy of a statue originally sculpted by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Praxiteles</ENAMEX>.
        The main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Batsi</ENAMEX> on the west coast, just south of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gavrion</ENAMEX>. The small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> still retains vestiges of its heritage as a
        fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>, but modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> have been built on
        the outskirts.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monastery of Zoodohos Pighi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>-giving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring</ENAMEX>) lies
        in the hills above <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Batsi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> what is considered to be the most
        sacred of several freshwater springs found on the island.
        Tinos
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinos</ENAMEX> is a surprise because it is a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
        Catholic worship in an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land</ENAMEX>. This is in part because the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island</ENAMEX> remained under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic Venetian</ENAMEX> rule far longer than other
        islands in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Aegean‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇfrom 1207</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1714‚</NUMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbut also because it was t
        he scene of a blessed miracle, ensuring its fame throughout the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1823</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convent of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kechrovouni</ENAMEX> had a dream in which the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> told her that a sacred
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">icon</ENAMEX> could be found in land nearby. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX> went out and found the
        portrait just as her dream had foretold. Since that time, the icon has
        been held responsible for many feats of healing, giving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinos</ENAMEX> the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">epithet ‚ÄúLourdes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is a delight, because it has
        few foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> and retains its strong <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> character.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of the island, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> the icon in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panagia Evangelistria</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> that sits at the top of a gentle
        slope rising up from the port <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.6 miles</NUMEX>) away. The icon has a
        powerful influence over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pilgrims</TIMEX>, who crawl up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> steps on
        their hands and knees to pray for divine intervention. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> major
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">festivals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assumption Day</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 August</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annunciation Day</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX> crawling up the hill from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> to
        worship the icon. Don‚Äôt travel to the island at either of these times
        without a reservation.
        Travel into the countryside and you‚Äôll soon see how hilly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinos</ENAMEX> is. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> of terraces cover the hillsides, giving them a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">textured</ENAMEX> look. Today, many lie <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">overgrown</ENAMEX> and unused, but during
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Venetian</NUMEX> times, they brimmed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> and grew fodder for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">livestock</ENAMEX>.
        They are made accessible by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">donkey tracks</ENAMEX>, which
        are used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hikers</ENAMEX> and ramblers.
        Scattered across the land are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of dovecotes, which
        were introduced throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aegean</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venetians</ENAMEX>, who enjoyed
        pigeon as a part of their diet. On other islands, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> have been
        allowed to decay, but on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinos</ENAMEX> they stand proud, many with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> still
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>. Some of the most accessible can be found near the village
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarabados</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">13 miles</NUMEX>) north of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tinos Town</ENAMEX>.
        The ground rises dramatically behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tinos Town</ENAMEX> to a rocky
        peak called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Exobourgo</ENAMEX>. Here the remains of a massive <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Venetian</ENAMEX> fortress
        destroyed by invading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> can be found. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wander</ENAMEX>, at your own
        risk, among the walls, crumbling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">turrets</ENAMEX>, and caves, and look out
        toward the surrounding islands of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mykonos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andros</ENAMEX>. In the shadow of
        the peak is a network of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>, unspoiled both by the influence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> and the excesses of modern life. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the prettiest, Dyo
        Chorio, has fresh spring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> fountains which are still used by hill
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> to collect <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> for their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. Village <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> still wash
        their laundry in these waters.
        The central section of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinos</ENAMEX> has little of interest, but
        make your way over the hills to the pretty village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pyrgos</ENAMEX>, famed for
        its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of marble carving. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>, nestled into a narrow
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">valley</ENAMEX>, is one of the prettiest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aegean</ENAMEX>. A number of craftsmen
        have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> fronting onto the narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pyrgos</ENAMEX>, head down
        to the fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panormos</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 miles</NUMEX>) away, where you can
        enjoy delicious fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the many tavernas.
        Sifnos
        In ancient times, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sifnos</ENAMEX> was famed for its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and silver
        deposits. The island‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">treasury</ENAMEX>, stored at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delphi</ENAMEX> (the most important
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sanctuary</ENAMEX> in ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>) was said to be the richest of the many
        deposited there. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more recent times</TIMEX>,wealth has passed the island by,
        but it still produces some jewelry and has a reputation for
        particularly fine pottery, which can be seen outside the workshops
        drying in the sun. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> also claims <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 365</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> and
        monasteries nestled among its abundant olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">groves</ENAMEX>.
        The main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kamares</ENAMEX>, lies <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 miles</NUMEX>) from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">capital Apollonia</ENAMEX>, and its sister town <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artemon</ENAMEX> (both named for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> god and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> mythology). The
        oldest continually occupied settlement on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kastro</ENAMEX>, where
        most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> date from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 14th century</TIMEX> and were laid out in a
        circular pattern atop a rocky outcrop <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100 m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">300 ft</ENAMEX>) above the east
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coast</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is a fascinating mixture of crumbling grandeur and
        renovated splendor. An archaeological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> is housed in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> of
        Venetian origin and contains finds from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mycenaean and Archaic</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">periods</TIMEX>.
        The main beaches of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sifnos</ENAMEX> lie on the south coast. Platis
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gialos</ENAMEX> is popular with a range of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bars</ENAMEX> and tavernas, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vathi</ENAMEX> is
        perhaps the most visually stunning, with the now de-consecrated
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hrysopighi Monastery</ENAMEX> set on a small offshore island
        reached by a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paros</ENAMEX> and Antiparos
        A veritable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Central Station</ENAMEX> of ferry services, Paros
        is an island with something for almost everyone. Across a narrow
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX> sits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiparos</ENAMEX> (translated as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äúopposite Paros‚Äù</ENAMEX>), with a main
        settlement which takes you back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> Islands of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paros, Parikia</ENAMEX>, serves the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX>, and
        although it is extremely busy throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the peak season</TIMEX>, it still
        retains the feel of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. Away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX>, a maze of narrow
        streets disguise the remains of a kastro, or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>, dating from the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13th century</TIMEX>, which recycled marble from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> temples on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island</ENAMEX>.
        To the left of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX>, beside the new medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, is
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panagia Ekatontapiliani</ENAMEX>, known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of 100 Doors</ENAMEX>. The
        present <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are based around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a fourth-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> that is
        said to have been commissioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constantine</ENAMEX> the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constantinople</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who converted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> to Christianity), and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixth-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">chapel</ENAMEX> uses columns from
        an earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>.
        Nearby, the archaeological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> has a section of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Parian Chronicles</ENAMEX>, a history of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> enscribed on marble
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slabs</ENAMEX>, along with other examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paros</ENAMEX> marble, which was coveted
        throughout the ancient world for its fine translucence.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leave Parikia</ENAMEX> behind and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paros</ENAMEX> has a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> to
        explore. In the north, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naoussa</ENAMEX> has one of the prettiest fishing harbors
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>. Although popular with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, it has not lost
        its traditional industry. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boats</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> use lie within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">feet</NUMEX> of the
        fashionable bars and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs no surprise that the harbor has
        some of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seafood restaurants</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aegean</ENAMEX>, including several
        traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> ouzeries. To the west of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naoussa</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kolymbithres</ENAMEX>, a
        growing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> whose beaches are surrounded by strange rock features
        that are folded by immense natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and eroded by the wind. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resort</ENAMEX> has a large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> slides and a children‚Äôs play
        area.
        Along the eastern coastline are several fine beaches with
        perfect windsurfing conditions in their wide, shallow bays. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>
        Windsurfing Championships have been held here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> for the last
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Beach</ENAMEX> is perfect for soaking up the sun and
        watching the sport. Farther along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">east coast</ENAMEX> is the pretty port of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piso Livadi</ENAMEX>.
        The interior of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> has a number of interesting
        attractions. Lefkes village occupies high ground in the interior, and
        its narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> are perfect places to explore. Look out for the
        remains of a marble-covered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>- to
        century‚<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Äì14th-century</TIMEX>) that once connected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lefkes</ENAMEX> with the nearby
        village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karampoli</ENAMEX> down in the valley.
        Near the village of Marathi you will find the ancient
        marble quarries that sent stone to all parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">empires</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> was mined rather than cut from the surface, and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tunnels</ENAMEX> can be explored with a flashlight. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> remains you‚Äôll
        see once housed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workmen</ENAMEX> who came here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1844</TIMEX> to cut marble for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Napoleon‚Äôs</ENAMEX> tomb in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H√¥tel des Invalides</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>.
        If you visit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Paros</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, be sure to take a
        trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petaloudes</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Valley of the Butterflies</ENAMEX> south of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parikia</ENAMEX>, a
        breeding ground for giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tiger moths</ENAMEX>. Here you can see <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tiger</ENAMEX> moths
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinging</ENAMEX> to the leaves of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, sometimes in vast numbers.
        Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5,000 years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antiparos</ENAMEX> was attached to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paros</ENAMEX>, but
        seismic activity and climatic change have produced a narrow sea channel
        with several tiny islands between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiparos</ENAMEX> can be reached by
        a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20-minute</TIMEX> ferry ride from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Parikia</ENAMEX>, or a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five-minute</TIMEX> car ferry trip
        from the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pounda</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paros‚Äôs western</ENAMEX> coast.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antiparos</ENAMEX> seems to move at a slower pace than
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parikia</ENAMEX>; in fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> can be almost somnolent out of season. At
        its heart is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venetian</ENAMEX> kastro that still retains original dwelling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> along its interior walls.
        The main attractions on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> are the caves under the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mountain of Agios Ilias</ENAMEX> in the south. The interior is cavernous, but
        the caves have suffered from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> of vandalism. The number of
        steps built down into the interior means that it is unsuitable for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infirm</ENAMEX> or those with heart problems.
        Naxos
        The largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyclades, Naxos</ENAMEX> is a place of
        contrasts. It has ranges of barren hills and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX> as well as green
        fertile valleys that produce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX> and olives in abundance. The island
        has a long history; its marble deposits were coveted around the ancient
        world. In fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions of Delos</ENAMEX> were made from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naxos</ENAMEX> marble. The
        wonderful beaches along the western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">coast</ENAMEX> were, until recently, a
        secret, but they have now been discovered. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourism</ENAMEX> has grown over the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last ten years</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naxos, Hora</ENAMEX>, sits on the western coastline
        and is served by a rather breezy but extremely busy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX>. There is a
        wide promenade along the seafront with caf√©s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, but the
        heart of the magnificent old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> lies just above this, overlooking the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">harbor</ENAMEX>. It comprises a labyrinth of alleyways and narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> around
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venetian citadel</ENAMEX>, which caps the highest point. Small <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX>
        churches sit on street <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corners</ENAMEX>, side by side with family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church of Panagia Theoskepastos</ENAMEX> houses a fine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14th-century</TIMEX> icon, and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Cathedral</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a tenth</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Child</ENAMEX>. Next door
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">cathedral</ENAMEX> is the archaeological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> with finds from every era
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naxos‚</ENAMEX>Äôs long history.
        On a rocky promontory beside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is the site of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo</ENAMEX>, dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixth century</TIMEX> b.c. It was planned as
        the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aegean</ENAMEX>, but was never completed. Only the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">portal</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> ft) tall, was in place when work stopped, but
        it gives an indication of how immense the whole task would have
        been.
        The interior of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naxos</ENAMEX> offers a range of environments not
        found on other islands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aegean</ENAMEX>. Fertile valleys with precious
        water supplies offer a cool and fragrant break from the heat of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">towns</ENAMEX> and beaches. The valley between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chalki</ENAMEX> and Filoti
        (known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tragea Valley</ENAMEX>) is perhaps the most beautiful, and easily
        reached by bus from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hora</ENAMEX>. Ancient olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">groves</ENAMEX> play host to donkeys and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herds</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX>, and low-growing vines cover the ground under tall
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cypress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trees‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe archetypal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> landscape. The heart of Chalki
        hides a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venetian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> and the whole valley has a number of small
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> chapels.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Filoti</ENAMEX> sits in the shadow of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Zas</ENAMEX>, a treeless brown
        rock rising from the green valley below. Although you can‚Äôt climb to
        the summit, there are beautiful walks or cycle paths on its lower
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slopes</ENAMEX>, with caves to explore and cooling streams to enjoy.
        Traveling north out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tragea Valley</ENAMEX> past villages
        seemingly clinging to the valley sides, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keramoti, Koronos</ENAMEX>, and Korinada
        are all fascinating places to explore. All give glimpses of traditional
        family life. A small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> on the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">coast</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Apollon</ENAMEX>, holds a
        fascinating artifact from the past. A giant block of marble, formed
        into a kouros (male statue) over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,600 years ago</TIMEX> lies prostrate on the
        ground. The marble cracked before the figure was finished and it was
        abandoned where it lay.
        The best sandy beaches of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naxos</ENAMEX> lie on the sheltered west
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coast</ENAMEX> to the south of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chora</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agia Anna</ENAMEX>, and the long sandy spit of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agios Prokopios</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the most popular.
        Santorini
        The island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorini</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thira</ENAMEX>) is one of the must-see
        places of the world, for no other reason than because it frames the
        earth‚Äôs largest volcanic caldera. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Santorini</ENAMEX> looked exactly like many of
        the other islands in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyclades</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">around 1500 b.c.</TIMEX> , when a
        massive eruption of its volcano carried the whole interior of the
        island high into the atmosphere, changing the climate of the earth for
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> afterwards. In place of land came <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, surging in to fill the
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11-km</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7-mile</NUMEX>) long void and causing massive tidal waves around the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean Sea</ENAMEX>.
        What <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">remains</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is the outer rim of the original
        circular island. Sheer cliffs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">984 ft</ENAMEX>) high bound the
        caldera, and a number of whitewashed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">settlements nestle</ENAMEX> along their
        crests, looking from a distance like icing melting down the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>.
        Another section of the original island sits to the west.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thirasia</ENAMEX> now has separate settlements that can be visited by ferry from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorini</ENAMEX>. In the center of the caldera are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> low-lying areas of land
        that appeared after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1500</TIMEX> b.c. eruption: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nea Kameni</ENAMEX> and Palea
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kameni</ENAMEX>. Because the volcano is still <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">active‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇalthough dormant</ENAMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">present‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthese</ENAMEX> areas continue to grow, and experience earthquakes. The
        last major one, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>, inflicted a great deal of damage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>
        on the main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>.
        Once on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorini</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> are usually surprised to see,
        beyond the high steep caldera to the east, coastal plains that are
        covered in a blanket of vines. Indeed, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100,000</NUMEX> bottles of
        wine are produced here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> and shipped worldwide.
        The main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fira</ENAMEX>, set atop the high
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cliffs</ENAMEX> in the center of the long interior curve. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> tumble
        down toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> with stunning views. A narrow cobbled trail of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">587</NUMEX> steps leads from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to the small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> below, now the domain
        of a fleet of donkeys that wait to carry cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> into
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX>. For those who would prefer a quicker method, there is a cable car
        that wings you from sea level to the cliffs in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of minutes</TIMEX>.
        Most commercial ferries arrive at the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Athinios</ENAMEX> farther
        along the coast.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fira</ENAMEX> is a shopper‚Äôs paradise, a series of narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX>
        where you can wander free from the fear of traffic, although keep your
        eyes and ears open for donkeys. You can buy anything from a
        reproduction icon to a genuine Faberg√© <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>, plus jewelry of the finest
        quality and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> clothing by the most desirable names. Find a spot
        for a drink at sunset (which has to be one of the most spectacular on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">earth</ENAMEX>).
        Among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> of cultural
        interest. The archaeological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> on a square next to the cable car
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX> (a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is under construction near the main bus
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX>, which will eventually house the collection) features pottery
        and other artifacts found on the island. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Megaron Gyzi Museum</ENAMEX> to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">north</ENAMEX> of the cable car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> is housed in a beautiful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX>
        fortified <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. Most exciting of its varied collections is a display
        of photographs showing island scenes from before the devastating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>
        earthquake.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fira</ENAMEX> is beautiful, but it can get oppressive when visitors
        crowd the narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. A little way north is another smaller town
        where the pace is less frantic. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ia</ENAMEX> (pronounced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oya</ENAMEX>), set on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">northern cliffs</ENAMEX>, became home to a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> early on, and it
        maintains a more bohemian atmosphere than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fira</ENAMEX>. There are many homes
        built into the hillsides; some have been converted into art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> selling collectibles. The architecture is typical of the
        Cyclades, and the buildings‚Äô multicolored fa√ßades make it one of the
        most photographed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> in the world.
        Aside from the stunning views, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorini</ENAMEX> has much more to
        show its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. In the center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is the village of
        Pirgos, with the remains of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venetian</ENAMEX> fortress at its heart. On a
        rocky bluff beyond the village you will find <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monastery</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Profitis Ilias</ENAMEX>. As the road climbs toward the entrance, you‚Äôll pass
        fields full of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Santorini‚Äôs famed tomatoes</ENAMEX> growing on the steep slopes.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> is only open when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> inside take liturgies
        (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> and early evenings), but it is well worth taking the time to
        visit. Pride of place goes to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15th-century</TIMEX> icon of the prophet
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elijah</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> also has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, which conveys the flavor of
        monastic life along with icons and manuscripts. Unfortunately, the hil
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ltop</ENAMEX> is also shared by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> military, and it bristles with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satellite</ENAMEX> and digital technology, prohibiting photography of the
        beautiful panorama.
        On the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slopes</ENAMEX> of this rocky outcropping is the
        site of the ancient capital of the island, also called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thira</ENAMEX>, which
        dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third century</TIMEX> b.c. (when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aegean</ENAMEX> was under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ptolemaic</ENAMEX>
        rule). The site sprawls over a wide area, but unfortunately, some
        remains are in poor condition, a situation which causes the site to
        close intermittently because of the danger of falling masonry. Check
        with the tourist information <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fira</ENAMEX> before setting
        out.
        In the south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is one of the most important
        ancient sites in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>. Near the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> of
        Akrotiri, a complete city dating from before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> b.c. was discovered.
        It was covered by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several feet</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ash</ENAMEX> during the eruption of c.<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1500</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">b.c.</ENAMEX> , but unlike the tragic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pompeii</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, no human remains
        have been found. This has led <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> to believe that the population
        escaped before the disaster took place.
        Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>, the site has been painstakingly excavated to
        give a picture of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life before the great eruption. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">society</ENAMEX> of
        complexity and sophistication has been unveiled, one that had urban
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">planning</ENAMEX>, heating, sanitation, and a standard script. However, much of
        the beautiful artwork found here is, for the moment, in the
        archaeological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>. The site is still an active dig and
        new discoveries are being made all the time. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">remains</ENAMEX>, which include
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and pretty communal squares, have been placed under
        a protective, corrugated roof that gets hot and crowded, so try to
        visit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early in the day</TIMEX> as possible.
        The beaches of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorini</ENAMEX> are made of fine black or red
        volcanic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX>, which heats to a ferocious temperature in the summer
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sun</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamari</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perissa</ENAMEX> are growing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> with a range of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bars</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. Both make pleasant retreats after a day of
        sightseeing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fira</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akrotiri</ENAMEX>.
        Some of the best views of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorini</ENAMEX> are from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Try
        taking a trip around the caldera, with stops at the new volcanic
        islands of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palea Kameni</ENAMEX>. Allow time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thirasia</ENAMEX> to explore
        Santorini‚Äôs smaller sibling islands.
        Ios
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ios</ENAMEX> is hands-down the party island of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aegean</ENAMEX>; its bars
        and clubs boom out the latest dance tunes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours a day</TIMEX>. Traditionally
        a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>, the native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> has happily embraced the new
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> lifestyle that has brought them prosperity, and the old ways
        have almost completely disappeared.
        Arriving by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> gives you splendid views of the
        magnificent unspoiled, treeless landscape, which bears scant evidence
        of the hand of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Only the southeastern corner has any real
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, and the road system comprises <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less than 10 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">16 miles</NUMEX>)
        from the pretty, narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chora</ENAMEX>, the island‚Äôs only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, to
        the beach at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milopotamos</ENAMEX> in the neighboring bay. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milopotamos</ENAMEX> is one of
        the best and busiest beaches in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aegean</ENAMEX>. This leaves a whole island
        to explore on foot, or by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4-wheel</NUMEX>-drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>. Residents of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ios</ENAMEX> will
        tell you that an ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> in the north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> is that of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Odyssey and The Iliad</ENAMEX>. (His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was born on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ios</ENAMEX>. ) Unfortunately, no positive proof has ever corroborated the
        claim.
        The Dodecanese
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodecanese</ENAMEX> islands take their name from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
        phrase dodeka nisi, meaning twelve islands, although the group
        incorporates far more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one dozen</NUMEX> in its number. The islands did not
        become part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1912 to 1947</TIMEX>, they were ruled by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>; before that, they were part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman Empire</ENAMEX>. The major
        islands exhibit faded remains of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> influence, though this was
        just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of several cultures to leave its mark on the islands.
        Kos
        Now the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> most populated island in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodecanese</ENAMEX>, Kos
        has seen human settlement since ancient times. With safe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">harbors</ENAMEX> and
        wide fertile plains, it could both protect and feed its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Today
        it is very popular with package <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vacationers</ENAMEX>, particularly high-spirited
        young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>. Try to visit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early or late in the season</TIMEX> to avoid the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> and their worst excesses.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX> on the western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">coast</ENAMEX> is the main settlement, and a
        fascinating place to explore. Settled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many centuries</TIMEX>, it suffered
        an earthquake in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX> that damaged much of the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town center</ENAMEX>, but
        allowed Italian archaeologists to excavate a large section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
        city which lay directly underneath. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it is possible to walk
        through the old agora (marketplace) and stroll along <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>.
        Later, after the fall of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> became a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stronghold of the Knights of St. John</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 15th century</TIMEX>, they built
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle of the Knights of St. John</ENAMEX> at the water‚Äôs edge. It still
        forms an impressive backdrop for photographs of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mandraki Harbor</ENAMEX>, and is
        filled with historical ‚Äúlitter,‚Äù including carved marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaques</ENAMEX>,
        statuary, and cannons.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> ousted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knights</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1522</TIMEX>, and evidence of
        their stay can be found just inland from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>. The minaret of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loggia Mosque</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX> and the largest on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kos</ENAMEX>, now
        stands silent and closed, but it is matched by a number of smaller
        examples throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, some still in use by the small <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
        Beside the mosque‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇin fact, almost overshadowing it‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇis
        a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> tree. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> extend so far that it has had to be
        supported for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> by a framework of scaffolding. The local
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will tell you that this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hippocrates Tree</ENAMEX>, under which the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of medicine, a native of the island, lectured to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
        over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,500 years ago</TIMEX>. Sadly, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> has been proved to be
        among the oldest in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> believe that it is only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> and therefore not of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hippocrates‚Äôs</ENAMEX> era.
        In the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> (walk inland from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mosque</ENAMEX> on the south side of the agora) is the archaeological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>,
        which features finds from ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kos</ENAMEX>, including mosaics and domestic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">utensils</ENAMEX>. On the outskirts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">E Grigorou Street</ENAMEX>, is a small
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Odeon</ENAMEX> or theater, used in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> for performances. Nearby is Casa
        Romana, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman villa</ENAMEX> recreated in every detail. It really brings to
        life the daily routines of a wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> family.
        If you don‚Äôt want to walk around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, a small motorized
        train runs past all the major <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>. It operates several times a day
        during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kilometers</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 1‚ÅÑ2 miles</NUMEX>) outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX> are the
        remains of a medical school founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth century</TIMEX> b.c. , just
        after the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hippocrates</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asclepium</ENAMEX> was a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of
        healing. Many of the largest remains date from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX>, rather than
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Classical Greek</ENAMEX> era, and the site was damaged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knights of St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> when they removed marble from it to build their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> in Kos
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Town</ENAMEX>. The main <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Doric</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> rested on the upper level of the three
        terraces that make up the site. There are fine views across to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>
        from here.
        Resorts outside <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kos Town</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kardamena</ENAMEX> on the south
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coast</ENAMEX>, a young, energetic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tigaki</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">north coast</ENAMEX>, a quiet
        resort more suited to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kamari</ENAMEX>, which sits the
        farthest from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kos Town</ENAMEX>. All offer a selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX>.
        The flat landscape, especially in the east, is ideal for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cycling</ENAMEX>, where you can get away and explore such inland <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pyli</ENAMEX> (and the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paleo Pyli</ENAMEX> high in the hills), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Asfendiou</ENAMEX>, and
        Kefalos, with the last working windmill on the island. Here you can
        still find a quiet spot to enjoy authentic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> island life.
        Patmos
        This small, barren island in the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dodecanese</ENAMEX> may
        have remained the deserted outpost it once was, had it not been for a
        decision in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first century</TIMEX> a.d. to use it as a penal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> for
        political and religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX>. It was here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95</TIMEX> a.d. that one
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> received divine inspiration in the form of an apocalyptic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX> while he sat in his small cave high above the harbor. The words
        which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John the Theologian</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evangelist</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>) recorded became the
        Book of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Revelation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apocalypse</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>), the last book of the New
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Testament</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1098</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> ceded land on the island to
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Christodoulos</ENAMEX>, who founded a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> here in honor of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">saint</ENAMEX>. It soon became a place of contemplation, learning, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pilgrimage‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa</ENAMEX> role it still performs for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX> to the
        present day.
        Since there is no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> on the island, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> must
        arrive at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Skala</ENAMEX>, where most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> are located and all
        commercial activity is carried out. Despite the number of visitors
        passing through, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skala</ENAMEX> is still a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> at heart, with a number
        of traditional tavernas to be found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> around the small
        main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>. A new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">yacht</ENAMEX> basin to the east allows safe harbor for
        independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>.
        Everyone who arrives at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> can look up and see their
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monastery of St. John the Theologian</ENAMEX>, surrounded by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chora</ENAMEX> atop a nearby hill. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> was built at a
        tumultuous time in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> history and its design was based on that
        of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>, to act as a protection of the faith and its treasures, as
        well as for worship. It stands high above myriad whitewashed walls.
        Historically, a narrow cobbled track transported pilgrims
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX>, either on foot or by donkey. The path
        still exists, and in the cool of the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early morning</TIMEX>, it is a pleasant
        uphill walk. Others can take one of the regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> or a taxi for the
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten-minute</TIMEX> ride.
        Halfway up the hill is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Convent of the Apocalypse</ENAMEX>, at
        the site of the cave where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. John</ENAMEX> received his divine revelation. Now
        tended by nuns, it is regarded as holy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ground</ENAMEX> (follow the same rules of
        dress expected at other holy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX>). The small <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cave</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Anne</ENAMEX> has a
        silver <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> where it is said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. John</ENAMEX> laid his head <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each night</TIMEX>, and a
        simple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock ledge</ENAMEX> is said to have been his desk. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chapels</ENAMEX> now grace
        the grounds.
        On reaching <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chora</ENAMEX>, you will need to walk through the
        pedestrian-only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> have an almost
        eerie emptiness, although in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> small kittens scamper away as you
        approach, disappearing into cracks in the thick, high walls. Eventually
        the signposts will lead to the strong <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone archway</ENAMEX> that signals the
        entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monastery of St. John</ENAMEX>.
        Immediately on entering the cobbled main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>, you
        will find a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> on the left, built on the site of an ancient
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temple of Artemis</ENAMEX>. Inside you will find the marble sarcophagus of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monastery‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christodoulos</ENAMEX> and icons that date from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1190</TIMEX>. Behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">chapel</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 11th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">refectory</ENAMEX> where it is
        possible to gain an insight into the daily lives of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monks</ENAMEX> who made this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> their home. The utilitarian communal
        tables and simple decorations offered no distractions from their
        serious vocation.
        Take the staircase in the eastern corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>
        to find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">treasury</ENAMEX>, which displays only a fraction of the wealth
        accumulated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX>. Beautifully displayed are a range of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">icons</ENAMEX> dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 12th century</TIMEX>, silver altar pieces and bejeweled
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vestments</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> received bequests from nobility throughout the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX> world, and was not averse to making money from commerce,
        particularly shipping. In this way, it amassed vast fortunes still kept
        under lock and key.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> was once one of the most important in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> world. Large numbers of volumes were evacuated from here
        before the fall of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constantinople</ENAMEX>, comprising the best in early
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> decorated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">manuscripts</ENAMEX> and books of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>. However, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">library</ENAMEX> is only open to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and requires prior written permission
        for research.
        Despite the importance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX>, a great deal of
        ordinary life can be seen around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patmos</ENAMEX>. Small holdings abound, and
        traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> sit low on the treeless hillsides. The beaches on
        the northern coastline beyond the village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kambos</ENAMEX> are said to be the
        best, although some are difficult to reach. Most accessible is Lampis
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX>, with a couple of good tavernas. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South of Skala</ENAMEX> is the small resort
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grikos Bay</ENAMEX>.
        Kalymnos
        For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kalymnos</ENAMEX> were renowned for
        their diving prowess. They developed it in order to harvest the sponges
        that grew abundantly in the seas all around the island. However, the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 20th century</TIMEX> saw several catastrophic changes that ruined the
        commercial sponge industry on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kalymnos</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> emigrated to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> to make new lives, and the natural
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> dropped dramatically.
        Although the traditional industry is a great deal smaller
        than it once was, tourism has taken up the slack; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, Kalymnos
        is busy with vacationing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> from several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kalymnos</ENAMEX> has a barren interior with dramatic cliffs and
        caves all around its coastline. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pothia</ENAMEX>, is a splash of
        bright color climbing a hillside on the south coast. With a population
        of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around 11,000</NUMEX>, it is one of the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodecanese</ENAMEX> and
        is the major port on the island. Today, a small fleet of sponge
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX> still sets sail every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> remains in
        decline. The statue of a mermaid sits on the breakwater as a lucky omen
        for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> turn out to perform a religious ceremony
        to guide and protect their loved ones.
        Beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pothia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pera Kastro</ENAMEX>) at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horio</ENAMEX>, the
        medieval capital, is clearly visible. The beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirties</ENAMEX> and
        Massouri on the west coast take the bulk of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massouri</ENAMEX> has
        fleets of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> that offer day trips to the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Telendos</ENAMEX> only a
        mile or so offshore.
        To the east of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pothia</ENAMEX>, the road leads to a fertile
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fruit</ENAMEX>-producing valley near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vathi</ENAMEX>. In the clear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> offshore are the
        remains of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> naval <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX> sunk by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>
        II.
        Karpathos
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karpathos</ENAMEX> is a rugged and wild island lying between Rhodes
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crete</ENAMEX>, almost at the foot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aegean</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last one</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hundred years</TIMEX> a large percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, tired of fighting
        the hard economic conditions, immigrated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
        The remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is based mainly in the south,
        around the capital, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pigadia</ENAMEX>, which is relatively modern by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
        standards (built since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-19th century</TIMEX>). Around it lie fields of
        fertile soil supporting orchards and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grain crops</ENAMEX>.
        The middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> has mountains that rise over
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,200 m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4,050 ft</NUMEX>), separating the northern part of the island, and
        protecting it from the effects of development in the south. From
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pigadia</ENAMEX> to the small southern port of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diafani</ENAMEX>, where vehicles find it
        difficult to travel, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> move <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and goods. From here it is a
        steep journey up to the village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olimbos</ENAMEX>, which still holds fast to
        its traditional way of life. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> are built to a long-standing
        design and are filled with embroidery, lace, and crochet work. Older
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> still dress in colorful traditional costumes which
        the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> wear on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">feast days</TIMEX>.
        The remaining parts of the north, although enticing, are
        difficult to explore. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> exception is the hike north from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olimbos</ENAMEX> to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. John the Baptist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vrykounda</ENAMEX>, site of a major island
        festival on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29 August every year</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> Aegean
        Close to western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> large islands lie aligned
        from north to south: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lesvos, Chios</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samos</ENAMEX>. These islands, known as
        the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aegean Islands</ENAMEX>, have been at the forefront of waves of
        invasion from the east. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Persians</ENAMEX> came here to attack
        the kingdoms of the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> mainland; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ottomans</ENAMEX> used
        this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> as a base when they forced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venetians</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genoese</ENAMEX> to
        flee back to their homelands. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> islands
        played a major role in the fight for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> statehood at the beginning
        of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>. They also saw a wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> mainland during and after the proclamation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> state
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923</TIMEX>.
        Despite hostile feelings in the past, relations between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> are now genial, at least on a day-to-day basis. One
        of the most exciting facets o f a trip to the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aegean Islands</ENAMEX> is
        the possibility of taking a day trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, where you can
        experience the contrasting (though sometimes surprisingly similar)
        culture, and see the majestic ancient archaeological sites of old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia</ENAMEX>
        Minor.
        Lesvos
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lesvos</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aegean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> (after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crete</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evia</ENAMEX>), and it has a long and independent cultural tradition. Music,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poetry</ENAMEX>, and dance have always been important parts of the island‚Äôs
        identity. It was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX> of the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sappho</ENAMEX>, said by
        Homer to be the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> muse, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alcaeus</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> music. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman Sultans</ENAMEX> held <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lesvos</ENAMEX> in high esteem for its
        fertile lands and the fine olive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> produced here, however, following
        the creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>, it lost its main market
        and became a backwater of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aegean</ENAMEX>.
        The island‚Äôs capital is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mytilini</ENAMEX> (and you may sometimes
        hear <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> call the island <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mytilini</ENAMEX>, rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lesvos</ENAMEX>). A trading
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX>, its main shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ormos Ermou</ENAMEX>, still throngs
        with the energy of an eastern bazaar. Fine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villas</ENAMEX> can be
        found along the seafront, both north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> and south toward the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">airport</ENAMEX>. The villas were built for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">overseers</ENAMEX>, but
        were abandoned in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>.
        But the most impressive structure is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">medieval castle</ENAMEX>
        built atop <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hellenistic</ENAMEX>, and more ancient settlements. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the
        largest fortifications in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aegean</ENAMEX>, the interior Venetian walls were
        later expanded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ottomans</ENAMEX>. Resting in the shadow of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>
        walls is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lesvos Archaeological Museum</ENAMEX>, with one of the finest
        collections of artifacts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>. A new, air-conditioned,
        state-of-the-art <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> has been added on to the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, a
        fine old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>. Throughout the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> there are finds from
        all eras of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lesvos‚</ENAMEX>Äôs history. Intricate mosaics depicting scenes from
        Menender‚Äôs comedies are displayed beautifully, with clear glass tile
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">walkways</ENAMEX> allowing close access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">detail</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> statuary,
        jewelry, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utensils</ENAMEX> are all thoughtfully arranged.
        Around the island, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lesvos</ENAMEX> offers wonderful impressions of
        Greek village life. Its economy depends far less on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tourist</TIMEX> earnings
        and much more on agricultural production (re-established since the
        problems of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>); therefore, traditional lifestyles are much more
        common here.
        The east of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> has most of the estimated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
        million olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> which produce the island‚Äôs major <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX>. They blanket
        the hills with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">silvery leaves</ENAMEX>, shimmering in the breeze. Small
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> with narrow cobbled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> sit among them, built inland to
        offer protection against pirate raids.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North of Mytilini</ENAMEX>, stop at the village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moria</ENAMEX>, where you
        will find the remains of a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">aqueduct</ENAMEX> surrounded by grazing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX>. Mandamadhos <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> in the far north still carries on a
        traditional pottery industry on a small scale. On its outskirts, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monastery of Taxiarhis</ENAMEX> has a revered black icon that is believed to be
