
  
  
    
      
        Where to Go
        Setting your priorities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> before you start out is
        essential to making your trip both pleasant and satisfying. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Happily,</ENAMEX>
        many destinations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> offer a key activity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> will be
        searching for, such as exploring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysia‚Äôs</ENAMEX> culture and history or
        engaging in a sport like fishing, but often there is an added bonus: a
        nearby jungle for trekking or a beachside resort‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand this is true
        throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
        Malaysia‚Äôs well developed transportation
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">infrastructure‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇboth road</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">air‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇalso</ENAMEX> offers the chance to step
        away from rigid planning if you desire to stay an extra day by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">beach</ENAMEX> or want to do some more extensive shopping. Caution is needed if
        you are not used to a hot and humid climate (a constant but not
        necessarily hostile factor), and often requires a little extra planning
        when heading out on tour, trekking, or just lazing by the pool.
        At the back of the book, our helpful A to Z section provides
        detailed practical information on how to handle your stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>.
        Here we provide some general touring strategies before describing the
        places you will be visiting.
        Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Touring Strategies</ENAMEX>
        Starting in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Town</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> hold a mirror to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malaysia‚</ENAMEX>Äôs ethnic blend of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eurasians</ENAMEX>, living side by side or in their
        separate neighborhoods. This takes on a metropolitan dimension in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lumpur</ENAMEX>. (In true <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> style, we will refer to the capital by its
        abbreviation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX>. ) The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northeast</ENAMEX> coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, especially between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kota Bharu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kuantan</ENAMEX>, is one of the best places to see traditional
        Malay life with its rich <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> culture, particularly evident in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kampungs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>) of the interior. Step back into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia‚Äôs</ENAMEX> history
        in the port <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kota Kinabalu</ENAMEX>, where colonial rivals
        once battled for supremacy, and where princes and sultans dealt in
        palace intrigue. You will also be caught by the beauty of the many
        mosques, temples, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX> as the country‚Äôs faithful
        practice their beliefs, their places of homage often existing within
        steps of each other in harmony. But remember when visiting places of
        worship to dress in an appropriately dignified manner and to slip off
        your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoes</ENAMEX> before entering a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melaka</ENAMEX>,
        observe the way of life of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babas</ENAMEX>, the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, and
        its more modern manifestation in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Penang‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇor indeed elsewhere, as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chinatowns</ENAMEX> throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> offer chances to explore, browse, or
        buy.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, while being few in number, provide an excellent
        chance to gain insight into the path the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has taken, as well as
        offering a sense of the country‚Äôs culture and folklore. The major ones
        are in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melaka</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuching</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kota Kinabalu</ENAMEX>. And the picture
        of life on the peninsula is best completed with a visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singapore‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, if you happen to be passing through.
        Heading Out to the Country
        Beyond city limits you will find myriad opportunities to
        enjoy the rural and forested <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>. But finding your way around the
        riches of rainforest, coral reef, or marine reserve can be bewildering
        if you plunge in unprepared. Unless you already have some experience in
        the region, we recommend that you use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of the many
        first-class local tour <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>. For jungle tours, they provide
        experienced English-speaking guides, most of them with a good knowledge
        of the rainforest. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Offices</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Development</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX> in your home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> can provide guidance to the most
        reputable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">190</NUMEX>). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> have their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX> and organize tours nationwide. They may sub-contract
        to smaller but equally reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in outlying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> has done a fine job of giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> access to
        its natural treasures without ‚Äútaming‚Äù them too much. At the heart of
        the peninsula, the huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taman Negara</ENAMEX> gives you the most comprehensive
        view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">country‚Äôs animals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> in their wild <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. A more
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äúcompact‚Äù</ENAMEX> approach is possible on the islands, notably with excursions
        into the wilderness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tioman</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Langkawi</ENAMEX>. If you are attracted by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>-laying habits of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rantau Abang</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> and
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>.
        On the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borneo</ENAMEX>, the great natural attractions are
        Sarawak‚Äôs caves at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mulu</ENAMEX>, river cruises with a visit to tribal
        longhouses, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabah‚Äôs</ENAMEX> national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Kinabalu</ENAMEX> and the offshore
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">islands</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sepilok wildlife sanctuary</ENAMEX>. If your desire is to
        escape the coastal heat, highland retreats will refresh and invigorate,
        offering a chance to enjoy what was once the exclusive domain of
        colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>.
        And Then the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX>
        White sandy beaches and gentle sea breezes are for many the
        perfect recipe for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a holiday</TIMEX> from the stresses of modern life, and in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> the offerings are plenty. Whether on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Peninsula</ENAMEX> or at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sabah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarawak</ENAMEX>, you‚Äôll find many opportunities to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bask</ENAMEX> and laze under the tropical sun. (Just remember to use
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sunscreen‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsunburn</ENAMEX> and possible dehydration are never too far away.
        )
        On the west coast the best beaches are at the island
        resorts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Langkawi</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unspoiled</ENAMEX> stretches of fine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX> can
        also be found on the east coast, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pantai Chinta Berahi</ENAMEX>, north of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kota Bharu</ENAMEX>, down to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beserah</ENAMEX>, north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuantan</ENAMEX>. Farther south are the
        resorts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tioman Island</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desaru</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Malaysia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuching</ENAMEX> and Kota
        Kinabalu both have fine hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX>.
        Speaking the Language
        Though the official tongue is <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahasa Malaysia</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> is still the common language of communication between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>. After an initial nationalist resistance to using
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> to accompany <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> road signs, a new effort is being made to
        accommodate foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>. But you may still like to use a few words
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> as a courteous gesture to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>.
        You will find a comprehensive list of useful phrases in the
        back of this book.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>
        Malaysia‚Äôs prosperity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent decades</TIMEX> is most evident in
        the central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> of the peninsula, where the signs abound. From the
        new international <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL‚</ENAMEX>Äôs dramatic skyline to the middle class
        seen driving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX>-made <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Proton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedans</ENAMEX> on six-lane highways‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇall
        are evidence to the country‚Äôs rising economic maturity. But even as a
        new light rail system wends its way through the capital, progress has
        not entirely buried <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> under chrome and concrete. Still thriving
        are the old commercial areas which brought so much of the wealth to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> generally.
        Beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">past‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwhose structures</ENAMEX> now
        more often stand in the shadow of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL‚</ENAMEX>Äôs new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">skyscrapers‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇcontinues</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">echo</ENAMEX> amid the northern hill <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>. Here amid the cool afternoon
        breezes or gentle mountain mists of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Highlands</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
        palate for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> (on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation scale‚ÄÇ</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">strawberries</ENAMEX> still thrive.
        Those retreats within easier reach of the city‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genting Highlands</ENAMEX> or theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> born out of former tin mines‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇdraw
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX> entertainment, a far cry from the more
        traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, zoos, and aquariums.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> and industry line the way to the port <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of
        Klang on the coast, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ipoh</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perak</ENAMEX> state‚Äôs most flourishing tin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Kangsar</ENAMEX> is the leisurely, royal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state capital</ENAMEX>. The vast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taman Negara</ENAMEX>, which translates as ‚Äúnational <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>,‚Äù is one of the best
        preserved primary rainforests in the world, at once accessible to the
        public and lovingly protective of its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wildlife</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX>
        At times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuala Lumpur‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇoften</ENAMEX> referred to as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KL‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇappears
        to be a criss-cross of pedestrian-unfriendly overpasses and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">expressways</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> opens to islands of almost jungle-like
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>-cover before descending again into lively market centers
        surrounded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that look down upon the city‚Äôs busy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> may initially be drawn to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petronas Twin</ENAMEX>
        Towers or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL Communications Tower</ENAMEX>, which are potent symbols of
        modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX>. But the more fascinating splendors of the past are
        closer to street level, where distinctive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Neo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gothic</ENAMEX> styles are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beautifully</ENAMEX> preserved.
        As in other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is
        predominantly <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Chinese</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is prominent in the modern
        business world. Chinatown itself remains a hive of bustling activity,
        standing cheek by jowl with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little India</ENAMEX> of pungent spice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">ornate Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temples</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethnic Malays</ENAMEX> are present in the upper echelons
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, civil service, and tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historic Center</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL‚</ENAMEX>Äôs main historic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> lies near <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jalan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX>
        Hishamuddin, where on the east side of the broad avenue is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Abdul Samad Building</ENAMEX>. The handsome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">crypto</NUMEX>-Moorish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Secretariat</ENAMEX>,
        now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, was begun in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1894</TIMEX> (finished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1897</TIMEX>) and capped
        with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> fine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX> onion-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">domes</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> tops a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40-m</NUMEX>- (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">120-ft-</ENAMEX>) high
        clock <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> that suggests inspiration from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Ben</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. That is
        perhaps not a surprise, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">architect A. C. Norman</ENAMEX>. At the other end of this building you‚Äôll also
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">find Infokraf</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Handicraft Development Corporation</ENAMEX>
        has a permanent exhibition of national craftwork, with many exhibits
        for sale. Near this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Hall</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lebuh</ENAMEX> Pasar
        Besar, which now houses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Textile Museum</ENAMEX>.
        Among the many impressive skyscrapers, one of the most
        striking is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dayabumi Complex</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>), southeast of Dataran
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merdeka</ENAMEX>. The soaring white <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> successfully integrates traditional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Islamic architectural themes‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇpointed arches</ENAMEX>, delicate open
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tracery‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwith</ENAMEX> its otherwise modern design. Included in the
        southernmost end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">adjoining</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pejabat Besar</ENAMEX> Pos
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Post Office</ENAMEX>), in a similar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> modern style, and a
        shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>.
        On the western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">side</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">boulevard</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dataran</ENAMEX> Merdeka
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom Square</ENAMEX>). In the colonial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, the sound of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">cricket</ENAMEX> bat‚Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">willow</ENAMEX> would have been heard as the afternoon‚Äôs sun-rays stretched
        across the field. It was here that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the mock-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudor Royal</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selangor Club</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1884</TIMEX>), also designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. C. Norman</ENAMEX>, took time off from
        the affairs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> to play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">cricket</ENAMEX>. On the wide span of lawn the
        cheers of independence were heard on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31 August 1957</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> now
        hosts National Day state parades. On the square‚Äôs northern side, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican St. Mary‚Äôs Church</ENAMEX> dates to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1893</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. C. Norman</ENAMEX> was rivaled in commissions by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. B. Hubback</ENAMEX>,
        whose work is reflected in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Railway buildings</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, located south on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jalan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hishamuddin</ENAMEX>. The main
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX> (completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX> and extensively renovated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>) resembles
        nothing so much as a gleaming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sultan‚Äôs palace</ENAMEX> and is more attractive
        than the somber brown headquarters <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. It is a
        fine example of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Moorish</ENAMEX> architecture, reflecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mogul</ENAMEX>
        glory of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 13th and 14th centuries</TIMEX>. The north <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> was bombed in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> was gutted by fire in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>.
        Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbock</ENAMEX> also designed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masjid Jamek</ENAMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1909</TIMEX> this
        building has marked the confluence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gombak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klang Rivers</ENAMEX>,
        where tin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX> loaded supplies to be sent upriver and unloaded their
        tin for shipment west to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Klang</ENAMEX>, and where the city‚Äôs roots were
        set down. It was designed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1907</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hubback</ENAMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian Moghul</ENAMEX> style:
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-pointed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">domes</ENAMEX> over the prayer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> minarets and balustrades
        above an arcade of cusped arches‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe whole predominantly gleaming
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">white</ENAMEX>, with pink terracotta brick.
        Across the river going east from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dayabumi Complex</ENAMEX> is
        the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pasar Seni</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Market</ENAMEX>), set in an attractive Art-Deco
        building (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>) in pastel blue and pink with a bold, bright skylit roof
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a buff</NUMEX>-tiled floor. Clothes and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> arts and crafts have
        replaced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> that used to be sold here, but
        the fine old marble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counters</ENAMEX> have not been touched.
        Chinatown
        Away from the expressways and southeast from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>
        Market lie the exotic offerings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinatown</ENAMEX>, within the boundaries of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jalan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jalan Bandar</ENAMEX> (now known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jalan Tun H. S. Lee</ENAMEX>), and
        especially along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jalan Petaling</ENAMEX>. You will find everything from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apothecaries</ENAMEX> who display their herbs and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX> in porcelain jars to
        Nepalese <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> offering exotic jewelry, from fortune-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tellers</ENAMEX> to pet
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>.
        At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jalan Petaling</ENAMEX> is closed to traffic, the
        area comes alive, giving way to peddlers selling watches (bewildering
        replicas of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> brands), music and video cassettes, clothing,
        jewelry, and ornaments. The side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> are full of open-air
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX> offering dishes of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">barbecued pork</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>, and seafood,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">noodles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX>-pots, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">do-it-yourself ‚Äústeamboats</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        Past the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jalan Tun H. S. Lee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jalan Cheng Lock</ENAMEX> junction
        is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">See Yeoh Temple</ENAMEX>, founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yap Ay Koy</ENAMEX>, a city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early days</TIMEX>. The largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chan See Shu Yuen</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1906</TIMEX>, is
        dedicated to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chong Wah</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sung dynasty emperor</ENAMEX>. It also marks
        Chinatown‚Äôs southern boundary.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the breathtaking displays of color comes soon after
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kwoong Siew Association Temple</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sri Mahamariamman Hindu</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jalan Bandar</ENAMEX>, on the west side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinatown</ENAMEX>. It was built in
        the style of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">south Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gopuram</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> gatehouse-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>), covered
        with a riot of colorful statuary from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu pantheon</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> erected
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1873</TIMEX>, it was shunted across to its present <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> to make way for the
        railway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1855</TIMEX>, and it is from here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the annual</TIMEX> Thaipusam
        pilgrimage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Batu Caves</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX>) commences.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX> and east of the historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> is KL‚Äôs ‚ÄúGolden
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triangle</ENAMEX>,‚Äù which is a newer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, entertainment, and shopping
        district. Nearby are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the tallest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">landmarks</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX>
        drawn to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Petronas Twin Towers</ENAMEX>, located north of this triangle and
        known officially as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuala Lumpur City Centre</ENAMEX> (KLCC), will be
        disappointed to find that there is no public access to the upper
        stories. It is possible to retreat into the shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> next door for
        up-market fashions and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. For the best views of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> try the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Menara Kuala Lumpur‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇor</ENAMEX> communications <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tower‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwhich</ENAMEX> opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> and rises to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">421</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,381 ft</NUMEX>) on the western edge of the district.
        The non-stop lift takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">55 seconds</TIMEX> from ground to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">observatory</ENAMEX>, but
        offers spectacular views of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and beyond! For those wanting to
        eat on the move, there is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seri Angkasa</ENAMEX> revolving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> on the
        level above.
        Cultural and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Historical Sights</ENAMEX>
        Located on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jalan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hishamuddin</ENAMEX> opposite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL Railway</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Station‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇin what was once the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Majestic Hotel‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇis the Balai</ENAMEX> Senilukis
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Art Gallery</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> and foreign art. West of the
        railway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and within view is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masjid Negara</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Mosque</ENAMEX>),
        a vast, modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> covering <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 5 hectares</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">13 acres</NUMEX>). On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fridays</TIMEX>
        and other important religious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> it can house <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,000</NUMEX> worshippers under
        the tent-like stone roof of its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Hall</ENAMEX>. Walls of openwork stone
        tracery support a canopy of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> folds fanning out in a circle. These
        symbolize the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> pillars of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> faith. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mosque</ENAMEX> also includes ceremonial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, a library, a meeting hall, and a
        mausoleum for national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>, set around cool pools mirroring the blue
        stained-glass of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Hall</ENAMEX> and marble <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>. Soaring above it
        all is a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">73-m</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">239-ft</ENAMEX>) high minaret, with a graceful balcony from which
        the muezzin calls the faithful to prayer.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muzium Negara</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Museum</ENAMEX>) stands on Jalan
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Damansara</ENAMEX> south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Gardens</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>,
        blends modern and traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> design. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> glass mosaic murals
        flanking the entrance depict themes of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysia‚Äôs</ENAMEX> culture and history.
        There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> dedicated to such subjects as history,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> sports, and na tural history.
        Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National History Museum</ENAMEX> on Jalan
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raja</ENAMEX> south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dataran Merdeka</ENAMEX>, with exhibits on the country‚Äôs
        history dating back <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">520 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> (metamorphic sandstone) as well
        as a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40,000-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homo sapiens</ENAMEX> skull. The older <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Malaysian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Museum</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>) on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jalan Semarak</ENAMEX> highlights the war against the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insurgents</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948 to 1960</TIMEX>, known as <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúThe Emergency</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù On
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Malaysia</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Art Museum</ENAMEX>, with
        exhibits of sculptures and textiles from within the region. Given the
        extent of wealth it has brought to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, it is not surprising to
        have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural Rubber Museum</ENAMEX>, which opened since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rubber</ENAMEX>
        Research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Institute‚Äôs Experimental Station</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sungai Buloh</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taman Tasik Perdana</ENAMEX> (The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Gardens</ENAMEX>)
        West of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masjid Negara</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taman Tasik Perdana</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gardens</ENAMEX>). These <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">911‚ÅÑ2 hectares</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">238 acres</NUMEX>) of parkland were landscaped
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1888</TIMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Swettenham</ENAMEX> for the
        citizens‚Äô relaxation. It is a popular place for picnicking, jogging,
        and resting beneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, and it features an artificial lake for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boating</ENAMEX>, providing a lovely escape from the city‚Äôs tensions. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gardens</ENAMEX> are also home to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">deer park</ENAMEX> and a vast expanse of netting
        marking the aviary of the bird <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, within which are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>.
        Within the bounds of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gardens</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planetarium</ENAMEX> and exhibition as
        well as space theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>.
        Set on a hill at the northern end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> across a main
        road, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tugu Negara</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Monument</ENAMEX>) commemorates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malaysia‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        recent dark history through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúEmergency‚Äù</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX> to
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>. The bronze <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> sculpture <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> in an attractive setting of
        reflecting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> and fountains with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one end</TIMEX>. It was
        designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felix de Weldon</ENAMEX> and bears a striking similarity to his Iwo
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jima Memorial</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pacific War</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>. Triumphant
        flagbearers are flanked by armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> while another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> helps a
        wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrade</ENAMEX>. Beneath them sprawl the enemy‚Äôs dead. Also on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Monument</ENAMEX> grounds is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cenotaph</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Commonwealth‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        dead of the two <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World Wars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West of the Monument</ENAMEX>, just outside the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">park</ENAMEX>, is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament House</ENAMEX>, which holds the sessions of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX>.
        Away From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Center</ENAMEX>
        To see the tin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">magnates‚Äô mansions</ENAMEX> that remain standing,
        take a taxi ride on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jalan Ampang</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">some 10 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 miles</NUMEX>) northwest out of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX>. A few of these grand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th- and 20th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX> survive
        tucked away among the skyscrapers, the jungle often invading the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gardens</ENAMEX>. They offer insight into the massive wealth amassed by the tin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magnates</ENAMEX> during their heyday.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of thebest preserved is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dewan Tunku Abdul Rahman</ENAMEX>,
        built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> tin and rubber <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eu Tong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nowadays it</ENAMEX>
        is a one-stop center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Information Complex</ENAMEX>.
        Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> will be able to point out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bok House</ENAMEX>,
        transformed into the elegant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coq</ENAMEX> d‚ÄôOr <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restaurant</ENAMEX>. It is a beautiful
        structure, retaining its porticoed verandas, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th- century</TIMEX> paintings,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX>. It was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chu Cheng Bok</ENAMEX>, a
        legendary rags-to-riches <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX> who gave up the old iron of his
        bicycle repair <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> for a fortune in tin and other business. His will
        decreed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> never to be sold, ensuring the mansion‚Äôs future, even
        as other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX> fell into disrepair and demolition, often to be
        replaced by skyscrapers.
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> to the new sports <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bukit Jalil</ENAMEX> takes you
        to the centerpiece of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malaysia‚Äôs</ENAMEX> site for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Commonwealth Games</ENAMEX>.
        The spectacular partially covered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> has a capacity of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>;
        nearby is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX>-seat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aquatic Center</ENAMEX>. The complex adds to the Negara
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Merdeka</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> near the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
        While there are an ever-increasing number of major
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> stalls and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> markets remain a favorite throughout
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> for good deals, excellent local <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, and just plain
        entertainment value. The cheapest of the markets is at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chow Kit</ENAMEX>, where
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batu Road crosses Jalang Dang</ENAMEX>. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">market</ENAMEX> catering to more
        traditional tastes is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kampung Bahru</ENAMEX> (new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>), behind the Chow
        Kit area. This market is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pasar Minggu</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Market</ENAMEX>), but like so
        many other similar markets throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, it begins late
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> and trades on into the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early hours</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day Trips</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theme Parks</ENAMEX>
        As prosperity has taken hold in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, so too has the
        style of entertainment. Just beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> now are several theme
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parks</ENAMEX> built out of the remains of the gorges created from tin mining.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mines Wonderland</ENAMEX> has been built on what was the world‚Äôs largest
        open-cast mining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South of Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> along <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jalan</ENAMEX> Sungai
        Besi, it includes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX>-making <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> feel in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tropics</ENAMEX>. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunway Lagoon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bandar Sunway</ENAMEX>, located near
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selangor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shah Alam</ENAMEX>; it is known for its water
        attractions and rides.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Batu Caves</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Batu Caves</ENAMEX> are a popular excursion <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> minutes‚Äô
        drive north of town just off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ipoh Road</ENAMEX>. Set in limestone cliffs
        hidden in the jungle, they were ‚Äúdiscovered‚Äù in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1878</TIMEX> by a group of
        explorers, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">naturalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Hornaday</ENAMEX>. The
        caves were a hide-out for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Japanese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX> during
        <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. Now transformed into a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX>, they receive their
        most attention during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Thaipusam festival</ENAMEX> celebrated in the early
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months of each year</TIMEX>.
        There are in fact dozens of underground limestone vaults
        attracting botanists and zoologists to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> their unique <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flora</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fauna</ENAMEX>, but only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> caves are open to the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>. At the top
        of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">272</NUMEX>-step staircase is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cathedral Cave</ENAMEX>, the most breathtaking of
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, with its architectural columns of lofty stalactites and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stalagmites</ENAMEX>. At the foot of the hill, a bridge over a pond leads to the
        Art <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gallery Cave</ENAMEX>, with displays of garish statues of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">deities</ENAMEX>, and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Poets Cave</ENAMEX>, where verses of the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tamil</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thiruvalluvar</ENAMEX>
        are painted on stone tablets. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-line kural verses deal
        variously with morals, wisdom, love, and finances.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Templer Park</ENAMEX>
        Farther north (another <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9 km/6 miles</NUMEX> along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ipoh Road</ENAMEX>)
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Batu Caves</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Templer Park</ENAMEX>, which offers the sights of a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> rainforest for those with little time to venture into the
        major national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and forested areas. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britain‚Äôs</ENAMEX> last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX>, Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Templer</ENAMEX>, conceived the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">‚Äúvast</ENAMEX> jungle
        retreat for the public‚Äù in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>. Covering an area of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,200 hectares</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,000 acres</NUMEX>), the rainforest comes complete with waterfalls, rushing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">streams</ENAMEX>, lagoons for swimming, and caves in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bukit Takum</ENAMEX> limestone
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">cliffs</ENAMEX> to explore. There are several clearly defined paths, with the
        highest point being <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bukit Takum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">740 m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,428 ft</NUMEX>) on the western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">side</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">river</ENAMEX> in the park‚Äôs northern corner. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">golf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX>, two
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">courses</ENAMEX> reassure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> you are close to civilization.
        The Highlands
        By the time <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> came under the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> imperial sway,
        colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> had fully developed the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, where they could cool off from the hot and humid lowlands
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> before air-conditioning. These <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">havens</ENAMEX> of relaxation set
        among golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, gardens, and orchards still do the mountain ranges
        of the peninsula‚Äôs interior, but they are now holiday <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nowadays</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are lured to the highlands closest to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kuala Lumpur‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇThe Genting</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Fraser‚Äôs Hill‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇwhile the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highlands</ENAMEX> is most popular region for foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. These retreats
        offer everything from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> to horseback riding, golf to jungle
        trekking, depending on the location. The jungles, especially in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Highlands</ENAMEX>, were once the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strongholds</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> during the
        Emergency, so some caution is required when venturing into undeveloped
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>; good maps are a must, and on occasions a guide would be
        recommended.
        Genting Highlands
        Nearest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">highland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">resort areas</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">km</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 miles</NUMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gentings</ENAMEX> rise to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,000 m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6,560 ft</NUMEX>) and are a far
        cry from the peaceful, misty, forested mountains they were just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades ago</TIMEX>. Now, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> and hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> is variously described
        as simply noisy to a ‚Äúone-stop destination for fantasy, excitement, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adventure‚Äù</ENAMEX>; your conclusion obviously depends on your point of view.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find a wide range of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> here, from an 18-hole golf
        course to a theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> with cinemas, a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">monorail</ENAMEX>, boat-rides, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">restaurants‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇeven</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32-</NUMEX>lane <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>-pin bowling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. The resort‚Äôs
        casino is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malaysia‚</ENAMEX>Äôs only such legal gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, with strict dress
        codes requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to wear ties or long-sleeved batik shirts.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fraser‚Äôs Hill</ENAMEX>
        In contrast to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genting Highlands</ENAMEX>, this charming,
        old-fashioned hill <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, located <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60 miles</NUMEX>) northwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX>,
        is built across <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> hills, its highest point being <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4,921 ft</NUMEX>)
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Titiwangsa</ENAMEX> mountain range. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX> it offers a retreat for
        Malaysia‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> set. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> was named after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis James Fraser</ENAMEX>,
        an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> adventurer and scoundrel, who dealt in mule hides, tin,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opium</ENAMEX>, and gambling. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fraser</ENAMEX> disappeared mysteriously before the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> came into being, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>.
        Road access may be difficult, with the last <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 miles</NUMEX>)
        along a winding, narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roadway</ENAMEX> where an alternating, one-way traffic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> is in place. It was along this portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, where you‚Äôll now
        see a sign <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúEmergency Historical Site</ENAMEX>,‚Äù that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British High Commissioner</ENAMEX>
        Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Gurney</ENAMEX> was killed during the height of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insurgency</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>.
        The countryside is wilder and less cultivated than that in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Highlands</ENAMEX>, but the sedate side of colonial life is also
        more recognizable here in the white-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grey stone bungalows</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">roses</ENAMEX>, rhododendrons, poinsettias, hollyhocks, and dahlias in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gardens</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find a range of accommodation on offer, from the Jalai
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill Resort</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puncak Inn</ENAMEX> in the top tier to more middle-range <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">inns</ENAMEX>,
        bungalows, and even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> hostel. There are good tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, a
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>-hole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX>, tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playgrounds</ENAMEX>, and even horseback
        riding.
        Several nature <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> are also marked out through the
        nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">forests</ENAMEX>, and the wealth of wildlife makes jungle rambles
        particularly enjoyable. A swim is possible at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeriau Waterfall</ENAMEX>,
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">41‚ÅÑ2 km</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 miles</NUMEX>) north of town. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birdwatchers</ENAMEX> look out for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 270</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> which may be seen in the immediate area. Each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature Society</ENAMEX> supports an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúinternational bird</ENAMEX> race,‚Äù
        where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> compete to identify the largest number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Highlands</ENAMEX>
        The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">finest</TIMEX> of the cool hill resorts, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">240 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">150 miles</NUMEX>)
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX>, stands on a splendid plateau of rolling green valleys
        surrounded by the rugged granite peaks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Titiwangsa Range</ENAMEX>, the
        tallest of which is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Brinchang</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,032</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6,664 ft</NUMEX>). If you‚Äôve
        been traveling on the coast, or elsewhere in semi-tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Highlands</ENAMEX>, located <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 1,520 m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4,987 ft</NUMEX>) above sea
        level, offer great relief amid morning mists and cool breezes.
        Spread over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">townships</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ringlet</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tanah Rata‚ÄÇ (‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">township</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinchang</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ringlet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">township</ENAMEX>, the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> point of arrival, offers little that is special, apart from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flower nurseries</ENAMEX> and access to some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX>. Thirteen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kilometers</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7 miles</NUMEX>) farther brings you to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanah Rata</ENAMEX>, the main
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">township</ENAMEX>. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ringlet</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Bakar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX>, an
        artificial lake formed by the damming of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bertam River</ENAMEX>. Brinchang, a
        few <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more kilometers</NUMEX> beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanah Rata</ENAMEX>, is better known for its
        vegetable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">farms</ENAMEX>, and of course, the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">hill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> was named after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cameron</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        surveyor, who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1885</TIMEX> reported the finding of the ‚Äúfine plateau. ‚Äù His
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúdiscovery‚Äù</ENAMEX> was soon followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea planters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> vegetable
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">growers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highlands</ENAMEX> also still hold the answer to the mysterious
        disappearance of wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Thai</ENAMEX>-silk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Thompson</ENAMEX>,
        who disappeared on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> after going off for stroll while
        on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX> at the hill <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highlands</ENAMEX> are best reached by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KL‚ÄìButterworth</ENAMEX> line to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tapah Road</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and then by taxi up into the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hills</ENAMEX>. Driving yourself on the narrow winding road with frequent
        back-ups imposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> in a hurry could be a hazardous business.
        Let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> worry about that, while you admire the magnificent
        scenery changing from lowland mangrove, bamboo, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">palms</ENAMEX>, to denser
        rainforest of lush greenery and, as the heat drops away to the more
        comfortable mountain air, montane <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oaks</ENAMEX> and laurels familiar to
        temperate climates.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanah Rata</ENAMEX> is festooned with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tearooms</ENAMEX> serving the
        local Cameronian <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">brew</ENAMEX> together with cakes and servings of locally grown
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">strawberries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Stores</ENAMEX> offer everything from the practical to
        glass-mounted scorpions and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX>.
        A visit to a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX> is easily arranged, with bus
        service readily available to and from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX>. The main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX>
        are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boh Tea Estate</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sungai Palas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">estates</ENAMEX>. Accommodation options in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tanah Rata</ENAMEX> vary depending on your
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX>, with the upper tier offering international-class <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> such
        as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strawberry Park</ENAMEX>, to the moderately priced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cameronian Holiday Inn</ENAMEX>.
        Worth a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">visit‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇeven</ENAMEX> if you can‚Äôt afford the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> rates‚<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇis Ye</ENAMEX> Olde
        Smokehouse near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX>. The ivy-covered, mock-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tudor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> has
        become something of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> since it was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>. An
        afternoon traditional ‚Äúcream tea‚Äù or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> roast lunch or dinner is
        an experience in itself. Nearby is a fine 18-hole public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beautifully</ENAMEX> kept despite the strange hazard of a narrow, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concrete</ENAMEX>-sided
        canal running across the middle of it.
        The cooler climate makes jungle walks here a special
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pleasure</ENAMEX>, not least of all for the myriad brightly colored butterflies
        around the waterfalls, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost a dozen</NUMEX> officially listed. Several
        of the walks pass <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">through‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇor close to‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇthe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research Development Institute</ENAMEX>, just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few kilometers</NUMEX> from Tahan
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rata</ENAMEX>.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most clearly marked paths from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanah Rata</ENAMEX>, easiest
        for the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, lead within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> to a refreshing swim at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parit</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falls or Robinson Falls</ENAMEX>. Other, more challenging choices, for which you
        should enlist the help of a guide, take you up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Perdah</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,576</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">m/5</ENAMEX>,169 ft), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Jasar</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,696 m/5,562 ft</NUMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Beremban</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,841</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">m/6</ENAMEX>,040 ft). Besides the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX>, look out for red-bellied
        squirrels, wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX>, and, if you are lucky, an occasional tapir. The
        local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Butterfly Farm</ENAMEX> is probably your best chance of seeing the grand
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúRajah Brooke Birdwing‚</ENAMEX>Äù and other rare <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>.
        Perak
        A journey to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perak</ENAMEX> takes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> into what once was
        the key region for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia‚Äôs</ENAMEX> economic prosperity, standing as a lure
        to powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and interests as well as (mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>) migrant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tin</ENAMEX>, the basis for the state‚Äôs wealth, was once taken from
        diggings that claimed to be the largest such <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> in the world. The
        wealth from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> paid for many of the historical structures
        evident through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Perak, which means ‚Äúsilver‚Äù in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>, is
        Malaysia‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, reaching from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tanjung Malim</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">south</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> border, covering some <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">21,000 sq km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">13,125 sq miles</NUMEX>).
        Its sultan‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is also the last to be able to trace its ancestry
        to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sultans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ipoh</ENAMEX> may be considered the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of the
        world‚Äôs tin industry. It superseded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perak‚</ENAMEX>Äôs other rich mining <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taiping</ENAMEX> (formerly known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Larut</ENAMEX>), in this role in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ipoh</ENAMEX> is now
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuala Kangsar</ENAMEX> is the royal
        capital and has been home to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perak‚</ENAMEX>Äôs sultans since the 15th
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>.
        The journey north from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX> either by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> takes you
        through a captivating landscape of jungle reaching back from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coastal</ENAMEX> plains to climb the blue hills of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Barisan Titiwangsa Range</ENAMEX>.
        Amid this wild beauty, enhanced by spectacular outcrops of limestone
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rock</ENAMEX>, are the tell-tale scars of the tin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kinta Valley</ENAMEX>.
        Ipoh
        Once the harbo r for all incoming junks and sampans from
        the Straits of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Perak River</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is located on
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kinta River</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">220 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">135 miles</NUMEX>) north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX>. The town offers good
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accommodations</ENAMEX> and amenities, including a range of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> specialties, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steamed chicken</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bean sprouts</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">noodles</ENAMEX>.
        The echoes of colonialism are clearly evident in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Railway Station</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Moorish</ENAMEX> architecture is reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and is locally nicknamed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚Äúthe Taj Mahal‚Äù;</ENAMEX> nearby is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Majestic Station Hotel</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Court</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shanghai Bank</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are also excellent examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Edwardian</ENAMEX> architecture. Other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memories</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">presence</ENAMEX> are in the clock <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>, commemorating
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Birch</ENAMEX>, who was assassinated
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1875</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Michael‚Äôs School</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Ipoh Club</ENAMEX> are also
        monuments of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">colonial</ENAMEX> era.
        Around <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jalan Dato‚Äô Sagor</ENAMEX> and the nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> are some of
        the best preserved examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> architecture in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>. For
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX> into the local tin mining industry, visit the excellent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geological Museum</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jalan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Azlan Shah</ENAMEX>. In addition to exhibits
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perak‚</ENAMEX>Äôs rich variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">minerals</ENAMEX>, ores, and fossils are models of
        tin-mining equipment. Other insights into history are to be found at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darul Ridzuan Museum</ENAMEX>, housed in the former <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of wealthy tin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miner Foo Choong Yit</ENAMEX>.
        Outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, amid vast caves in limestone outcrops,
        are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> temples. In the south the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kek Lok Tong</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Poh Tong</ENAMEX>
        temples are nestled within high limestone caves and cavities near
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gunung Rapat</ENAMEX>. The latter dates back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890s</TIMEX>, while the present fa√ßade
        was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> still home to a group of monks
        and nuns. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kilometers</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 miles</NUMEX>) north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ipoh</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perak Tong</ENAMEX>,
        built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1926</TIMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Here the main attraction
        is a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">13-m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX>-ft) sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> amid the eerie darkened cavern;
        altogether there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> statues.
        Saved from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> over-growth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two decades</TIMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7 miles</NUMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ipoh</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kellie‚Äôs Castle</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> whose
        construction was halted when its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kellie Smith</ENAMEX>, a rubber
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">planter</ENAMEX>, died while visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1920s</TIMEX>. Farther south,
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Teluk Intan</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia‚Äôs</ENAMEX> equivalent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">leaning tower of Pisa</ENAMEX>.
        The pagoda-like structure, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1885</TIMEX>, is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">251‚ÅÑ2 m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84</NUMEX> ft) tall and
        was once used for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> storage.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kuala Kangsar</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Home</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sultans of Perak</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 500 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kangsar</ENAMEX> is built on a sweep of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Perak River</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sungei Perak</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 km</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ipoh</ENAMEX> on a newer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">royal palaces</ENAMEX>;
        the brash stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Istana Iskandariah</ENAMEX>, and the more elegant
        traditional timbered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Istana Kenangan</ENAMEX>, now used as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Museum</ENAMEX>. This
        is also where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malaysia‚</ENAMEX>Äôs rubber industry started with the planting of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> seedlings by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Low</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1877</TIMEX>, one of which still
        survives near the district <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jalan Raja Bendahara</ENAMEX>. The most
        striking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, up on a grass mound, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ubudiah Mosque</ENAMEX>, with its
        massive onion <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> of glowing copper <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">set</ENAMEX> in a nest of white. Begun in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX>, its construction was interrupted on several occasions, most
        dramatically when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idris</ENAMEX> went on a rampage
        on the imported <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuala Kangsar</ENAMEX> has long been famous for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malay College</ENAMEX>, set
        amid spacious grounds near the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, a prestigious and
        exclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> aristocracy since it was founded by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904</TIMEX>. It is now open to the best (<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> of all
        classes.
        Taiping
        Another <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 minutes‚Äô</NUMEX> drive from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Kangsar</ENAMEX>, this old
        mining <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> was formerly known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Larut</ENAMEX>. Its present-day name, meaning
        ‚Äúeverlasting peace,‚Äù was proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> as part of its diplomatic
        contribution to the end of the bloody feuds between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> secret
        societies fighting over control of the tin-mining industry in the
        1870s. They were forced to end their conflict under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Treaty</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pangor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1874</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> intervention.
        Happily boasting the peninsula‚Äôs heaviest rainfalls,
        Taiping, the former capital of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, is now a sleepy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> full
        of large treesoverhanging the wide <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. It was able to landscape a
        magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Gardens</ENAMEX>, from an tin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> abandoned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890</TIMEX>,
        then owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chung Keng Kwee</ENAMEX>. The grounds are now home to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-hole
        golf course, a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX>, and an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Rest House</ENAMEX> (now a
        hotel) combining <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Neo-Classical Doric</ENAMEX> columns with a slightly curving
        Minangkagau <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">roof‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇideal</ENAMEX> for shedding the heavy rains.
        Built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1886</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perak Museum</ENAMEX>, housing an interesting
        display of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orang Asli</ENAMEX> implements, is the oldest in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>. On the way, you will pass the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> and then for guerrilla <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> captured during the
        Emergency. Built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1885</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> carries out most of the
        executions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malaysia‚</ENAMEX>Äôs drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX>.
        Beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Gardens</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taiping War Cemetery</ENAMEX> bears
        impressive witness to the peninsula‚Äôs early role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific War</ENAMEX>
        against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>. The tombs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Australian Air</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Army Corps of Clerks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambulance Sepoy</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>
        Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Air Force</ENAMEX> reveal that many of them died on the
        very <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first day</TIMEX> of active duty: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1941</TIMEX>.
        Once a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> estate, cool, cloud-enshrouded Bukit Larut
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell Hill</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">71‚ÅÑ2 miles</NUMEX>) northeast from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taipin</ENAMEX>, was
        Malaysia‚Äôs smallest and oldest hill <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and the retreat for
        colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,035</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,400 ft</NUMEX>) above sea level, it has
        great views when the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">misty rain</ENAMEX>-clouds break. Near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jeep terminal</ENAMEX>,
        pretty bungalows and rest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> offer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> for rent, with balconies
        overlooking the valley, but booking in advance is necessary. The walk
        to the summit is signposted, and upon reaching the top on a clear day
        it is possible to view the sweep of the coastline from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penang</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pangkor</ENAMEX>.
        Pulau Pangkor
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the few locations on the west coast to offer
        palm-fringed beaches is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pulau Pangkor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pangkor Island</ENAMEX>). The beaches are
        a regular holiday retreat, offering swimming and other activities as
        well as jungle walks. The ferry from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lumut</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 50 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">31 miles</NUMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">south of Taiping</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pangkor Island</ENAMEX> takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 45 minutes</TIMEX>. Once there,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">you‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find the wide sands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pantai Puteri Dewi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beach</ENAMEX> of the
        Beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX>) along the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">122</NUMEX>-hectare (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">301-acre</NUMEX>) island‚Äôs northern
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shore</ENAMEX>. It is part of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pangkor Laut Resort</ENAMEX>, one of the most exclusive
        destinations in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>.
        Taman Negara
        This grand national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> provides an ideal setting for
        exploring vast expanses of rainforest, fast-flowing rivers, and
        mountains of the peninsula‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main Range</ENAMEX>. It covers an area of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4,343 sq</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">km</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,676 sq miles</NUMEX>), spreading across <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pahang, Terengganu</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelantan</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Backpackers</ENAMEX> may want to go it alone, but most are advised
        to plan their visit through a tour <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX> or before they leave
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>. Armed with an entry permit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> make <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">park</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">300 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">187 miles</NUMEX>) northeast of the national capital
        by road via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerantut</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">37 miles</NUMEX>) by motor-powered longboat
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Tembeling</ENAMEX>. (Buy your film, batteries, mineral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>,
        insect-repellent, etc. , at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerantut</ENAMEX>: everything is more expensive
        inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. )
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> ride on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tembeling River</ENAMEX> is likely to be one
        of the highlights of your visit. Along the way, you will see aboriginal
        Negrito <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fishermen‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> only human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> allowed to stay here by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">park authorities‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsetting</ENAMEX> or checking their nets. Keep a look out,
        too, for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> buffalo taking a soak, river-lizards slipping in and out
        of the water and looking as large as crocodiles (the latter do not come
        this far upstream), and even an occasional otter. Among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>, you
        will see the flash of a kingfisher or hornbill. Wear a hat and bring
        along plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mineral water</ENAMEX>. The journey usually takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX>,
        even longer when short stretches of the river dry up, forcing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> to walk along the riverbank while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">boatmen</ENAMEX> push the
        launch through the shallows.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuala Tahan</ENAMEX> have a good range of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accommodation‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇchalets</ENAMEX>, a hostel, and a rest house‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇplus washing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and a grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. Payment is strictly in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> currency. (For your trekking requirements, see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">181</NUMEX>. )
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park headquarters</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">organize evening</TIMEX> slide-shows as a general
        introduction to the features of the surrounding rainforest.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jungle Trails</ENAMEX>
        There are marked <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> leading from the park‚Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> into the jungle. Guides use them for organized walking and
        boat tours, but you can, of course, go off in your own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. There are
        both day trips and overnight tours to observation-hides, from where you
        can watch for wildlife visiting nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX>-licks and watering holes.
        Overnight stays are organized at several observation-hides in the
        region, namely at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kumbang, Yong, Tabing, Belau</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cegar Anjing</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Headquarters</ENAMEX> will provide sheets if you do not have a sleeping bag. You
        should be in the hide by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX> and out again the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">next morning</TIMEX>
        at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">around 9:30am</TIMEX>. From <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park headquarters</ENAMEX>, day trips leaving in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> include: a walk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bukit Indah</ENAMEX>, followed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> ride
        through the rapids to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Trenggan</ENAMEX>, returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> on
        foot; a walk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tabing Hide</ENAMEX>, followed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> ride to the Lata
        Berkoh rapids, then another trek back to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>; a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> ride on
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tembeling River</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gua Telinga Bat Cave</ENAMEX>, which you enter on
        hands and knees until you can stand‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇyou then find yourself in a great
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vault</ENAMEX> inhabited by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>- and insect-eating bats not at all
        interested in attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. Only the squeamish will object to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toads</ENAMEX> and harmless little white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cave-racer snakes</ENAMEX>.
        The most adventurous trek for experienced climbers is a
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full nine-day</TIMEX> walk up and down the peninsula‚Äôs highest peak, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tahan</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,187 m/7,173 ft</NUMEX>) high. A jungle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> accompanies the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Flora</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fauna</ENAMEX>
        The dipterocarp rainforest here includes the tualang <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>.
        At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 m</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">164 ft</ENAMEX>), it is the tallest <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX>. Among the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">jungle fruit</ENAMEX> are mango, durian, rambutan, and wild <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX>. At over
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,500 m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5,000 ft</NUMEX>), you will see montane <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oaks</ENAMEX> and conifers.
        With patience and luck by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> or rotating shift watches by
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, you may see wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX>, sambars, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">barking deer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gibbons</ENAMEX>,
        pig-tailed macaques and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">leaf monkeys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree shrews</ENAMEX>, and red flying
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">squirrels</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kumbang Hide</ENAMEX> have seen rare <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leopards</ENAMEX>.
        During the fruit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">birdwatchers</ENAMEX> have spotted up to
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> just around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park headquarters</ENAMEX>. Among them: lesser fish
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eagle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">crested serpent eagle</ENAMEX>, osprey, peacock pheasant, and garnet
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pitta</ENAMEX>. From <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September to March</TIMEX> you can also see migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arctic</ENAMEX>
        warblers, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> paradise flycatchers, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Siberian</ENAMEX> blue <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">robins</ENAMEX>.
        Even if you do not spot much of the wildlife we
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mention‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇand you are almost assured of seeing something‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe sheer
        experience of the jungle at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, with its incredible noises, the
        flitting of mysterious fireflies, and the sense of invisible but
        omnipresent life and movement around you make it all worthwhile.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX>
        For the romantics, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">township</ENAMEX> names of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Dickson</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX> (formerly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malacca</ENAMEX>) on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX> evoke stories of the
        glorious past of sailing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> junks carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX>,
        silks, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, of cutlasses, noble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">princesses</ENAMEX>. In
        many ways this is the story of southwestern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia‚</ENAMEX>Äôs southwest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coastline</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nowadays</ENAMEX>, the rich tapestry of history lies in the monuments
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> colonizers. In the far north,
        Pulau <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penang</ENAMEX> is both holiday destination and commercial center, while
        closer to the border with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulau Langkawi</ENAMEX> is the newest resort
        destination for those in search of white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sands</ENAMEX> and gentle seas.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX> to Melaka
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selangor</ENAMEX> leads through
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Negeri Sembilan</ENAMEX>, literally the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúnine states‚Äù federated</ENAMEX> as one in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th century</TIMEX>. You travel past the vast palm oil and rubber plantations
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seremban</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">64 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 miles</NUMEX>) southwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX>.
        Sereban
        Here the architecturally distinctive Minangkabau
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">buffalo</ENAMEX>-horn roofs of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sumatran</ENAMEX> heritage are evident, together with the
        more recent colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> style and the traditions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
        commercial shophouses. The main attractions are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Legislative</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assembly Building</ENAMEX>, a nest of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> roofs, one for each founding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>,
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taman Seni Budaya Negeri</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts and Culture Complex</ENAMEX>). Visit the
        state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, and in the grounds opposite is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kampung Ampang Tinggi</ENAMEX>,
        built entirely of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> prince‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>. On show in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX> are weapons as well as brass and silverware and a tableau
        portraying a grand royal wedding. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neo-Classical State Library</ENAMEX>, with
        its imposing colonial fa√ßade, was once the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">State Secretarial Building</ENAMEX>.
        Opposite is the extensive <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Gardens</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sri Menanti</ENAMEX>
        For what is probably the best original example of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Minangkabau</ENAMEX> architecture, take a side trip to the old royal capital, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">km</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">23 miles</NUMEX>) east of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seremban</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuala Pilah Road</ENAMEX>. The ruler‚Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">palace, Istana Lama</ENAMEX>, was the official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> of the royal family
        until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX>, replacing an earlier palace which had burnt down. The
        palace features <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99</NUMEX> pillars, denoting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX> of various luak
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">clans</NUMEX>).
        Melaka
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melaka</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malacca</ENAMEX>), easily reached by air or express bus
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KL</ENAMEX>, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malaysia‚Äôs</ENAMEX> first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, built on the trading empires of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX> and textiles and a history soaked in the blood of battles as
        rival colonial powers challenged each other to take hold of the port.
        In its glorious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15th-century</TIMEX> heyday, it had been the most vital <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> docked as the city‚Äôs
        sultans expanded their territorial reach from the wealth of trade to as
        far as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pahang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> and even to the east coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumatra</ENAMEX>.
        Today, even as the high-rise makes its present felt, the colonial past
        remains in the architecture and monuments. The city‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinatown</ENAMEX> and
        especially along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jalan Hang Jebat‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇonce</ENAMEX> known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jonker Street‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇare
        havens for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antiques buyers</ENAMEX> or those who just want to browse along the
        street‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shophouses</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historic Center</ENAMEX>
        The main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of historical or cultural significance
        are all within easy walking distance of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch Square</ENAMEX>,
        down by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Melaka River</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> is situated just off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Melaka Bridge</ENAMEX>. Spanning
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">river</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> was once the town‚Äôs main strategic link between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">port</ENAMEX> and city and the site of major battles against the European
        invaders.
        The most prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> overlooking the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch Stadthuys</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Town Hall</ENAMEX>), dating from around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1650</TIMEX>. It was originally
        the official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. Behind
        the red fa√ßade is a structure of masonry hauled from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citadel</ENAMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> has housed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Ethnography</ENAMEX>
        and History, tracing the town‚Äôs colonial and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> past.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jam Besar</ENAMEX> (clock <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>) was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1886</TIMEX> by the
        family of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tang Bee Sweng</ENAMEX>. In the middle of the square
