
  
  
    
      
        Where To Go
        A good introduction to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> is a ride on the number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99</NUMEX>
        bus, which makes a circuit that includes many of the most important
        sights. After that, you‚Äôll want to explore the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>, magnificent
        and mysterious behind its walls, and filled with the most venerated
        sites of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>, Christianity, and Islam. You can wander on your own
        or join a guided walking tour (for routes and times, check with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Information</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Safra Square</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jaffa Gate</ENAMEX>). The walk
        atop the walls that surround the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX> is highly recommended.
        There is also much to see outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>, including
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">bustling</NUMEX> downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">districts of East</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Jerusalem</ENAMEX>; the ancient
        sites and vistas on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount of Olives</ENAMEX> and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kidron Valley</ENAMEX>; and,
        on the western hills of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, the dynamic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel Museum</ENAMEX>, the
        powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yad Vashem Holocaust Memorial</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>, and the contemporary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that house the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knesset</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court of the State of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most endlessly fascinating
        attraction, and it is easy to cover on foot. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> are narrow,
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of twisting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> souk or suq), steep stairways, and dark
        covered passageways. It will take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> to familiarize yourself
        with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">maze</ENAMEX>, several more before the principal landmarks become
        easily identifiable. Nobody ever seems to be able to pass from one holy
        place or historical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> to another without stopping along the way to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">browse</ENAMEX> through boxes of broken <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX>-era glass at an antiquities <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>,
        bargain for figs and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX> in the markets, sample <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> desserts, or
        examine old Hanukkah menorahs and hand-embroidered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bedouin</ENAMEX> caftans.
        Enjoy the experiences and give yourself plenty of time.
        The area of much of the present-day <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX> began to be
        included inside the walls of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only about 2,200 years ago</TIMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hasmonean</ENAMEX> and (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>) Herodian times. The original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, where
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX> reigned and where the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Testament</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prophets</ENAMEX> walked, was
        located on a lower ridge just to the south of the present <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>. As
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">warfare</ENAMEX> became more sophisticated, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> slowly moved northward and
        uphill to more defensible ground. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calvary</ENAMEX> (the site of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crucifixion</ENAMEX>), which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is deep inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>, was probably
        just outside its walls in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jesus‚Äôs</ENAMEX> time.
        The present city walls that make the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX> so impressive
        and give it architectural coherence were built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1538</TIMEX>, on the
        foundations of ancient walls that had been demolished at the end of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crusades</ENAMEX>. They were constructed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suleiman the Magnificent</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ottoman Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sultan</ENAMEX>, who never visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> but (according to
        tradition) had a dream that he would be devoured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX> unless he
        rebuilt the walls of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> walls, like much of the Old
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>, are composed of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> from many parts of the city‚Äôs long
        history.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jaffa Gate</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Armenian Quarter</ENAMEX>
        As you approach the walls near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jaffa Gate</ENAMEX>, look for flat,
        Herodian-era <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> with slightly recessed borders among the rougher
        square <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> from other periods. There are also beautiful carved
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX>, probably from the ruins of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crusader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, high in the wall
        just to the left of the gate itself. Facing the direction of both the
        port <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaffa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem‚Äôs New City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jaffa Gate</ENAMEX> is the
        traditional entrance for Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>.
        Just through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Information Office</ENAMEX>, and
        beside it are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX> tombs behind an iron fence.
        According to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> tradition, these are the tombs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> who were commanded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suleiman the Magnificent</ENAMEX> to rebuild
        the long-ruined city walls. Some say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> were executed for
        failing to include the entire area of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> inside the
        walls, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sultan</ENAMEX> had decreed. They were buried at this busy public
        place as a warning not to try to outsmart the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sultan</ENAMEX>. Another legend
        claims these are the graves of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> who chose death over
        separation by their powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
        Follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> inside <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jaffa Gate</ENAMEX> around to the right. The
        best way to enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citadel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> is through the ceremonial gate
        built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suleiman the Magnificent</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1531‚Äì1532</NUMEX>. A pair of massive
        medieval towers form part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citadel</ENAMEX>, which was the prime bastion
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,000 years</TIMEX> (built <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 1,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> of the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>). It bears inscriptions in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> varieties
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> script and leads to a bridge over the remains of the
        Citadel‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moat</ENAMEX>. Take time to mount the stairs to the battlements for
        views of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>; you can also explore the ruins and excavations.
        Inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tower of David</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> of the History of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> has
        displays outlining the history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX>). In the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evening</ENAMEX>, a dramatic sound-and-light show is held under the stars in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courtyard</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX>).
        Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moat</ENAMEX> entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citadel</ENAMEX> is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christ Church</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> built in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
        (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1849</TIMEX>). There are also a few caf√©s as well as public services including
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX>, a telephone kiosk, and a police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jaffa Gate</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citadel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Armenian</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Quarter</TIMEX>, which has been inhabited by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Armenians</ENAMEX> (the first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> to
        accept Christianity) since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early fourth century</TIMEX>. A short walk up
        the road past the police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, along the Street of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Armenian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patriarchate</ENAMEX>, brings you to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Armenian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral of Saint James</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">11th‚</ENAMEX>Äì12th <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>) and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convent</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> are allowed into the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ancient</ENAMEX> and mysterious church only during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Street</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX>
        The most direct route from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jaffa Gate</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citadel</ENAMEX>
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX> is by way of the intriguing bazaars along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">David</ENAMEX>
        Street (as you come through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaffa Gate</ENAMEX>, just walk in a straight line to
        the descending steps that begin beside the once-grand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petra Hotel</ENAMEX>). These markets are always fascinating. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Souvenir shops</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abound</ENAMEX>, their fa√ßades draped with carpets and cloths, their interiors
        piled high with treasures and trash. After examining the tourist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">establishments</ENAMEX>, don‚Äôt miss a look into the many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> aimed at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>.
        Arabic spice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> are filled with sacks of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fragrant powders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX>,
        and at the butchers‚Äô bazaar your eyes will meet those of a dozen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">disembodied sheep</ENAMEX> heads ready for the pot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tailors</ENAMEX>, cobblers,
        pita-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bakers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">metalworkers</ENAMEX> all ply their trades amid the din
        of hagglers in the endless labyrinths.
        As you continue your descent on the steps of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">David Street</ENAMEX>,
        you‚Äôll pass a gateway on the right that leads to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardo</ENAMEX>, which is
        worth a detour. Originally the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> times
        (cardo means ‚Äúheart‚Äù in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>), it was once a broad colonnaded market
        and ceremonial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> that went through the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Damascus Gate</ENAMEX> in the north to the southern edge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. In
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusader</ENAMEX> times, the wide, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Classical Cardo</ENAMEX> was re-shaped into the
        narrow, parallel bazaars that still lead northward (to the left) to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Damascus Gate</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, the southern portions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardo</ENAMEX>,
        long covered by the ruins of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jewish Quarter</TIMEX>, were excavated.
        Sections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardo</ENAMEX> just south of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">David Street</ENAMEX> have been renovated
        with modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>, but some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>-fronts have been left in
        their original <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> from the time of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crusades</ENAMEX>. Further south,
        Byzantine columns and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Corinthian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX> found in situ were
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-installed to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> an idea of how the original Cardo
        looked.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Street</ENAMEX> continues into the Street of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chain</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Es-Silsila</ENAMEX>), which leads straight toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate of the Chain</ENAMEX> (Bab
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">es-Silsila</ENAMEX>). This is only one of several entrances to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Haram</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">es-Sharif</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúnoble enclosure‚Äù</ENAMEX> atop the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX>. As you approach
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX> along the Street of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Chain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">you‚Äôll</ENAMEX> notice the
        imposing doorways of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mameluke</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from the 14th century</TIMEX>, with their stalactite-like ornamentation. You
        can visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, but on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fridays</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> Sabbath) and on major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> holidays, including
        the entire holy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Haram</ENAMEX> is closed to
        non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Moriah</ENAMEX>), where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX> built
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Temple</ENAMEX> and where later <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> returning from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babylonian Captivity</ENAMEX> built the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Temple</ENAMEX>, is holy ground to both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>. So sacred are the confines of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> site that
        strictly observant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> dare not even come here, for fear of walking on
        the unknown spot where the Holy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holies</ENAMEX> (sacred <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>) of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Temple</ENAMEX> once stood. The beautifully ornamented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Temple</ENAMEX>
        was completed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 960</NUMEX> b.c. , built on what had been the ceremonial
        high point of earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canaanite Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
        tradition, in even earlier times this site had been the altar where
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham</ENAMEX> prepared to sacrifice his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac</ENAMEX> and where the voice of God
        proclaimed such sacrifice was not necessary, an episode that forms one
        of the theological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> stones of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX> and of Western
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monotheism</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Babylonians</ENAMEX> destroyed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solomon‚Äôs Temple</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">587 b.c. and</TIMEX>
        led the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> into captivity. But by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">539</NUMEX> b.c. the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> (under the rule
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrus of Persia</ENAMEX>) were allowed to return from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babylonia</ENAMEX> and to build
        a modest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Temple</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 515</NUMEX> b.c. It was to last for 600 years
        (lavishly renovated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herod</ENAMEX> starting in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18 b.c.</TIMEX> ) until it was
        destroyed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> in a.d. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>.
        The magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome of the Rock</ENAMEX> is one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> sublime
        holy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> (the others are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mecca</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medina</ENAMEX>). Built by
        early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> in a.d. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">691</NUMEX> on the approximate site of the First
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Temples</ENAMEX>, it commemorates the spot to which the Prophet
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muhammad</ENAMEX> came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mecca</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">winged horse</ENAMEX> in a miraculous night
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">journey</ENAMEX> described in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koran</ENAMEX>. From this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prophet</ENAMEX> began his
        journey to paradise. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome of the Rock</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kubbet es-Sakhra</ENAMEX>) is
        Jerusalem‚Äôs most strikingly beautiful holy place; it is indeed one of
        the most extraordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in the world. Panels of brilliantly
        colored tiles (added by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suleiman the Magnificent</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-16th</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>) and bands of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koranic</ENAMEX> inscriptions surround the upper part of
        the octagonal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX>, while marble panels in muted colors offset this
        brilliance from below. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome</ENAMEX> was restored and gilded with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kg</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">176 pounds</NUMEX>) of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">24-karat</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> as a gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>.
        After purchasing a combined entrance ticket from a nearby
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stone</ENAMEX> kiosk for all the major <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX>, climb the
        steps to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome of the Rock</ENAMEX>. You must leave your shoes, bags, and
        cameras on the shelves near the door as you enter. If you visit with a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, plan for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to stay outside and guard valuables.
        The richness of the exterior of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dome</ENAMEX> is echoed, even
        excelled, inside. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> is surrounded by a richly worked wooden
        screen, and above it are stained-glass windows and black-and-gold
        mosaics, breathtaking in their beauty. Look carefully at the rock to
        find <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Muhammad‚</ENAMEX>Äôs footprint, and inspect the small tabernacle at its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern</ENAMEX> extremity, which holds <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several hairs</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prophet‚</ENAMEX>Äôs beard.
        Underneath the sacred rock is a grotto where, according to tradition,
        great prophets and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> of the past came to pray and where the souls
        of the dead travel for their devotions.
        Surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome of the Rock</ENAMEX> are smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> built at different times. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome of the Chain</ENAMEX> is a
        miniature copy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome of the Rock</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabeel Qait Bey</ENAMEX>, an ornate
        little <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosk</ENAMEX>, shows the fine design and craftsmanship of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Mameluke</ENAMEX> period; from this kiosk, fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> was served to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> times. By the arches and stairs leading down to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Aksa Mosque</ENAMEX> is the exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minbar</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kadi Burhan el-Din</ENAMEX>, a pulpit
        used in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> when prayers are said outdoors. Pass under the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arches</ENAMEX> and down the steps that lead to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El-Aksa Mosque</ENAMEX>. Note the
        sundial at the center top of the archway. It‚Äôs accurate to within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> and has the advantage of needing no winding, though it
        does ‚Äústop‚Äù on cloudy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. Further down the steps, you pass <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> places
        reserved for ritual ablutions required before <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Islamic prayer</ENAMEX>. One is
        called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">El-Kas (‚ÄúThe Cup‚Äù</ENAMEX>), a circular fountain with a pool fitted at
        the bottom with spigots and seats.
        The caliph <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Walid</ENAMEX> built the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Aksa Mosque</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX>
        Mount‚Äôs great place of prayer in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 715</NUMEX>. Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome of</ENAMEX>
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Aksa</ENAMEX> has been heavily reshaped and rebuilt a number of
        times. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusaders</ENAMEX> used it as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Aksa</ENAMEX>
        became a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> once more after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saladin</ENAMEX> conquered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> is especially imposing once you‚Äôve slipped
        off your shoes and entered the great cool interior. Mammoth marble
        pillars support the beams and ceiling, which is painted in colored
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arabesques</ENAMEX>; the floor is graced by carpets with intricate patterns.
        Stained-glass windows add to the calm and peaceful atmosphere,
        especially when worshippers are at quiet prayer: be careful not to walk
        in front of those at prayer. At the far (southern) end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mosque</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">facing Mecca</ENAMEX>, toward which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> pray, you‚Äôll see pillars made of
        precious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">breccia</ENAMEX> and chalcedony; the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>-work in the mihrab (niche
        for prayers) is delicately carved.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Aksa</ENAMEX> is a large open <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pavement</ENAMEX> beneath which lie
        tremendous vaulted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Solomon‚Äôs Stables</ENAMEX> (actually the
        structures hold up the vast artificial platform of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX>
        originally built by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Herod 2,000 years ago</TIMEX>). This entire area of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX> is currently off-limits to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. From the eastern side
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX> is a marvelous view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount of Olives</ENAMEX> and the
        Garden of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gethsemane</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biblical</ENAMEX> tradition says that the southeastern
        corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX> is the ‚ÄúPinnacle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX>,‚Äù where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>
        was tempted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX>.
        Beneath the western edge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX>, just below
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome of the Rock and El-Aksa</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Wall (‚ÄúWailing Wall‚Äù</ENAMEX>),
        the most revered holy place in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>. Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Temple‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        destruction and the exile of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 70</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
        have come here to worship, to mourn the loss of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of God</ENAMEX>, and
        to pray the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> would one day be restored to them. When that hope was
        realized in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1967</TIMEX>, old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that had crowded the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wall</ENAMEX> were
        demolished and a wide <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX> was constructed for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worshippers</ENAMEX> who arrived <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>.
        The Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wall</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herodian</ENAMEX> retaining
        walls that support the vast ceremonial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX> built by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herod</ENAMEX> around the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> to accommodate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> pilgrims
        who visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> in ancient times. No part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> building
        once surrounded by these walls still stands. The giant ashlars (square
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stone</ENAMEX> blocks) represent for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> their past glory, as well
        as a promise and a dream come true.
        Only the lower portions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall‚</ENAMEX>Äôs great ashlars, with
        carefully recessed borders, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX> from the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Herod</ENAMEX>; smaller stones
        higher up represent later constructions and repairs. What you see at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Plaza</ENAMEX> is only a small section of the complete Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wall</ENAMEX>,
        extending from the southern side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX> to its northern
        end, sunk deeply in the rubble-filled <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX> has been
        excavated along the entire western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">side</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX>, so that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> can see the extent of the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wall</ENAMEX>.
        There are separate sections of the prayer area facing the
        Wall reserved for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> and female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worshippers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> must have head
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coverings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> must not have bare shoulders or short skirts when
        entering the prayer enclosure. Skull caps and shawls are lent free of
        charge to those who need them.
        The gate in the city walls nearest the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX> has the
        unusual name of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dung Gate</ENAMEX>, probably due to the activities of the city‚Äôs
        waste collection <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> times. Outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dung Gate</ENAMEX> lies the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silwan</ENAMEX>, on the site of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">City of David</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Quarter</ENAMEX>
        Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX> from the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wall</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Quarter</TIMEX>, virtually destroyed during the fighting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>,
        including the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jewish Quarter</TIMEX>, was in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hands</ENAMEX> and off limits to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> until reclaimed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>. Since then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Quarter</TIMEX> has been rebuilt. Reconstructed older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are
        interspersed with new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, and synagogues, and throughout the
        area you can see archaeological finds uncovered during excavations in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramban Synagogue on Rehov HaYehudim</ENAMEX> is the oldest house
        of worship still standing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the quarter</TIMEX>, its site consecrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rabbi</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moshe Nahmanides</ENAMEX> when he re-established the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> here in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1267</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusader</ENAMEX> wars had left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">depopulated</ENAMEX> and in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ruins</ENAMEX>. Next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramban</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yehuda HeHasid Synagogue</ENAMEX>, also known
        as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hurva (‚Äúruined‚Äù</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Synagogue</ENAMEX>. This synagogue‚Äôs construction was
        begun by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem‚Äôs Ashkenazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> of central
        and eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> ancestry) around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1700</TIMEX>. Soon afterward, permission
        to build the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX> was revoked and the partially completed building
        fell into ruin; only in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1864</TIMEX> was it finally completed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX>
        was the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashkenazi</ENAMEX> worship until the fighting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>, when
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was destroyed and the site became a ruin once more.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yohanan Ben Zakkai Synagogue</ENAMEX> is actually four
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synagogues</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>; the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">room</ENAMEX> gives the complex its name.
        Completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1586</TIMEX>, it was the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sephardic</ENAMEX> worship for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">centuries</ENAMEX>. Heavily damaged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>, its interior was refurbished after
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">synagogues</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> had
        immigrated to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiferet Israel Synagogue</ENAMEX>, also called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nisan Bek</ENAMEX>, was
        dedicated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just over a century ago</TIMEX> at a spot off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Misgav Ladach</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chayei Olam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. Although not as venerable as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>,
        Tiferet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> was the tallest and perhaps the grandest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. Destroyed in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX> war, it is now being
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rebuilt</ENAMEX>. For a look at domestic life in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jewish Quarter</TIMEX> during the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th century</TIMEX>, pay a visit to the exhibit at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Yishuv Court Museum</ENAMEX>
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehov Or Hayyim</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">82</NUMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Dolorosa</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim Quarter</ENAMEX>
        A stroll through the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim Quarter</ENAMEX> provides a glimpse of
        some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most ancient sites as well as the vibrant
        contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> life of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. You will also find here the start
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Dolorosa</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stations of the Cross</ENAMEX> hold a fascination
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> no matter what their backgrounds or beliefs.
        Begin at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Damascus Gate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bab el-Amud</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>: Shaar
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shechem</ENAMEX>) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City‚Äôs northern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX>, the most impressive of all of
        Jerusalem‚Äôs gates and the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Suleiman the Magnificent‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builders</ENAMEX>. Recent excavations allow you to see
        the present gate‚Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">second-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, which is just below it
        to the left and, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the focus of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Gate Museum</ENAMEX>.
        Always a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of business activity, the area inside
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Damascus Gate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bustles</ENAMEX> with activity and contains many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>
        moneychangers‚Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>. Their heaps of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> coins and delicately
        balanced scales have long been replaced by paper notes and pocket
        calculators.
        Inside the gate, a stepped street leads downhill. At the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fork</ENAMEX>, bear left onto <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Al-Wad (‚</ENAMEX>Äúthe valley‚Äù) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Road</ENAMEX>. Continue through this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bazaar</ENAMEX> until you pass the fortress-like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian Hospice</ENAMEX> on the left.
        Turn left into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Dolorosa</ENAMEX> and continue to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions‚Äô</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephen‚Äôs</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate</ENAMEX> at the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. This is the traditional site of
        the martyrdom of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>, and one of the more modest gates in the
        walls erected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suleiman the Magnificent</ENAMEX>. Just outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions‚</ENAMEX>Äô
        Gate, look back at the city walls and note the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two bas</NUMEX>-relief <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX>.
        These derive from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suleiman‚</ENAMEX>Äôs dream that he would be devoured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX>
        unless he rebuilt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem‚</ENAMEX>Äôs walls; they were designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suleiman‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ill-fated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> to symbolize the hope that by restoring the walls,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suleiman</ENAMEX> would avoid such a grisly demise. Stop here to admire the view
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kidron Valley</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount of Olives</ENAMEX> on its far side: the
        Garden of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gethsemane</ENAMEX> is a green patch on the mountain side, and the
        white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cemeteries</ENAMEX> are ranged on the slopes to
        the south.
        Re-entering the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lion‚Äôs gate</ENAMEX>, and
        entering the church‚Äôs gardens through a doorway on the right side of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, you come to the purest example of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusader</ENAMEX> architecture in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of St. Anne</ENAMEX>. According to tradition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah) and Joachim</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>, lived on this
        site when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> was born; you can visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">grotto</ENAMEX> beneath the church
        where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX> gave birth. Built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">approximately 1140</TIMEX> in a spare,
        unornamented style that combines <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Frankish Romanesque</ENAMEX> with local
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">traditions</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> was turned into an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">seminary</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1187</TIMEX>,
        when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusaders</ENAMEX> lost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the centuries</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was
        abandoned and fell into ruin until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Napoleon III</ENAMEX> completely restored the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-19th century</TIMEX> and presented it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Order</ENAMEX> of the
        White <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fathers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P√®res Blancs</ENAMEX>). The church‚Äôs acoustics are exquisite;
        visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> are welcome to test the acoustics with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religious</ENAMEX> songs of all denominations.
        Next to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Anne‚</ENAMEX>Äôs are excavations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pool</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bethesda</ENAMEX>,
        where sacrificial <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> were washed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Temple</ENAMEX> period, and
        where it is believed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> cured the crippled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">John 5</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2‚Äì9</ENAMEX>). The
        site is a microcosm of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem‚</ENAMEX>Äôs history: the lowest level of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool</ENAMEX> dates from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hasmonean</ENAMEX> times, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> subsequently built a pagan
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> here, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Byzantines</ENAMEX> built a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> to commemorate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miracle</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusaders</ENAMEX> constructed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chapel‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇall</ENAMEX> swept away over
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>.
        After leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, rejoin the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Dolorosa</ENAMEX> and walk
        up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Convent of the Flagellation</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Franciscan</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monastery</ENAMEX>. This is the starting point for the walk along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stations</ENAMEX>
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX>, which commemorate the route that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> took to his death.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Franciscan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monks</ENAMEX> have been retracing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jesus‚Äôs</ENAMEX> steps and caring for the
        holy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Dolorosa</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 15th century</TIMEX>. Organized
        walks are usually offered on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fridays</TIMEX>; check with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Centre</ENAMEX> inside <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jaffa Gate</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stations of the Cross</ENAMEX> (also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúThe Way of the</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross‚Äù</ENAMEX>) are marked with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> numerals on the walls of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> along
        the way and with a sunburst made of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">paving stones</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> itself
        at each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>. Some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> have mapped out other possible routes, based on alternative
        traditions and archeological evidence. The original route cannot be
        precisely followed because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Herodian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus‚</ENAMEX>Äôs time was
        destroyed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 70</TIMEX>; it was rebuilt in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 135</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emperor Hadrian</ENAMEX> with a different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> plan and pattern of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>,
        making accurate identification of sites in the earlier city difficult.
        Whatever their exact locations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stations of the Cross</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via</ENAMEX>
        Dolorosa have been an itinerary of faith and reverence venerated by
        most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilgrims</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late medieval times</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stations of the Cross</ENAMEX>
        The details of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biblical</ENAMEX> account of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Jesus‚Äôs</ENAMEX> final days
        can be found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gospels</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Station I</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condemnation</ENAMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> was condemned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Herod‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonia</ENAMEX> fortress, the site of which is now covered by modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>.
        It is thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pilate</ENAMEX> delivered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> at a spot now
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El-Omariyah School</ENAMEX>, across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franciscan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Station II</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> receives the cross): After being
        condemned, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> was taken away by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> who beat and mocked him in
        the fortress <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>, put a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crown</ENAMEX> of thorns on his head, and led him
        away to be crucified (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mark 15</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">16‚Äì20</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franciscan Church</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Condemnation</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel of the Flagellation</ENAMEX> (a medieval building
        that contains a Biblical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>) mark the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> of these events. Before
        being given the cross in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> was presented to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pilate</ENAMEX>, who said ‚ÄúBehold the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">John 19</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>). This site is
        likely to have been near the fortress entrance, or somewhat past the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arch</ENAMEX>, which was built in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">a.d. 135</ENAMEX> and now named <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúEcce Homo Arch</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Station III</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> falls): The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gospels</ENAMEX> carry no word of
        this event, but according to tradition <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> fell under the weight of
        the cross just around the first corner you reach. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chapel</ENAMEX>, with
        a relief on its outer wall showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> bearing the cross, marks the
        spot.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Station IV</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> meets his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>): A small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> near
        the entrance to Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lady</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spasm Armenian Catholic Church</ENAMEX>
        commemorates the meeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Station V</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> carries <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jesus‚Äôs</ENAMEX> cross): In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gospels</ENAMEX>, a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cyrenaica</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>) was forced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> to carry the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX> when it appeared that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> couldn‚Äôt go on (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">27:32</TIMEX>). A small
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Franciscan chapel</ENAMEX> marks the spot.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Station VI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Veronica wipes Jesus‚Äôs face</ENAMEX>): Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> may
        have a door in the wall opened to reveal the little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veronica</ENAMEX>, built in the restored vaults of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crusader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX>.
        Tradition says that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> wiped the sweaty, bloody face of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> here
        and an imprint was left on the cloth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äútrue image‚Äù</ENAMEX> has
        given us the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúVeronica</ENAMEX>,‚Äù and since the woman‚Äôs name is unknown she
        is revered as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúSt</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veronica</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù The legend has been a part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
        lore since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the seventh century</TIMEX>; the cloth bearing the image is now kept
        at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Peter‚</ENAMEX>Äôs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Station VII</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> falls again): At the intersection of the
        Via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolorosa</ENAMEX> and the market street called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Souk Khan</ENAMEX> ez-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zeit</ENAMEX> is the spot
        where, according to traditional belief, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> fell under the weight of
        the cross a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Station VIII</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> speaks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>): A cross
        in relief on the stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> marks the site. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gospel of Luke</ENAMEX> reports
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> stopped along the way to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golgotha</ENAMEX> and told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who
        were following him that they should weep for themselves and their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> rather than for him (Luke <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">23:28</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> was destroyed by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36 years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus‚</ENAMEX>Äôs crucifixion; its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> were
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">starved</ENAMEX>, killed in battle, executed, or sold into slavery.
        Station <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IX</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> falls a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> time): Jesus‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> fall
        under the weight of the cross is legend, and therefore the exact
        location is disputed. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> can lead you south along <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Khan</ENAMEX> ez-Zeit
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Station VIII</ENAMEX> and up a stairway to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ethiopian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convent</ENAMEX> on the
        roof of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of the Holy Sepulcher. A bit of column embedded in a
        wall is now marked as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Station</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IX</NUMEX>, though it is of less interest than
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convent</ENAMEX> itself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stately Ethiopian</ENAMEX> monks from one of the world‚Äôs
        most ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> share the church‚Äôs roof with a rival
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian Coptic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convent</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Way of the Cross</ENAMEX> now leads into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of the Holy</ENAMEX>
        Sepulcher itself, which shelters the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stations</ENAMEX>. There has
        been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of the Holy Sepulcher on this spot for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 1,650</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>,
        ever since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen Helena</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constantine</ENAMEX>, who made
        Christianity the state religion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>) visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> in a.d. 326
        and identified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Golgotha</ENAMEX>, the site of the crucifixion itself.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constantine</ENAMEX> then had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">magnificent Classical basilica</ENAMEX> and rotunda built
        to house the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>. This, the grandest and richest of all
        churches to stand here, was destroyed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 614</TIMEX> by invading
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Persians</ENAMEX>. It was rebuilt in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">629</TIMEX> but partially destroyed by an insane
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> caliph in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 11th century</TIMEX>. The form it has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> dates
        mostly from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusader</ENAMEX> times, but successive changes were drawn more by
        the tides of history than by a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>, and bickering among
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX> of various sects over rights within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> often added to
        the confusion. Disagreement was so bad in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX> that the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ottoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sultan</ENAMEX> ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> had to step in and adjudicate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
        disputes. The portal through which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> is from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusader</ENAMEX> times (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1149</TIMEX>). The western door of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> is open; the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eastern</ENAMEX> door was bricked up after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusaders</ENAMEX> lost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1187</TIMEX>
        and has remained shut ever since.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Station X</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is stripped): After entering the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>,
        turn right and climb the narrow staircase. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> here rests
        partly on the rock of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golgotha</ENAMEX> itself. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> stripped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> of
        his clothes (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">27:35</TIMEX>), which they later divided among
        themselves.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Station XI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is nailed to the cross): The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Franciscan</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chapel on the platform‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇthe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">right‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇis</ENAMEX> where tradition
        places the spot at which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> was nailed to the cross.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Station XII</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus‚</ENAMEX>Äôs death): To the left of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Franciscan</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chapel</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Orthodox</ENAMEX> altar, profusely decorated with hanging oil
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lamps</ENAMEX>. Under the altar, a silver disc surrounds a hole marking the
        place where, tradition says, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus‚</ENAMEX>Äôs cross was raised alongside those
        of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> on either side.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Station XIII</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is taken down from the cross): Between
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Franciscan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> altars is a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> containing a wooden
        figure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> in a glass case. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gospels</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> was present at
        Jesus‚Äôs death (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:26</TIMEX>).
        Take the right-hand stairs down from the platform to the
        ground floor. Just in front of you will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unction</ENAMEX>,
        where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> was anointed with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX> and myrrh and then interred
        a few steps away in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph of Arimathea‚Äôs</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Station XIV</ENAMEX> (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Sepulcher</ENAMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arimathea</ENAMEX>, a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">follower</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, donated the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX>, which was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-room <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">crypt</ENAMEX> cut in
        the rock of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golgotha</ENAMEX>. Most of the rock was cut away with the
        construction of earlier Churches of the Holy Sepulcher; all that
        remains is the stone shelf on which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> lay, now covered in
        polished marble. The present structure enclosing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> was designed
        by an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Orthodox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>. The tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> in
        which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> was buried holds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at a time, so there might
        be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few minutes‚</NUMEX>Äô wait.
        Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the centuries</TIMEX> each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corner</ENAMEX> and nook inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>
        of the Holy Sepulcher has taken on significance, and small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chapels</ENAMEX> have
        been dedicated to the different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and events related to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crucifixion</ENAMEX> and resurrection. Opposite the entrance to the tomb is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Orthodox Katholikon</ENAMEX>, a brilliantly decorated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nave</ENAMEX>. If you stand
        facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> with your back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katholikon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Franciscan Chapel</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Magdalene</ENAMEX> is on your right. This is the spot where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magdalene</ENAMEX> is believed to have discovered the resurrection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>. A
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Franciscan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convent</ENAMEX>, seminary, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> are grouped around the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chapel</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Zion</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount</ENAMEX> of Olives
        Directly south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>, just outside its walls, is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Zion</ENAMEX>, revered by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> and visited by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> daily. Leaving
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>, pass through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zion Gate</ENAMEX>, which is pitted with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet</ENAMEX> holes
        from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX> war. For a good look at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Zion</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surrounding Judean hills</ENAMEX>, take a walk along the top of the walls near
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Zion Gate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stairways</ENAMEX> and railings just inside the gate make a tour of
        the battlements safe.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Zion</ENAMEX> is dominated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dormition Abbey</ENAMEX> of the
        Benedictine monks. Coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Zion Gate</ENAMEX>, you should bear right to
        reach the entrance; note that no visits are allowed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between noon</TIMEX> and
        2pm. Built in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Neo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Romanesque</ENAMEX> style during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first years</TIMEX> of the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20th century</TIMEX>, consecrated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">abbey</ENAMEX> contains a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX>
        ornamented with beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>-and-polychrome mosaics in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX>
        style. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey‚Äôs</ENAMEX> spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> is beneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX>,
        marked by a crypt where the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> is said to have fallen into
        eternal sleep (dormition).
        On the opposite side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey</ENAMEX> from its entrance are two
        more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> of great religious significance. A low-ceilinged <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in one
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> has been venerated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomb of King</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>. Biblical references are not precise, but they do indicate that
        David‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial place</ENAMEX> was inside the walls of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">City of David</ENAMEX>, which
        most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archaeologists</ENAMEX> believe did not extend this far up <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Zion</ENAMEX>.
        Directly above the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coenaculum</ENAMEX> (‚Äúdining
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">room‚Äù</ENAMEX>). This is believed to be the place where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Supper</ENAMEX>, in celebration of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first night</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Passover</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusaders</ENAMEX> built the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> archwork, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> added a prayer niche and inscriptions. It‚Äôs a small and
        humble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, hardly the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo da Vinci‚</ENAMEX>Äôs famous
        painting.
        Before you leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Zion</ENAMEX>, visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of the</ENAMEX>
        Martyrs, an independent memorial commemorating the sacrifice of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> lives in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Nazi Holocaust</ENAMEX>. The plaques on the
        walls give the names of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> that were destroyed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX>
        Schindler, whose struggle to save <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave laborers</ENAMEX> from death
        during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> was made famous by the film <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Schindler‚Äôs List</ENAMEX>, is
        buried in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> graveyard on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Zion</ENAMEX>; his interment was
        arranged by the many who owed their lives to his courage and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ingenuity</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount of Olives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gethsemane</ENAMEX>
        The best way to visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olives</ENAMEX> is to take a taxi
        or bus (number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Et-Tur</ENAMEX>, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Damascus Gate</ENAMEX> bus <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>) to the
        top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount</ENAMEX>, visit the points of interest there, and then walk
        down the hillside through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Garden</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gethsemane</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cemeteries</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kidron Valley</ENAMEX>.
        Driving through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wadi Jodz</ENAMEX> valley and up the slopes of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olives</ENAMEX> takes you past the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta Victoria</ENAMEX> Hospital; after
        you turn at the crest of the hill, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> of Viri Galilei
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">(‚ÄúMen of Galilee‚Äù</ENAMEX>) is on the right. Farther along is the imposing tower
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Church of the Ascension</ENAMEX>. The tower‚Äôs apex is the highest
        point in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, marking the spot from which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Russians</ENAMEX>
        believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> ascended to heaven. The nuns in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convent</ENAMEX> here preserve
        their seclusion; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> must have special permission to enter.
        Most other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> denominations accept the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel</ENAMEX> of the
        Ascension as the place of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus‚</ENAMEX>Äôs ascension. Down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chapel‚Äôs dome</ENAMEX> is now in the grounds of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>.
        The modest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> is built over a rock said to be the last upon
        which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> stood. Despite its significance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">chapel</ENAMEX> is very plain.
        Near it you‚Äôll find relief for weary feet: several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camel drivers</ENAMEX> often
        wait around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> entrance and will be glad to order their huge
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX> to kneel so that you can climb aboard. Depending on how much
        you‚Äôre prepared to pay, they will trot you down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven</ENAMEX> Arches
        Hotel, with its spectacular vistas, or just wait while you have your
        photo taken.
        Just south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">chapel</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pater Noster Church</ENAMEX>,
        thought to be built on the spot where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> taught his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX> the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lord‚Äôs Prayer</ENAMEX>. The present church dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 19th century</TIMEX>.
        Inside, wall decorations include the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Lord‚Äôs Prayer</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of
        languages. In the same compound you‚Äôll find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basilica of Eleona</ENAMEX>,
        finished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923</TIMEX> on the site of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. From the Pater
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Noster</ENAMEX> church <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>, a road heads to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bethphage</ENAMEX>, the traditional
        starting-point for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">triumphal</ENAMEX> ride into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> on the first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.
        The views of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX> from here are spectacular. A
        short distance along the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pater Noster Church</ENAMEX> is the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arches Hotel</ENAMEX> and, in front of it, an observation point that
        offers a breathtaking view of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. Looking across the Kidron
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, one‚Äôs eye is immediately drawn to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">golden Dome of the Rock</ENAMEX>
        and its brilliantly colored tiles. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> also see the eastern city
        wall, with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> graveyard at its foot. The wall there is broken by
        the graceful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Gate</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate of Mercy</ENAMEX>), which has been walled in
        for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>; many believe it will not be reopened until the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Messiah</ENAMEX>
        appears and enters <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Byzantines</ENAMEX> built the splendid gate on
        the ruins of earlier ones. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusaders</ENAMEX> enlarged and embellished it in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 12th‚ÄÇcentury</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suleiman</ENAMEX> repaired it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions‚Äô</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Stephen‚Äôs</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gate</ENAMEX> is to the right of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Gate</ENAMEX>. At
        the southern end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>, the hill of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Zion</ENAMEX> stands out,
        crowned by the conical roof of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dormition Abbey</ENAMEX>. This sweeping vista
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> has changed greatly over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>, but has never
        failed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dazzle millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilgrims</ENAMEX> who have made the long journey to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Land</ENAMEX>.
        A narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from the observation point descends into the
        extensive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery</ENAMEX> on the slope, one of the oldest and most
        venerated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial sites</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">world‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsome graves</ENAMEX> date back to
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">biblical</NUMEX> times. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pebbles</ENAMEX> placed on gravestones symbolize a visit by
        a mourner.
        On the way down the hill, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dominus Flevit (‚ÄúThe Lord Wept‚Äù</ENAMEX>) commemorates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus‚</ENAMEX>Äôs weeping over his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX> of the destruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. During construction of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> found artifacts, tombs, and ruins from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        history, some dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late Bronze Age times</TIMEX> (about 1600 b.c. ).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Garden</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gethsemane</ENAMEX> occupies the lower part of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slope</ENAMEX>, and various plots are cared for by different sects. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orthodox Church of Mary Magdalene</ENAMEX>, with its gilded onion-shaped <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">domes</ENAMEX>,
        is in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> section of the garden. This exquisite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> was built
        by order of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Czar Alexander III</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> during the late
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteenth century</TIMEX> in memory of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian Orthodox</ENAMEX> nuns
        oversee the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and its grounds. Entering the church‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> large
        room, you are immediately struck by the lustrous white marble of the
        icons on display. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Grand Duchess Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reposes</ENAMEX> in the church‚Äôs crypt; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">British-born Princess Alice</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth II</ENAMEX>) is buried nearby. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Princess Alice</ENAMEX>,
        who lived much of her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> life in religious seclusion, was
        posthumously honored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">State of Israel</ENAMEX> for saving the lives of a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> by hiding them at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> royal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>
        II.
        On the lower slopes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Garden</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gethsemane</ENAMEX>, leading to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jericho Road</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Basilica of the Agony</ENAMEX>, also called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">All Nations</ENAMEX>. The tympanum of its fa√ßade shines with gold mosaics
        depicting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> as he prayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gethsemane</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> was built on
        the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusader</ENAMEX> ruins, paid for by donations from
        all over the world, and dedicated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Franciscans</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1924</TIMEX>. Glass
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plates</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> floor allow you to see fragments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX>
        floor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mosaics</ENAMEX> left from the floor of an earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. The highlight
        of a visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basilica</ENAMEX> is a walk in the garden, which harbors
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gnarled</ENAMEX> and ancient olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>. Well-tended olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> never die but
        sprout new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> when an old trunk decays, so these ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> might
        have been here when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> walked in the garden. The word gethsemane
        comes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> gat shemen, meaning ‚Äúolive oil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        A few steps from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Basilica of the Agony</ENAMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kidron Valley</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Mary‚Äôs Tomb</ENAMEX>. Through a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusader</ENAMEX> arch, stairs lead
        down a long passageway to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orthodox Church of the Assumption</ENAMEX>. In the
        gloomy subterranean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> is a rock-hewn sepulcher. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> of smoky,
        scented votive lamps hang from the ceiling. Ancient traditions mark
        this as the place of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial</ENAMEX> and assumption into heaven (while
        the site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dormition Abbey</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Zion</ENAMEX> is the place of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        death). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Traditions</ENAMEX> also identify the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex structure</ENAMEX> containing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary‚Äôs Tomb</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial places</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> and of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joachim</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Franciscan</ENAMEX> Grotto of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gethsemane</ENAMEX>, entered by turning
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">right</TIMEX> before reaching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusader</ENAMEX> arch, is a less somber place. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>
        might well have gathered here with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> of
        his teaching. Visiting <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> here are slightly shorter than at the
        Basilica of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agony</ENAMEX>.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> and structure has its
        significance. The little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mary‚Äôs Tomb</ENAMEX> is
        the grave of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 15th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mujr el-Din</ENAMEX>.
        Nearby, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kidron Valley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Orthodox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Stephen</ENAMEX> commemorates the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX>, and up the Jericho
        Road toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is a small but dramatic monument to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> killed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1967 Six Day War</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kidron Valley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley of Jehoshaphat</ENAMEX>)
        The valley between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount</ENAMEX> of Olives
        holds traces left by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem‚</ENAMEX>Äôs earliest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX>. The original
        settlement of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, founded before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3000</TIMEX> b.c. , was on the western
        side of the valley, and tombs and monuments have been built here ever
        since.
        Gravestones with crosses and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> inscriptions at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the valley remind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> that many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>. Most
        of the graves are recent, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">barely a century old</TIMEX>, but the cone-roofed,
        timeworn monument seen down the valley dates from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Temple</ENAMEX>
        period over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,000 years ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Legend</ENAMEX> calls this the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomb of Absalom</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ill-fated</ENAMEX> and rebellious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>. Behind it is the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomb of</ENAMEX>
        Jehoshaphat, dating from the same period. Just beyond is a carved tomb
        with a pyramid-shaped roof, known as both the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tomb of the Pharaoh‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Daughter</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomb of Zechariah</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archaeologists</ENAMEX> agree that this
        extraordinary ensemble of monuments represents the tombs of wealthy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Jerusalem‚Äôs Hellenistic</ENAMEX> period.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX> of the city walls is the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>,
        which would have been only the size of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> by today‚Äôs standards.
        It occupied the slope of the hill south of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Aksa Mosque</ENAMEX>, a
        neighborhood called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ophel</ENAMEX> (or the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">City of David</ENAMEX>). This area is
        partly the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">present-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silwan</ENAMEX> and partly open to the
        public as an archaeological <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>.
        Modern excavations here have brought to light several
        historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, including the support wall of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David‚Äôs citadel</ENAMEX> (which is
        itself vanished) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Warren‚Äôs Shaft</ENAMEX>, a portion of the pre-Davidic
        Canaanite water system. A later <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX>, built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hezekiah</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">701</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">b.c.</ENAMEX> , from inside the city walls to to the hidden <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gihon Spring</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">valley</ENAMEX> outside the walls allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> to survive the onslaught of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assyrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> that had already destroyed the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and swept its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> from the annals of history. Without
        this wildly curving water <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX>, cut through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX> under
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> by frantic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> who worked from both ends to meet in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">middle, Judaic</ENAMEX> monotheism would have been destroyed and the development
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> civilization would have been considerably altered. Legend
        says <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">that‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇlong afterward‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇthe Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> brought her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant son‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        clothes here to wash them. The collection point for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tunnel‚Äôs water</ENAMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pool of Siloam</ENAMEX>, is believed to be the place where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> restored
        sight to a blind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> was once built over this spot, but today
        the minaret of a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> is the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landmark</ENAMEX> for finding the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool</ENAMEX>.
        Under present political circumstances, it is best to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">explore Silwan</ENAMEX> and surrounding areas with a guided tour. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> can
        wander the hillside and wade waist-deep in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gihon Spring</ENAMEX>
        that still flow through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX>. Soon to go on view in the
        archaeological <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> are reconstructed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> from various periods,
        including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canaanite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dwellings</ENAMEX> built <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5,000 years ago</TIMEX>.
        The lower reaches of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kidron Valley</ENAMEX> are now part of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silwan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> tumbles down the southern end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olives</ENAMEX>,
        which is known here as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúMount of Offense,‚</ENAMEX>Äù a name acquired in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX>. The great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> had built altars to pagan gods
        worshipped by his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> on this slope, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> against
        the God of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. Today nothing remains of those altars.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
        Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> was reunited after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Six Day War</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX> and other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> previously held by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> retain their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> way of life. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX> has both modern
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and ancient monuments, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Jerusalem</ENAMEX> does. And because
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> were separate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier years</TIMEX>, you will find a
        central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX>, bus <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX>, and even consulates duplicated
        in both parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX> (whether
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian or Muslim</ENAMEX>) welcome foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> of all religions.
        If you are not staying in one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>,
        spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least one morning</TIMEX> in this part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, perhaps with a
        return in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> for an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> dinner and a performance of local
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">entertainments</ENAMEX>. Remember the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabbath</ENAMEX> difference: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> as
        their day of rest (beginning at sunset on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> and ending at sunset
        on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>). Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> are closed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabbath</ENAMEX>, but
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX> are open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all week</TIMEX>.
        A good place to begin your touring is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Damascus Gate</ENAMEX>. Walk
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">north</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nablus Road</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Derech Shechem</ENAMEX>), past parked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX>, and look
        for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lane</ENAMEX> on the right with a sign pointing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Garden Tomb</ENAMEX>, a cave
        venerated by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Gordon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Khartoum</ENAMEX>, visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1883</TIMEX>. He found that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX>
        denominations had come into being far too late to have been allotted
        rights in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of the Holy Sepulcher. He noted that this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">rock-hewn cave</ENAMEX> matched very well the description of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX>; a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skull</ENAMEX>-like hill nearby strengthened <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gordon‚</ENAMEX>Äôs belief in its
        authenticity. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British Protestants</ENAMEX> owns and maintains
        the attractive grounds and gardens, welcoming all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. Whether
        this is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial place</ENAMEX> or not, the tomb is relatively ‚Äúunspoiled‚Äù
        compared to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of the Holy Sepulcher.
        At the intersection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nablus Road and Saladin Street</ENAMEX>
        is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Colony</ENAMEX>, named after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late-19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">benefactors</ENAMEX>
        who started a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> here as modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> expanded beyond the
        ancient city walls. The imposing church <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> is that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. George‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican Cathedral</ENAMEX>, seat of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Archbishop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> and of
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and seminary. You may stroll into the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúclose‚Äù</ENAMEX> if the gates are
        open. Just east of the intersection, in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saladin Street</ENAMEX>, is the entrance
        to the eerie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tombs of the Kings</ENAMEX>, which is actually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first-century</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tomb of Queen Helena of Adiabne</ENAMEX> (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mesopotamia</ENAMEX>), a convert to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nablus Road</ENAMEX> takes you past the famous and atmospheric
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Colony Hotel</ENAMEX>, once the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pasha</ENAMEX>, to the small
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheikh Jarrah Mosque</ENAMEX> which gives this part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> its name. Turn
        right past the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> and then left to reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tomb of Simon the Just</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimeon Hazadik</ENAMEX>), a high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Temple</ENAMEX> period. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jews</ENAMEX>
        hold the site sacred, although an inscription attributes the grave to a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>. As this is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, both accounts of the ownership might
        be true.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon‚Äôs</ENAMEX> tomb rises <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Scopus</ENAMEX>. From here,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> looked down upon besieged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> until they conquered
        and destroyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 70</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> and the
