
  
  
    
      
        Where to Go
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, measuring just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">445 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">260 miles</NUMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">north</ENAMEX> to south and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">112 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">70 miles</NUMEX>) at its widest point, yet it packs
        in so many sights that you couldn‚Äôt possibly see them all in the space
        of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a two-week</TIMEX> or even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-week</TIMEX> trip.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> is the undisputed star attraction of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. And
        within easy travelling distance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> are the other major sights
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dead Sea</ENAMEX> region. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> bustle and noise become tiresome,
        or you simply cannot face another religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>, try a week in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">south</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eilat</ENAMEX>) or in the north (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galilee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golan</ENAMEX>). It could be the
        tonic you need.
        Don‚Äôt try to get around all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> in one trip, however, or
        you will short-change them all by not having enough time to really
        appreciate the scenery and lifestyle.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>
        The historic walled heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> dates back beyond the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs intensely atmospheric, satisfying even the most
        demanding expectations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.
        Start by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jaffa Gate</ENAMEX>, one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> entrances that
        punctuate the towering city walls built mainly by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suleiman</ENAMEX> the
        Magnificent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX>, though some parts date back more than
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,000 years</TIMEX>.
        The landmark <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> just to the right, inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jaffa Gate</ENAMEX>,
        is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citadel</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King David‚Äôs Tower</ENAMEX>, also built by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suleiman</ENAMEX>.
        Beautifully restored and with lush archaeological gardens, its towers
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> now house an impressive state-of-the-art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> encompassing
        the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, and offering a perfect introduction to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old City</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>, you can enjoy the dazzling sound and light
        shows that are staged on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> evenings.
        Diagonally opposite <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jaffa Gate</ENAMEX> is the narrow entrance to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Street</ENAMEX>, the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">thoroughfare</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>. Here begin the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">souqs</ENAMEX> (the traditional markets) and your <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> taste of the old
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerusalem‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwith</ENAMEX> its narrow, cramped <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX>, dimly lit by bare <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bulbs</ENAMEX>,
        bustling with exotically-dressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> of many nationalities. Show
        even the merest interest in any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and you‚Äôll be warmly
        welcomed, indeed sometimes dragged inside!
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX>
        At the far end of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">David Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX> is one of the
        world‚Äôs most sacred spots to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major religions. It was here, on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hill</ENAMEX> known as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Moriah</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX> created the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Temple</ENAMEX> in
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">964‚Äì957</NUMEX> b.c. as home to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ark of the Covenant</ENAMEX>. It was destroyed by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebuchadnezzar</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">586 b.c.</TIMEX> and replaced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Temple</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">525‚Äì520</NUMEX>
        b.c. This was enlarged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herod</ENAMEX>, sacked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 70</TIMEX>, and totally
        flattened by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hadrian</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 135</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX> is now a large
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stone</ENAMEX>-paved <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>, an oasis of tranquillity and well-deserving of
        its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> name <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Haram ash-Sharif</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Noble Courtyard</ENAMEX>. For admission to
        its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> great mosques buy a ticket at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX> by the foot of the
        steps. Note that photography is not allowed.
        Standing at the centre of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        greatest architectural achievement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome of the Rock</ENAMEX>, whose golden
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cupola</ENAMEX> is the city‚Äôs most famous landmark. Built in a.d. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">688‚Äì691</NUMEX>, it is
        decorated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of exquisite, predominantly blue and yellow,
        Persian ceramic tiles, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koranic</ENAMEX> scriptures on the lintels. Looking
        up at the interior of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> is just as breathtaking as seeing
        it from outside. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> floor rests a huge ancient slab, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX> itself, on which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX> prepared to sacrifice his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac</ENAMEX> (but
        was given a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last-minute</TIMEX> reprieve by an angel) and from which the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prophet Mohammed</ENAMEX> rose to Heaven during his dream-visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeru¬≠salem.</ENAMEX>
        You can still see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed‚</ENAMEX>Äôs footprint, but you‚Äôll need a guide to
        point it out.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed</ENAMEX> also visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Aksa Mosque</ENAMEX>, which is adjacent
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dome</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Aksa</ENAMEX> is actually the most important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> in
        the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. The present silver-domed building largely dates from
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1034</TIMEX>, but the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">715</TIMEX>. This too is a splendid
        place, hung with magnificent chandeliers, laid with priceless carpets,
        and decorated with fine mosaics, but you should visit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">El-Aksa</ENAMEX> before
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome of the Rock</ENAMEX>, as it is bound to suffer by comparison.
        Your admission ticket also allows you entry to a
        fascinating small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Museum</ENAMEX>. Take your time poring over the other
        sites of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX>, which contains some fantastic medieval
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fountains</ENAMEX>, arches, and gateways.
        The Western Wall
        Just below <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX> is the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Wall</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ha-Kotel Ha-Ma‚Äôaravi</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>), better known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚ÄúWailing Wall</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        To reach the entrance, go back up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">David Street</ENAMEX> and turn left up a small
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alleyway</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Airport-style</ENAMEX> security checks leave you in no doubt as to the
        importance of the site. A remnant of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second century</TIMEX> a.d. wall that
        once supported the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Mount</ENAMEX>, this is the most revered place in the
        world for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> faith. Since the sacking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> and their
        banishment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 70</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> from all over the world have come here to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weep</ENAMEX> and wail at the loss of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of God</ENAMEX> and pray for the
        restitution of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
        Whatever your beliefs, the giant stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> is an awesome
        sight. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> pray to the left, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to the right. Prayers
        can be scribbled on paper and inserted into the cracks between the
        great <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone ashlars</ENAMEX> (blocks). Gentiles may also approach; simply don
        the skull cap or shawl provided.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Quarter</ENAMEX>
        Immediately west of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wall</ENAMEX> lies the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jewish Quarter</TIMEX>. After
        the claustrophobic rough and tumble of the dimly-lit medieval souqs,
        stepping into this area is like entering an oasis of light, space,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cleanliness</ENAMEX>, and tranquillity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> has been razed many times, most
        recently during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1948 War</ENAMEX>, so it‚Äôs not surprising that most things
        here are modern. From <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">David Street</ENAMEX> head into the recently excavated
        Cardo, the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">thoroughfare</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> and a
        former <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusader</ENAMEX> marketplace. Nowadays it is bordered by ancient columns
        and lined with expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>.
        Nearby is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Yishuv Court Museum</ENAMEX>, where you can
        experience something of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> through
        restored living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX>, kitchens, and prayer areas. The Herodian
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Quarter</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>, in the remains of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX> which somehow survived
        the destruction of a.d. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX> and now lie <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several feet</NUMEX> below the surface
        of the present <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, gives a fascinating insight into life in the city
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,000 years ago</TIMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most memorable sights of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Quarter</TIMEX> is the
        graceful arch of the defunct <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurva Synagogue</ENAMEX>, most recently destroyed
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX> and left unrestored in memory of the area‚Äôs turbulent
        history.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Dolorosa</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> back into the chaos and noise of the souqs and turn
        right off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">David Street</ENAMEX>, either into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Wad Road</ENAMEX> or along the more
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colourful Souq el Attarin</ENAMEX> into the long <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Souq Khan es Zeit</ENAMEX>, where
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">butchers</ENAMEX> and food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> make for fascinating window shopping. Either
        street will lead you along to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christianity‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most melancholy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thoroughfare</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Dolorosa</ENAMEX> (Street of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorrows</ENAMEX>). Here <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousands of</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilgrims</ENAMEX> walk in the final footsteps of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> as he made his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calvary</ENAMEX>, many bearing a cross to express their piety.
        Many of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stations of the Cross</ENAMEX>, the marked points
        which show <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus‚</ENAMEX>Äôs progress along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, are highly disputed. Some
        can be matched with places and events in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gospels</ENAMEX>; a few are
        certainly the stuff of legend, mapped out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX> by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European Christians</ENAMEX> who had never been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. As these ‚Äúfalse
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stations‚Äù</ENAMEX> gained credence with pilgrims, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Franciscan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monks</ENAMEX> living in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> decided that faith could be served by accommodating the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fabrications</ENAMEX>, and so legend was allowed to became ‚Äúreality. ‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Station I</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Here Jesus</ENAMEX> is condemned in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Herod the Great‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonia Fortress</ENAMEX>. However, there is nothing to see, as the site is
        overlain by modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Station II</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Here Jesus</ENAMEX> receives the cross, is taken away,
        beaten, and mocked by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> in the fortress <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>. Much of the
        actual <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">courtyard pavement</ENAMEX> (lithostrotos) survives in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monastery</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flagellation</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX> was scourged, and in the adjacent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Convent of the Sisters of Zion</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are open to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.
        Here too you‚Äôll find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ecce Homo Arch</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 135</TIMEX>. The name
        (‚ÄúBehold the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Man‚Äù</ENAMEX>) echoes the words of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> prefect Pontius
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pilate</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Station III</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> falls. There is nothing in the Gospels
        about this, though a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Polish Chapel</ENAMEX>, with a relief showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> bowing
        under the weight of the cross, marks the spot.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Station IV</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> meets his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. A small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> and a
        relief mark this poignant point.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Station V</ENAMEX>: It is from here that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> carries the cross. A
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Franciscan</ENAMEX> oratory is now on the site.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Station VI</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Veronica wipes Jesus‚Äôs face</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veronica</ENAMEX> stands on the site.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Station VII</ENAMEX>: At this point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> falls again.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Station VIII</ENAMEX>: It is from here that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> consoles the women
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> and tells them to weep for themselves and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,
        rather than for him, thus prophesying the impending destruction of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. A cross in stone relief now marks the site.
        Station <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IX</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> falls for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> time. This is the most
        curiously located of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethiopian Convent</ENAMEX> on the roof
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of the Holy Sepulchre. The monks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convent</ENAMEX> are often
        happy to show you around their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of the Holy Sepulchre
        The final <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> are in this strange and sacred
        building, which is actually <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, each closely
        administered by one of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five</NUMEX> denominations: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Armenian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orthodox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Orthodox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abyssinian Coptic</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian Orthodox</ENAMEX>
        (demarcation lines are drawn on the floors and even on some of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pillars</ENAMEX>). This bulky fortress-like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> dates mainly from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusader</ENAMEX> period of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 12th century</TIMEX>. The interior is a heady mix of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusader</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> styles, and because of inter-denominational
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bickering</ENAMEX>, false partitions, and poor maintenance it is difficult to
        understand without a guide.
        Go up the stairs to the right of the entrance to see the
        next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Station X</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is stripped; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Station XI</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is
        nailed on to the cross; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Station</ENAMEX> XII: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> dies on the cross. The
        hole beneath the altar is traditionally considered the exact spot where
        the cross was erected (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Station XIII</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is taken down
        from the cross, the point being marked by a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX>, with an
        ancient wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> in a glass case.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Station XIV</ENAMEX>: This is the Holy Sepulchre itself, now reduced
        to the simple stone shelf on which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> lay. You view it
        from an aedicule (a highly decorated, though very sombre, kiosk)
        holding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at a time. The idea of enclosing it in this bizarre
        fashion came from a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim Quarter</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most charming and peaceful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of St. Anne</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>) is
        actually in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim Quarter</ENAMEX>, and just inside <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Stephen‚Äôs Gate</ENAMEX> at
        the far end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Dolorosa</ENAMEX>. This stern, solid structure, built in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 12th century</TIMEX>, is the finest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crusader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. A chapel
        in the crypt marks the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX> of the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>. Adjacent is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">impressively deep Pool of Bethesda</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> cured the crippled man
        with the famous words ‚ÄúStand up, take your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mat</ENAMEX> and walk‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">John 5</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-9</ENAMEX>).
        The lowest level of the pool dates back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the eighth century</TIMEX> b.c.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this quarter</TIMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Wad Road</ENAMEX>
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Souq Khan es Zeit</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Dolorosa</ENAMEX>, page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>), both of which
        meet at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Damascus Gate</ENAMEX>. This is the finest of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> gates,
        dating mainly from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th-century</TIMEX> reign of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Suleiman the Magnificent</ENAMEX>.
        It is also the busiest, with a steady stream of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> travelling in
        from their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX> to shop and work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>. A
        further exotic touch is added by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> just inside the
        gate, selling brightly coloured cloth and clothes, alongside street
        vendors selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruits</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, and other wares.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX> is mainly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">territory</ENAMEX> and you will see
        few, if any, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">vicinity‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthough visitors</ENAMEX> should not be put
        off. From the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jeru</ENAMEX>-salem starts at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Damascus Gate</ENAMEX>.
        Ironically, just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few yards</NUMEX> from here, in the midst of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hubbub</ENAMEX> and bustle, you‚Äôll find a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX>, marvellously peaceful
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">site</ENAMEX>.
        A little way along the busy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nablus</ENAMEX> Road a sign on the right
        points to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Garden Tomb</ENAMEX>. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Gordon</ENAMEX> (of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khartoum</ENAMEX> fame) who
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 19th century</TIMEX> popularized the idea that this was the true
        site of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Golgotha</ENAMEX> both <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mean ‚Äúskull‚Äù</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">there‚Äôs</ENAMEX> certainly a pronounced skull-shape to the adjacent hill. As the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Prot¬</ENAMEX>≠estant guardians of the tomb modestly inform you on a free
        guided tour, there is much evidence that this, rather than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>
        of the Holy Sepulchre, is the place where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> was crucified and
        buried. Whatever conclusion you may reach, this beautifully laid-out
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">garden</ENAMEX>, containing a typical rock-hewn <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cave tomb</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first century</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">a.d.</ENAMEX> , is a highlight of many pilgrimages.
        Farther along the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nablus Road</ENAMEX>, the sturdy, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>, handsome
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">tower of St. George‚Äôs Cathedral</ENAMEX>, which was consecrated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>, is a
        little piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> in the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">A few yards</NUMEX> on,
        at the heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Colony</ENAMEX> established by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 19th century</TIMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Colony Hotel</ENAMEX>, a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">mansion</ENAMEX> built in the style of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fort¬≠ress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860</TIMEX>. The American
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> was based here around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX>. It is famous as
        a place of tolerance where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> can meet without enmity.
        On the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, alongside the walls close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Damascus</ENAMEX>
        Gate, you will find <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Solomon‚Äôs Quarries</ENAMEX>, which are also known as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zedekiah‚Äôs Cave</ENAMEX> after a legend that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zedekiah</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> fled
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylonians</ENAMEX> via this route in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">587</NUMEX> b.c. These atmospheric red
        caves stretch <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several hundred yards</NUMEX> back beneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX>, and it
        isn‚Äôt difficult to imagine the slaves of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX> quarrying stone
        by candlelight to build the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Temple</ENAMEX>. Follow the city walls a
        little farther along until you come to the landmark <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller Museum</ENAMEX>,
        built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX>, which contains the city‚Äôs finest collection of
        archaeological artefacts.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount</ENAMEX> of Olives
        The best way to visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olives</ENAMEX> is to start at
        the top and work your way down. From the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Damascus Gate</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>)
        take either a shared <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> (sherut) or a bus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42 or 75</NUMEX> to get to the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arches Hotel</ENAMEX>. The view from the promenade here is arguably the
        finest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>; go in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>, when the sun is at your back,
        for the best photographs, or go in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">sunset</ENAMEX>.
        Immediately below is the most sacred <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery</ENAMEX> in the world.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> tradition has it that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> Coming the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messiah</ENAMEX> will descend here to resurrect the dead, who will then follow
        him through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate of Mercy</ENAMEX> (the now-blocked <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Gate</ENAMEX>, directly
        below the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome of the Rock</ENAMEX> from here) into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>.
        Just down the path on the right, you will find the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franciscan Church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dominus Flevit (‚ÄúThe Lord Wept‚Äù</ENAMEX>) marking the spot
        where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> wept as he predicted the destruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> (Luke
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:41-4</TIMEX>). Just below this lies the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tomb of the Prophets</ENAMEX>, believed to be
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial place</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haggai, Malachi</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zechariah</ENAMEX>. The tomb guardian
        will unlock the gate to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX> and give you a candle to explore the
        small circular catacomb, but for what little you can see, it is hardly
        worth the effort.
        Go back up to the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">promenade road</ENAMEX>, turn left, and you
        will find <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more sites associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of the Pater</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noster</ENAMEX> is where he is said to have taught the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples the Lord‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        Prayer, and around the cloisters of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">adjoining convent</ENAMEX> there are
        tiled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX> bearing the famous w ords in almost every world language.
        Adjacent is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chapel/Mosque</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ascension</ENAMEX>, located on the spot
        where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is believed to have begun his ascent to heaven. This is
        actually a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> place of worship (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> recognise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> as a
        prophet, though not as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Son of God</ENAMEX>). A rather damaged footprint,
        purportedly that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, is on display.
        Follow the steep road right down the hill, and on your left
        you will soon see the highly picturesque <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian Orthodox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Magdalene</ENAMEX>. The great attraction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> is the splendid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exterior</ENAMEX>, which is crowned by golden onion-shaped cupolas. However, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> is only open on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:00 a.m. to 11:30 a.m.</TIMEX>
        ).
        Beyond this, to the right, is <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Mary‚Äôs Tomb</ENAMEX>. A fine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crusader</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arch</ENAMEX> leads down a dimly-lit broad stairway to the dark subterranean
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of the Assumption</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Orthodox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. The recess on the
        right half-way down contains the tombs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virgin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anne</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joachim</ENAMEX>; the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the right is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>. At the bottom
        of the stairs, encircled by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of smoky, scented votive lamps, a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">rock</ENAMEX>-hewn sepulchre marks the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> of the Virgin (though this is also
        claimed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of the Dormition</ENAMEX>, see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX>). Turn left out of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary‚Äôs Tomb</ENAMEX> to the adjacent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Franciscan Grotto</ENAMEX>, which is thought to have
        been used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> while teaching his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX>.
        A short way along the busy main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Garden</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gethsemane</ENAMEX>. This charming, peaceful spot, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> grieved, prayed,
        was betrayed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judas</ENAMEX>, and arrested by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, takes its
        name from the ancient olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> (geth-shemna means oil-press) which
        have been grown here since before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christ‚</ENAMEX>Äôs time.
        Alongside the garden, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of All Nations</ENAMEX> is best
        seen in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX> when the sun‚Äôs rays bounce off the brilliant
        mosaic fa√ßade. Built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1924</TIMEX> and funded by many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, it contains
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> at which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is said to have prayed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> before he
        entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Passover</TIMEX> supper.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX> the road to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> leading down into the Kidron
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, immediately below the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX> walls. Here are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> fine
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">b.c. tomb monuments</ENAMEX>. The finest is the huge
        conical-roofed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tomb/Pillar of Absalom</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King David‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>). Nearby, with
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a pyramidal</NUMEX> roof, is the impressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomb of Zechariah</ENAMEX> (though it‚Äôs
        unclear whether this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zechariah</ENAMEX> the prophet or Zechariah the father
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John the Baptist</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX>, which belongs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bene Hezir</ENAMEX>,
        is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> to have been authenticated. This is also the place
        where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> is said to have hidden, following the arrest
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount</ENAMEX> Zion
        Despite its romantic name <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Zion</ENAMEX> is actually little
        more than a hill immediately south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX> walls. Its great
        landmark is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church/Abbey</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dormition</ENAMEX>. Its name, meaning ‚Äúto
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sleep,‚Äù</ENAMEX> comes from the legend that the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">her last</NUMEX>
        earthly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> here before she ‚Äúfell asleep. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù Consecrated</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908</TIMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> is a handsome Neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Romanesque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> with a relatively small,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bright</ENAMEX>, modern interior. Follow the stairs at the right of the entrance
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> where the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> slept.
        Behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> of great religious
        significance. In a tiny low-ceilinged <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, draped with blue velvet, is
        the revered but questionable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tomb of King David</ENAMEX>. In the same building
        is a small, humble, vaulted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coenaculum</ENAMEX> (‚Äúdining
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hall‚Äù</ENAMEX>). It is here that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is said to have washed the disciples‚Äô
        feet and presided over the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Supper</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusaders</ENAMEX> built the Gothic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archwork</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 12th century</TIMEX>; it was rebuilt in its present form in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14th century</TIMEX>.
        Finally, on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Zion</ENAMEX>, you will find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of the</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, an eerie, candle-lit place with disturbing images and grim
        reminders of the horrors of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazism</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Jerusalem</ENAMEX> is a general name for the area west of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old City</ENAMEX>. It is thoroughly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, almost entirely modern, and still
        growing.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New City</ENAMEX>
        The heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New City</ENAMEX> is around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kikkar Zion</ENAMEX> (Zion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Square</ENAMEX>), where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> are great attractions for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> alike. The most attractive enclave is the
        pedestrianized precinct centred on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ben Yehuda Street</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yoel Salomon</ENAMEX>
        Street. Formerly the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nahalat Shivia</ENAMEX> residential district, founded in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1869</TIMEX> and restored in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, the area is characterized by small
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">golden</ENAMEX>-stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard houses</ENAMEX>, many converted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, caf√©s,
        and arts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>. More <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> can be found on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ben Yehuda Street</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King George V Street</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jaffa Street</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Yemin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moshe</ENAMEX>
        Just south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New City</ENAMEX> and immediately west of the Old
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> is the exclusive residential suburb of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yemin Moshe</ENAMEX>, named after
        Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses Montefiore</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1784‚Äì1885</ENAMEX>), a famous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropist</ENAMEX>.
        The best-known <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> here is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hotel</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX>,
        and now a solid, aristocratic home-away-from-home for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX>, and other well-heeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">132</NUMEX>). Directly
        opposite is another famous landmark, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA Building</ENAMEX> (built in
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1928‚Äì1933</NUMEX>), with a very handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Art-Nouveau</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">133</NUMEX>).
        The focal point of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yemin Moshe</ENAMEX> is the elegant whitewashed
        Windmill, erected by Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1858‚Äì1860</NUMEX> to help feed the first
        residents here. A small display inside is dedicated to the benefactor.
        There are a number of other minor attractions in this grassy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> area:
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Herod‚Äôs Family Tomb</ENAMEX>; a fine replica of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia‚Äôs Liberty Bell</ENAMEX>; and
        a modern Lion <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fountain</ENAMEX>. Just below here you‚Äôll find the Cinematheque
        (see pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90 and 140</TIMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel Museum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farther West</ENAMEX>
        Take <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 17</TIMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">24</NUMEX> for the short journey west to the
        finest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel Museum</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs a large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>,
        focusing mainly on archaeology, arts of the world, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> art. Many
        of the exhibits are of international standing and all are beautifully
        displayed and well-captioned.
        The most striking part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shrine of The</ENAMEX>
        Book, whose gleaming white conical structure represents the shape of
        the lid of the jars in which were discovered the world‚Äôs oldest
        biblical manuscripts, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead Sea Scrolls</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX>). The
        imaginative display of the actual scrolls inside should answer all your
        questions. The excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Youth Wing</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teenagers</ENAMEX> is opposite.
        To get your bearings take the free daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum Highlights</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tour</ENAMEX> and/or pick up the leaflet A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quick General Tour</ENAMEX>.
        Directly opposite is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible Lands Museum</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs too much
        to do this and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel Museum</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> history should definitely return.
        A <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five-minute</TIMEX> walk away is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel‚Äôs Parliament</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knesset</ENAMEX>. The modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> wins few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX>, but there is a free
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tour</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30 a.m. to 2:30 p.m.</TIMEX> ) and you can watch
        the debates (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:00 to 7:00 p.m.</TIMEX> ). Passports
        needed for both. Tapestries by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chagall</ENAMEX> and mosaic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> are the
        interior highlights.
        Another site within walking distance is the beautiful,
        ancient walled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monastery of the Cross</ENAMEX>, now hemmed in by suburbs. Built
        by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gregorian</ENAMEX> monks, it stands on the site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> from
        which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">True Cross</ENAMEX> was made.
        Farther to the west (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13, 17, 18, 20, 23, 24, 26, 27</TIMEX>)
        lies one of the world‚Äôs saddest memorials. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yad Vashem‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit</ENAMEX> means ‚Äúa
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monument</ENAMEX> and a name (which shall not perish<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">)‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇis Israel‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. It tells the story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> in words, pictures,
        art, sculpture, and other exhibits. It is imaginative, dignified, often
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">harrowing</ENAMEX>, deeply moving, and essential viewing to get an historical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX> of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. Entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> complex is
        free.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX>
        Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> still use the evocative biblical names of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Judea</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Samaria</ENAMEX>, but to the rest of the world this area is much better
        known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> (or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Occupied Territories</ENAMEX>, though this term
        is unacceptable to many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>). The designation of the name came
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> after the land west of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordan River</ENAMEX> was annexed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>. Recaptured by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>, it has become synonymous with the
        the other encroaching onto what they perceive as their rightful
        territories.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> is in political limbo. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only a few years ago</TIMEX>
        it would have been dangerous for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to travel anywhere within the
        region. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> official tourist-office advice still tends to be
        cautious; many areas are relatively safe for independent travel, though
        it is vital to keep abreast of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> news and best to avoid potential
        flashpoints such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nablus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hebron</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaza</ENAMEX>, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coast</ENAMEX>, is most troubled of all and is best avoided altogether. The
        safest way to travel in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> is as a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>-led
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tour</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Cars</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> license <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plates</ENAMEX> (including rented <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>)
        are often targets of violent attacks.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">‚Äúlittle town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem‚</ENAMEX>Äù is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> settlement
        where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> worship and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> trace the line of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>. Not
        surprisingly, therefore, it is one of the Holy Land‚Äôs many religious
        hot-spots. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main sights here. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, which lies on the
        main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Rachel‚Äôs Tomb</ENAMEX>, revered by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX>
        religions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Land</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> and died here
        while giving birth to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin</ENAMEX>). It is a very simple, low-key site,
        housed in a small <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>.
        The heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manger Square</ENAMEX>, now a car park
        ringed by souvenir <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and packed with street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawkers</ENAMEX>. Everyone who
        comes visits the fortress-like structure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of the Nativity</ENAMEX>.
        Imposing but not beautiful, it is not only the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Land</ENAMEX>, but also one of the oldest in the world. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> built in a.d.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">325</NUMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constantine</ENAMEX>, it was remodelled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two centuries later</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justinian</ENAMEX>,
        and again by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusaders</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 12th century</TIMEX>. The entrance is through
        a tiny <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixth-century</TIMEX> doorway, so low you have to bend almost double.
        This may have been to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">horseback</ENAMEX> storming into the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX>. The dark and atmospheric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">basilica</ENAMEX> is divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> naves,
        with a floor made from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>. Trapdoors swing back to reveal
        original mosaics, while gilded lamps hang from the oaken ceiling. Like
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Sepulchre</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jeru-salem</ENAMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> is too important to stay
        in the hands of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> denomination, so it is administered jointly by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Orthodox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Armenian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Franciscan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Altar of the Nativity</ENAMEX> just about drips with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>. To the side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> pilgrims queue to descend to the
        Grotto of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manger</ENAMEX>, a simple marble-clad niche in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cave wall</ENAMEX> that
        is lit by an array of hanging lamps. A blackened <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>-pointed silver star
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>.
        Minor sights include the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Milk Grotto</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> is said to
        have hidden with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> before the flight to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shepherds‚</ENAMEX>Äô
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fields</ENAMEX>, where biblical flocks were supposedly watched by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
        Herodian
        For spectacular views of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, and
        for countryside straight out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>, take a trip <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 km</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 miles</NUMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">southeast</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herodian</ENAMEX>. This hill fort was built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herod the Great</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">74‚Äì‚ÄÇ4 b.c.</ENAMEX> ), whose misdeeds were so enormous that he felt he needed a
        bolt-hole closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masada</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>) to protect him
        from his many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 b.c. and 15 b.c.</TIMEX> , he had a small
        natural hill carved into an impregnable <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">metre</NUMEX>- (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">300-foot-</ENAMEX>) high
        artificial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>mountain, capped by a mighty fortress and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>. The
        site is still compelling, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">fort</ENAMEX> itself is ruined.
        Jericho
        Jericho, one of the most famous names in antiquity, is the
        oldest walled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in the world. Radio-carbon dating on the lowest
        portions of the walls (sent tumbling by the horns of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1200</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">b.c. ‚ÄÇ ‚Äî‚ÄÇJoshua 6:20</ENAMEX>) indicates that there was a settlement of some
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at this spot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as long ago as 7800</TIMEX> b.c.
        There is little for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> in the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">centre</ENAMEX>. The
        remains of the ancient city, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tel Jericho</ENAMEX>, are on the northern edge of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX>. Legendary associations aside, however, even this site is of minor
        interest, except to archaeology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX>. Look northwest from here and you
        will see a much more impressive sight in the distance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monastery</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Temptation</ENAMEX>, said to be on the spot where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> was tempted by the
        Devil for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 days</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>, clings to the mountainside. Built in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1874</TIMEX>, it houses some very fine icons.
        Jericho‚Äôs other main attraction is the ruin of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hisham‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winter Palace</ENAMEX>, located <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">21‚ÅÑ2 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11‚ÅÑ2 miles</NUMEX>) northeast of town. Used as
        a hunting lodge by the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>- and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighth-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> Ummayad
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dynasty</ENAMEX>, from what little remains, including some excellent mosaics, it
        is obvious that it must have been palatial.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> and Jaffa
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> is in many ways the epitome of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Israel</ENAMEX>
        dream. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that has become <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> in size only to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> began
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as recently as 1906</TIMEX> as a tiny neighbour to the noisy, crowded <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaffa</ENAMEX>. The settlement burgeoned, and it soon became evident that
        this was no mere garden suburb, but a major new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Indeed, it was to
        become the first new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,000 years</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Over a million</NUMEX> people
        now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greater Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> and its surrounding ‚Äúsatellite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Jaffa</ENAMEX> has become the quiet neighbour.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was built in a hurry, with little planning or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>, and so has few <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> or open spaces and only limited
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">architectural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> or charm. It does have a certain polyglot
        big-city style, however, and it is a major centre for culture,
        business, fashion, and nightlife, with some superb <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> as well as
        an attractive beach. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Jaffa</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, is worth a day of
        anybody‚Äôs time.
        Central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>
        If you want an overview of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>, take the lift to the
        35th floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shalom Tower</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">132 metres/433 feet</NUMEX>), formerly the
        tallest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> (a communication <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> in the
        military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> near the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX> recently surpassed it).
        Just to the west is the beach, obscured by serried ranks of huge
        high-rise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ha-Yarkon Street</ENAMEX>. The beach, which runs all the way
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaffa</ENAMEX>, has soft, golden sand, best tended near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>. At
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weekends</ENAMEX> and holidays it is packed and is the place to be seen.
        Parallel with the north end of the beach is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tel Aviv‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        busiest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">thoroughfare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dizengoff Street</ENAMEX>. A good place to stroll and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>-watch, it has many of the city‚Äôs busiest and most important
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shopping</ENAMEX>, eating, and drinking places. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dizengoff Circle‚</ENAMEX>Äôs bizarre
        multi-colour <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cog-</ENAMEX>wheel fountain, known as <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Water and Fire</ENAMEX>, has the same
        sort of magnetic appeal for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">London‚Äôs Piccadilly Circus</ENAMEX>. Every
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX> on the hour from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:00 a.m. to 10:00 p.m.</TIMEX> it revolves to music,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> dances, and it emits a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> of flame.
        Just north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shalom Tower</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yemenite Quarter</ENAMEX>, its
        main attractions being the bustling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carmel</ENAMEX> market and good <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oriental</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX>. Nearby, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hagana Museum</ENAMEX> tells the fascinating story of
        underground Zionist activity in the run-up to independence.
        The modern <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concrete</ENAMEX>-and-glass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Art</ENAMEX> houses an excellent collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
        art spanning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th</TIMEX> to 20th <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of its features is a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">notable Impressionist Gallery</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> is well laid out and the
        perfect size for relaxing away <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of hours</TIMEX> on a wet day.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tel Aviv University Museums</ENAMEX>
        To the north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
        campus, lie <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>. The more conventional of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eretz Israel</ENAMEX> (the Land of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>), spread out over small
        pavilions which deal with conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> subjects such as coins,
        glass, philately, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ceramics</ENAMEX>, ethnography, folklore, etc. In addition
        there is an artisan‚Äôs workplace, and you can visit archaeological sites
        still under excavation.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Hatefutsoth</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of the Diaspora</ENAMEX> (the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Diaspora</ENAMEX> relates to the dispersal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> worldwide), is
        quite possibly the finest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and certainly the most
        innovative, yet it doesn‚Äôt contain a single exhibit of any age. Instead
        of ancient artefacts it shows the lifestyle and achievements of myriad
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> around the globe through high-tec h audio-visual
        displays, hands-on exhibits, scale models (many of which are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exquisite</ENAMEX>), and reconstructions.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Buses</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13, 24, 25, 27, 74</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX> serve both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>,
        though you wouldn‚Äôt have the energy to see both in a day. In addition,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45 and 572</TIMEX> serve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diaspora Museum</ENAMEX> and bus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX> will take you to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eretz Israel Museum</ENAMEX>.
        Jaffa
        In stark contrast to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">metropolis</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tel</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aviv</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a mere 30-minute</TIMEX> walk away, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaffa</ENAMEX> is one of the oldest cities
        in the world and almost certainly the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> still in use. It was
        from here that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonah</ENAMEX> boarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarshish</ENAMEX> in his attempt to
        flee the instructions of God (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonah</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 3</ENAMEX>), only to be swallowed by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mythology</ENAMEX> also has it that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andromeda</ENAMEX>, the beautiful
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">King of Jaffa</ENAMEX>, was chained to a rock at sea just
        outside the harbour, as a sacrifice to a sea <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> (but she was
        rescued just in time by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perseus</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaffa</ENAMEX> has been courted, crushed, and rebuilt by a
        succession of conquerors, from the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptians</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Jaffa</ENAMEX>, the heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, on a hill overlooking the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">port</ENAMEX>, was last refurbished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> has a thriving artists‚Äô
        colony as well as various tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and nightspots.
        For some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it‚Äôs become a little too gentrified, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> below
        still has something of a salty, working atmosphere.
        The best way to learn about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Jaffa</ENAMEX> is to join a free
        guided walking tour <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> (meet at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 a.m.</TIMEX> by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">landmark Clock Tower</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yefet Street</ENAMEX>). The centre is small and compact,
        perfect for strolling. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">A few yards</NUMEX> uphill from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Clock Tower</ENAMEX>, turn
        right and you will see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">el-Mahmoudia Mosque</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1812</TIMEX>. Return
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yefet Street</ENAMEX> and continue up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jaffa Flea Market</ENAMEX>, a crowded,
        covered <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aladdin‚Äôs Cave</ENAMEX> of shiny goods and trinkets (closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>).
        Keep on going along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yefet Street</ENAMEX> and then turn right and go down
        Pasteur Street to the port. The restored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> of the artists‚Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>
        lie in the maze of alleyways to the right. Turn right and you will find
        yourself in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kedumin Square</ENAMEX>, which is marked by the handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Peter</ENAMEX>. This is the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Jaffa</ENAMEX>. In the middle of the square
        there is an underground <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visitors‚Äô Centre</ENAMEX> exhibiting a fascinating
        history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> through excavations and lively display panels. From
        here you can then walk uphill to the right, to the pretty hilltop
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gardens</ENAMEX> for a superb view of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>. A little way down, in front of
        the hill, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Jaffa Antiquities</ENAMEX>. Return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kedumin Square</ENAMEX>
        and make your way down to the picturesque fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> by way of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ancient</ENAMEX>, narrow honey-coloured alleyways. At the port you‚Äôll find
        working fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>, excursion <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">marina</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>.
        Go in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early evening</TIMEX> and enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jaffa‚Äôs famous sunset</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coastal Strip</ENAMEX>
        With the possible exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is not
        known for its <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> beaches, yet between the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza Strip</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">south</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosh Hanikra</ENAMEX> in the north there are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">190 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">118 miles</NUMEX>) of
        good sandy coastline. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About half</NUMEX> of it, however, is out of bounds to
        all but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, but that still leaves huge areas of sand and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surf</ENAMEX>. The northern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">coast</ENAMEX> is the most attractive region, being
        characterized by bays, capes, valleys, islands, and peninsulas. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesarea</ENAMEX> the coastline changes dramatically and becomes almost
        straight, just as it appears on maps.
        Caesarea
        The ancient city of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesarea</ENAMEX> is the jewel of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coastal</ENAMEX>
        Strip, an extensive, dramatically excavated archaeological site and an
        attractive beach resort rolled into one. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesarea</ENAMEX>, built in
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">22‚Äì10 b.c.</TIMEX> , is said to have been Herod‚Äôs attempt to rival the pomp and
        splendour of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>. Creating a city
        boasting a major harbour, including a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500-metre</NUMEX>- (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,640-foot-</NUMEX>) long
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">breakwater</ENAMEX>, with little more than soft <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX> as a base, was undoubtedly
        a colossal feat of engineering. Caesarea became the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judea</ENAMEX>, its chief <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX>, and home to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> and to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontius Pilate</ENAMEX>.
        It was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">day‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇloud</ENAMEX> and licentious, the place where
        it all happened. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Caesarea</ENAMEX> lived, and died, to the full. In the First
        <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Jewish War</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">a.d. 66‚Äì70</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were massacred here,
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> more died later in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> amphitheatre here in the
        name of entertainment. This was where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX> were confronted by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Ghost</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Paul</ENAMEX> was imprisoned in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">as long as</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> captured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesarea</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Byzantines</ENAMEX> in a.d.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">639</NUMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusaders</ENAMEX> conquered the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1101</TIMEX>, discovering a green
        crystal vessel which they claimed to be the Holy Grail, the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">cup</NUMEX> from
        which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX> drank during the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Supper</ENAMEX> (it now
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reposes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Genoa</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was conquered and reconquered for 200 years
        before being destroyed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 13th century</TIMEX>. Ancient
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caesarea</ENAMEX> disappeared from history, only to be uncovered in the
        1940s.
        The most notable remains of the ancient city are the
        massive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">aqueduct</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> hippodrome, the amphitheatre (which
        is now used for classical music concerts) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a fourth-century</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">synagogue</ENAMEX>. You can eat and shop in and around the once-magnificent and
        heavily fortified <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, with its enormous ramparts and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cathedral</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Modern Caesarea</ENAMEX> boasts a couple of high-quality beachside
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotels</ENAMEX>, a handful of other accommodations, some pleasant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, a
        country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, and the only 18-hole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">beach</ENAMEX>, right beside the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">aqueduct</ENAMEX>, is particularly charming.
        Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resort</ENAMEX> Towns
        There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> along the strip, used almost
        exclusively by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashkelon</ENAMEX> is a site of great antiquity
        (perhaps <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4,000 years old</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samson</ENAMEX> had his famous haircut here, but he
        would find it hard to recognize the thoroughly modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
        Herzliya, which was named after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Herzl</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zionism</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most upmarket <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX>, with
        superb beaches and high prices, but nothing of historical or
        sightseeing interest.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prosperous Netanya</ENAMEX> has a large expatriate English
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>, excellent beaches, a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, and low cliffs which form an
        attractive backdrop and keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> from encroaching onto the sand.
        It is also the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon Plain</ENAMEX> citrus-growing area and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centre of Israel‚</ENAMEX>Äôs diamond industry (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haifa</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern Coast</ENAMEX>
        This northwest corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has been relatively
        unexplored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, yet it holds some of the country‚Äôs finest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sights</ENAMEX>, including the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haifa</ENAMEX>, and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusader town of Akko</ENAMEX>, better known as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Acre</ENAMEX>.
        Haifa
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilly Haifa</ENAMEX> drapes itself dramatically over the slopes of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Carmel</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> had a fairly nondescript history until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, when the construction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haifa</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Damascus</ENAMEX> railway and the
        massive new harbour (finished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>) transformed it into the vital
        trading and communications centre it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. It became a focus of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> confrontation just after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> tried to run the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> blockade (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>), and became
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> control at the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        Mandate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>. Today, it is a busy industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with the country‚Äôs
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> metro service, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carmelit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX>. This subterranean funicular
        shuttles from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> to the residential district in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just six</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beach/Port Area</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haifa</ENAMEX> has a number of good beaches, just to the west of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bat-Galim</ENAMEX> area.
        Nearby, the fine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Maritime Museum</ENAMEX> in Allenby
        Street charts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5,000 years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Sea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> seafaring, while
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clandestine Immigration and Naval Museum</ENAMEX> documents the defiance of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> blockade to smuggle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. On the other
        side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Elijah‚Äôs Cave</ENAMEX>, a venerable spot where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elijah</ENAMEX> hid
        from the irate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahab</ENAMEX> after wiping out his religion (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX>. )
        Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Family</ENAMEX> are said to have sheltered here on their return
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>.
        From here, a steep path and stairs lead <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> metres (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2184</TIMEX>
        feet) up an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age-old</TIMEX> pilgrims‚Äô path to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stella Maris Carmelite Church</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monastery</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1836</TIMEX> over a cave also believed to have been
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inhabited by the prophet Elijah</ENAMEX>. Alternatively, take one of the bulbous
        black cable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> which make the ascent from the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bat</ENAMEX>-Galim
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promenade</ENAMEX>.
        If you can bear the thunderous traffic, the area around
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Place de Paris Carmelit</ENAMEX> terminus is a good earthy place to explore,
        with a street market and several interesting small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and eating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">houses</ENAMEX>. The enormous <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">68-metre</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">223-foot</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dagon Grain Silo</ENAMEX>, by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX>,
        is still working, but opens for tours (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a.m.</TIMEX> ) and contains a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haifa Railway Museum</ENAMEX>, on Hativat
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golani Road</ENAMEX>, has a number of large locomotives and exhibits to please
        any train-spotter.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadar Area</ENAMEX>
        Haifa‚Äôs most famous attraction is the splendid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">golden-domed Baha‚Äôi Shrine and Gardens</ENAMEX> (entrance on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Zionism Avenue</ENAMEX>;
        Shrine open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00 a.m. to noon</TIMEX>, gardens open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00 a.m</TIMEX> to
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:00 p.m.</TIMEX> ), the international <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4-million</NUMEX>-strong
        Baha‚Äôi faith, which was founded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> holy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baha‚</ENAMEX>Äôu‚Äôllah
        (who died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1892</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> believes in universal peace,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brotherhood</ENAMEX>, and charity, and incorporates elements of all the major
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">religions</ENAMEX>, accepting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed</ENAMEX> as prophets.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shrine</ENAMEX>, completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>, is also the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bab</ENAMEX>, the
        forerunner of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baha‚Äôu‚Äôllah.</ENAMEX> It is surrounded by luxuriant formal gardens
        with marvellous views. The gardens are being extended in a massive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX>
        million project designed to include even more magnificent hanging
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gardens</ENAMEX>.
        Just up the hill from here is the bucolic Mitzpe
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha-Shalom</ENAMEX>, also called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Peace View Park</ENAMEX>, containing a peaceful sculpture
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">garden</ENAMEX>, and also offering splendid views.
        For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haifa Museum</ENAMEX>, take the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carmelit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha-Nevi‚Äôim</ENAMEX>, and walk along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shabtai Levi Street</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> has ancient
        and modern art, an excellent archaeology section, and temporary
        exhibits of music and ethnology.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Carmel</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carmel Man</ENAMEX>, a relation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Neanderthal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, lived
        here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">600,000 years ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carmel</ENAMEX> is now an elegant residential and hotel
        district (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carmelit</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gan Ha-em</ENAMEX>) featuring the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>,
        and caf√©s. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> stay up here and stroll at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> along the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">charming Louis Promenade</ENAMEX>, by the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, to enjoy the vast,
        spectacular panorama of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haifa‚</ENAMEX>Äôs lights glittering below.
        Other places of interest are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mane Katz Museum</ENAMEX>, Yefe
        Nof Street, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prehistory Museum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ha-Tishbi Street</ENAMEX>, and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edith Hecht Museum of Archaeology</ENAMEX>, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haifa University</ENAMEX>
        campus at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Carmel</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Druse Villages</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haifa</ENAMEX> (bus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>), the pleasant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dalait el-Carmel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isfiya</ENAMEX> are occupied by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Druse</ENAMEX>, a sectarian
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> who reject many of the teachings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> and share very
        few allegiances with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian Arabs</ENAMEX>. There‚Äôs not a great deal to
        see but the markets and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> are good for souvenir hunting, and you‚Äôll
        find that the hospitable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Druse</ENAMEX> make the visit very enjoyable.
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">About</NUMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five-minute</TIMEX> drive south stands the Muhraka
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carmelite Monastery</ENAMEX>, on the spot where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elijah</ENAMEX>, with the help of Yaweh
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God</ENAMEX>), defeated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ba‚</ENAMEX>Äôal god in a test of spontaneous combustion,
        leading to the death of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX> heathen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>. Stunning views extend from
        this peaceful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX>, which is open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00 a.m. to 1:30 p.m. and</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:30 to 5:00 p.m.</TIMEX> (closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akko</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Acre</ENAMEX>)
        An important ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phoenician</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> city
        long before the arrival of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusaders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akko</ENAMEX> is one of the
        most rewarding places to visit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. It has the colour and
        vitality of an old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, but little of the usual hassle, boasting
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">superb Crusader</ENAMEX> and caravanserai <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>, and a
        picturesque <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX>. This is all within a few blocks, interwoven with
        narrow ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mosque</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Jezzar</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1781</TIMEX>, dominates the
        landside of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> (the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> jut into the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Jezzar</ENAMEX> (‚Äúthe butcher‚Äù) was a brutal <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian</ENAMEX> pirate
        who became pasha (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX> regional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>) during the late 18th
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> and was responsible for building much of the surviving Old
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> largest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and the most important
        outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> are welcome from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early morning until 12:30</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m.</TIMEX> , then for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours in the afternoon</TIMEX> (enquire at the tourist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>).
        Almost opposite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> gate are the tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and
        the entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crusader City</ENAMEX>, which was buried by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Jezzar</ENAMEX>, who
        simply constructed his new citadel on top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> in
        order to avoid dismantling their enormous foundations.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Crusade</ENAMEX> to recover <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> reached its climax
        here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1099</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Acre</ENAMEX> became the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Crusaders‚Äô</ENAMEX> capital and a key <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> in
        their struggles for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Land</ENAMEX>. Only a small part of their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has
        been excavated for fear that further work may cause the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to
        collapse. Nonetheless, enough is open to get a very good feel for its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandeur</ENAMEX> and enormity. As there is little interpretation inside, try to
        see the introductory film <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> (showing throughout <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day from 9:00</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a.m. to 5:00 p.m.</TIMEX> ). Your ticket also entitles you to visit the
        Municipal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>, which is actually no more than a well-preserved
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-18th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hammam</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> bath).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Browse</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> market behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> and
        wander the alleyways towards the port. You will pass some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akko‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> khans or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">caravanserais‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇinns</ENAMEX> with large inner courtyards used by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">travellers</ENAMEX> and their caravans. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The 18th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khan el-Umdan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inn</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pillars</ENAMEX>) is the finest. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> near the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX>; its clocktower is a
        famous landmark.
        The old fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a bustling</NUMEX>, colourful hubbub of
        activity, from where you can take excursions or hire your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>.
        Continue round the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> seawalls to the northernmost
        corner and you will come to the entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citadel</ENAMEX>. This imposing
        structure, built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Jezzar</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX>), nowadays holds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Underground Prisoners</ENAMEX>, which documents the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> resistance
        movement that fought against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Mandate</ENAMEX> period
        (part of the film <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exodus</ENAMEX> was shot here). It‚Äôs an interesting account of
        the violent history of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, and ends in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scaffold Room</ENAMEX>
        where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were executed. The highlight of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citadel</ENAMEX> is the
        rooftop view over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El-Jezzar Mosque</ENAMEX>.
        Leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> by its eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nikanor Gate</ENAMEX> for a
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five-minute</TIMEX> walk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hof Argaman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Purple Beach</ENAMEX>), one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel‚</ENAMEX>Äôs finest
        beaches. There is a fee, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> are good.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nahariya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosh Hanikra</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nahariya</ENAMEX> is a quiet beach <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> with fine white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sands</ENAMEX> and
        good leisure <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosh Hanikra</ENAMEX>, near the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lebanese</ENAMEX> border, is
        famous for its dramatic sea grottoes embedded in the white chalk cliffs
        and reached by cable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
        The Galilee
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galilee</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel‚</ENAMEX>Äôs lushest landscape, with grassy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slopes</ENAMEX>, fertile valleys, and, to the north, rolling hills and majestic
        mountains. Above all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HaGalil</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galilee</ENAMEX> is known in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>) is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, who based his short <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX> here and performed
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> most famous miracles on and around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galilee</ENAMEX>. This area is not just for pilgrims, however; it is also for
        those in search of the great outdoors, whether for sports activities or
        simply hiking.
        Nazareth
        The place where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> grew up, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazareth</ENAMEX>, is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> a small,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">dusty Christian Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> with sprawling modern developments swamping
        the old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and ancient sights. Its enormous, ornate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> are a
        far cry from the simple biblical sites of the imagination. The main
        sights are not obvious, so call in at the tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casa Nova</ENAMEX>
        Street for a free guide map.
        The centre of attention is the huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basilica</ENAMEX> of the
        Annunciation, standing on the traditional site of the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> and the cave where the archangel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX> appeared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> to
