
  
  
    
      
        Where to go
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> has many different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sides</ENAMEX>, which means you‚Äôre in
        ‚ÄÇ for the ideal vacation whether you‚Äôre a tranquil beach-loving type, a
        city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slicker</ENAMEX>, a born shopper, a celebrity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chaser</ENAMEX>, or simply a
        pleasure-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seeker</ENAMEX> who goes with the flow. While there‚Äôs much to see
        wherever you go, the essence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> vacation is experiencing
        the southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> ‚Äúvibe,‚Äù which means all you really have to do
        is explore and watch life unfurl.
        To savor the abundant flavors of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>, you need a taste for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adventure</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> (ideally), and a good map. Add savvy plans that keep
        you off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeways</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">rush hour</TIMEX> (generally <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekdays</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7am</TIMEX> to
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30am and 3:30pm</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7pm</NUMEX>) and a dash of patience for the guaranteed
        gridlock traffic nightmare, and you will discover firsthand why
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Angelenos</ENAMEX> consider their home the center of the universe.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">HOLLYWOOD</ENAMEX>
        ‚Äú <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>,‚Äù as it is perceived by the world, is no longer
        an actual place but, rather, a lifestyle unique to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. While
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> might once have had a glamorous reputation, for
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few decades</TIMEX> the neighborhood, which stretches along the base
        of the northern hills emblazoned with the landmark <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> sign, has
        deteriorated like a faded movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> first became the center of the film industry in
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1920s</NUMEX>, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecil B. DeMille</ENAMEX> set up the town‚Äôs first movie studio
        near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Highland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sunset</ENAMEX> in a horse <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX> and filmed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Squaw Man</ENAMEX>, the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> feature-length film, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1913</TIMEX>.
        For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next four decades</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> was the film industry.
        As home to such entertainment royalty as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garland</ENAMEX> and host of the first public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Awards</ENAMEX> at the historic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roosevelt Hotel</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was genuinely the epicenter of
        entertainment and celebrity stardom.
        But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the area‚Äôs golden history has been tarnished by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abandonment</ENAMEX> and an ongoing parade of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hustlers</ENAMEX> and lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> wandering
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood Boulevard</ENAMEX>. In fact, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> here now are those inlaid
        into the mildly interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Walk of Fame</ENAMEX> (or headed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientology</ENAMEX>); the rest of the commotion is caused by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists shuffling</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> attraction or cheesy T-shirt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> to the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next</TIMEX>.
        Still, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraris</ENAMEX> and
        chauffeured <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> steer clear of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is
        indeed attempting a bonafide comeback. There are plans to sink <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
        of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to develop new attractions,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. However, the curtain has not yet gone
        up for the city‚Äôs encore performance.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinseltown Triumphs</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> sign over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beachwood Canyon</ENAMEX> is perhaps the
        most recognized landmark in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and a favorite photo
        background. Originally constructed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923</TIMEX> to promote real estate sales
        in the neighborhood then called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúHollywoodland</ENAMEX>,‚Äù the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50-foot</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15-m</NUMEX>)
        letters were abbreviated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX> and replaced due to age in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>. Even though you can‚Äôt get close to the sign (it has a security
        system surrounding it), it‚Äôs still a powerful and beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX>,
        reminding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles‚</ENAMEX>Äôs status as the center of the fast
        and glamorous world of movie making.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> certainly get a kick out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> Walk of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fame</ENAMEX>, even if it does keep your interest for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a few minutes</TIMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúwalk‚Äù</ENAMEX> refers to the legwork you‚Äôll need to do to check out the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,174</NUMEX>
        (as of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Feb 2001</ENAMEX>) bronze-and-terrazzo stars embedded in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pavement</ENAMEX> to
        honor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> in the music and entertainment industries. Stars
        stretch for a total of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">31‚ÅÑ2 miles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">51‚ÅÑ2 km</NUMEX>) along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hollywood Boulevard</ENAMEX>
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sycamore Avenue</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gower Street</ENAMEX>, and along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vine Street</ENAMEX> from Yucca
        Street to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunset Boulevard</ENAMEX>. Among the most sought-after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> are those
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX> (in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald‚</ENAMEX>Äôs at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6774</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hollywood Boulevard</ENAMEX>),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Chaplin</ENAMEX> (at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6751</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1541</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Vine</ENAMEX>).
        What does it take to get one‚Äôs name on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>? It‚Äôs not as
        difficult as you might think. To attain such concrete notoriety, you
        must be nominated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> and then, if
        selected, come up with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> to pay for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mann‚Äôs Chinese Theater</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6925</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hollywood Boulevard</ENAMEX>), which
        you can‚Äôt miss due to its flashy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>-style architecture and
        the swarms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> out front, is one of the other worthwhile stops
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hollywood Boulevard</ENAMEX>. While current films are still shown here, the
        real attraction is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exterior courtyard</ENAMEX>, where autographs,
        hand-prints, and foot-prints in cement commemorate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood‚</ENAMEX>Äôs greatest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>.
        This <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Art-Deco</ENAMEX> picture palace, originally called The
        Graumann, was built by the great showman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sid Graumann</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">courtyard</ENAMEX> tradition allegedly began at the grand opening, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Talmadge</ENAMEX> accidentally stepped in wet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cement</ENAMEX>. Among the famous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">signatures</ENAMEX>, you can also spot such unusual impressions as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX>
        Durante‚Äôs nose and the hoof prints of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Autry‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Champion</ENAMEX>.
        While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mann‚</ENAMEX>Äôs is undoubtedly the hot spot for your
        ‚ÄúThat‚Äôs-me-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX> snapshots, the area‚Äôs other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landmark</ENAMEX> cinemas
        deserve a peek as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Citizen Kane</ENAMEX> premiered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX> at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moorish</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Capitan Theater</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6838</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hollywood Boulevard</ENAMEX>), which
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is a primary venue for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> films. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6712</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boulevard</ENAMEX>) was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollywood‚Äôs</ENAMEX> first movie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>, built by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graumann</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX> after the discovery of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tut‚Äôs</ENAMEX> tomb. It‚Äôs just undergone major
        renovation.
        Also noteworthy is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood Roosevelt Hotel</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7000</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood Boulevard</ENAMEX>), which established itself as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> of the film
        world when it opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just two years later</TIMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>, the
        landmark building hosted the first public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX> ceremony; it was also
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>. Its lobby features hand-painted
        ceilings and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>-revival d√©cor of wrought-iron grillwork. On
        display on the mezzanine floor are historic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> photographs and
        other memorabilia.
        For a fascinating look at the nuts and bolts of movie and
        TV production, visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood Entertainment Museum</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7021</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blvd</ENAMEX>. ), where hi-tech interactive exhibits reveal the history of the
        entertainment arts.You can go on a guided tour of a mock movie studio
        back lot, put your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foley</ENAMEX> sound effects into a short film, walk onto
        the sets of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers and Star Trek</ENAMEX>, have your picture taken with
        green-screen technology backgrounds, and see relics of early movie and
        TV technology. They also have rotating special exhibits that change
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every two months</TIMEX>.
        Strictly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ripley‚Äôs Believe It or Not</ENAMEX>! offers lightweight
        entertainment, starting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Tyrannosaurus rex towering</ENAMEX> above the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entrance</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6780</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hollywood Boulevard</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Highland Avenue</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Ripley</ENAMEX>
        was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX> who traveled the far corners of the globe in the 1930s
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1940s</ENAMEX>, searching for the bizarre. His <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ‚ÄúOdditorium‚Äù opened at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago World‚Äôs Fair</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>, and the cartoon features based on his
        collection are still syndicated worldwide. Here you‚Äôll see a shrunken
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-headed goat, and a statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX> made of
        shredded money, among other curiosities.
        Next door to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripley‚</ENAMEX>Äôs is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guinness World of Records</ENAMEX>
        (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6764</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hollywood Boulevard</ENAMEX>) offering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> of displays about
        bizarre facts, feats, and achievements. Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unimpressive Hollywood Wax Museum</ENAMEX>, which features a collection of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstars</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ to Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX>, can also be visited
        on a joint ticket.
        Further along you‚Äôll spot the flashy pink exterior of
        Frederick‚Äôs of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6608</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hollywood Boulevard</ENAMEX>), the shop renowned
        for glamorizing trashy undergarments. Behind the racks of feathery,
        satin bras and panties is their renowned ‚ÄúLingerie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>,‚Äù where you
        can peek at the intimate apparel of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>.
        The intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vine</ENAMEX> was once touted as
        the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tinseltown</ENAMEX>, but now it is rather nondescript, save for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">landmark Capitol Records Building</ENAMEX>, which is shaped like a stack of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX>. The building‚Äôs distinctive design is credited to recording
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stars Nat King Cole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Mercer</ENAMEX>.
        Movies-in-the-Making
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Studios</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5555</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Melrose Avenue</ENAMEX>) is the only major
        motion picture <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> still physically located in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. If peeking
        in through the wrought-iron gates isn‚Äôt enough shoulder-rubbing with
        stardom for you, you can view the back lot on a walking tour. The tour
        takes you through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>, film sets (when not in use), sound
        stages, and props <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, and offers a glimpse of other
        behind-the-scenes activities. It reveals a peek at such tricks of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tank</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> parted the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> in The Ten
        Commandments, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New York Street</ENAMEX>, a fa√ßade of brownstones made of
        fiberglass that has been aged to look like real brick.
        If you drive west on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melrose</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Studios</ENAMEX>, you‚Äôll
        arrive at the trendy section of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Melrose Avenue</ENAMEX> (between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Brea</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fairfax</ENAMEX>), where young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, local hipsters, and fashionable freaks
        populate the funky <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and caf√©s.
        THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WILSHIRE DISTRICT</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilshire Boulevard</ENAMEX> began as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX> connecting the
        downtown area with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Brea</ENAMEX> tar pits and later was developed as an
        upscale shopping and business district. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it is one of the widest
        and longest boulevards in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>, showcasing the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faces</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. Stretching <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">16 miles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 km</NUMEX>) from downtown to the sea, it
        passes through a variety of ethnic neighborhoods and financial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brackets‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇfrom the very poor to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ridiculously</ENAMEX> wealthy. The stretch
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilshire</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Brea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX>, known as the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Wilshire</ENAMEX> district or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">‚ÄúMiracle Mile</ENAMEX>,‚Äù is slowly being restored after
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of neglect. Until restoration is complete, the main reason to hit
        the area is to check out cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>.
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Peek</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prehistoric Times</ENAMEX>
        A curious and fascinating attraction is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Brea Tar</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pits</ENAMEX>, one of the world‚Äôs richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pleistocene</ENAMEX> fossils that
        date back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40,000 years</TIMEX>. In the large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pit</ENAMEX> in front of the Page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
        (see below), life-size replicas of mastodons are shown trapped in the
        tar. From viewing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> alongside other pits, you can watch on-going
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">excavations</ENAMEX> and view the amalgamated bones of the unfortunate
        prehistoric <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX> that perished here.
        The adjacent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George C. Page Museum</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Brea Discoveries</ENAMEX>
        (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5801</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wilshire Boulevard</ENAMEX>) provides fascinating insight into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ice Age</TIMEX>
        life in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15-minute</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">La Brea Story</ENAMEX> is an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">introductory</ENAMEX> film illustrating how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> became trapped in the
        asphalt as they edged down to a pool of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to drink. Skeletons of
        such extinct <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">saber-toothed cat</ENAMEX>, imperial mammoth, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giant</ENAMEX> ground sloth have been reconstructed from the fossils. The wall
        display of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">400 wolf skulls</ENAMEX> brings a startling realization of just how
        many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> have been unearthed here.
        Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">420</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal species</ENAMEX> found in the area, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> human
        fossil has been unearthed: the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9,000-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Brea Woman</ENAMEX>. Killed by
        a blow to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, she was perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A.‚Äôs</ENAMEX> first murder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX> also features a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fishbowl laboratory</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> can see
        fossils being cleaned and catalogued. The peaceful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">atrium</ENAMEX> nurtures
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">primitive plants</ENAMEX>, several of which have evolved over a period of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> Row
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles County Museum of Art</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5905</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilshire</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boulevard</ENAMEX>), the city‚Äôs largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, is located next door. Among the
        treasures housed in this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-building <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> are a collection of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pre-Columbian</ENAMEX> artifacts that were found in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
        modern and contemporary art, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> colonial art and furniture,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> masterpieces, and what is generally regarded as the finest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast Asian</ENAMEX> art collection in the West. There are also
        ever-changing special exhibits.
        The small but significant <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Craft</ENAMEX> and Folk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art Museum</ENAMEX>, at
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5814</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wilshire Boulevard</ENAMEX>, rotates exhibitions from around the world.
        Nearby, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6060</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilshire</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petersen Automotive Museum</ENAMEX>
        celebrates the town‚Äôs love affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, showcasing over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">160</NUMEX>
        distinctive motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>, with special exhibits on automotive
        themes.
        Local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Color</ENAMEX>
        A few blocks north on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax</ENAMEX> is the lively <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmers‚Äô Market</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">6333 West Third Street</ENAMEX>). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Depression-era</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> gathered here, in what was then a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> at the edge of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> produce directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Its popularity as a meeting place
        has kept it busy all these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> perusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vegetable</ENAMEX> stands for the best bargains, a maze of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> selling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foodstuffs</ENAMEX> and gifts, and inexpensive food <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX> serving up a variety
        of tasty cuisines.
        THE WESTSIDE
        Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> make up the area known as the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúWestside.</ENAMEX> ‚Äù They are linked not only by geographical location but also
        by image: here are the upmarket and fashionable neighborhoods, with
        affluent residential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX>, trendy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A.‚Äôs fabulous</ENAMEX>
        shopping areas.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Hollywood</ENAMEX>
        While <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> is more remembered than experienced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nowadays</ENAMEX>, its neighbor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">West Hollywood‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa</ENAMEX> separate, incorporated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">city‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇdefines the new cutting edge. Within its tiny <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 square miles</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">sq km</NUMEX>) you will find over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, many of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>‚Äôs best known
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nightclubs</ENAMEX>, unique interior design <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art galleries</ENAMEX>, swank
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotels</ENAMEX>, and the high-powered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of the entertainment and music
        industries.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Melrose Avenue</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robertson Boulevards</ENAMEX> are
        known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúAvenues of Design</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> here are lined with
        design <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">showrooms</ENAMEX>, fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX>, and a growing number of art
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">galleries</ENAMEX>, including the notable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Design Center</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8687</TIMEX> Melrose
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenue</ENAMEX>), a gigantic, blue-glass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesar Pelli</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Some 200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">showrooms</ENAMEX> are housed here and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adjoining Green</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>, which displays an impressive range of traditional and
        contemporary home and office furniture created by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous designers</ENAMEX>. The
        showrooms are for trade only, meaning the only way you can make
        purchases is to buy through an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interior designer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> are welcome
        to browse <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekdays</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9am</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5pm</TIMEX>.
        Spanning the length of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Hollywood</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Boulevard‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe center</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>‚Äôs gay and lesbian nightlife. Every year
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> holds the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Street West Gay</ENAMEX> and Lesbian
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pride Celebration</ENAMEX>, a lively <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">festival and parade</ENAMEX> which has grown
        into the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> largest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> also goes wild each
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halloween</ENAMEX> as the lively <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> parade around in crazy costumes.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sunset Strip</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Hollywood‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">thoroughfare</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sunset</ENAMEX>
        Strip, stretching from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8200</TIMEX> block of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sunset Boulevard west</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Doheny Drive</ENAMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX> it has been the stomping grounds for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.A.‚Äôs</ENAMEX> partying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>. With many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renovations</ENAMEX> dating from the 90s
        economic boom, its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> remain spectacularly impervious to
        the curent downturn. Many top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedians</ENAMEX> started here in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> such as
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Store</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rock‚Äôn‚Äôroll legends</ENAMEX> were born in the dance
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">halls of The Roxy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Whisky-A-Go-Go</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends the strip‚</TIMEX>Äôs traffic
        still slows as the young and the hip traipse from one happening night
        spot to the next. But even if you never leave your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, the huge
        billboards beaming with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faces</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> promoting their latest
        movie or recording (or simply themselves) announce this is the town‚Äôs
        wild play <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>. Among the landmarks that you‚Äôll pass is The Argyle
        (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8358</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunset Boulevard</ENAMEX>), a stately <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Art-Deco masterpiece</ENAMEX> built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX>.
        Formerly called the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunset Tower</ENAMEX>, it was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> all-electric
        apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark Gable</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Errol Flynn</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jean</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harlow</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> who once lived here. Further west
        is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mondrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8440</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunset Boulevard</ENAMEX>), which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Schrager</ENAMEX> made
        trendy again with sleek modern d√©cor by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillippe Starck</ENAMEX> and a parade
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> who frequent the beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">outdo</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">SkyBar</ENAMEX> cocktail
        lounge.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sunset Plaza</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8600-8700</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunset Boulevard</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sunset Plaza</ENAMEX>
        Drive) has been an elite shopping area since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>. This cluster of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Georgian</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Selkirk</ENAMEX> was once home to
        the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mocambo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trocadero</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclubs</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX> is
        lined with upmarket, one-of-a-kind specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, pleasant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk caf√©s</ENAMEX>, and swarms of the wealthy and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wannabes</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hip</ENAMEX> gives way to chic at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Doheny Drive</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX> ends
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunset Boulevard</ENAMEX> enters <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>. Here, luxurious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and
        landscaped <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX> sit on some of the most expensive real estate in the
        world. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> worth sidetracking into the hills just to marvel at how
        much money some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> actually have. On this stretch of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sunset</ENAMEX> you‚Äôre
        bound to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawkers</ENAMEX> on street <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corners</ENAMEX> selling ‚ÄúMaps to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stars‚</ENAMEX>Äù to
        lead you to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> of the rich and famous.
        This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire mecca</ENAMEX> is a testament to the region‚Äôs
        unparalleled success. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX> the land was
        practically worthless, covered with failed oil <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> and fields of lima
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX>. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>, when a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> built the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>
        Hotel (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9641</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunset Boulevard</ENAMEX>), everything changed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
        Colonial-style <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was soon dubbed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pink Palace</ENAMEX> and fast became
        popular with the movie set. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Polo Lounge</ENAMEX> is now a notorious watering
        hole for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood‚</ENAMEX>Äôs power-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX>
        were said to be among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> who met secretly in the private
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bungalows</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> is now owned‚<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇappropriately‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇby one of the
        richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in the world, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brunei</ENAMEX>, who restored it to its
        blatant grandeur for a whopping <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1920</TIMEX>, silent screen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Pickford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX>
        Fairbanks built their opulent estate, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pickfair</ENAMEX>, just up the hill (at
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1143</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Summit Drive</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Chaplin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Swanson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Valentino</ENAMEX>,
        and others also flocked in to establish one of the most concentrated
        celebrity enclaves in the world. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> ‚Äúin the hills‚Äù are regarded
        as somewhat more prestigious than those ‚Äúin the flats. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù</ENAMEX> )
        It‚Äôs not surprising that the highest number of business
        licenses in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> are issued to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardeners</ENAMEX>. Those who are not
        busy manicuring the residential <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX> are often to be found working in
        the lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Garden Park</ENAMEX>, which borders <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica Boulevard</ENAMEX>
        for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 miles</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 km</NUMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doheny</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilshire</ENAMEX>.
        Another stretch of beautiful gardens can be seen at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Greystone Mansion</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">905</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loma Vista Dr.</ENAMEX>), the spectacular neo-Gothic
        estate of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oilman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Doheny</ENAMEX>. The grounds are open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily May-Oct.</TIMEX>
        10am to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6pm</NUMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. -Apr. 10-5</TIMEX>; but the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>, now city property and a
        frequent film set (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witches of Eastwick</ENAMEX>), is closed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.
        The most renowned section of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>, however, is
        open to the public. Take a walk through the elite shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> known
        as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rodeo Drive</ENAMEX> (pronounced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ro-DAY-oh</ENAMEX>), where top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> showcase
        their fashions to a glamorous, sophisticated, and of course rich
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clientele</ENAMEX>. While the shopping is still world-class, real estate prices
        and corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> have forced out most of the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>
        who gave the place <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in the past, making it almost impossible
        to find that one-of-a-kind treasure.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least one</NUMEX> historically fashionable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> still
        resides here in all its glory. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regent Beverly Wilshire</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9500</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilshire Boulevard</ENAMEX>) has been a landmark since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>. The luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> is
        still a favorite of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> and visiting royalty, some of whom have
        been known to rent entire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> for their stay. It‚Äôs more publicly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">renowned</ENAMEX>, however, as the setting where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts‚</ENAMEX>Äô and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
        Gere‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> found love in the film <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pretty Woman</ENAMEX>.
        The quaint <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills Trolley</ENAMEX> offers a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">40-minute</TIMEX> guided
        tour of landmarks and residential areas for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>). It runs
        on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hour summer afternoons</TIMEX> and during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas season</TIMEX>; other
        times, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays only</TIMEX>. Catch it at the corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rodeo Drive</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayton</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX>. For more information, call <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">310-285-2438</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century City</ENAMEX>
        Though there is not much to see at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century City</ENAMEX>, it‚Äôs worth
        noting that this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> was built on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">180 acres</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">73</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hectares</ENAMEX>) of what was once <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twentieth Century Fox‚</ENAMEX>Äôs enormous back-lot
        studio. The motion picture <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, now relegated to a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX> on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pico Boulevard</ENAMEX>, is still active. But the surrounding area is a sleek
        Westside business <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of high-rise office towers, high-flying
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> and shopping to support the affluent
        residents on its periphery.
        Opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Tolerance</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9786</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">West Pico</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boulevard</ENAMEX>) is a chilling and provocative experience, with impressive
        high-tech, exhibits exploring racism and prejudice in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and
        elsewhere. Of particular note are the interactive video stations
        exploring the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> riots. A major part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> is devoted to
        Hashoah, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. This tour alone lasts <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a full hour</TIMEX>, and at least
        equal time is necessary to appreciate the other collections and the
        multi-media learning center on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bel</ENAMEX>-Air, and Brentwood
        The sprawling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California at Los</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX>) dominates the area known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westwood</ENAMEX>. The grounds, with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lovely Romanesque-style Royce Hall</ENAMEX> dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell Library</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Murphy Sculpture Garden</ENAMEX> (with works by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rodin</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir√≥</ENAMEX>), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mathias Botanical Gardens</ENAMEX>, offer a welcome respite from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motor metropolis</ENAMEX>. Maps and information are available from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kiosks</ENAMEX> at the main entrances and at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">visitors‚Äô center</ENAMEX>; ask for the
        free <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90-minute</TIMEX> campus tours during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">310/825-4321</ENAMEX>).
        To the south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westwood Village</ENAMEX> is an area
        that was once the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hub</ENAMEX> of social activity but suffered a decline due to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">revitalization of Santa Monica‚Äôs Third Street Promenade</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it‚Äôs
        still a popular place to catch the latest film at any of the enormous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theaters</ENAMEX> or cruise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. At the village‚Äôs southern
        tip, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA/Armand Hammer Museum of Art</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cultural Center</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10899</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilshire Boulevard</ENAMEX>) presents a small, exquisite collection of artworks
        gathered over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past fifty years</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armand Hammer</ENAMEX> himself. Its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> display masterpieces by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rembrandt</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Gogh</ENAMEX>,
        with an extensive collection of lithographs by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honor√© Daumier</ENAMEX>. Check
        out what else is on display while you are here, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> regularly
        hosts special exhibitions.
        To the north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX>, across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sunset Boulevard</ENAMEX>, is the
        exclusive neighborhood of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bel Air</ENAMEX>. As the tight-knit community is an
        enclave of old-money estates for such royalty as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagans</ENAMEX>, you won‚Äôt
        get to glimpse more than big front gates and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX>. You can, however,
        get a peek into the good life at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel Bel Air‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX>,
        and gardens (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">701</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone Canyon Road</ENAMEX>), where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebs</ENAMEX> often linger.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> art world‚Äôs most hyped new attraction is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Getty</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>, the long-awaited visual-arts <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Meier</ENAMEX>
        and perched on a bluff high above the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">405</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeway</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brentwood</ENAMEX>, just
        west of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX>. The cost: a whopping <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one billion dollars</NUMEX>. Several
        attractions in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> comprises the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Paul Getty Museum</ENAMEX> plus
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institutes</ENAMEX> for arts education, conservation, and research. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
        boasts a major collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> antiquities, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
        paintings (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rembrandt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Gogh</ENAMEX>, among others),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drawings</ENAMEX> (including a few by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo da Vinci</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">illuminated medieval manuscripts</ENAMEX>, photographs, sculpture, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> decorative arts displayed within <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five two</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilions</ENAMEX>. After
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> antiquities will return to their renovated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Getty Villa</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malibu</ENAMEX>, for permanent exhibition (see page
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX>).
        The impressive architecture, sculpture gardens (one of
        which was designed by southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Irwin</ENAMEX>), and
        panoramic views of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, mountains, and ocean are awesome attractions
        in themselves.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">COASTAL LOS ANGELES</ENAMEX>
        From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malibu</ENAMEX> in the north to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX> in the south, the
        shoreline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles County</ENAMEX> stretch for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">72 miles</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">115</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">km</ENAMEX>) along the striking edge of the ocean.
        Driving north on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pacific Coast Highway 1</ENAMEX> (often marked
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúPCH‚Äù</ENAMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malibu</ENAMEX> is an excellent introduction to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern California‚</ENAMEX>Äôs seductive beach life. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Palos Verdes Drive</ENAMEX> is
        another eye-catching stretch, hugging the cliffs along the southern tip
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa Monica Bay</ENAMEX>. But to really appreciate the allure of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> lifestyle, you must ditch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and hit the sand and
        experience the natural beauty of the beaches first hand.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marina del Rey</ENAMEX>
        Ever since it was founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1870s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX> has
        been thought of as the perfect seaside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. Nonetheless, in the 1930s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> games, bingo <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parlors</ENAMEX>, and a casino barge anchored offshore
        brought such notoriety to the area that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Chandler</ENAMEX> used
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX> as the model for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">freewheeling ‚ÄúBay City‚Äù</ENAMEX> of his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">detective</ENAMEX> novels. Today, with trendy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX>, blue-chip art
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">galleries</ENAMEX>, a buzzing nightlife scene, and some of the finest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX> looks as if it is set to
        continue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">forever</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>‚Äôs most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica Pier</ENAMEX>, site of the famous carousel as well as
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">La Monica Ballroom</ENAMEX>, was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908</TIMEX>. Much of this historic
        structure was demolished by storms in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, prompting restoration to
        its original look. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arcades</ENAMEX> and amusement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> rides lining
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX> lure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> with their wonderfully tacky old-world ambiance,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">locals</ENAMEX> also come here to rent fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tackle</ENAMEX> at the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX> or
        check out the festive free concerts held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each summer</TIMEX>.
        Beneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX> and as far as the eye can see to the north
        and south you‚Äôll find beachgoers at play on the widest band of sand on
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Coast</ENAMEX>. The busy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">path</ENAMEX> running alongside the beach to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>
        is a coveted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bicyclists</ENAMEX> and rollerbladers, who either bring
        their own gear or rent from the numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX> nearby.
        Above the sand is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palisades Park</ENAMEX>, a pretty, palm-lined
        stretch that runs for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11‚ÅÑ2 km</NUMEX>) along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ocean Avenue</ENAMEX>. The broad
        walkway offers spectacular views of the ocean, especially at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sunset</ENAMEX>.
        Just inland you‚Äôll find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Monica‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main Street</ENAMEX>, which
        is awash with unusual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. Looming over its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern</ENAMEX> end at the intersection with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rose Avenue</ENAMEX> is a giant sculpture
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Borofsky</ENAMEX> known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballerina Clown</ENAMEX>. As its name implies,
        this is a giant clown‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on a tutu-clad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Edgemar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, located in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2400</TIMEX> block, exhibits
        the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>‚Äôs favorite postmodern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gehry</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX>). Inside is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monica Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, which showcases the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde</ENAMEX> and performance
        art of contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> also mount shows in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-floor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">galleries of the California Heritage Museum</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2612</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main Street</ENAMEX>). This
        former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> was moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main Street</ENAMEX>, and its lower
        floor has been completely restored to reflect a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">turn-of-the-century</TIMEX>
        lifestyle. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Upstairs rooms</ENAMEX> are reserved for exhibitions.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Dozens</NUMEX> of prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art galleries</ENAMEX> have set up shop in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, with the result that it is now a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of the
        contemporary art scene. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> are situated along a stretch of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Avenue</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 9th</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">10th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>.
        Aside from the beach, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Street Promenade</ENAMEX> has become
        the most popular destination in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX>. This <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-block
        pedestrian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>, with its street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">performers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur topiaries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>,
        movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, is perennially teeming with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">locals</ENAMEX>, especially on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> evenings, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX>, pool <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">caf√©s</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> guarantee an action-packed night out.
        Curiously enough, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX> has a large contingent of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, evident in the authentic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ye Olde King‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> (complete with dart <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>), just off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promenade</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>
        room at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudor House British Centre</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Roughly 10</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> of the
        city‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> are of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> descent, making up, perhaps, the
        largest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>.
        Further inland is the chic shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenue</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> living in the coastal enclaves come to shop
        (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica Airport‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Flying</ENAMEX> displays vintage
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">planes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergamot Station</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2525</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michigan Avenue</ENAMEX>), a converted
        trolley <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> a number of art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> including the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Monica Museum of Art</ENAMEX> (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">310-586-6488</ENAMEX>)
        Just south of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rose Avenue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main Street</ENAMEX> abruptly enters the
        bohemian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice Beach</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cottages</ENAMEX> are scattered along
        small, quaint residential side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean Front</ENAMEX> Walk is an
        explosion of exuberance, with an ongoing parade of outrageous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> exhibiting their only-in-southern-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">California individualism</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> worth a stroll just to check out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX> and muscle-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> pumping
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iron</ENAMEX> at the open-air beachside gym known as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Muscle Beach</ENAMEX>, but the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sidewalk artists</ENAMEX>, snack <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shacks</ENAMEX>, T-shirt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> also
        contribute to the local flavor. The show is at its best on weekend
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">afternoons</ENAMEX>, with everything from beach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> on unicycles to rock
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> on roller blades. Make time for this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> happening if
        you possibly can.
        Everything mellows out at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mother‚Äôs Beach</ENAMEX> to the south, a
        lagoon specifically preferred by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, and becomes ultra-civilized
        at the vast man-made harbor of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marina del Rey</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor cruises</ENAMEX> and
        fishing trips can be arranged. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fisherman‚Äôs Village on Fiji Way</ENAMEX> attracts
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> with its collection of gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and caf√©s. But if you just
        want to watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>, you should be able to find a shady spot along
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mindanao Way at Burton Chase Park.</ENAMEX>
        To the north, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCH</ENAMEX> meets the western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terminus</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sunset</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Boulevard</ENAMEX>. Follow this winding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> into the hills and you will enter
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">well-to-do</ENAMEX> residential enclave of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pacific Palisades</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">A few miles</NUMEX>
        farther is the turn-off for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Will Rogers State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Historic Park</ENAMEX>(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1501</TIMEX> Will
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park Rd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pacific Palisades</ENAMEX>), a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">186-acre</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">75-hectare</NUMEX>) ranch
        that belonged to the late cowboy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humorist</ENAMEX>. Tours of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch house</ENAMEX>
        reveal some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers‚</ENAMEX>Äô eccentricities, namely a porch swing in the
        living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and a raised ceiling that allowed him to practice rope
        tricks indoors. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX> was an enthusiastic horseman and an experienced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">polo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend</ENAMEX> games are still held on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">polo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> in the
        front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX>. A good system of hiking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> extends into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tel</ENAMEX>:
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">310-454-8212</ENAMEX>).
        A deeply centering experience comes free with a stroll
        through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Self-Realization Fellowship Lake Shrine</ENAMEX>,(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17190</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sunset Bvd</ENAMEX>.
        , a few blocks before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCH</ENAMEX>). Adjoining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> (founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swami P.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yogananda</ENAMEX>) is a beautiful gardenwith gazebos, lakes, and waterfalls
        (tel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">310-454-4414</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Malibu</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malibu</ENAMEX> is best known for its exclusive beachfront <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>. You‚Äôll get to see only the
        backsides of these expensive bungalows as you travel the ribbon of
        highway that lies between the mountains and the sea. Sadly, many homes
        were destroyed by the brush fires and mudslides of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1993‚Äì1994</NUMEX>, but there
        are several beach access points where you can still admire the rolling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surf</ENAMEX> and idyllic beach life that have done so much to make <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malibu</ENAMEX>
        famous.
        One such place is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malibu Pier</ENAMEX>, a popular spot for fishing.
        Constructed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1905</TIMEX>, rebuilt several times since, and getting ready for
        another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million-dollar</NUMEX> facelift, this was the main connection with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">south</ENAMEX> until the state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>.
        Another is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malibu Lagoon State Park</ENAMEX>, one of the few
        remaining wetlands in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boardwalks</ENAMEX> extend into the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marsh</ENAMEX>, where you can see shorebirds such as the great blue <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">heron</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> avocet. A popular surfing beach adjoins the lagoon.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the coastline‚Äôs most visited attractions in the past
        was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Paul Getty Museum</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17985</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Coast Highway</ENAMEX>), now called
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Getty Villa</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malibu</ENAMEX>. It first opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX> to house the
        billionaire‚Äôs personal collection. The museum‚Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> addition was a
        re-creation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Villa dei Papiri</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">villa</ENAMEX> destroyed by the
        terrible eruption of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Vesuvi</ENAMEX> us in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 79</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> was closed
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1997</TIMEX> for more renovation and to move part of the collection to
        the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Getty Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brentwood</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX>).
        Scheduled to reopen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002 or 2003</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malibu</ENAMEX> site will house only
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Getty</ENAMEX> holdings in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> antiquities, some of which date
        as far back as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3000</TIMEX> b.c.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOWNTOWN</ENAMEX>
        For the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, ‚ÄúDowntown‚Äù is
        not a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hub</ENAMEX> but a distant skyline visited a few times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> when
        attending the opera or going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Contemporary Art</ENAMEX>. But
        that‚Äôs not to say the region east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, defined by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">freeways</ENAMEX> and the river, doesn‚Äôt have its merits. A core of beautiful
        historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and colorful ethnic enclaves
        makes for excellent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daytime</TIMEX> exploration. Several stellar performing
        arts venues and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> of politics and finance also draw
        attention. But if it‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles‚</ENAMEX>Äôs infamous glitter and glitz you‚Äôve
        come to experience, you won‚Äôt find them here. What you will find is a
        lively workaday business world, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> overflowing with conventioneers,
        and an atmosphere that is a refreshing diversion from the celluloid
        images to the west. Come nighttime, however, the place can be all but a
        ghost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.
        By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>, downtown is best explored on foot and on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DASH</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX>, which run through the area during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just 25 cents</NUMEX> a
        ride. By nightfall, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commuters</ENAMEX> flee to the suburbs and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deserted‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsave</ENAMEX> for a few homeless begging for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">change‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit‚</ENAMEX>Äôs best to drive or take a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX>. As in any large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, simple
        precautions are recommended.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the best ways to appreciate the area is to take one
        of the excellent walking tours given on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservancy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pershing Square Landmark Tour</ENAMEX> is highly recommended:
        in addition to providing a wealth of historical information, it
        includes access to the stunning interiors of such edifices as the
        Guarantee Trust and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edison</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, with their marble pillars and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flooring</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugo Ballin</ENAMEX> murals, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Deco</ENAMEX> styling. A variety of
        special-interest tours are also offered. For information, call (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">213</ENAMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">623-2489</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekdays between 9am and 5pm</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bustling Commerce</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convention Bureau</ENAMEX>, on Figueroa
        Street between <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">7th Street and Wilshire Boulevard</ENAMEX>, offers extensive
        information on attractions throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">blocks</ENAMEX> north, at
        5th and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figueroa</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> cylindrical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonaventure Hotel</ENAMEX> form the city‚Äôs most futuristic-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX>.
        You can survey the area from the revolving restaurant and bar on the
        35th floor.
        To the east at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">630</NUMEX> West <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">5th Street</ENAMEX>, between <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Avenue</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flower Street</ENAMEX>, is the beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pyramid-</ENAMEX>topped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Library</ENAMEX>. A
        devastating fire caused by arson destroyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, but
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> reopened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> after a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$221 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reconstruction</ENAMEX>.
        Across from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">73</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Library Tower</ENAMEX>, (an
        office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>), the tallest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX>, designed by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I. M. Pei</ENAMEX>. Running alongside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">majestic Bunker Hill</ENAMEX>
        Steps lead to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Plaza</ENAMEX>, forming a symbolic link between the old
        downtown and the new.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biltmore Hotel</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">506</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Grand Ave.</ENAMEX> ), which opened in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923</TIMEX>, is the grande dame of all the downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>. The prestigious
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy Awards</ENAMEX> were originally launched here in a private ceremony in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal Room</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX>. It is said that the award acquired its name
        after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bette Davis</ENAMEX> glanced at a sketch of the statuette penciled on a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">napkin</ENAMEX> and remarked, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX> looks like my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Uncle Oscar</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù The majestic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rendezvous Court</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Olive Street</ENAMEX> was originally the hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>; from
        here, you can climb the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> baroque staircase leading up to the
        galleria, with its coffered ceiling. On the other side of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Olive Street</ENAMEX>,
        the landscaped <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pershing Square</ENAMEX> is the oldest public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>. Its history as a public commons dates back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1781</TIMEX>.
        Art <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deco</ENAMEX> is at its best in the nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Oviatt Building</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">617</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Olive Street</ENAMEX>). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX>, merchant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Oviatt</ENAMEX> was entranced with
        the new architectural style that he saw in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. He subsequently
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commissioned Ren√© Lalique</ENAMEX> to design all the decorative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> for his
        building, which was home to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">haberdashery</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">penthouse suite</ENAMEX>.
        From its terminal situated on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">3rd and Hill Streets</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angel‚Äôs</ENAMEX> Flight inclined <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">railway</ENAMEX> carried downtowners up and down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bunker</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX>. Dismantled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> due to redevelopment,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angel‚Äôs</ENAMEX> Flight has been reconstructed and plans to activate the
        original cable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. Its new terminus will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watercourt</ENAMEX>,
        a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11‚ÅÑ2 acre</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1‚ÅÑ2 hectare</NUMEX>) urban garden along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Olive Street</ENAMEX> that features
        outdoor stages for the performing arts and high-tech synchronized water
        fountains. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watercourt</ENAMEX> and the funicular railway make up part
        of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Plaza</ENAMEX> urban renewal project.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Civic Center</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Civic Center</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">area</ENAMEX> bordered by
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Temple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Main Street</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Grand Avenue</ENAMEX>)
        are the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> culture and politics. City <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N.</ENAMEX>
        Spring Street), built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>, was the tallest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in the city
        until height restrictions were lifted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>. Best known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
        Planet building of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Superman</ENAMEX> TV series, its observation deck is open
        weekdays from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 am</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4pm</NUMEX>.
        The historic theater district on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> has evolved into
        a bustling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> good for bridal gowns and
        electronic equipment. However, one monument to its past is the Million
        Dollar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">307</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Broadway</ENAMEX>) with its whimsical terra-cotta
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ornamentation</ENAMEX>. This famous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX> vaudeville and movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, newly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">renovated</ENAMEX>, now features live <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hispanic acts (‚Äúvariadades‚Äù</ENAMEX>), after
        briefly serving as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>.
        Built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1893</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bradbury Building</ENAMEX> (at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">304</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>) is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles‚</ENAMEX>Äôs oldest commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. It is also one
        of the grandest, with its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Victorian</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wrought-iron balconies</ENAMEX>, marble
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">staircases</ENAMEX>, and open-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage elevators</ENAMEX> surrounding a skylit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">atrium court</ENAMEX>.
        Tours are given on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> Conservancy
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">213-623-2489</ENAMEX>).
        Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Central Market</ENAMEX> (at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">317 South Broadway</ENAMEX>)
        has provided the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with a daily cornucopia of enticing fresh
        produce, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poultry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>, and exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foodstuffs</ENAMEX>. Today, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of
        stalls display a wonderful ethnic diversity: you can sample everything
        from fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tortillas</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">herbs</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs a great place for browsing
        and a quick snack or inexpensive lunch.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historic Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
        The city‚Äôs first settlement in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1781</TIMEX> was at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Pueblo de</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, now a state historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Main Street</ENAMEX> and Paseo
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de</ENAMEX> la <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Plaza</ENAMEX>. The heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Olvera Street</ENAMEX>, a festive
        marketplace brimming with pi√±atas (hanging decorations filled with toys
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX>), masks, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> handicrafts, and surrounded by numerous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and food <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">visitors‚Äô center</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">685</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
        Figueroa, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">213-689-8822</ENAMEX>) provides information on the historical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> of
        the district, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avila Adobe</ENAMEX> (the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Plaza Church</ENAMEX>, and the shady <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX> with its
        wrought-iron gazebo. Mariachi <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> dance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> can usually
        be seen here on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>.
        In a region that long ago eschewed train travel, railway
        romance still permeates <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union Station</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800 N. Alameda St.</ENAMEX>). This
        handsome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1939</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mission</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> has a massive waiting room
        with arched <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corridors</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX>-ft- (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16-m-</NUMEX>) ceiling. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> once
        served <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>; now, it is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>‚Äôs new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metro</ENAMEX>
        Rail <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system hub</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A.‚Äôs Asian Communities</ENAMEX>
        Although <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian Americans</ENAMEX> live throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX>, there are several special cultural and shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">enclaves</ENAMEX> that
        deserve visitors‚Äô special attention.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinatown</ENAMEX> is bounded by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> block of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Broadway</ENAMEX>
        and bordered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ord</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alameda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. Here
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX>, souvenir <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, dim sum <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parlors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> grocers fan
        out from the central pedestrian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gin Ling Way</ENAMEX>) with its ceremonial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gates</ENAMEX> and exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX> dragons.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Tokyo</ENAMEX>, is situated east
        of downtown on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1st</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>. A medieval fire
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tower</ENAMEX> marks the entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Plaza</ENAMEX> shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">335</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East 2nd Street</ENAMEX>). Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> highlights are a cultural
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American National Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">369 East</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Street</ENAMEX>).
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> neighborhood, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Koreatown</ENAMEX>, lies west of
        downtown along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Olympic Boulevard</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> and Western <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX>.
        All the signs here are in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX>, and there are a multitude of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX> and a large shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koreatown</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Plaza</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Marino</ENAMEX>). This area was badly damaged during the
        riots of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downtown Museums</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Contemporary Art</ENAMEX>, known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MOCA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> S.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Ave.</ENAMEX> ), is one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most exciting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, presenting
        major contemporary shows and a rotating permanent collection by such
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piet Mondrian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Rothko</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franz Kline</ENAMEX>. There‚Äôs a
        superb gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> on the premises. The celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arata Isozaki</ENAMEX> designed the attractive red sandstone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> with
        pyramid skylights. The museum‚Äôs annex, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geffen Contemporary</ENAMEX>, is a
        few blocks away in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Tokyo</ENAMEX> (at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">152</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Central Ave.</ENAMEX> ) and
        features zany installations, multi-media, and the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 years</TIMEX> of the
        museum‚Äôs permanent collection.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exposition Park</ENAMEX>, south of the central downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">area</ENAMEX> near
        several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> and attractions, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Memorial</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coliseum and Sports Arena</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural History Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">900 Exposition Boulevard</ENAMEX>) is
        popular for its <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur skeletons</ENAMEX> and other prehistoric fossils. Among
        the highlights of some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> are dioramas of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in
        their natural habitats, an impressive mounted megamouth <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shark</ENAMEX>, a
        collection of pre-Columbian artifacts, major exhibits on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
        history, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Birds</ENAMEX>,with an animated rainforest. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">excellent Discovery Center</ENAMEX> is a hands-on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> (see page
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ScienceCenter</ENAMEX> andIMAX <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">700 State Drive</ENAMEX>)
        presents technological exhibits from robotics and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber optics</ENAMEX> to a
        miniature <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">winery</ENAMEX>. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aerospace Complex</ENAMEX> there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">satellites</ENAMEX> and an impressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMAX Theater</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>). Rotating
        exhibitions on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX>- <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> experience in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
        are offered at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California African-American Museum</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
        Drive), which has become a showcase for black history and culture.
        THE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MOUNTAINS</ENAMEX> AND VALLEYS
        When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelenos</ENAMEX> refer to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">‚ÄúThe Valley</ENAMEX>,‚Äù they are talking
        about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Fernando Valley</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> north across the
        mountains from western and downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. Although it‚Äôs also
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to such major film and television studios‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇin <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burbank</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glendale‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇas Universal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Brothers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> is
        forever battling its reputation as a boring and actionless suburbia.
        Nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">San Gabriel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Clarita Valleys</ENAMEX>, also separated from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> basin by ranges of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX>, suffer from the same
        monotonous landscape of suburban sprawl.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason to head north is to do as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harley Davidson</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> do: cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mulholland Drive</ENAMEX>, a scenic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> that
        twists and turns through the mountains from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Highway 101</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX>. It is especially beautiful at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, when the lights of the
        city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shimmer</ENAMEX> below.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffith Park</ENAMEX>
        An equally enticing reason to head to the hills is to
        visit the country‚Äôs largest urban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffith Park</ENAMEX>, which separates
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burbank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Glendale</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and covers <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 4,000 acres</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,620</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hectares</ENAMEX>). There are several entrances to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>; you can pick up a
        free map at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">visitors‚Äô center</ENAMEX> near the eastern entrance, off the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden State Freeway</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Highway 5</ENAMEX>).
        Perhaps the best view of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> can be seen on clear
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffith Observatory</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Hollywood</ENAMEX>, a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">location</ENAMEX> also featured in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dean</ENAMEX> classic Rebel Without a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cause</ENAMEX>.
        Exhibits include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of Science</ENAMEX>, with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foucault Pendulum</ENAMEX> and a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cosmic Ray Cloud Chamber</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> can look at the heavens
        through a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12-inch</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30-cm</NUMEX>) telescope. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planetarium Theater</ENAMEX> presents
        dramatic astronomical shows several times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Evening</TIMEX> shows are
        followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laserium</ENAMEX> light concerts.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Zoo</ENAMEX>, on the northeastern side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>,
        harbors <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 400</NUMEX> different species of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> and reptiles,
        grouped according to their continental <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> is known for its
        extensive breeding program for endangered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>.
        Environmentally-friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> are justifiably proud of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">zoo</ENAMEX>.
        Adjacent is the (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene) Autry Museum</ENAMEX> of Western
        Heritagefounded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of the balladeer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX>, who rode the
        range in films from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>. His tribute to the ‚Äúwild
        West‚Äù features an impressive collection of historical artifacts,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">furniture</ENAMEX> and art as well as examples of how the West was romanticized
        in the arts, literature, film, and advertising.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Fernando Valley</ENAMEX>
        In addition to seeing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California‚</ENAMEX>Äôs original
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">missions</ENAMEX>, you‚Äôll want to visit this valley to see the movie
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Studios</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> (off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hollywood/101 Freeway</ENAMEX>
        at either the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Universal Center Drive</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lankershim Boulevard exits</ENAMEX>)
        is the area‚Äôs biggest draw; it combines a real working <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">behind-the-scenes tours</ENAMEX> with amusement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> attractions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> can
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> a tram that travels through famous film sets. Along the way you
        are threatened by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">King Kong</ENAMEX> and attacked by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer shark</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jaws</ENAMEX>;
        if that‚Äôs not enough, you then survive a collapsing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>, a flash
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flood</ENAMEX>, and a bone-shaking simulated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.3</NUMEX> earthquake. You are then free
        to explore the magic of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> in attractions such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jurassic Park</ENAMEX>:
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ride</ENAMEX>, a water ride with a big bite; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Backdraft</ENAMEX>, a firestorm of
        special effects; and the ever-popular Back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future</ENAMEX>
        motion-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">simulator</ENAMEX> ride that sends you rocketing through avalanches,
        molten volcanoes, and the jaws of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX>. Although the linesfor
        major attractions are often long, musical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> shows are always at
        hand to entertain you.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal City‚Äôs CityWalk</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Universal Center Drive</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal City</ENAMEX>) gets its fair share of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> venture
        to this fantasy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>, where whimsical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and fun, informal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants vie</ENAMEX> for tourist dollars, though some undesirable characters
        often loiter around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>.
        Nothing is staged just for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> at the nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brothers Studios</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Boulevard</ENAMEX>). Here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the two-hour</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIP</ENAMEX> tour
        changes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekday</TIMEX>, depending on shooting schedules, as small groups
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years of age</TIMEX> walk through the back lot past
        familiar TV and movie sets and tour production <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. If
        scheduling allows, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> are permitted to watch rehearsals and the
        filming of TV shows.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California‚</ENAMEX>Äôs finest missions lies in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fernando Valley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission San</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando Rey de Espa√±a</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15151</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Fernando</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission Boulevard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mission Hills</ENAMEX>), built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1797</TIMEX>, was named for
