
  
  
    
      
        Where To Go
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast</ENAMEX>
        A land of rolling hills and deciduous <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, tiny hamlets
        and green meadows, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast</ENAMEX> is the most popular area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX>
        District, if not the most dramatic visually. (You‚Äôll have to go farther
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">north</ENAMEX> to reach the rugged fell landscapes. ) The reputation of this
        area was guaranteed when the Victorian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">railway</ENAMEX> was built. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Workers</ENAMEX> from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> came to enjoy the fresh air, and rich
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">industrialists</ENAMEX> built large lakeside houses surrounded by pleasant
        landscaped gardens. Many of these manors have now been converted into
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotels</ENAMEX> known for comfortable accommodations and stunning views.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX> Windermere
        The largest of the lakes at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">17 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 miles</NUMEX>) north to south,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Windermere</ENAMEX> has always been the most accessible, and therefore, not
        surprisingly, it is now the most developed. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> you will
        have to share the shoreline with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many thousands</NUMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.
        Ferry services plying the lake provide one of the best ways to view
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coastline</ENAMEX> and the thickly wooded hills above. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boats</ENAMEX> are available for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rent</ENAMEX>, and water-skiing and powerboat racing are very popular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pastimes</ENAMEX>.
        Among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> islands of interest on the lake is Belle
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isle</ENAMEX>, still privately owned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curwen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fletcher Christian</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mutiny</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bounty</ENAMEX> fame, who was born near
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cockermouth</ENAMEX>. It is said that after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bounty</ENAMEX> settled on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pitcairn Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fletcher</ENAMEX> somehow found his way back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, living
        out his life on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Belle Isle</ENAMEX>, protected by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Several local
        residents are said to have caught a glimpse of him but there is no firm
        evidence to support this claim.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowness</ENAMEX> and Windermere
        Originally separate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">settlements</ENAMEX>, these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> have now
        merged to the point that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> can‚Äôt tell where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> starts and the
        other finishes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genteel Windermere</ENAMEX> is more modern, having grown up
        around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">railway station</ENAMEX> after the line was opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1847</TIMEX>. If you
        travel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX>, this is where you will arrive. Just
        around the corner from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Information Centre</ENAMEX>,
        which will supply all the information you need about touring,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accommodations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> has a number of art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>
        and many fine period <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, and although it has few attractions it is
        a good base for trips farther afield in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowness</ENAMEX> began as small fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> on the lakeside, but
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> still modest in size, but it becomes full to
        the brim on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer weekends</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families head</ENAMEX> here for fresh air. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> has many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> where you can buy souvenirs
        or outdoor clothing.
        Everyone seems to congregate around the lake‚Äôs edge, where
        feeding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX> and swans is a popular pastime. This is where the
        cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> dock. The ticket <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX> are right next to the wooden
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">berths</ENAMEX>. You can take a lake tour or a ferry trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambleside</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">north</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeside</ENAMEX> in the south.
        In the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowness</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Laundry Visitor Centre</ENAMEX>;
        the theater housed here offers a program of performances throughout the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. Next door to the theater is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The World</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatrix Potter</ENAMEX>, an
        her work. The presentation begins with a short video about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX>
        stories and how they relate to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> landscape. A
        delightful series of dioramas then introduce <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Rabbit</ENAMEX>, Mrs.
        Tiggi-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winkle</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squirrel Nutkin</ENAMEX>, among others, set in scenes taken
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Potter‚Äôs</ENAMEX> books. Another longer video relates to the life of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX>
        and her transformation from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and illustrator (she did the
        original drawings for the books) to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>, solicitor‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and early
        eco-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windermere Steamboat Museum</ENAMEX> looks back
        to the golden age of lake transport. A number of steamboats dating from
        the Victorian age until the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1920‚</NUMEX>Äôs are on display, all lovingly
        restored. Pride of place goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SL Dolly</ENAMEX>, the oldest mechanically
        powered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> in the world (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">c. ‚ÄÇ 1850</ENAMEX>), which was restored after
        spending over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 years</TIMEX> at the bottom of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Windermere</ENAMEX>. Weather
        permitting, you can take a ride on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the steamers.
        At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brockhole</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 2 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 miles</NUMEX>) northwest of Windermere
        along the lake shore, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District National Park Visitor</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre</ENAMEX>, a very good place to gather information and plan your strategy
        for exploring. An audio-visual show gives information not only about
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Park</ENAMEX> but also about the work the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> does to protect the
        landscape. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> that now houses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visitor Centre</ENAMEX> was once a
        private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>. Built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>, it reflects the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Crafts</ENAMEX> style
        that was fashionable at the time. Surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre</ENAMEX> are beautiful
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gardens</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> that lead through woodland and along the lake
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shore</ENAMEX>. There are places to relax or enjoy a picnic, and adventure
        playgrounds for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Special events such as pet shows, dog
        trials, and historical theme days are held throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>.
        Ambleside
        Just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few kilometers</NUMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brockhole</ENAMEX>, at the northern
        tip of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Windermere</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambleside</ENAMEX> is one of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> of the
        region. At the height of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> season you‚Äôll share the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> with
        many <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, all jostling to stay on the narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalks</ENAMEX>.
        In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Victorian era</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> expanded northward from its original
        site (a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> settlement at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waterhead</ENAMEX>); the commercial center now lies
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1‚ÅÑ2 mile</NUMEX>) from the lake.
        Waterhead, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ambleside‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX>, has a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> that cater
        to the ferries, cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX> here. There‚Äôs
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Information Centre</ENAMEX> in the main car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> (open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> only).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find the remains of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman fort Galava</ENAMEX> a little way to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">north</ENAMEX>, at the confluence ofthe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brathay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothay</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the rivers
        that feed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Windermere</ENAMEX>. Loughrigg, a low fell that gives spectacular
        views of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windermere</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grasmere</ENAMEX>, is a short climb to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">northwest</ENAMEX>.
        Bridge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ambleside</ENAMEX> is one of the most popular sites
        and perhaps one of the most photographed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">the Lake</ENAMEX>
        District. Dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX>, it was a summerhouse for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambleside Hall</ENAMEX>, a large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> built <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century earlier</TIMEX>, which, sadly,
        no longer exists. The tiny <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">slate house</ENAMEX>, which spans the
        bubbling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stock Ghyll</ENAMEX>, now serves as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Trust</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Centre</ENAMEX> and pick-up point for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Trust</ENAMEX> tour <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>.
        Across the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> are several small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> that
        illustrate how the old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> must have looked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX>. Soak
        in the atmosphere as you wander down narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> and cobbled lanes
        among white-washed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cottages</ENAMEX>.
        Stock <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghyll Force</ENAMEX> was one of the most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>
        attractions during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Victorian times</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">21-m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>-ft) waterfall was
        easily accessible from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, even by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> wearing the large heavy
        skirts of the time. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still take the same route to the force
        (sign-posted behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barclays Bank</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town center</ENAMEX>) and to Stock
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghyll Water Mill</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armitt Library</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum Centre</ENAMEX>, just a little
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bridge House</ENAMEX>, offers an interesting view on the life of the
        Lakes through the letters and books of local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louisa Armitt</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1909</TIMEX>, it provided a resource for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> in the area;
        she donated her own collection of books, which encouraged others to
        follow suit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> absorbed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambleside Book Club</ENAMEX> (Wordsworth
        had been its most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruskin Library</ENAMEX>, which included
        many of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruskin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs private letters. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> the collection has
        grown to incorporate many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> and works of art, including a number
        of original scientific watercolors by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatrix Potter</ENAMEX>, which show yet
        another facet of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>. The collection is accessible via a hi-tech
        touch-screen directory.
        Troutbeck
        Sitting on the slopes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Troutbeck Valley</ENAMEX> high above
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowness</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambleside, Troutbeck</ENAMEX> is a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> of traditional farms
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barns</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> is historically significant, and there are many
        fascinating architectural details to be found here. The most famous
        building in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Town End Yeoman‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farmhouse</ENAMEX>. A perfect example of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">statesman farmer‚Äôs house</ENAMEX>, this
        structure had been in the hands of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> from the time it was
        built until it was taken over by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Trust</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>. There are
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> downstairs‚<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe ‚Äúfirehouse</ENAMEX>,‚Äù a utility area for washing
        and brewing, and the ‚Äúdownhouse,‚Äù a living area with fireplace. The
        master <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> is just off the downhouse; other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
        household slept in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">loft</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Town End</ENAMEX> is full of wonderful artifacts
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 17th-century daily</TIMEX> life, such as cooking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">utensils‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbowls</ENAMEX>, pans,
        crockery, and hooks to hang hare and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pheasants‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇrag rugs</ENAMEX> made by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of the household, and laundry implements such as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">‚Äúdolly‚Äù</ENAMEX> used
        for stirring the clothes in the washing tub.
        Grasmere
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Grasmere</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11‚ÅÑ2 km/1 mile</NUMEX> long) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grasmere</ENAMEX> village
        lie below a circle of rounded hills. Access to the lakeside is
        restricted, but the view from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Loughrigg Terrace</ENAMEX> is one of the best in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> and an easy walk from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rydal Water</ENAMEX>, the
        smallest of the lakes in the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX>, sits beside it;
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of rushes line its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. Grasmere <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> is one of the
        prettiest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX>, but also one of the busiest. A
        settlement of stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cottages</ENAMEX> founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Norse</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>, it became home
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Wordsworth</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1799</TIMEX>. The surrounding
        landscape, with dry¬≠stone walls, farmhouses, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rothay</ENAMEX> river
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">valley</ENAMEX>, became a source of inspiration for their artistic endeavors.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dove Cottage</ENAMEX> was their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> home. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wordsworth</ENAMEX> loved the place and wrote
        some of his most memorable poetry while living here. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> has
        changed little since then; it has been faithfully preserved along with
        the garden the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> faithfully tended. Much of the furniture inside
        belonged to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1802</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William married Mary Hutchinson</ENAMEX>; the cottage became
        their family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. Eventually there wasn‚Äôt enough space to house their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and their many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, so in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1808</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> moved to a
        larger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> on the other side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wordsworth Trust</ENAMEX> now
        manages the property and offers a guided tour of the cottage that
        provides insights into the life of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Behind the cottage, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wordsworth Museum</ENAMEX> displays many of
        Wordsworth‚Äôs original manuscripts and other personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX>.
        Headphones allow you to listen to some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William‚Äôs</ENAMEX> works while you
        view images of the landscapes that inspired him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> and many
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> are buried in the graveyard of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parish Church</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oswald</ENAMEX>, in the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grasmere</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> itself is worthy of
        investigation. The structure dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 13th century</TIMEX>, but a rather
        dull stucco finish was added in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>. A rush-bearing
        ceremony (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX>) is held here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each August</TIMEX>. At the corner of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">churchyard</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Nelson‚Äôs Gingerbread Shop</ENAMEX>, which is still making
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gingerbread</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goodies</ENAMEX> just as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara</ENAMEX> herself once did for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> who came to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wordsworth‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. The tiny shop
        was once the village schoolroom, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> would sit with chalk
        and slate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wordsworth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more move, to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rydal Mount</ENAMEX> at
        the eastern tip of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rydal Water</ENAMEX>, and it was here that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX> lived for
        the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37 years</TIMEX> of his life. It is a much grander <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dove</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cottage</ENAMEX>, yet it remains true to the poet‚Äôs philosophy and world
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">view‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit‚Äôs</ENAMEX> neither too imposing nor too lavish. Still owned by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>, it is a family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> rather than a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>,
        though it has been open to the public since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>. There are many
        personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> and family portraits in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, along with original
        Wordsworth manuscripts. The grounds are also very much as Wordsworth
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX> landscaped them, with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four acres</NUMEX> of sculptured lawn and a
        natural environment in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> thrive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> has
        beautiful views of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Windermere</ENAMEX>, which must have brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>
        great pleasure in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX>.
        The whole area around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grasmere</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rydal Water</ENAMEX> is full of
        gentle walks in beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">deciduous woodland</ENAMEX>. For a wonderful walk that
        fills a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">whole day</TIMEX>, try linking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grasmere</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dove Cottage</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rydal Mount</ENAMEX>. The route is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 miles</NUMEX>) long and includes some
        beautiful scenery. You could finish the trip with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dove</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cottage Teashop</ENAMEX>.
        Hawkshead
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> in miniature that is a delight to the eye,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawkshead</ENAMEX> is comprised of whitewashed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> huddled together around
        a tiny central <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>. The maze of narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> that link the houses
        can be confusing, as there are few street signs to guide you, but the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Information Centre</ENAMEX> provides an invaluable guide. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> in the
        main car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and walk the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">few meters</NUMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>. There are many
        gems to be discovered: tiny leaded windows, gargoyles in the eaves, and
        flower-filled boxes on every window ledge.
        The area was part of a huge tract of land owned by Furness
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey</ENAMEX>, and the village produced cloth from their flocks, which went to
        market at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kendal</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Courthouse</ENAMEX>, was
        built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 15th century</TIMEX>. Just outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawkshead</ENAMEX>, it is all that
        remains of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">manor house</ENAMEX> built by the monks of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furness</ENAMEX>, most of
        which was destroyed during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reformation</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Courthouse</ENAMEX> now houses
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Rural Life</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1778 to 1787</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wordsworth</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pupil</ENAMEX> at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawkshead Grammar School</ENAMEX>, situated across from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Centre</ENAMEX>. The fledgling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> carved his name in one of the
        plain wooden desks, which proves that even a literary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> can once
        have been a naughty schoolboy. During <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX> he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>
        lodged with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Tyson</ENAMEX> in a little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beatrix Potter Gallery</ENAMEX> is housed in a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main Street</ENAMEX> that was once the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Heelis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Potter‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solicitor husband</ENAMEX>. Exhibiting a range of art works by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> manages to convey a sense of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> life of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beatrix</ENAMEX> the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> and illustrator and of her other life as Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heelis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other notable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawkshead</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quaker</ENAMEX>
        Meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1688</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Minstrel‚Äôs Gallery Caf√©</ENAMEX> on
        Flag Street, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that now provides refreshment for
        today‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.
        In the hills northeast of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawkshead</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarn Hows</ENAMEX>. Created
        by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> (the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of the land) as a garden
        attraction, it has become one of the most popular sites in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">the Lake</ENAMEX>
        District. The family dammed the narrow valley and planted many of the
        lakeside <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatrix Potter</ENAMEX> bought the tarn in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX> and bequeathed
        it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Trust</ENAMEX>. Not just beautiful, it is a good place for
        those who enjoy a gentle stroll, popular with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and visitors
        with disabilities. The car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> is barely <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">500 m</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1‚ÅÑ2 mile</NUMEX>) from the
        tarn, and the footpaths around the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> are wide, with gentle
        slopes.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> Top
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatrix Potter‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm house</ENAMEX> and retreat is on the western
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shore</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Windermere</ENAMEX> at the village of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Near Sawrey</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was
        bought with the royalties she earned from her first book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tales of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Rabbit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX> received inspiration for many more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> and surrounding farmland. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The 17th-century</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cottage</ENAMEX> was her home from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1905</TIMEX>; this was the place where she enjoyed
        the life of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady farmer</ENAMEX>, tending her <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> and breeding Herdwick
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sheep</ENAMEX>, a breed which was at that time waning in popularity but of which
        she was very fond. It is said that one of the conditions of her bequest
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Trust</ENAMEX> was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Herdwick sheep</ENAMEX> must always be bred on
        her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tower Bank Arms</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX> that was featured in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tale of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gemima Puddleduck</ENAMEX>, is very close to the cottage and a good place to
        stop for refreshment. Nearby is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Esthwaite Water</ENAMEX>, a quiet lake that has
        a reputation for go od <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> fishing.
        Grizedale
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizedale</ENAMEX> is a forested area of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">nearly 121‚ÅÑ2 sq km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 sq</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX>) between <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lakes Windermere</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston</ENAMEX>. This ancient woodland of
        mixed deciduous and coniferous <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> provided a source of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> for the
        furnaces of the charcoal industry and the bobbin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX>. Now under the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control of the Forestry Commission</ENAMEX>, the forest has <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">many kilometers</NUMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">footpaths</ENAMEX> and cycle-ways to enjoy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grizedale Visitor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wildlife</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre</ENAMEX> has maps and information, particularly about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> sculptures
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> can find out in the woodland. These were all fashioned out of
        natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> by local and international sculptors. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gallery</ENAMEX> in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forest</ENAMEX>, once the old sawmill, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> many other exhibits, and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forest</ENAMEX> holds concerts and performances on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> in
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South of Grizedale</ENAMEX> are a number of interesting attractions
        that you can reach by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or by lake ferry. Once at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeside</ENAMEX> on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern</ENAMEX> shore of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Windermere</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> belonging to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeside</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haverthwaite Railway</ENAMEX> can take you on a pleasant <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5-km</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">31‚ÅÑ2-mile</NUMEX>) trip
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeside</ENAMEX> and the village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haverthwaite</ENAMEX>. The thundering engine
        will transport you back to the age of steam. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Aquarium of the</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lakes</ENAMEX>, which is just beside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeside Railway Station</ENAMEX>, you can
        familiarize yourself with the varieties of aquatic life that can be
        found around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Park</ENAMEX> and beyond. Freshwater <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish species</ENAMEX> swim
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>; there‚Äôs also a seashore exhibit with a wave machine. More
        exotic exhibits include playful otters and a large <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">sea-</ENAMEX>water tank
        housing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> and sting rays. It‚Äôs an exciting and well-planned
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aquarium</ENAMEX>, interesting whatever the weather but certainly a good place
        to spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a rainy afternoon</TIMEX>. (You can buy a combination ticket for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">railway</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">aquarium</ENAMEX>. )
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Over 60</NUMEX> bobbin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX> once dotted the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Windermere</ENAMEX> area. At
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newby Mill</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lakeside Stott Park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bobbin Mill</ENAMEX> was still operating
        commercially <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as recently as 1974</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> once worked to produce
        turned goods for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX>, a market that eventually dried up when
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> industry went into decline. The steam engine that
        traditionally powered the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> was recommissioned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and is
        running <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days a week</TIMEX>. Guided tours through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX>, passing the
        leather belts that turn the shafts and over the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood shavings</ENAMEX> that
        scatter the floor, give an account of life at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> during Victorian
        times.
        Cartmel
        Situated in the middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cartmel</ENAMEX> peninsula south of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Windermere</ENAMEX>, the village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cartmel</ENAMEX> has been at the heart of some
        important events in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> history. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1188</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Marshall</ENAMEX> gave land
        to build a priory at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cartmel</ENAMEX>, and during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Middle Ages</TIMEX> it was a large
        and very wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. In his original covenant, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX> stipulated
        that money would be available for the priory only if a part of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> were opened to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the surrounding countryside for
        worship. Thus, in effect, the priory‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> became a parish church
        even though it was tended by a closed religious order. This clause
        became important at the time of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúdissolution,‚Äù</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry VIII</ENAMEX>
        destroyed other monasteries and priories. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cartmel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> was saved only
        because it also served as a parish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. Wander
        around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13th‚Äì15th century</TIMEX>) to find some interesting
        artifacts of local history. Look for the plaque dedicated to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX>, who, it says, died on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 February 1762</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">There‚Äôs</ENAMEX> also the
        so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vinegar Bible</ENAMEX>, dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1716</TIMEX>. This volume shows a rare
        printer‚Äôs error: in the story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gospel of John</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>
        changing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, the word ‚Äúvineyard‚Äù was misprinted as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äúvinegar.</ENAMEX> ‚Äù There is very little left of the actual priory‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇafter it
        had been destroyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> was used to build the village houses‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbut
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gate House</ENAMEX> remains intact. It has been used over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> as a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courthouse</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, and a village <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, and now houses a small
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cartmel</ENAMEX> is a picturesque village, with winding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and
        fine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. As you wander you may be surprised to find a horse-racing
        track, and you may be even more surprised to find no one is here: the
        track stays silent except for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> race meetings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late May</TIMEX> and
        late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, on the long <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank Holiday</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>). On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> the
        whole neighborhood turns out and the tiny grandstand is full of people
        cheering.
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">A few kilometers</NUMEX> to the southwest you‚Äôll find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holker Hall</ENAMEX>,
        a historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Cavendish</ENAMEX>. It has beautiful
        landscaped <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gardens‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit‚Äôs</ENAMEX> said that the warm air of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf Stream</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">aids</ENAMEX> in the production of the many exotic blooms. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> offered
        their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> as a refuge to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Mary</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> after the abdication
        of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward VIII</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>. She came here to escape the public eye.
        (All this was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> before the paparazzi, of course. ) The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeland Motor Museum</ENAMEX> on the grounds has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">around 100</NUMEX> exhibits of various
        forms of vintage transport. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is open to the
        public, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">estate</ENAMEX> also supports a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50-hectare</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">125-acre</NUMEX>) deer
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">park</ENAMEX>.
        Kendal
        The gateway to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX> for those traveling from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">south</ENAMEX>, this small sturdy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> grew rich from trade in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> and cloth
        that came from the central lakes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kendal Green</ENAMEX> cloth was famed
        throughout the land from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Middle Ages</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">onward‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit</ENAMEX> was said to have
        been worn by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX>. Kendal was the first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in the area to
        receive a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Market Charter</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1189</TIMEX>, which ensured its commercial
        prosperity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is still bustling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The oldest sections are
        constrained within a one-way traffic system that gets clogged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>
        but there are many surprises to be found if you take the time to wander
        the narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. Look out for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chocolate Shop</ENAMEX>, which first opened
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1657</TIMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> sells sumptuous and brightly wrapped
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">treats</ENAMEX>, and the caf√© on the upper floor serves unusual chocolate dishes
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>.
        The remains of historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Kendal Castle</ENAMEX> overlook the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parr</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, famous for having
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">provided Henry VIII</ENAMEX> with his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> and last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine</ENAMEX>. She
        outlived him and returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> after his death. The Parish
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of Kendal</ENAMEX>, built on land bequeathed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
        times, has the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> widest nave in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. Next to it is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbot Hall</ENAMEX>,
        a handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Georgian Mansion</ENAMEX> that now houses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbott Hall Art Gallery</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Lakeland Life</ENAMEX> complex. The main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1759</TIMEX>,
        holds the largest collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Romney</ENAMEX> paintings in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romney</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1734‚Äì1802</ENAMEX>) was considered to be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of portraiture
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX>, alongside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Gainsborough</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Reynolds</ENAMEX>.
        Because of the gallery‚Äôs high profile it attracts many important
        traveling exhibitions; check with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Information Centre</ENAMEX> about
        the current program. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>, situated in the renovated stable block
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, has many dioramas of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeland</ENAMEX> life and industry from the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last 200 years</TIMEX>. It highlights the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craftsmen</ENAMEX> who helped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kendal</ENAMEX> and
        the other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> to thrive, and provides a comprehensive overview
        of how the economy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX> has evolved and how the landscape has
        been changed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kendal Museum of Archaeology</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Natural History</ENAMEX>, near
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Railway Station</ENAMEX>, displays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neolithic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> finds from sites
        throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX> area, geological specimens, and a curious
        collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stuffed animals</ENAMEX> from the region and throughout the world.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Wainwright</ENAMEX>, prominent fell walker and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curator</ENAMEX> here
        for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>. His guides with their maps and plans provide the
        classic companion to the high ground of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX> and his larger books
        make beautiful souvenirs. He died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>; his old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> has been
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recreated</ENAMEX> in his memory.
        Brewery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts Centre</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of community art in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kendal</ENAMEX>,
        offers classes, exhibitions, and performances, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>. The continually changing program provides something
        for everyone, whether you want to join in or simply watch a master
        craftsman at work. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Centre</ENAMEX> sits just back from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Highgate</ENAMEX>, on the same
        street with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Information Centre</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>
        The southwestern corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> has some of
        the moodiest landscapes in all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Home</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of sheep
        and a few scattered farming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, the area is characterized by the
        stark beauty of bare peaks, rugged fells, and the most remote lakes,
        combined with challenging, narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>. You‚Äôre sure to find a little
        remote spot all to yourself.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston</ENAMEX>
        Historically a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX> mining and smelting,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston</ENAMEX> was a true working <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and this heritage sets it apart from
        the other major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX>. Less sophisticated than Ambleside
        and less commercial than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowness</ENAMEX>, it has a simple charm that many
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> find more appealing. The remains of mining and quarrying sites
        on the face of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Old Man</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston</ENAMEX>, the mountain above the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>,
        are a reminder of its history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ruskin</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> sits on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eastern</ENAMEX> shore of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston Water</ENAMEX>, chose to be buried here, in the
        graveyard of the parish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, rather than in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster Abbey</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in turn has honored him with a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston Water</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston Water</ENAMEX> is long and narrow, the straightest of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX> District lakes. It was this feature that attracted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speedboat racer</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Campbell</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">He‚Äôd</ENAMEX> had a series of victories in various types of
        powered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>, including a victory on land at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Daytona Beach</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, before coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> to attempt to break the
        world record in speed boating. His efforts at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston</ENAMEX> ended in
        tragedy, however, as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> left the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> at high speed and broke
        into several pieces on shore. Campbell‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> was never recovered.
        Happier experiences were recorded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Ransom</ENAMEX> in his
        book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Swallows and Amazons</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX>). The lake and its islands were his
        inspiration for the story about the adventures of a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
        who are left to their own devices <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one summer</TIMEX> in an age when innocence
        and security were taken for granted.
        A pleasant way to enjoy the lake is to take a trip on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Victorian steamer Gondola</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Trust</ENAMEX> runs the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>, which
        resembles the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venetian</ENAMEX> rowboats, and the plush interior takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> back
        to the genteel times when tourism was just in its infancy, when this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">steamer</ENAMEX> ride would have been just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European ‚ÄúGrand Tour</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        The whole journey on this steamer takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> port of call for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gondola</ENAMEX> and the other local boat
        service, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coniston Launch</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brantwood</ENAMEX> on the eastern shoreline. This
        was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruskin</ENAMEX>, one of the preeminent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of his time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 250</NUMEX> books
        and a prolific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> and art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX>, he is perhaps best remembered
        as a social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX>; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX> many prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX>, including
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahatma Gandhi</ENAMEX>, have been inspired by his writings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruskin</ENAMEX> lived at
        Brantwood from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1872</TIMEX> until his death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>, and in that time the house
        became a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of artistic and literary energy, much as
        Wordsworth‚Äôs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grasmere</ENAMEX> had just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years before</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruskin</ENAMEX> funded
        educational programs on the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in society and research into
        environmental pollution long before these issues became fashionable.
        Sadly, he became mentally unstable in his later life and died a broken
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, which contains <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruskin‚Äôs</ENAMEX> study and examples of
        his drawings and paintings, has magnificent views of the lake and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town of Coniston</ENAMEX>. The gardens, laid out by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruskin</ENAMEX> himself, cover nearly
        one <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">square kilometer</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">250 acres</NUMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each year</TIMEX> numerous exhibitions and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">open-air</ENAMEX> performances are held on the estate, and a commercial gallery
        on the grounds has an excellent selection of contemporary arts and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crafts</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Langdale</ENAMEX> Fells
        If you have limited time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> and want to
        experience the high fells, do a little beginners-level hiking, or
        simply drive through some breathtaking countryside, then this is the
        place to visit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Langdale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Langdale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> can be
        said to be the true heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX>, lying as they do in the
        very centre of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Park</ENAMEX>. Interestingly enough, although
        possibly the best loved landscape in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> for walkers and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">artists‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇWordsworth</ENAMEX> described it as ‚Äúunity, austere but
        reconciled,<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthere</ENAMEX> is not a lake in sight. Their beauty and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accessibility</ENAMEX> (being only a short drive from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambleside</ENAMEX>) make them a
        must for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.
        The initial approach route, along the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">A593</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ambleside</ENAMEX>,
        is characterized by rocky knolls rising from the valley bottoms. The
        River <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brathay</ENAMEX> runs alongside the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> from the
        fells that eventually flows into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Windermere</ENAMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Skelwith Bridge</ENAMEX>,
        turn right on to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the B5343</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> leaves the valley floor and takes
        you past the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elterwater</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel Stile</ENAMEX> before
        offering the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> real views of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Langdale Fells</ENAMEX>. The beautiful
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">valleys</ENAMEX> and magnificent volcanic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peaks‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwith</ENAMEX> such whimsical names as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Stickle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crinkle Crags‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇproduce some of the finest vistas
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX>. No matter what the weather is like, the landscape is
        dramatic and breathtaking. If there is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> place where you get out
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and do a little walking, this has to be it. Make a stop at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blea Tarn</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only about a ten-minute</TIMEX> walk from the car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>; this
        beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, surrounded by the high fells, offers one of
        the most beautiful views in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Park</ENAMEX>. On a quiet day you‚Äôll
        feel as if you have the world to yourself.
        From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blea Tarn</ENAMEX> the road drops sharply down to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>junction,
        with signs right to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wrynose Pass</ENAMEX>. Take a left, towards the tiny village
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Langdale</ENAMEX>. You will need to take care here, as there may be
        walkers on the road, especially at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch time</TIMEX> when everyone gathers in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúpint‚Äù</ENAMEX> and a sandwich. Finally, once through the
        village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colwith</ENAMEX>, you will reach the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the A593</TIMEX>, and a right
        turn will lead you back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambleside</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wrynose Pass and Hardknott Pass</ENAMEX>
        West from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Little Langdale</ENAMEX> toward the coast of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea</ENAMEX>, there is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only a single route‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</NUMEX>ÄÇand it is one that tests the nerve
        of even the most experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> climbs up through the
        tree line and into bracken fell (plateaus with thickets of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">shrubs</ENAMEX>) and
        sheep <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> until you reach the most difficult stretch of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake District</ENAMEX>, over the passes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wrynose</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hardknott</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wrynose Pass</ENAMEX> comes first: a single-track road with
        gradients of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX> will have you dodging <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">motorists</ENAMEX> around
        blind bends. As the road climbs, though, it offers spectacular views
        back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Langdale</ENAMEX> in the east; get out at the small car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> at
        the top of the pass and take photographs. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shires Stone</ENAMEX> at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">roadside</ENAMEX> marks the meeting place of the historic shires of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lancashire</ENAMEX>,
        Cumberland, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westmoreland</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> then drops down to Wrynose
        Bottom, a plain bereft of human life. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> shares the valley bottom
        with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Duddon River</ENAMEX>, flowing west to the sea. The fell has an eerie
        beauty about it; clouds frame the peaks here even on sunny <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hardknott Pass</ENAMEX>, with gradients of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of all
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeland</ENAMEX> passes; the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> is narrow and steep and twists like a
        switch-back ride. At the height of the season it can be choked with
        traffic and there are few passing places. It‚Äôs a challenge, but many
        say that you haven‚Äôt seen the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX> unless you‚Äôve traveled this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>.
        Try it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the day</TIMEX> when there‚Äôs much less traffic, or, if you
        really don‚Äôt want to test your own driving skills, you can arrange for
        an organized tour with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>; contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cumbria Tourist Board</ENAMEX> for
        more details (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hardknott Castle Roman Fort</ENAMEX>, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mediobogdum</ENAMEX> by its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">builders</ENAMEX>, sits on a shelf near the summit of the pass. The thick walls
        still clearly outline the fort‚Äôs boundaries. Take a walk around the
        perimeter for breathtaking views of the valley below. Even on the
        warmest day a stiff, cold breeze blows steadily up the fell. Just
        imagine the kind of homesick letters a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX>-born legionnaire would
        have written back home.
        Eskdale
        Once you make it over the high point of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hardknott Pass</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Eskdale</ENAMEX> opens up in front of you. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">It‚Äôs</ENAMEX> almost like catching sight of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shangri-la</ENAMEX>: the vibrant green vall ey contrasts starkly with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rust</ENAMEX>-colored high ground. High drystone walls curb the narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rugged farmhouses nestle</ENAMEX> in the bottom of the valley. The tiny village
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boot</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two hundred yards</NUMEX> from the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, is the first sign of
        civilization you‚Äôll encounter after coming over the passes. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dozen</ENAMEX> or so houses‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇincluding some of the best self-catering lodgings
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lakes‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇare</ENAMEX> clustered in a peaceful setting surrounded by the
        higher fells of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eskdale</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eskdale Corn Mill</ENAMEX> sits at the very top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>,
        over <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pack Horse Bridge</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This 16th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> is still powered by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force of Whillan Beck</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> that comes racing down from the fells
        above. There are many sign-posted walks from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boot</ENAMEX> into the surrounding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">countryside</ENAMEX>, including a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3-km</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2-mile</NUMEX>) walk to the waterfalls of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanley Force</ENAMEX> across the valley.
        A little way along from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Boot you‚</ENAMEX>Äôll find the terminus of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ravenglass</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eskdale Railway</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúLa‚Äôal Ratty</ENAMEX>,‚Äù as it‚Äôs
        affectionately known. A <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">38-cm</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>-in) narrow-gauge <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">railway</ENAMEX>, it carries
        a tiny engine and even smaller carriages through rolling countryside
        towards the coast at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ravenglass</ENAMEX>. Opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1875</TIMEX> to carry iron, it been
        operating as a recreational <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">railway</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>; a favorite with
        railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX>, it runs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> round.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wast Water</ENAMEX>
        The deepest of all the lakes at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">75 m</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">250 ft</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wast Water</ENAMEX>
        is bounded on the east side by steep slopes of gray scree (small loose
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX>) that tumble into the watery depths, and on the west by
        stretches of bracken. The lake itself lies in the shadow of several
        high mountains, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scafell Pike</ENAMEX>, the highest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">977 m</ENAMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,205 ft</NUMEX>).
        This remote area is reached by a single long route from the
        central lakes, at the end of which you‚Äôll find the scattered buildings
        of the village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wasdale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX>. The rocks in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">volcanic</ENAMEX> and relatively young compared to the hills of the north. They
        have produced a stark and uncompromising landscape, with few trees
        breaking the lines of the mountain-tops. A total contrast to the pretty
        rolling hills of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Derewentwater</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grasmere</ENAMEX>, it is a stark beauty,
        though no less alluring. On fine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> the sunshine and shadows chase
        constantly across the water and rocky <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wastes</ENAMEX>, but stormy fronts that
        form in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic Ocean</ENAMEX> are caught by the mountain tops here, as a
        result of which they are almost always enveloped in clouds.
        Wasdale, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> fell-walking, is still
        very popular with experienced fell-walkers because its rocky crags give
        access to some of the most challenging hiking in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX>. Many who
        have their sights set on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alps</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Himalayas</ENAMEX> come to train on the
        peaks in this area. There are few easy walks on the higher ground, but
        around <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wast Water</ENAMEX> and in the valley bottom you can enjoy footpaths that
        offer panoramic views of the mountains. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wasdale Head Inn</ENAMEX> is a
        traditional meeting place, resting as it does in the lea of all the
        sheer ascents. You‚Äôre bound to meet some hardy outdoor types in the
        bar.
        A curious competition is held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wasdale</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each November</TIMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúBiggest Liar</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World‚Äù Competition</ENAMEX> is an amateur ‚Äústory-telling‚Äù
        contest open to all comers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fishermen</ENAMEX> and anglers seem to have the edge
        over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> are actually banned from
        taking part, since they are regarded as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>.
        Ravenglass
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District National Park</ENAMEX> encompasses a short area of
        coastline where the tidal estuaries of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Sea</ENAMEX> meet the streams
        and rivers flowing down from the western lakes. The main settlement on
        this coast is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ravenglass</ENAMEX>, a curious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> with a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hundred</ENAMEX> or so neat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cottages</ENAMEX> huddled together against the prevailing
        winter winds. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> settled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX>, it sits on a wide estuary
        created by the confluence of three rivers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romans</ENAMEX> called their town
        Clanoventa (‚Äúthe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> on the bank‚Äù). All that remains of the original
        settlement are the ruins of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> bathhouse, just a little ways from
        today‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. Walk under the railway line and turn right down a farm
        track. This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ravenglass</ENAMEX> and Eskdale
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Railway‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> little trains spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> in the sidings here. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and a collection of railway memorabilia.
        The tidal estuary harbors a number of islands that serve as
        important breeding grounds for seabirds. It can be dangerous to explore
        the open, sandy areas on these islands since the tides rise very
        quickly; be sure to check the tidal tables before setting out.
        Nearby is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muncaster Castle</ENAMEX>, a structure offering much in
        the way of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> history. Built on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> was
        erected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 13th century</TIMEX> to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">bay‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇits</ENAMEX>
        strategic position affords good views of the surrounding lowland. Since
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 13th century</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> has been owned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pennington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
        who feel that their tenancy is protected by the terms of an ancient
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">royal</ENAMEX> gift. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1464</TIMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle of Hexham, King Henry VI</ENAMEX> wandered
        the countryside and many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landowners</ENAMEX>, unsure whether he was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">victor</ENAMEX> or vanquished, refused to give him shelter. Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Pennington</ENAMEX>,
        however, invited him into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muncaster</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> returned to his duties
        he gave his drinking bowl to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, saying that as long as the cup
        remained unbroken the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> would remain at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muncaster</ENAMEX>. Needless to say
        the bowl, which is still in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> piece, is kept under lock and key at
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX> times.
        Over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> has been expanded, but it
        is still essentially a family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, full of furniture, books, and
        family portraits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> can tour the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with a tape-recorded
        narrative that gives detailed information about each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hectares</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">80 acres</NUMEX>) of garden are equally pleasing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhododendrons</ENAMEX> and
        other exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> imported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX> have
        created one of the finest gardens in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>
        grounds are also home to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Owl Centre</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conservancy</ENAMEX> devoted to
        saving the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> species of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">owl</ENAMEX> found around the world. Calling itself a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúNoah‚Äôs ark</ENAMEX> for owls,‚Äù the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owl Centre</ENAMEX> hosts a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> flight event every
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:30</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muncaster Mill</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 miles</NUMEX>) north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>, started
        operating in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1455</TIMEX>, although the present <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> dates from the 18th
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>. It is still used to grind oatmeal and whole-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat flour</ENAMEX>, which
        is available for sale. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> sits on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">River Mite</ENAMEX>, and ‚ÄúLa‚Äôal
        Ratty‚Äù makes a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stop</ENAMEX> here.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duddon Valley</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Duddon Valley</ENAMEX> and the rolling hillsides around the
        village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulpha</ENAMEX> were much favored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wordsworth</ENAMEX>. He wrote ‚ÄúSonnets on
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">River Duddon‚Äù</ENAMEX> in praise of the area. This is true moorland‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇopen
        stretches of heath that contrast sharply with the high peaks in the
        background. The views of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scafell</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cumbrian Mountains</ENAMEX> from the
        road that crosses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulpha Fell</ENAMEX> (in the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eskdale</ENAMEX> and Eskdale
        Green) are splendid. And if you really cannot face the excitement and
        exhilaration of crossing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wrynose</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hardknott</ENAMEX> passes, this road offers
        a far less taxing way to reach the coast and the far west of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeland</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>
        Boasting some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Wordsworth‚</ENAMEX>Äôs favorite haunts as
        well as an old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> that is now a very popular hiking route, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> is spectacular walking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, transitional terrain between
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District‚</ENAMEX>Äôs high fells and peaks and the lowland passes around
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penrith</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eden valley</ENAMEX>. These passes were used as a gateway to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX> District by armies of marauding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX>. All of these passes and
        many <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kilometers</NUMEX> of walking trails surround the region‚Äôs single (though
        impressive) large <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lake‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇUllswater</ENAMEX>. At the eastern reaches the high
        ground gives way to undulating farmland.
        Kirkstone Pass
        Leading northeast from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Windermere</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ullswater</ENAMEX>,
        Kirkstone Pass on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the A592</TIMEX> is the highest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lakes‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇ446 m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,489</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ft</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirkstone Inn</ENAMEX>, an old coach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and now local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landmark</ENAMEX>, was
        built here to shelter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> on the hazardous trip between Penrith
        and the central <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">lakes area</ENAMEX>. Despite the high altitude, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirkstone Pass</ENAMEX>
        is in fact the easiest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> passes to traverse, since
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> is very wide, even at the highest level. Watch for a
        car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> just beyond the summit, where you can stop and enjoy the
        awe-inspiring view north over the diminutive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brothers Water</ENAMEX>, so called
        because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> were said to have drowned in its depths.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> then follows the valley bottom through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patterdale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glenridding</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>, once <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> for mining, are
        good starting points for walking, hiking, and pony trekking into the
        surrounding fells and mountains.
        Ullswater
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ullswater</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> major lake in the northeast corner of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">71‚ÅÑ2 miles</NUMEX>) in length, it is the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest lake after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windermere</ENAMEX>, but it does not have the
        commercial development of its big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and is far less busy. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the lake changes as you travel along its length; the shape
        of the valley constantly alters the perspective, a fact that has not
        been overlooked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>. Many
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> visit the area to take advantage of the water sports; it is
        particularly popular with canoeists. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glenridding</ENAMEX> and Patterdale
        offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> rentals. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambleside</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penrith</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">A592</NUMEX>) runs
        along the length of the north shore. From here it is possible to stop
        and admire the view. Those who don‚Äôt want to drive or walk around it
        can take the ferry, which travels down the whole length of the lake
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glenridding</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pooley Bridge</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gowbarrow Park</ENAMEX>
        Just beyond the turning for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dockray</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gowbarrow Park</ENAMEX>,
        which rolls across the hillside above <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ullswater</ENAMEX>. This is the spot where
        Wordsworth‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX> was stopped in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX> by what she
        believed were the most beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">daffodils</ENAMEX> she had ever seen; her
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">astonishment</ENAMEX> inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wordsworth</ENAMEX> to write about this ‚Äúhost of golden
        Daffodils‚Äù in one of the best-loved poems of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language, ‚ÄúI
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wandered Lonely</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cloud‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1804</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> is at its very best in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">spring</ENAMEX>, when you can walk through a carpet of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> surrounded by the
        fresh green leaves of the newly awakened woodland.
        Here you‚Äôll also encounter one of the most popular
        waterfalls in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX>. Beautiful at any time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, Aira
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX> is a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20-m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">60-ft</NUMEX>) waterfall spanned at its peak by a narrow stone
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">foot-bridge</ENAMEX>. It is a favorite subject for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>, in part
        because of the wonderful woodland setting with rare mosses and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fantastic Monkey Puzzle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>. The car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the A5091</TIMEX> offers the
        shortest route to the falls.
        At the northern tip of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ullswater</ENAMEX> there is a right turn to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pooley Bridge</ENAMEX>, the northernmost <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stop</ENAMEX> for the lake steamer. The road
        leads farther along the eastern shore of the lake to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Martindale</ENAMEX> with
        its pretty Elizabethan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Martin</ENAMEX>. Though the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> eventually
        reaches a dead end, there are a number of marked hiking routes back
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">towards Ullswater</ENAMEX> or south over higher ground to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patterdale</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">About 3 km</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 miles</NUMEX>) farther down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharrow Bay Hotel</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and
        arguably still the best country-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house hotel</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX>. Try
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch or afternoon</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalemain Country House</ENAMEX>
        This distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is remarkable for its longevity
        and conglomeration of architectural styles. Behind the fine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fa√ßade</ENAMEX>, made of local sandstone, is a genuine Tudor structure
        (including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fretwork Room</ENAMEX>, with its magnificent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16th-century</TIMEX> oak
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paneling</ENAMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">manor hall</ENAMEX> dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1400</TIMEX> (which now houses the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">restaurant/caf√©</ENAMEX>), and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> pele <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 12th century</TIMEX>, when
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> consisted of little more than the pele <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>, it was owned by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Morville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> (one of the more infamous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of this
        family, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh de Morville</ENAMEX>, was one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knights</ENAMEX> who murdered
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas √° Becket</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Canterbury Cathedral</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1170</TIMEX>). Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1679</TIMEX> it has
        been owned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hasell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, who built the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> extension, and
        who over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> have carefully managed the treasures that fill
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> can examine the traces of the house‚Äôs
        complicated architectural legacy and explore such fascinating
        historical oddities as the ‚Äúpriest‚Äôs hiding hole,‚Äù built during the
        Reformation as an emergency escape route for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> who had
        been invited in to say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX> Access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">chapel</ENAMEX> and the hiding hole
        was through the fireplace, which would be lit to help confound
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pursuers</ENAMEX>. There are also a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> in the magnificent
        grounds, including a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fell Pony Museum</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeoman‚Äôs Museum</ENAMEX>.
        Rheged
        This attraction, an amazing adventure in an ancient kingdom
        opened during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1999</TIMEX>, and offers a chance to take a journey
        through the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cumbria</ENAMEX>. There are displays, exhibitions, and a
        massive multi-screen cinema experience, complimented by speciality
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, caf√©s, and an indoor play <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. All this is in a
        fantastic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in the middle of an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarry</ENAMEX>. The roof
        is covered in <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX>, making it the largest earth covered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>.
        Penrith
        The gateway to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX> for those traveling from
        the north, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penrith</ENAMEX> was often at the center of battles between the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX> for control of this frontier territory. The town
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> is a curious tangle of winding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, laid out that way, some
        say, to confound enemies. The many little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúyards,‚Äù as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">they‚Äôre</ENAMEX> called, were used to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herds</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> brought down from
        the fells during times of crisis. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it is a thriving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">market town</ENAMEX>,
        not yet in the full grip of the tourist boom. The lively cattle market
        makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Penrith</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for the economic activity of the area. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Information Centre</ENAMEX> and a small town <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> are housed in a
        plain, sturdy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Elizabethan</ENAMEX> times known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robinson‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        School. Above the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, across from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">railway station</ENAMEX>, are the
        remains of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penrith Castle</ENAMEX>, built to protect against raids from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">north</ENAMEX>. Traditional home of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> fell into
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">royal</ENAMEX> possession after a series of skirmishes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Edward IV</ENAMEX> granted
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> and land to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard of Gloucester‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwho</ENAMEX> later became King
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard III‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇand it stood as a bastion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crown</ENAMEX>. Later, as
        it fell into disrepair, the walls were dismantled and used to build
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. You can see the characteristic red stone
        on almost every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.
        Askham
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South of Penrith</ENAMEX> is an area of farmland that forms the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eastern</ENAMEX> boundary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Park</ENAMEX>. With its wealth of pretty
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cottages</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Askham</ENAMEX> is a true farming community. The long village green is
        a wonderful place for a stroll, and an even better place to take a
        break, thanks to number of good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX>. A little way from Askham village
        is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lowther Park</ENAMEX>. This large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">estate</ENAMEX> once centered on a fairy-tale
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">castle</ENAMEX>, the remains of which can still be seen from the outside (it‚Äôs
        not open to the public). The vast grounds have been turned into a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leisure</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> (open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> only) which has more than forty attractions.
        Set in grassland and rolling countryside is a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">deer park</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>-of-prey
        attraction, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circus</ENAMEX>, and a theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. There‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to
        do, and there are some wonderful spaces for secluded picnics.
        Haweswater
        This windswept area of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is close to the central lakes
        as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">crow flies</ENAMEX>, but it takes a long time to reach by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. Many
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> walk the distance, using <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">High Street</ENAMEX>, the path of an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
        road that cuts across the fell tops from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Windermere</ENAMEX> toward
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penrith</ENAMEX>. Gentler footpaths radiate from it on to the vast commons of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brampton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martindale</ENAMEX>, but the main part of this route is not for the
        inexperienced or the unfit.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haweswater</ENAMEX> that you see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is man-made. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">61‚ÅÑ2-km</TIMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4-mile</NUMEX>) long reservoir was created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> travels to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the reservoir, and footpaths lead through wonderful undulating
        countryside all around the lake and onto <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mardale Common</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> gets
        crowded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, partly due to interest in the nesting golden <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">eagles</ENAMEX>,
        which have been returned to the area because of the efforts of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX>. There are no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> here, so bring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and
        drink with you.
        Caldbeck
        The northernmost village in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Park</ENAMEX> and once a
        mining <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caldbeck</ENAMEX>, with its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pa stel cottages</ENAMEX> on either side of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chalk Beck</ENAMEX>, is now rather sleepy. The only remaining evidence of
        industry is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Priests Mill</ENAMEX>, which has been a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX>, a bobbin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX>,
        and a sawmill. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> wheel and sluice gate still operate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>,
        and there is a small display of artifacts used over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>; the mill
        buildings themselves have been converted to a gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and caf√©. In
        the churchyard of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Kentigern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, opposite the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX>, is the grave
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Peel</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landowner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the local hunt, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peel</ENAMEX> was a
        larger-than-life character, well known throughout the region in his
        day. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Graves</ENAMEX>, wrote a poem about his
        antics. The verses were set to music in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-19th century</TIMEX> and since
        then the song ‚ÄúD‚Äôye <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken John Peel‚</ENAMEX>Äù have been taught in every English
        school. You will also find the grave of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúBeauty of Buttermere‚</ENAMEX>Äù
        nearby (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>
        With forests and fells, a valley of breathtaking beauty,
        and the most spectacular lake setting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Park</ENAMEX>, this area
        has a greater variety of views than any other in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake District</ENAMEX>.
        Keswick
        This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of sturdy Victorian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> made of gray <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakeland</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stone</ENAMEX> has a stunning setting, nestled as it is in a natural bowl on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shores of Derwentwater</ENAMEX> and surrounded by green hills. The biggest town
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Park</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keswick</ENAMEX> (pronounced <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äúkezzick‚Äù</ENAMEX>)
        swells <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each summer</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hikers</ENAMEX>, boaters, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sightseers</ENAMEX> arrive. Keswick
        makes a good base for touring the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Park</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>. A
        working <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> through much of its history, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> and mining
        industries as major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keswick</ENAMEX> also aroused the interest of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coleridge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Southey</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the more prominent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Poets</ENAMEX>, both lived here and raised the profile of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and the
        surrounding area. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greta Hall</ENAMEX>, once the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southey</ENAMEX> and his family
        and now part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keswick School</ENAMEX>, is unfortunately not open to the
