
  
  
    
      
        Where To Go
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of several different ages, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> has distinct
        districts that are all eminently walkable. You can divide your visit
        into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> separate tours, each of which could fill either an
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> or an entire day. There are also bus tours around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to
        help you get your bearings before you visit special attractions. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> stand in line on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Waverley Street</ENAMEX> near the main railway
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Town</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Edinburgh‚Äôs Old Town</ENAMEX> occupies an amazing site where the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">geology</ENAMEX> has its own fascinating story to tell. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Rock</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur‚Äôs Seat</ENAMEX> are the remains of lava streams that hardened after the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> volcanoes around them became dormant and cold. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last Ice</TIMEX>
        Age, huge glaciers covered the region, moving west to east across the
        land and gouging trenches on either side of the volcanic mounds. They
        resisted the great power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and caused a long stream of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sediment</ENAMEX> to collect. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the Ice Age</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 13,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>),
        the glaciers melted, leaving a long ridge of sediment sloping gradually
        from the top of the volcanic hills.
        When the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> was built atop the hill, the original city
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> grew on this ridge, reaching down in a ribbon of
        development toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey of Holyrood</ENAMEX>, at the foot of the hill in
        the east. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX>, a strong city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇnow</ENAMEX> almost
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">completely destroyed‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇprotected the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. Combined with the
        geological setting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, this stifled development. Instead of
        expanding outward, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> had no choice but to grow upward.
        The famous tenements (or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äúlands‚Äù</ENAMEX>) began to be built. At
        least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> stories high, they were reached through narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> called
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúcloses‚Äù</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúwynds‚Äù that became the focus of city life. A constant
        cycle of building, decay, collapse, and rebuilding‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇplus the
        occasional catastrophic fire‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇgave the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Town</ENAMEX> its characteristic
        irregular layout and chimney-strewn skyline.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edinburgh Castle</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> has always been considered the heart of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>, but its site is older than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> itself: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excavations</ENAMEX> show
        evidence of settlement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronze Age</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ca. 900 b.c.</ENAMEX> ). It dominates
        the skyline, sitting atop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Rock</ENAMEX>. The dramatically rising cliff of
        black <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">basalt stone</ENAMEX> made the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle impregnable</ENAMEX> to all but the most wily
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>. It was the seat of power for anyone who ruled the region,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> of which passed from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> many times over the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">centuries</ENAMEX>.
        Following the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúAct of Union‚</ENAMEX>Äù with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1707</TIMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">castle</ENAMEX> lost its strategic importance but later, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Victorian times</TIMEX>,
        experienced a rebirth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Victorians</ENAMEX> reworked the history and legends
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> to add romantic, neo-Gothic touches. They also greatly
        expanded the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>, for decorative purposes rather than for defense.
        Today <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh Castle</ENAMEX> is the most-visited attraction in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, with
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> passing through the entrance gate each
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.
        A visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> will take <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least two hours</TIMEX>, but
        many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> spend far longer there. There is an informative recorded
        tape in several languages (you listen on headphones as you tour the
        attractions) to help you make the most of your visit. The extremely
        helpful and knowledgeable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> is more than happy to answer any
        questions that you have.
        Your first view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate House</ENAMEX>, which
        you pass through to reach the inner ‚Äúwards. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù Built</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1886</TIMEX> and
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1888</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate House</ENAMEX> was a Victorian attempt to recapture the medieval
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">castle</ENAMEX> style, but it was more a cosmetic addition than a defensive
        structure. The dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ditches</ENAMEX> in front, however, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1650s</TIMEX>. In
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1920s</NUMEX> bronze statues of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes‚</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇWilliam Wallace</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert the Bruce‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwere</ENAMEX> added to the fa√ßade. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> you will find an
        honor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> of kilted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> standing sentry on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">walkway</ENAMEX> over the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ditches</ENAMEX>.
        Once inside, you will find yourself in the lower ward, the
        area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> that has been most heavily bombarded in many
        military campaigns. The Old Guard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> now houses <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> gift
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> grounds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">walkway</ENAMEX> here once had a ditch and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drawbridge</ENAMEX> to protect the inner gate, called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Portcullis Gate</ENAMEX>, which was
        reconstructed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 16th century</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14th-century</TIMEX> foundations. It
        was the main entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>, and a formidable obstacle to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>.
        Passing through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portcullis Gate</ENAMEX>, you enter the middle ward
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>. To your right is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Argyll Battery</ENAMEX>, with a line of
        muzzle-loading <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eighteen-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> pointing out over the skyline of the
        New <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX> (a prime spot for spectacular photography shots). To your
        right are the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúLang Stairs,‚</ENAMEX>Äù which lead up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">medieval castle</ENAMEX>. Walk
        along past the battery to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cart Shed</ENAMEX>, built in the aftermath of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jacobian</ENAMEX> uprising in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1746</TIMEX>. It now houses the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle caf√©‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwith</ENAMEX> a good
        selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX> and hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbut</ENAMEX> was originally used to store
        the provisions <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carts</ENAMEX>. Beside the caf√© is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mills</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Battery</ENAMEX>, the
        location of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">One O‚ÄôClock Gun</ENAMEX>, fired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> except <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> at‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇyou
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">guessed it‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇ1pm.</ENAMEX> Be prepared, for it is indeed noisy.
        The cobbled street leads inexorably upward, past the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governor‚Äôs House</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Barracks</ENAMEX>, neither of which is open to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. Eventually you will reach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Foog‚Äôs Gate</ENAMEX>, but take a right
        before you travel through the gate and follow the path around to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Vaults</ENAMEX>. These were cut into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Rock</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 15th century</TIMEX>
        to create an extra floor of space; they offer a fascinating insight
        into the lives of the ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> gone by. The vaults
        were used for a variety of mundane activities (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bakery</ENAMEX> and storehouse)
        but also functioned as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prisoners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, and
        the soldiers‚Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> endured the same harsh conditions. You‚Äôll see
        messages on the walls of the vaults carved by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> during
        their captivity.
        In the very bowels of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is one of the most
        famous attractions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mons Meg</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> weighing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6040 kg</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.6</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX>), was a gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James II</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1457</TIMEX> from his wife‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip</ENAMEX> the
        Good, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burgundy</ENAMEX>. Manufactured in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mons</ENAMEX> (now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>), the gun
        was state-of-the-art for the times, firing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cannonballs</ENAMEX> weighing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up to</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">150-kg</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">331-lbs</ENAMEX>). It was a formidable weapon but weighed so much that
        it could be transported <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only 5-kms</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3-miles</NUMEX>) per day; often the
        fighting had finished before it could be brought into play. It was
        fired to celebrate the first wedding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen of Scots</ENAMEX>, to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fran√ßois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1558</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1681</TIMEX>, when fired as a birthday salute in honor
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mons Meg</ENAMEX> burst her barrel and was retired from
        active duty.
        Return to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Foog‚Äôs Gate‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> name and age of the gate remain
        a source of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">debate‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇto</ENAMEX> enter the upper ward and the oldest parts of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>. Directly ahead is tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Margaret‚Äôs Chapel</ENAMEX>, said to have
        been built by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David I</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 12th century</TIMEX> in honor of his mother,
        Queen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>, who died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1093</TIMEX>. It is the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> and is still the site of weddings and baptisms. Although the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chapel</ENAMEX> has been renovated since its construction, you will find a
        wonderful example of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Romanesque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch</ENAMEX> in the interior. The
        stained-glass windows, one featuring a likeness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>, were
        inserted into the existing openings in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>.
        Another set of batteries can be found in an open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">area</ENAMEX> south
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">chapel</ENAMEX>. They are built on the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">David‚Äôs Tower</ENAMEX>, once the
        largest and most formidable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>. Begun in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1368</TIMEX>, it
        was the main royal lodging for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> until it was battered and left
        a wreck during the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúLang Siege‚</ENAMEX>Äù of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1571‚Äì73</NUMEX>. The remains of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe rooms</ENAMEX> in its foundations‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇare currently being
        restored.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown Square</ENAMEX>
        At the very pinnacle of the upper ward is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown Square</ENAMEX>, a
        beautiful collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> housing the treasures of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>. On
        your right as you enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish National War</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial</ENAMEX>, the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was originally
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks building</ENAMEX> but was suitably refurbished by Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Lorimer</ENAMEX>
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923</TIMEX> to commemorate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scots</ENAMEX> who fell in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">remembrance</ENAMEX> now also commemorate those who died in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> and all
        other conflicts. Inside are leather-bound regimental books with each
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serviceperson‚Äôs</ENAMEX> name duly inscribed. Splendidly ornate stone friezes
        realistically depict battle scenes of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>, with each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> represented. There is also a chapel dedicated to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who
        sacrificed their lives for their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
        Opposite the memorial is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Hall</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1503</TIMEX> for
        the wedding reception of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James IV</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English Mary Tudor</ENAMEX>. It was
        later used as the ceremonial and legislative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>. The original
        ‚Äúhammer-beam‚Äù wooden roof is the highlight of the design, with thick
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beams</ENAMEX> and painted decorations. Be sure to see the monogram of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">James‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇIR4‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇon some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone brackets</ENAMEX>, along with the red rose
        and the thistle signifying the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> was used as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks</ENAMEX> through much of its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> history
        before being renovated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1887</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interior d√©cor</ENAMEX> now says much more
        about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Victorians‚</ENAMEX>Äô romantic image of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> than it does about how
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> would have really looked: The walls are lined with suits of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">armor</ENAMEX> and swords.
        Along the east side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown Square</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Palace</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to the most precious of the country‚Äôs treasures: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Regalia</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>, much altered over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>, was
        generally used as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> only at times of dynastic importance or
        danger, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holyrood</ENAMEX>, down in the lowland, was difficult to defend. On
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 June 1566</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Stuart</ENAMEX> gave birth to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> (the future James
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VI of Scotland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James I of England</ENAMEX>) in the small antechamber off a
        larger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Mary‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Room</ENAMEX>. The last monarch to spend a
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles I</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1633</TIMEX>.
        On the upper floors (once the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX>) there is an
        exhibition telling the story of the royal regalia. Called the Honours
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, these are said to be the oldest complete <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">set‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇcrown</ENAMEX>,
        scepter, and sword‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇin <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, unchanged since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1640</TIMEX>. There are
        displays of artisans creating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">jewels‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇlook</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> with an
        uncanny resemblance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX>. The highlights
        of the tour are ‚Äúthe honours‚Äù themselves, lying on blue velvet in a
        secure glass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crown Room</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crown</ENAMEX> was
        fashioned of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> mined in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, greatly embellished during the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reign of Scotland‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James III</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1460‚Äì1488</ENAMEX>). The scepter and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> were
        each papal gifts, the former in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1494</TIMEX> and the latter in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1507</TIMEX>; these
        reinforced the links between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>. Following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1707</TIMEX>, however, there was little use for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">regalia</ENAMEX>. They were locked in a trunk in a sealed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">111 years</TIMEX> before Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Scott</ENAMEX> received permission to
        open the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1818</TIMEX>.
        Next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">regalia</ENAMEX> sits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone of Destiny</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> of
        Scone, which historically served as the seat on which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX>
        were crowned, a symbol of the land over which they would rule. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1296</TIMEX>
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> was captured by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> from its resting place in Scone
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey</ENAMEX> and taken to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. It has been used during crowning ceremonies
        for all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> (then <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>) monarchs since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that time</TIMEX>, sitting under
        the coronation throne throughout the ceremony. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> was
        returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> amid great pomp, though it will make the journey
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster Abbey</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> when the next coronation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monarch</ENAMEX> takes place.
        On the lower floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Palace</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laich Hall</ENAMEX> has been
        restored as closely as possible to its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1617</TIMEX> d√©cor, using traditional
        techniques and colors. This was where the monarch met <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>.
        Leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>, you will walk across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Esplanade</ENAMEX>, a
        broad open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">area</ENAMEX> originally created for regimental drill practice. Today
        it is usually used as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> parking lot, but it offers superb
        views of both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Princes Street</ENAMEX> to the north and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Town</ENAMEX> to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">south</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August each year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Esplanade</ENAMEX> is filled by a temporary
        arena erected for performances of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Military Tattoo</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Mile</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> eventually spread out below the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">castle</ENAMEX>, with a main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> leading out the entrance and down to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holyrood Palace</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX> this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">thoroughfare</ENAMEX> became known as
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Royal Mile</ENAMEX> because it was the route used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">royalty</ENAMEX> to make their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holyrood</ENAMEX>. Although <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> long, its name is
        misleading because it is not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> but several different <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>.
        In former times it even crossed the old outer boundary of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>
        before it reached the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>.
        Since the route has never seen any major redevelopment, it
        has grown haphazardly but organically over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>. Some of the
        buildings date from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX>, but it is also lined with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost every era</TIMEX>, including numerous 17th- and
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenements</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúlands</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äù</ENAMEX> sometimes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> stories high. These
        were the residential areas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, considered desirable when they
        were <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> built. Later they were often home to many large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>,
        rife with overcrowding and unsanitary conditions. A stroll along the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Mile</ENAMEX> will take around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-minutes</TIMEX>, but stop and explore the
        various attractions on its path and you might find that this <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one-mile</NUMEX>
        journey will last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a whole day</TIMEX>.
        Before you leave the castle‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Esplanade</ENAMEX>, be sure to see the
        small bronze fountain on the wall to the left of the entrance. This is
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Witches Well</ENAMEX>, marking the spot where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> condemned for black
        magic were burned at the stake.
        Beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Esplanade</ENAMEX> you enter the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> section of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Mile</ENAMEX>, a narrow, cobbled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Castlehill</ENAMEX>. On your left
        you will find the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Edinburgh Old Town Weaving Company</ENAMEX>, where you can
        follow the journey of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> to the finished product. You
        can watch a tartan pattern being woven by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine</ENAMEX> and then choose from
        over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> tartans in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>. There is an exhibition of highland dress,
        showing how it developed through the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>. There are also gift
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> selling quality <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> products. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> itself was at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
        time the major <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> storage <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> for the wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of the
        New <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX>. Built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1850</TIMEX>, it had a capacity of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.5 million-gallons</NUMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.
        Next to the weaving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, across narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ramsey Street</ENAMEX>,
        are the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Outlook Tower</ENAMEX> and its camera obscura, set high above the
        tenement chimneystacks. A series of lenses and prisms projects a live
        image of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> onto a concave viewing screen inside the camera. It
        was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1850s</TIMEX>, when cameras were the height of fashion.
        Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time can sit inside and watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> at work.
        The experience is best when the weather is bright. There is a viewing
        platform around the camera, allowing first-hand viewing of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cityscape</ENAMEX>; there are also helpful explanatory maps pointing out the
        highlights on the horizon.
        Across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Castlehill</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Whisky Heritage Centre</ENAMEX>,
        which tells the story of the development of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> whisky with
        interesting displays. You can also explore the various tastes of this
        complex <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX>, comparing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 100 single malts</NUMEX>. Bottles of your
        favorites are available in the gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> floor.
        At the bottom of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castlehill</ENAMEX>, where the road meets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnston</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Terrace</ENAMEX>, is the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tolbooth Kirk</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">kirk means ‚Äúchurch‚Äù</ENAMEX>), which has the
        highest steeple in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">73 m</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">239 ft</ENAMEX>). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1990s</TIMEX> the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> underwent a massive renovation and now acts as the permanent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Edinburgh International Festival</ENAMEX>. It has
        been re-christened the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hub</ENAMEX>.
        Lawnmarket
        Beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hub</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Mile</ENAMEX> is known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawnmarket</ENAMEX>. This
        was once the commercial center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Town</ENAMEX>, including a weekly
        fabric market. There are several old lands found down the narrow wynds
        leading off the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gladstone‚Äôs Land</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1620</TIMEX>, still has
        its period shopfronts at the roadside.
        Behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gladstone‚Äôs Land</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Stair‚Äôs Close</ENAMEX>, which leads
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Stair‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, now home to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writers‚Äô Museum</ENAMEX>. The house
        (dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1622</TIMEX>) has been beautifully renovated, and contains
        artifacts from the life of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> important <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX>, Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Scott</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Louis Stevenson</ENAMEX>. You will find
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">portraits</ENAMEX>, manuscripts, and personal effects from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX> exhibition on the lower floor is particularly interesting,
        with photographs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> traveling around the world before his
        untimely death at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 44</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Samoa</ENAMEX>.
        Next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writers‚Äô Museum</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Court</ENAMEX>, built in the
        1720s. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hume</ENAMEX> lived here and was regularly visited
        by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Smith</ENAMEX> and by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Johnson</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> must
        have been a hotbed of social reform at the time. At the corner of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawnmarket</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bank Street</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deacon Brodie‚Äôs Tavern</ENAMEX>. Named after the
        city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX> and infamous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">burglar</ENAMEX>, it is one of the best-known pubs
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Look left down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bank Street</ENAMEX> to see the ornate fa√ßade of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of Scotland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, a symbol of the city‚Äôs continuing
        important position in the financial world.
        High Street
        As you approach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Giles Cathedral</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Royal Mile</ENAMEX> becomes
        High Street. On the left you will find a bronze statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hume</ENAMEX>,
        depicted in calm, thoughtful pose.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Giles Cathedral</ENAMEX>, on your right, was the original parish
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and has been at the center of many of its most
        important developments. There has been a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> place of worship on
        the site since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 9th century</TIMEX>. Parts of the interior date back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1100</TIMEX>
        and its crown <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">spire</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">500 years old</TIMEX>; much of the exterior, however, is
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from the early 19th century</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Giles</ENAMEX> was a cathedral for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only five years</TIMEX> of its long
        history. A more accurate title for the edifice is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Kirk of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>. Yet it‚Äôs not only the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> itself that is fascinating;
        it is also its place in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> history. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Giles</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Knox</ENAMEX>, the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1559 to 1572</TIMEX> his fiery
        Calvinist sermons influenced worshippers far beyond the cathedral walls
        and fueled the religious discontent that split the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
        Visit the small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chapel</ENAMEX> dedicated to the Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient</ENAMEX> and
        Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noble Order of the Thistle</ENAMEX>, the highest order of chivalry in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>. The order was founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">VII</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James II</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>) and
        continues <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. There are a maximum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knights</ENAMEX> at any one time,
        headed by the reigning monarch.
        Outside the cathedral you will find a statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Knox</ENAMEX>
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> in hand. It was erected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1906</TIMEX> not far from the reformer‚Äôs
        supposed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial site</ENAMEX>. Nearby is a statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles II</ENAMEX> on a steed.
        Completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1688</TIMEX>, it is the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">equestrian</ENAMEX> statue made of lead in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. Look also for the heart-shaped stone mosaic on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pavement</ENAMEX>
        here, marking the site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh Tolbooth</ENAMEX>. The building
        collected city taxes during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 14th century</TIMEX> but fulfilled several
        additional functions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later centuries</TIMEX>. It was the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and place of
        execution immortalized in the novel <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heart of Midlothian</ENAMEX>, by Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>. It was demolished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1817</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament Square</ENAMEX>, adjacent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">cathedral</ENAMEX>, is home to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament House</ENAMEX>. After its construction in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1639</TIMEX>, it held sessions of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Parliament</ENAMEX> until the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúAct of Union‚</ENAMEX>Äù in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1707</TIMEX>, but since the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th century</TIMEX> it has been an integral part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Law Courts</ENAMEX>.
        You‚Äôll see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solicitors</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>) walking the alleyways and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>
        around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, carrying briefs in hand and adorned by wigs and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">capes</ENAMEX>.
        Between the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">cathedral</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">High Street</ENAMEX> entrance to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercat Cross</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> cross erected here, in the 14th
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, marked the heart of the marketplace and provided a place for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">royal</ENAMEX> proclamations to be given a public hearing. It was also a place
        of execution. The present cross, erected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1756</TIMEX>, is the starting point
        for many walking tours of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Town</ENAMEX>.
        Across High Street you will find the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Exchange</ENAMEX>,
        built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1750s</TIMEX>, which was taken over by the town <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edinburgh‚Äôs City Chambers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1811</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers stand</ENAMEX> on the site of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Mary‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX>, an old tenement abandoned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-17th century</TIMEX>
        after the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> had been wiped out by bubonic plague. The
        close can still be seen beneath the present <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, and guided tours
        are available despite the area‚Äôs reputation as a spot haunted by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the disease. If you take <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> tour, be prepared! Next
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anchor</ENAMEX> Close was once home to the printing works of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Smellie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and printer of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> edition of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Encyclopaedia Britannica</ENAMEX>, which appeared in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1768</TIMEX>.
        Continuing down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">High Street</ENAMEX>, you will walk past several
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> selling highland dress and cashmere before you reach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Knox</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, on the left side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. Said to be the oldest dwelling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, it dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1490</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Knox</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> here from
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1651 to 1672</TIMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Mosman</ENAMEX>, a royal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">goldsmith</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariota Arres</ENAMEX>; a plaque bearing their initials
        can be seen on the outer wall. Opened as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1853</TIMEX>, the small
        rooms display <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knox</ENAMEX> memorabilia and the influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manuscripts</ENAMEX> from
        which he preached his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvinist</ENAMEX> texts.
        Directly across <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">High Street</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knox House</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Childhood</ENAMEX>, said to be the noisiest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> in the world. Dedicated to
        games and toys of yesteryear, it is perhaps more suited to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> than
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find many amusing exhibits of street games, clockwork
        figures, dolls, and teddy bears to bring back memories of your own
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> also has an interesting gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> featuring toys of
        all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX>.
        Canongate
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Royal Mile</ENAMEX> becomes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canongate</ENAMEX> where it intersects <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mary‚Äôs Street</ENAMEX>. This is the former boundary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> and
        the neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canongate</ENAMEX>, which was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aristocrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> serving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Holyrood Palace</ENAMEX>. The
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> were united in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1856</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Canongate</ENAMEX> derived its name from an edict
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> I (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1124‚Äì1157</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey of Holyrood</ENAMEX>, who granted a
        right to raise a gate between the abbey and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Royal ‚Äúburgh‚</ENAMEX>Äù of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>.
        Several historical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> lead off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canongate</ENAMEX>, and a
        number have interesting stories to tell. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chessel‚Äôs Land</ENAMEX>, on the left,
        was the place where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deacon Brodie</ENAMEX> was finally caught in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1788</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Playhouse Close</ENAMEX> was the site of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> where performances resulted
        in so many riots that it was closed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1767</TIMEX>, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 20 years</TIMEX>.
        Dating from around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1625</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moray House</ENAMEX> saw a visit from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Cromwell</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord Protector of England</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> stayed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moray</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> until
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-19th century</TIMEX>.
        On the left as you walk, you will see the Canongate
        Tolbooth, with its distinctive clocktower overhanging the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pavement</ENAMEX>. The
        building on the site dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1591</TIMEX> and served as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> chamber
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in addition to collecting tolls. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Tolbooth</ENAMEX> houses <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The People‚Äôs Story</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> charting the history of
        the ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX> to the present day.
        Reconstructions of workshops, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX>, and family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> show how people
        lived in previous eras, augmented by written and oral testimonies from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">townsfolk</ENAMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20-minute</TIMEX> introductory video.
        Facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tolbooth</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huntly House Museum</ENAMEX>, the local
        history <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, presenting exhibits dating from
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">prehistoric</NUMEX> times to the present. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> itself dates from the 16th
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>. Inside you can find a model of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> as it appeared at that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Covenant</ENAMEX> document signed by leading
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish</ENAMEX> churchmen to protest the attempt by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles I</ENAMEX> to introduce
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Episcopacy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of England</ENAMEX> doctrine) to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>. On a more mundane
        but equally fascinating level, you will see the collar and bowl of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúGreyfriars Bobby‚Äù</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX>). Behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huntly House</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acheson House</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Craft Centre</ENAMEX>.
        Nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canongate Church</ENAMEX> was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1688</TIMEX>, and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">churchyard</ENAMEX> has a number of famous <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">‚Äúresidents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚Äù Buried</ENAMEX> here are the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">economist Adam Smith</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Ferguson</ENAMEX>, and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agnes McLehose</ENAMEX>
        (the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúClarinda‚Äù of Burns‚</ENAMEX>Äôs love poems).
        As the gates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holyrood Palace</ENAMEX> come into view, Whitehorse
        Close can be seen on the left. This was the site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Horse</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inn</ENAMEX>, the main coaching <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London‚</ENAMEX>ÄìEdinburgh route.
        On the right you will see the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Parliament Building</ENAMEX>,
        construction of which began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, and beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynamic</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth</ENAMEX>.
        Holyrood
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX> the busy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> at the bottom of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canongate</ENAMEX> to enter the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Holyrood</ENAMEX> area, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edinburgh‚</ENAMEX>Äôs current royal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>. It comprises the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">palace</ENAMEX>, abbey, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> along with their historic attractions. The
        easternmost stretch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Royal Mile‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇonly 50 m-</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">55 yards</NUMEX>-)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇis</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey Strand</ENAMEX>. It is flanked by a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that
        protected aristocratic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">debtors</ENAMEX> (known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey Lairds</ENAMEX>) from arrest
        and certain imprisonment; civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> had no jurisdiction within
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey</ENAMEX> grounds and could not enter to arrest them.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palace</ENAMEX> of Holyroodhouse
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palace</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holyroodhouse</ENAMEX> is the official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotland</ENAMEX> of the reigning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British monarch</ENAMEX>. However, it began life with a
        totally different purpose. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1128</TIMEX> the king, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">David I</ENAMEX>, ceded land to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Augustinian</ENAMEX> order for the creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey of Holyrood</ENAMEX>. The name
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holyrood</ENAMEX> means ‚Äúholy cross‚Äù (the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> word for ‚Äúcross‚Äù is rood),
        and it is suggested that it is derived from the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> gave
        the abbey a cross that had been owned by his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Margaret</ENAMEX>
        (later <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Legend</ENAMEX> gives us a different account: When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> was hunting
        in the woods, he was about to be attacked by a stag when the figure of
        a cross appeared between the antlers of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX>, which backed away
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> gave funds to build an abbey on this site in the
        depths of the forest in gratitude for his survival.
        With its detailed carvings, the beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">abbey</ENAMEX> was an
        important center of worship but continued to have royal connections
        because of the surrounding hunting grounds. The royal entourage needed
        some form of lodging, and a guesthouse was built <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">adjoining the abbey to</NUMEX>
        be used as a base for hunting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> came to favor the site, and it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James IV</ENAMEX>
        who decided to transform the simple <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lodgings</ENAMEX> into a true royal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1501</TIMEX> he had plans drawn up, which his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James V</ENAMEX> expanded after his
        death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1513</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1529</TIMEX> work started on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> and royal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary of Guise</ENAMEX>, which now constitute the western
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> of the current <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen of Scots</ENAMEX>, later
        occupied <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> here, and there are decorative friezes in the rooms
        from that time.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1544</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> invaded, set fire to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>, and
        sacked the abbey. The great <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>, however, survived. It was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">refurbished</ENAMEX> and the whole palace greatly extended in the following
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Early in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1650</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Cromwell</ENAMEX> stationed his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garrison</ENAMEX> here while
        attempting to subdue the rebellious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">monarchists</ENAMEX>; he was
        victorious at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle of Dunbar</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Later that year</TIMEX> another devastating
        fire destroyed much of the structure‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthough not the tower‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cromwell</ENAMEX> made funds available to rebuild the structure. But both the
        design and workmanship were considered poor.
        Following the return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> monarchy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1660</TIMEX>,
        Cromwell‚Äôs work was redone and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> extended. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles II</ENAMEX> never
        saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> on which he lavished so much money (the royal coffers
        expended <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">¬£57,000</NUMEX>, a fortune at the time), but he created the foundation
        of what we see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, with its amazing ornamental plaster work and
        carved wood paneling. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James VI</ENAMEX> lived at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> in the
        1680s, when the paint was barely dry.
        During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holyrood</ENAMEX> was neglected by
        succeeding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> monarchs, who preferred to stay in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">residence</ENAMEX>, though <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> noble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> lived within the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>. It
        was not until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1822</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George IV</ENAMEX> made a state visit, that the
        fortunes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> revived. Since then, almost every reigning
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monarch</ENAMEX> has spent time (or held soir√©es) at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holyrood</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> has
        been carefully tended throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> can tour the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> only when the monarch is not
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>. Queen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> will usually spend time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early August</TIMEX>,
        but you should check with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourist authorities</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holyrood</ENAMEX> is a must-see
        for you. Helpful guides take you down the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corridors</ENAMEX> and through
        the most interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Stair</ENAMEX> is the formal approach to the royal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> in the southwestern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>. The plaster ceilings here date
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1678</TIMEX> and depict angels carrying the symbols of royal power: crown,
        scepter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX>, and wreath of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">laurel leaves</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Dining Room</ENAMEX> is
        situated at the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Stair</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">majestic room</ENAMEX> is used for
        modern-day entertaining when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen hosts</ENAMEX> dinners and banquets. On
        the walls are portraits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie Prince Charlie</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Henry</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Throne Room</ENAMEX> is one of a series of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> built
        during the reign of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles II</ENAMEX>, though it was originally designed as a
        guard <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> that screened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrants</ENAMEX> to the private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX> beyond. The
        thrones on view here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX> from a visit by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George V</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Mary</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> magnificent state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> follow, both designed by Sir
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bruce</ENAMEX> as part of the extensions and refurbishment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1660s</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evening and Morning Drawing Rooms</ENAMEX> (originally the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presence Chamber</ENAMEX>
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Privy Chamber</ENAMEX>) were designed to meet visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dignitaries</ENAMEX> and
        are splendid in their detail; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oak</ENAMEX>-paneled ceiling is superbly
        decorated. Be sure to take a look at the painting above the mantle. The
        scene, depicting <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cupid and Psyche</ENAMEX>, was considered too risqu√© for the
        eyes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX>, and during her reign it was covered by a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mirror</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King‚Äôs Antechamber</ENAMEX> was where he entertained his more
        favored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King‚Äôs Bedchamber</ENAMEX>, perhaps the most richly
        decorated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seventeenth-century</TIMEX> tapestries
        depicting heroic scenes from the life of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander the Great</ENAMEX> adorn the
        walls. Although the bed dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1680s</TIMEX>, it has never been slept
        in by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">royalty</ENAMEX>. It belongs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamilton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, who have served as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hereditary keepers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>. Beyond this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">King‚Äôs Closet</ENAMEX>,
        where only his intimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entourage</ENAMEX> would be admitted for evenings of
        drinking and card games.
        From the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">king‚Äôs apartments</ENAMEX> you will enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Gallery</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> that is home to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX> portraits of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> rules
        dating back to antiquity. Commissioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles II</ENAMEX>, the paintings
        were all the work of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob de Wit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Wit</ENAMEX> worked
        from likenesses of actual monarchs to produce his portraits. For
        ancient or legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fergus‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwho</ENAMEX> was said to have been
        related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pharaohs of Egypt‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇfashionable</ENAMEX> imagery of the time
        helped to create the finished figures. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Wit</ENAMEX> was paid a reasonable
        stipend of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">¬£120</NUMEX> per year to produce the works, examples of which can
        also be seen in other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>.
        The oldest part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James V Tower</ENAMEX> (once
        called the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Tower</ENAMEX>), is for many the highlight of the tour. Its
        strong stone walls, which survived both fires in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX>,
        sheltered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> that were occupied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Stuart</ENAMEX> and her second
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darnley</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1560s</TIMEX>. On the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bed</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Mary, Queen of Scots</ENAMEX>, with her antechambers surrounding it.
        A set of stairs connects her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to that occupied by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.
        Nearby is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outer Chamber of Mary, Queen of Scots</ENAMEX>, where
        she socialized with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> and debated religion with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Knox</ENAMEX>.
        It is also where her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rizzio</ENAMEX>, was left to bleed to
        death after being stabbed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darnley</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cronies</ENAMEX>; a bronze
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plaque</ENAMEX> marks the spot. You will find a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary‚</ENAMEX>Äôs personal
        effects on display. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX> were totally refurbished by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX>, including larger windows to balance the design of the new
        extensions. However, the original ceiling of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary‚</ENAMEX>Äôs bedchamber is still
        in place.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey of Holyrood</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park</ENAMEX>
        Outside, set in manicured gardens, are the remains of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey of Holyrood</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it comprises little more than the walls of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> nave. The rest of the abbey was raised to the ground in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1570</TIMEX>,
        but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> was saved because it was a parish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and therefore
        served the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. Ornate carvings on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone fa√</ENAMEX>ßade can
        still just be discerned, though they have suffered greatly through
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weathering</ENAMEX> and pollution. A small stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> in the southeast corner
        houses the bones of several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Originally,
        these all had separate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial sites</ENAMEX>, but they were sacked by religious
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>. Queen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria</ENAMEX> arranged for the bones of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James V</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darnley</ENAMEX> to be re-interred in a common <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX>.
        To the south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> are the green landscapes of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Holyrood Park</ENAMEX>, including the volcanic peak known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Arthur‚Äôs Seat</ENAMEX>. Once
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">royal</ENAMEX> hunting grounds, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> these areas are used for open-air events,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concerts</ENAMEX>, and fireworks displays; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">park‚Äôs trees</ENAMEX> are almost
        completely gone. On sunny <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> picnic and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> spend
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> in the fresh air. The rugged peak of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Arthur‚Äôs Seat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">251 m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">823 ft</ENAMEX>)
        in height, can be reached by footpaths all around its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>. The path
        nearest the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> takes walkers along the base of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salisbury Crags</ENAMEX>, a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">volcanic ridge</ENAMEX>. The views from the summit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Arthur‚Äôs Seat‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇnobody</ENAMEX> is
        quite sure which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX> gave his name to the hill‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇoffer wonderful
        views of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Firth of Forth</ENAMEX> to the north.
        On the far side of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Arthur‚Äôs Seat</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duddingston Loch</ENAMEX>, which
        operates as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird sanctuary</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duddingston Kirk</ENAMEX>, near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of the
        loch, is one of the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> still in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">regular</TIMEX> use,
        founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 12th century</TIMEX>. Extensions date from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX>,
        including a watchtower erected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1800s</TIMEX> to deter body
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">snatchers</ENAMEX>. On the causeway leading off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Church Lane</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie‚Äôs Cottage</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúYoung Pretender‚</ENAMEX>Äù stayed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1745</TIMEX> while
        planning his strategy to defeat the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> and retake the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">throne</ENAMEX>.
        Back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Parliament Building</ENAMEX>
        overlooks the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Arthur‚Äôs Seat</ENAMEX>. The design for the
        new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was the subject of a competition won by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enric Miralles</ENAMEX>. Construction began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.
        Directly in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holyrood Road</ENAMEX>, is Our
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynamic Earth</ENAMEX>, which opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1999</TIMEX> in a futuristic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> under
        a brilliant white-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tented</NUMEX> roof. This interactive journey through the
        history of the earth takes you back to the moment of the ‚ÄúBig Bang. ‚Äù
        Experience the formation of the continental plates and the development
        of different climatic regions, then explore the complex and dynamic
        interactions that make our planet work. The exhibits are entertaining
        and educational for all age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, posing questions about our roles as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> of the earth‚Äôs resources and the future of the planet. The fun
        parts include getting to touch an iceberg, experiencing the effects of
        an earthquake in total safety, and lying on the floor of the Showdome
        to watch exciting weather phenomena flashing above.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grassmarket</ENAMEX> and Greyfriars
        In the shadows of the southern walls of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh Castle</ENAMEX>
        lies the rectangular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grassmarket</ENAMEX>. Starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1477</TIMEX> this was a
        marketplace for local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> as well as one of the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> for
        executions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> would gather for the gory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">events‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇas they did for the markets‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand a series of hostelries and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pubs</ENAMEX> set up business to cater to them. Some of these still operate,
        putting out tables in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> so you can enjoy alfresco <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grassmarket</ENAMEX> has a memorial to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Covenanters</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish Protestant</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clergymen</ENAMEX>) martyred by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Stuart</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX>.
        From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grassmarket</ENAMEX>, a road runs parallel to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Mile</ENAMEX> to
        Holyrood on a lower level. It has a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> spanning its
        route, creating a shadowy, dark, and almost somber appearance. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alleyways</ENAMEX> and passages leading off this main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">thoroughfare</ENAMEX> are some of
        the oldest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Below Grassmarket</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cowgate</ENAMEX>, known for generations as the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Quarter</ENAMEX> because many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> came here to escape the potato
        famine in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. At the western end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowgate</ENAMEX> (where it
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meets Holyrood Road</ENAMEX>), you will see one of the few remaining sections of
        Edinburgh‚Äôs old city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Flodden Wall</ENAMEX>), built following the ‚ÄúLang
        Siege‚Äù of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1570s</TIMEX>. In some ways the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> itself was responsible for
        subsequent overcrowding and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were too frightened
        to live outside it.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">West Bow</ENAMEX> (said to be so named because it was within a bow‚Äôs
        length of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> walls) and Candlemakers Row are <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> leading
        away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowgate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX>, at the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grassmarket</ENAMEX>. Here you‚Äôll find
        interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> for antiques, collectibles, and antiquarian books.
        Both these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> lead to the upper level of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George IV</ENAMEX> Bridge.
        From <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Candlemakers Row</ENAMEX>, enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greyfriars</ENAMEX> Churchyard
        through a gate on the right. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greyfriars Church</ENAMEX> was closely linked
        with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant Covenanters</ENAMEX>, and many of those hanged in the
        Grassmarket are buried here. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> was opened in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1620‚</NUMEX>ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe first
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Reformation‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand the National Covenant</ENAMEX> was signed here
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1638</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> became a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Cromwell‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        occupation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1650</TIMEX>; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1718</TIMEX> there was an explosion of
        gunpowder that had been stored by city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>. Fire did
        further damage in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1845</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greyfriars Church</ENAMEX> was restored in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX> to
        produce the building you see now.
        The graveyard has some extremely ornate and fascinating
        tombs, replete with skulls and crossbones and other symbols of death.
        Gravestones rest along the tenement walls marking the outer perimeter.
        Some of the eminent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> buried here are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Buchanan</ENAMEX>, tutor to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Queen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scots</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Craig</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Edinburgh‚Äôs New Town</ENAMEX>;
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Black</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemist</ENAMEX>. You will also find the grave
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyfriars Bobby</ENAMEX>, just beside the main entrance. From here you can
        see some of the most impressive views of the complex layout of the Old
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Town</ENAMEX>, with layer upon layer of crenulated rooftops and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chimneystacks</ENAMEX>.
        The main gate of the churchyard leads out to Greyfriars
        Place, and across the street you will find an excellent view of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
        Scotland‚Äôs newest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Scotland</ENAMEX>, with its main entrance on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>
        Street, is housed in a remarkable new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> building (opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>)
        designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">architects Benson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forsyth</ENAMEX>. It charts the history of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, bringing under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> roof a number of important collections of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">artifacts</ENAMEX>. The story begins <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.4 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> with displays of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fossils</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>, marking the geological changes that forged the
        landscape. It continues through the turbulent eras of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> history
        for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and state, and on to the industrial developments of
        modern times.
        Fascinating details such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie Prince Charlie‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        traveling canteen of cutlery, along with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> and targe (a small
        bag), bring history to life. Exhibits are devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX>
        Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Fleming</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Graham Bell</ENAMEX>, among others. A fine
        collection of medieval church artifacts and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtic</ENAMEX> carvings can be
        found on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> floor. A roof <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX> offers panoramic views over
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> skyline, and there is an excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> on the third
        floor.
        This new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> was built as an annex to the existing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>, a beautiful Victorian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">edifice</ENAMEX> with a large <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass roof‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇmuch
        like a glass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Museum</ENAMEX> has displays devoted to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anthropology</ENAMEX>, archaeology, natural sciences, and technology.
        Collections such as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> art and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> artifacts are on terraced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">balconies</ENAMEX>, allowing a full view of the roof from the ground floor.
        There are always several temporary exhibits to explore, along with a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">caf√©</ENAMEX> and gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>. Tickets for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Scotland</ENAMEX> allow entrance
        also to the main collections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Museum</ENAMEX>, fulfilling the stated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aim</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators</ENAMEX> of ‚Äúbringing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> to the world, and the world
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> are at the heart of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Edinburgh quarter</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> still attending lectures in the
        sandstone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> has grown and now occupies
        sites all around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> here have cheap eateries, stores
        selling eclectic clothing, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Thin</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Bridge</ENAMEX>,
        is the largest bookstore in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, a short walk down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forest Road</ENAMEX> brings
        you to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Edinburgh Royal Infirmary</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has a long-standing
        international reputation for research and development, which began in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1681</TIMEX> with the founding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal College of Physicians</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicine</ENAMEX> followed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few years later</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> infirmary was
        founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1737</TIMEX>; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1805</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edinburgh Medical</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surgical Journal</ENAMEX> was
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in the world published to promote discussion and knowledge of
        medicine. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Lister</ENAMEX> pioneered the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbolic acid</ENAMEX> to keep
        wounds clean, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Young Simpson</ENAMEX> experimented with chloroform as
        an anesthetic.
        Opposite the infirmary, with an entrance on Lauriston
        Place, is the ornate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Heriot School</ENAMEX>. Although not open to the
        public, its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> and beautifully carved stone walls can be seen from
        various vantage points in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. It has an interesting story to
        tell. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Heriot</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">goldsmith</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jeweler</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James IV</ENAMEX>.
        When he died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1624</TIMEX>, he bequeathed his fortune to the education and
        upkeep of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orphans</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was subsequently built for this
        purpose.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Town</ENAMEX>
        By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the 18th century</TIMEX>, life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> (today‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Town</ENAMEX>) was overcrowded and unsanitary. The city
        had grown very little since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 14th century</TIMEX>, yet its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> was
        said to be over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX>. Large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> lived in high tenements, sharing
        a well with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewage</ENAMEX> and dirty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> were
        thrown from upper floors to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> below and left to fester.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1725</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">provost</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Drummond</ENAMEX>, first
        raised the possibility of expansion to the northeast, across what was
        called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barefoot‚Äôs Parks</ENAMEX> to the green fields beyond. His ideas were not
        made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1752</TIMEX>, and it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another 14 years</TIMEX> before plans were
        put into place for a competition to create a design for this new
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, to be called the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Town</ENAMEX>.
        There were logistical problems to be overcome. At the foot
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nor‚Äô Loch</ENAMEX>, a large expanse of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> that required
        draining. There would also have to be adequate access between the older
        and newer parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, including a bridge over the valley between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barefoot‚Äôs Parks</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Mile</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX> for the competition
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> was a gold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medal‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇalong</ENAMEX> with world fame.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>, announced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1766</TIMEX>, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Craig</ENAMEX>, an unknown
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. His plan was a simple
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grid</ENAMEX>: a symmetrical design with straight <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and grand squares. The
        recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> was the inspiration for street names such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúRose‚Äù and ‚ÄúThistle</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Craig</ENAMEX> also praised the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
        Street, Queen Street, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Princes Street</ENAMEX>. Surprisingly, the plan
        contained little detail for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that would line the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>
        and frame the squares. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX> concentrated on the overall
        design.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1763</TIMEX> construction had already begun on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Bridge</ENAMEX>,
        which would provide access from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Town</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nor‚Äô Loch</ENAMEX> was drained
        (creating land for today‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princes Street Gardens</ENAMEX>), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mound</ENAMEX> was
        constructed to provide a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, westerly access between the two
        settlements. Initial demand for land in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Town</ENAMEX> was not
        spectacular; in fact, incentives had to be offered to entice
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> built here did not adhere to any set
        design. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1782</TIMEX>, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> decided to impose
        planning guidelines. At the same time, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Adam</ENAMEX>
        became popular in the fashionable circles of the well-to-do, having
        made a name for himself in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. It was he who would add the ‚Äúflesh‚Äù
        of handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">‚Äúbones‚Äù of Craig‚Äôs</ENAMEX> design.
        By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the 19th century</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Town</ENAMEX> had
        become so popular that plans were made for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> stage. This would
        be a largely residential area extending north from Queen Street,
        incorporating a number of traffic circles (circuses) as well as
        straight <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>. Most influential at this stage was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
        Playfair, and his flair can be seen in many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and public
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of the time. These <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> are still largely residential and
        make an interesting area to stroll, displaying a wealth of original
        detail. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> became known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚ÄúAthens of the North‚</ENAMEX>Äù for both
        its aesthetic beauty and its wealth of talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. Notable
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> seemed to flock to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Town</ENAMEX> have perhaps the
        greatest collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> architecture in the world. Many areas
        enjoy protected status to save them for future generations to enjoy.
        Because so many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are still <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX>, however, there are
        relatively few attractions to visit compared with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Town</ENAMEX>.
        Princes Street
        Looking north from the high ground of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Town</ENAMEX>, the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> street you can see is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Princes Street</ENAMEX>. It was once regarded as the
        most beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, a claim that is difficult to
        understand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> since so many of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> have been
        replaced. Princes Street is to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scots</ENAMEX> what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford Street</ENAMEX> is to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">English‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> premier shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> of the land. Wide walkways have
        plenty of room for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX>, and there are splendid views of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>
        all along its length.
        On the south side of the street‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇin the open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ground</ENAMEX> below
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> and on the site of the formerly marshy <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Nor‚Äô Loch‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇare
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princes Street Gardens</ENAMEX>, a welcome place to relax in a sunny <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Gardens</ENAMEX> have a number of interesting memorial statues and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sculptures</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Memorial</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots Memorial</ENAMEX>.
        An the center of the gardens is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ross Open Air Bandstand</ENAMEX>,
        which plays host to free concerts throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, particularly
        during the festival season. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>, beside the flight of
        steps carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mound</ENAMEX>, you will find the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Floral Clock</ENAMEX>.
        Planted with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of pretty blooms, all in pristine condition, it
        has kept accurate time since its creation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Gardens</ENAMEX> are split by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mound</ENAMEX>, an
        artificial slope of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> and soil that carries a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> connecting the
        New <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old</ENAMEX>. Here you will find <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the most important
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, housed in classical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> designed by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playfair</ENAMEX>. Set back from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Princes Street</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1858</TIMEX>, which houses a collection of works by native
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">collection‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> indeed
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> itself‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇis not huge or overbearing, allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to
        relax and enjoy the art perhaps more than is possible in such massive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">galleries</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Louvre</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rijksmuseum</ENAMEX>. Initially known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1830s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX> benefited from a number of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bequests</ENAMEX>, not least that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sutherland</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">London‚Äôs Victoria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albert Museum</ENAMEX> jointly purchased The
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graces</ENAMEX>, a sculpture by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Canova</ENAMEX> that was in danger of being
        sold abroad.
        What it lacks in size, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> makes up for in
        quality. Works such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raphael‚Äôs Bridgewater Madonna</ENAMEX>, a Rembrandt
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Self-Portrait</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vel√°zquez‚Äôs Old Woman Cooking Eggs</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX>
        from a collection that includes pieces by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titian, Van Dyck</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubens</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constable</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turner</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vermeer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Ramsey</ENAMEX>,
        Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Raeburn</ENAMEX>, and Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Wilkie</ENAMEX>.
        In front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Scottish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, designed as almost its twin. It holds regular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exhibits</ENAMEX> and displays by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy members</ENAMEX>.
        Between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Princes Gardens</ENAMEX> are
        smaller than the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Gardens</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> a large ice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rink</ENAMEX> covers the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX>, where you can enjoy outdoor skating in a picturesque setting.
        Rising above the flower beds is the solemn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Monument</ENAMEX>, complete
        with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> flock of pigeons that badger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on surrounding park
        benches for crumbs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Monument</ENAMEX> is a huge, stone Gothic
        structure with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> buttresses supporting a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">spire</ENAMEX>. The whole edifice is
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">61 m</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 ft</ENAMEX>) high. In its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shadow</ENAMEX> sits the statue of no velist Sir
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Scott</ENAMEX> (and his faithful <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maida</ENAMEX>) carved from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cararra</ENAMEX> marble.
        Designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Meikle Kemp</ENAMEX>, an unknown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">draftsman</ENAMEX> of humble birth,
        the monument took its inspiration from the design of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melrose Abbey</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Sixty-four</NUMEX> additional statuettes carved into the structure represent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scott‚Äôs</ENAMEX> books. Steps inside the outer columns lead up
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> levels, and the view from the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> is
        spectacular.
        A small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garden</ENAMEX> to the west of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Monument</ENAMEX> has a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memorial</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Livingstone</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">explorer</ENAMEX> and missionary. Created by
