
  
  
    
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawaiian Highlights</ENAMEX>
        Oahu: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waikiki Beach</ENAMEX> is the tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of the islands,
        worth strolling or playing on; so is the parallel shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.
        Hidden beneath the glitter are veins of the old royal and romantic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waikiki</ENAMEX> (see page‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ÄÇ28</NUMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bishop Museum</ENAMEX> is a repository of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawaiiana</ENAMEX> and its
        Polynesian legacies (see page‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ÄÇ36</NUMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USS Arizona Memorial</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> powerfully evokes
        the outbreak of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> (see page‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ÄÇ39</NUMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North Shore</ENAMEX> combines native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> culture and natural
        beauty with the modern charm of surfing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> and beaches (see
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">page‚ÄÇ41</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanauma Bay</ENAMEX>, a gorgeous volcanic amphitheater on the shores
        beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Diamond</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX>, draws <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of snorkelers to its gentle reefs
        (see page‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ÄÇ41</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maui</ENAMEX>: The vast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Haleakala</ENAMEX> caldera towers over the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island</ENAMEX> (see page‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ÄÇ51</NUMEX>).
        Lahaina, once the chief whaling port of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>, teems
        with period architecture and trendy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> (see page‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ÄÇ46</NUMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> to and from Hana goes through the heart of tropical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">forests and the ‚Äúreal Hawaii‚Äù</ENAMEX> (see page‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ÄÇ53</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Big Island</ENAMEX>): The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kona Coast</ENAMEX> has superb beaches and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Puuhonua-O-Honaunau City</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Refuge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawaii‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most striking native
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temple</ENAMEX> grounds (see page‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ÄÇ62</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Volcanoes National Park</ENAMEX> has active lava flows flowing to
        the sea at the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Chain</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Craters Road</ENAMEX> (see page‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ÄÇ64</NUMEX>).
        Kauai: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garden Island</ENAMEX> is lush with botanical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">estates</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waimea Canyon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">‚Äúgrand Canyon of the Pacific‚Äù</ENAMEX> (see page‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ÄÇ68</NUMEX>).
        The roadless <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Na Pali Coast</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">heavenly</ENAMEX> north shore is
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the world‚Äôs most challenging and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">majestic seaside hikes</ENAMEX> (see
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">page‚ÄÇ71</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molokai</ENAMEX>: The immense, sheer seacliffs of this rugged,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">sparsely-</ENAMEX>populated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> are the setting for the leper <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> founded
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damien</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kalaupapa</ENAMEX>, which can be reached by mule (see
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">page‚ÄÇ77</ENAMEX>).
        Lanai: This pineapple <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX> island has become a tiny
        hide¬≠away with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> splendid resorts and the remains of the historic
        company <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lanai City</ENAMEX> (see page‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ÄÇ80</NUMEX>).
      
    
  
