
  
  
    
      
        Where to Go
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dublin</ENAMEX> is a compact <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, and many of its important sites
        are within easy walking distance of one another. There is also an
        excellent bus service that will take you to attractions away from the
        city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. You can get bus information from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin Bus Office</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Upper O‚ÄôConnell Street</ENAMEX> or from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin Tourism Centre</ENAMEX> in Suffolk
        Street. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DART</ENAMEX> (railway) travels north and south along the coast, a
        pleasant scenic ride. Car rental is quite expensive, and, with
        congested traffic and parking problems, is not a good choice within the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, though you may wish to use a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to explore places in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">environs</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day Trips</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> on pages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66‚Äì78</NUMEX>). There are,
        however, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> tours to outlying destinations.
        A good orientation exercise is to start with an organized
        sightseeing tour with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin Bus</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Upper O‚</ENAMEX>ÄôConnell Street or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bus</ENAMEX>
        √âireann from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travel Centre</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bus√</ENAMEX>°ras in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Store Street</ENAMEX>. Your first
        port of call should be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin Tourism</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Suffolk Street</ENAMEX> in the former
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Andrew‚Äôs Church</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Monday‚ÄìSaturday 9am‚Äì5:30pm</ENAMEX>); there is also an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">O‚ÄôConnell Street</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find maps, leaflets, and other
        useful information there; you can also arrange accommodation and book
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tours</ENAMEX>, theater tickets, and other entertainment. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourism</ENAMEX> has devised and signposted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> self-guided walking tours of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, which you can follow using the booklets provided.
        Around <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grafton Street</ENAMEX>
        Grafton Street, south of the river, is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs main
        shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> probably often find yourself on this central
        pedestrian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">thoroughfare</ENAMEX>, crowded with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, sightseers,
        and street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entertainers</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs lined with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown Thomas</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Ashley</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>. The original <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bewley‚Äôs Oriental</ENAMEX>
        Caf√© is here; after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100 years</TIMEX>, it has become something of an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX>, and is the most interesting of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. The windows to the rear of its faded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Deco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ground floor</ENAMEX> were
        designed by the stained-glass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Clarke</ENAMEX>. It also has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>
        and theater. Down the narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> beside <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bewley‚Äôs</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Teresa‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>, with stained-glass windows by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Burke</ENAMEX>, and a fine
        sculpture by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hogan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine McAuley</ENAMEX>, who founded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sisters of</ENAMEX>
        Mercy to help the poor of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>, attended mass here‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit‚Äôs her face
        you see on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five pound</NUMEX> note.
        A number of more recent shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> are set around
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grafton Street</ENAMEX> area (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>). The upscale Powerscourt
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Townhouse Centre</ENAMEX> is probably the most interesting (a sign points the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> just beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bewley‚</ENAMEX>Äôs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Clarendon Street</ENAMEX> entrance). This 1770s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mansion</ENAMEX> was formerly the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> of viscount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powerscourt</ENAMEX> and still
        possesses some magnificent plasterwork, particularly in the rear exit
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hall</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> has been tastefully converted, with a pleasant
        glass-roofed central <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> surrounded with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">balconies</ENAMEX>. There are
        many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caf√</ENAMEX>©s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and you can shop on the various levels for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antiques</ENAMEX>, crafts, and clothes. At the top is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art gallery</ENAMEX> with
        changing exhibitions. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer months</TIMEX> there is a program of
        lunchtime recitals.
        Next to the shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South William Street</ENAMEX>, is the
        small and eclectic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dublin Civic Museum</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX>), an unassuming
        record of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> life over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>.
        At the top of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grafton Street</ENAMEX>, where it meets busy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>
        Street, you will see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Rynhart‚</ENAMEX>Äôs statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Malone</ENAMEX>, subject of
        the well-known <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballad</ENAMEX>, with her barrow and a very low
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">d√©colletage.</ENAMEX> Erected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> to celebrate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX> as a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, it has become known to irreverent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dubliners</ENAMEX> as the ‚ÄúTart with the
        Cart. ‚Äù
        Down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from the statue is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> (see
        page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX>), built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1729</TIMEX> to house the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is
        really a series of additions to an original structure, although the
        overall effect is one of elegance and superb proportion. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corinthian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">portico</ENAMEX> was designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Gandon</ENAMEX>, who was also responsible for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Custom House</ENAMEX> on the north <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liffey</ENAMEX>. Plans to house parliament
        here after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Independence</ENAMEX> came to nothing; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leinster House</ENAMEX> (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kildare</ENAMEX>
        Street) was chosen instead. Behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foster</ENAMEX> Place is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intimate Bank of Ireland Arts Centre</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> a variety of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exhibitions</ENAMEX>, plays, and concerts.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity College</ENAMEX>
        Across College Street is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity College</ENAMEX>. Founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1592</TIMEX>
        to educate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant Anglo-Irish</ENAMEX> ascendancy, it was formerly
        regarded as a place somewhat apart from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> affairs. All that has
        changed, however, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> is one of the geographical
        and social hubs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, attracting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of all creeds and
        nationalities from around the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Famous graduates</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swift</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Goldsmith</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bram Stoker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Wilde</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Beckett</ENAMEX>;
        resistance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Emmet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Tone</ENAMEX> also studied here.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> sits on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Green</ENAMEX>, an island of
        magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, open squares, and green spaces, surrounded by a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sea</ENAMEX> of traffic. Walk through the gates of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-m- (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">300-ft-</ENAMEX>) high
        west front, designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Jacobsen</ENAMEX> and built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1752</TIMEX>. The
        statues on either side are of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Burke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Goldsmith</ENAMEX>. You
        are welcome to explore or take a tour around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Green</ENAMEX>, but some of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> may be closed, depending on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the time of year</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Front Square and Parliament Square</ENAMEX>, dating from the 18th
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, are surrounded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dining Hall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examination Hall</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reading Room</ENAMEX>, and anchored by the splendid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campanile</ENAMEX>. On your left the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dining Hall</ENAMEX>, designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Castle</ENAMEX>, has been falling down ever
        since it was finished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1740s</TIMEX> and has undergone frequent
        rebuilding. It was beautifully restored after a damaging fire in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>.
        The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 18th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel</ENAMEX> displays some fine plasterwork and
        dazzling stained-glass windows, together with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20th-century</TIMEX> organ in
        an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> case.
        Opposite, and from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same era</TIMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examination Hall</ENAMEX>,
        where concerts are given occasionally when no examinations are in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progress</ENAMEX>, but is otherwise rarely open to the public (look through the
        spy hole in the door! ). The beautiful stucco ceiling is by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stapleton</ENAMEX> (who is also responsible for the ceilings in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writers Museum</ENAMEX>).
        Among the paintings is a portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Archbishop</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>
        Usher, who donated the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of Kells</ENAMEX> (see below) to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel and Examination Hall</ENAMEX> were designed by Sir
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Chambers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marino Casino</ENAMEX> (see page
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74</NUMEX>).
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>-m- (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100-ft-</ENAMEX>) high <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Campanile</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1853</TIMEX> by Sir
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Lanyon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> the university‚Äôs bells. It is impossible to miss
        the huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reclining Connected Forms by Henry Moore</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Library Square</ENAMEX>, or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Calder‚Äôs Cactus</ENAMEX> behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Library</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fellows Square</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Koralek‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley Library</ENAMEX>, fronted by Arnaldo
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pomodoro‚Äôs Sphere Within Sphere</ENAMEX>, fits seamlessly into the earlier
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. The eastern side of the square once housed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver</ENAMEX>
        Goldsmith‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> (renovated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Victorian times</TIMEX>, little of the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> remains).
        Trinity‚Äôs most important possession is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX>
        Book of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kells</ENAMEX>. The new exhibition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄúTurning Darkness</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Light‚</ENAMEX>Äù is in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colonnades</ENAMEX> beneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Library</ENAMEX>. It begins with a series of
        lighted panels illustrating the manuscript. The book itself is
        displayed along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of Durrow, the Book of Armagh</ENAMEX>, or another
        illuminated manuscript; pages of the books are turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every six weeks</TIMEX>.
        The exhibition is tremendously popular, so be prepared for some long
        lines at the entrance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Upstairs</ENAMEX> is the impressive <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Long Room, or Old</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>, opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1732</TIMEX>. A barrel-ceilinged chamber <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">64 m</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">209 ft</ENAMEX> ) <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long,</TIMEX>
        with windows along both sides, it holds <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trinity‚</ENAMEX>Äôs oldest books,
        including a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> folio. There is an elaborate gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> at the
        entrance to the exhibition. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open Monday‚</ENAMEX>ÄìSaturday <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30am‚Äì4:30pm</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
        noon‚<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Äì4:30pm</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> IR¬<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">£4.50</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> IR¬<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">£3</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> free; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IR¬</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">£6</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dublin Experience‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsee</ENAMEX> below. )
        Across <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fellows‚Äô Square</ENAMEX> in the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts Building</ENAMEX> is a
        wide-screen audio-visual show about the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>
        Experience, a good introduction for those unfamiliar with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> culture
        or Dublin‚Äôs history. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hourly</ENAMEX> shows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10am‚Äì5pm</TIMEX>, also available
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> noon‚<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Äì5pm</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> IR¬<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">£3</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IR¬</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">£2.50</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IR¬</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">£6</ENAMEX> combined with the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of Kells</ENAMEX>).
        Also in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts Building</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Hyde Gallery</ENAMEX>, a
        modern two-level exhibition <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">space‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit‚</ENAMEX>Äôs the place to go for the
        cutting edge in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> and international art (open <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monday‚</ENAMEX>ÄìFriday
        11am‚<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Äì6pm</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7pm</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11am‚Äì4:45pm</TIMEX>; lectures <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:15pm</TIMEX>, tours <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>; free).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kildare Streets</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Provost‚Äôs House</ENAMEX> on the southwest corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX>
        Green was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 18th century</TIMEX> and is one of the finest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> inside are beautiful, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is
        not open to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.
        From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Green</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau Street</ENAMEX> (site of many
        interesting crafts and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>), then turn right into Dawson
        Street. Here you‚Äôll find bookshops, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX>, and another shopping
        complex, this one built on the site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Hibernian Hotel</ENAMEX> and
        naturally called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Royal Hibernian Way</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Anne‚Äôs Church</ENAMEX> (facing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anne Street South</ENAMEX>) has some
        colorful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> stained glass, and provides the setting for
        lunchtime concerts (look for the notices in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vestibule</ENAMEX>). A few doors
        down is the charming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mansion House</ENAMEX>, official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1715</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1710</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an 18th-century</TIMEX>
        property <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculator</ENAMEX>, one <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Dawson</ENAMEX>, for whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> was named.
        Right behind it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Round Room</ENAMEX>, where in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> parliament
        Turn down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Molesworth Street</ENAMEX> to reach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kildare Street</ENAMEX>, where
        you will see the entrance to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leinster House</ENAMEX>, once home of the earls of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kildare</ENAMEX>, and now home to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is
        believed by some to have provided the basis for the design of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington‚Äôs White House</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, which was the work of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Hoban</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1870</TIMEX>. On the west side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> is
        the entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Library</ENAMEX> and next to it is the National
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX>). Tickets and advance notice are required for the
        reading <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>; the more than half-million items here are
        a vast archive of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. Exhibitions are often held in the
        splendid entrance <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deane & Woodward</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> responsible for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">library</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, also built the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kildare Street Club</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1861</TIMEX>. This
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">marvelous Victorian</ENAMEX>-Gothic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is famous for the fanciful stone
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carvings</ENAMEX> around the base of its pillars (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> pillar, reputedly
        depicting the club <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, shows monkeys playing billiards). The club
        itself was a bastion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ascendancy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> now
        houses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heraldic Museum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genealogical Office</ENAMEX>, with exhibits on
        the history of heraldry. The consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ireland‚Äôs Chief Herald</ENAMEX> will help you trace your own ancestry, and if
        you have a couple of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousand pounds</NUMEX> to spare, you can apply for a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grant</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open Monday‚</ENAMEX>ÄìWednesday 10am‚<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Äì5:30pm</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thursday‚</ENAMEX>ÄìFriday
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30‚Äì4pm</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30am‚Äì12:30pm</TIMEX>. )
        Walk to the bottom of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kildare Street</ENAMEX> and you will reach <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen‚Äôs Green</ENAMEX>, formerly an open common, but enclosed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1663</TIMEX> and now
        a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9-hectare</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">22-acre</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> in the heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> surrounded by some
        beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. It is the oldest green in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>, dating back to
        medieval times, although formally laid out as a public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> only in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1880</TIMEX>. It‚Äôs a popular and often crowded place. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green</ENAMEX> contains large
        formal <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX> with ornate gardens, a lake, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX> ponds, a bandstand, and
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">children‚Äôs playground</ENAMEX>.
        Entering the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Stephen‚Äôs Green North</ENAMEX> you will
        come across the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe Tone</ENAMEX> memorial opposite the famous Shelbourne
        Hotel (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1824</TIMEX>), and behind it a work entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Famine</ENAMEX>, both by sculptor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Delaney</ENAMEX>. Facing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Stephen‚Äôs Green South</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marjorie</ENAMEX>
        Fitzgibbon‚Äôs bust of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Joyce</ENAMEX>. Working your way around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, you
        will see the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1907 Fusilier‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arch</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grafton Street</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corner</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Stephen‚Äôs Green Shopping Complex</ENAMEX> at the south end
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grafton Street</ENAMEX>, a pseudo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> iron-and-glass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>, was
        built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, and has been christened <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúThe Wedding Cake‚Äù by</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dubliners</ENAMEX>. It houses a wide selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX> as well as a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pub</ENAMEX> and restaurant on the top floor.
        Halfway down the west side of the green is the massive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgian Royal College of Surgeons</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1806</TIMEX>. Those chips in the
        stonework are bullet holes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1916 Easter Rising‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> building
        was occupied by independence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> led by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Countess Markievicz</ENAMEX>; you
        may have seen a bust of the countess in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs best-kept secrets is the lovely Iveagh
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gardens</ENAMEX>, accessible from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Clonmel Street</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harcourt Street</ENAMEX> or from
        behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Concert Hall</ENAMEX> off <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Earlsfort Terrace</ENAMEX>. Designed as a
        series of pleasure gardens in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italianate</ENAMEX> style in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865</TIMEX>, with
        cascades, spectacular fountains, and rustic grottoes, an ongoing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restoration</ENAMEX> hopes to bring them back to the original plan. The gardens
        were opened to the public in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> curve of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harcourt Street</ENAMEX> (constructed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1775</TIMEX>)
        was once home to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bernard Shaw</ENAMEX> (numbers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60‚Äì61</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birthplace Museum</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Synge Street</ENAMEX>, is marked by a plaque
        written by the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> himself. From here it is a short walk,
        following the signs, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walworth Road</ENAMEX> (see
        page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>).
        Back along the south side of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Stephen‚Äôs Green</ENAMEX> there
        begins a fine array of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Church</ENAMEX>,
        built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1853</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cardinal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Newman</ENAMEX>, then rector of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX>. The interior is decorated in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> style and is strangely
        compelling. It is a very popular venue for weddings.
        Next door, numbers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">85 and 86</TIMEX> comprise the exquisite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newman</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University College</ENAMEX> (guided tours <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">June‚</ENAMEX>ÄìAugust
        Tuesday‚ÄìFriday noon‚<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Äì5pm</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2‚Äì5pm</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday 11am‚Äì2pm</TIMEX>; other times
        by arrangement; closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>; entrance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IR¬</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">£2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> IR¬<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">£1</NUMEX>). Number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85</NUMEX>
        dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1740</TIMEX> and contains the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo Room</ENAMEX>, with panels
        depicting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo</ENAMEX> and the muses, and the magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rococo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">salon</ENAMEX>, both
        by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Francini</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, who also worked on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Russborough House</ENAMEX> (see
        page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX>). Number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">86</NUMEX> next door, largely the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert West</ENAMEX>, has
        even more elaborate ornamentation.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Joyce</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> here, and, towards the end of his
        life, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerard Manley Hopkins</ENAMEX> lectured here. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classrooms Joyce</ENAMEX> attended can be seen on the guided tour, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        room has been restored. There is a very pleasant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX> and in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">basement</ENAMEX> is The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commons</ENAMEX>, which ranks among the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>.
        Just beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newman House</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iveagh House</ENAMEX>, home to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">government‚Äôs Department of Foreign Affairs</ENAMEX>, but closed to the public.
        Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newman House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Iveagh House</ENAMEX> were designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Castle</ENAMEX>.
        Beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Iveagh House</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Earlsfort Terrace</ENAMEX> (turn south) is
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Concert Hall</ENAMEX>, of impressive proportions and uncertain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">acoustics‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit‚Äôs</ENAMEX> a conversion of an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examination Hall of University</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX>.
        Back at the northeast corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Stephen‚Äôs Green</ENAMEX>, near
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shelbourne Hotel</ENAMEX>, you can turn right into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrion</ENAMEX> Row to peer
        through the railings at the small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Huguenot Cemetery</ENAMEX> (no entry to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery</ENAMEX> dates back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1693</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX>,
        fleeing persecution in their native land, settled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>, bringing
        with them their architectural and weaving skills, which greatly
        enriched their adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
        Old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Bar</ENAMEX>
        Between the river and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dame Street</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Temple Bar</ENAMEX> area,
        which has become famous for its nightlife andstreetlife. Here you will
        find narrow cobbled lanes dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th</TIMEX> century‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇpartly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pedestrianized</ENAMEX> and fairl y free of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">traffic‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇsome</ENAMEX> original
        architecture, and many lively <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, caf√©s, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Bar</ENAMEX> is also home to a wealth of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">musicians</ENAMEX>, and there are crafts and art workshops, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>, and music
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centers</ENAMEX>. It has mercifully escaped urban renewal, although a new
        housing project does loom at its far west end.
        You can enter <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Temple Bar</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dame Street</ENAMEX>, or from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleet</ENAMEX>
        Street (off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westmoreland</ENAMEX>), or you can walk through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merchants Arch</ENAMEX>,
        opposite the picturesque <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ha‚Äôpenny Bridge</ENAMEX>, into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Temple Bar Square</ENAMEX>.
        Continuing along <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Temple Bar</ENAMEX>, you‚Äôll come to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eustace Street</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Meeting</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Square</ENAMEX>. Most of the cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> that make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Bar</ENAMEX>
        interesting are located in this area. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of these to open was
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Film Centre</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eustace Street</ENAMEX>, with its popular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">caf√©</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>. Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eustace Street</ENAMEX> is an information <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and a
        cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX>). On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meeting House</ENAMEX>
        Square is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallery of Photography</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX>) and the recently
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">opened National Photo Archive</ENAMEX> (open <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Monday‚ÄìFriday 10am‚Äì5pm</ENAMEX>), both with
        exhibition spaces. On <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Curved Street</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthouse Multimedia Centre</ENAMEX> for
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX> brings art and multimedia together, hosting changing
        exhibitions and offering <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> and workshops (open <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monday‚ÄìSaturday</ENAMEX>,
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30am‚Äì6:30pm</TIMEX>, closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>; caf√© open <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10am‚Äì10:30pm</TIMEX>). Across the
        street, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Bar Music Centre</ENAMEX> is a resource <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for music,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>, and stage production (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX>). In its new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, the
        Project <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts Center</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East Essex Street</ENAMEX>, displays the most
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde</ENAMEX> in painting and sculpture; it has a performance space
        upstairs. If you want to see what‚Äôs happening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, this is
        definitely the place to come.
        On <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Temple Bar‚</ENAMEX>Äôs southern boundary, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dame Street</ENAMEX>, is a gem of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> architecture, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympia Theatre</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX>). Built in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1870</TIMEX>, its canopy of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stained glass</ENAMEX> and cast iron is the oldest in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>; its enthusiastic interior decoration is also typical of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">era</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happily</ENAMEX>, the restored theater leads <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a bustling</NUMEX>, active life, with
        a regular schedule of plays and concerts. Just across the way is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin‚Äôs City Hall</ENAMEX>, built originally as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Exchange</ENAMEX> in
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1769‚Äì1777</NUMEX>. This fine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> with its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Corinthian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">portico</ENAMEX> was designed
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Cooley</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was undergoing restoration at press
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. Just west of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Hall</ENAMEX> is one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most important historic
        sites, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin Castle</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin Castle</ENAMEX>
        Today, as you walk through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Gate</ENAMEX> into the spacious
        Georgian yard, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin Castle</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and admissions)
        looks serene and imposing. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven centuries</TIMEX> the real and symbolic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> military and social power, it is a monument that
        still has resonance for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dubliners</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> has been built and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rebuilt</ENAMEX>, and little remains of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> structure.
        Supposedly it sits on the site of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dubh Linn</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Pool</ENAMEX>) that gave
        Dublin its name.
        The guided tour commences with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Apartments</ENAMEX> on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">south</ENAMEX> side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. Lavishly furnished and decorated, with much
        original period furniture, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> are used for ceremonial events,
        visits from foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dignitaries</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> meetings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connolly Room</ENAMEX> is
        so called because it was here that the wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Connolly</ENAMEX> spent his
        last night before being executed for his part in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter Rising</ENAMEX>.
        Note the beautiful ceiling in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Granard Room</ENAMEX>. It was moved here from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mespil House</ENAMEX> and is called the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚ÄúHibernia Ceiling</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äù The Drawing Room</ENAMEX>
        was partially destroyed by fire in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX>, and its furnishings are
        faithful <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">reproductions</ENAMEX>; the huge (repaired) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX> punch bowl is
        striking.
        A magnificent carpet, with a design based on a page from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of Kells</ENAMEX>, (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>), covers the floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Throne Room</ENAMEX>.
        The rather large throne was last used in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George V.</ENAMEX> In the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lovely Picture Gallery</ENAMEX>, convex wall mirrors made it possible for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> at table to keep his eye on everyone, particularly the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Wedgewood Room</ENAMEX> contains a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> carpet given by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Valera</ENAMEX>, and
        plaques by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sculptor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Flaxman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sculptor</ENAMEX> Berthel
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thorwaldsen</ENAMEX>. The enormous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saint Patrick‚Äôs Hall</ENAMEX> with its painted ceiling
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vincenzo Valdre</ENAMEX> contains the banners and coats of arms of the now
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defunct Knights of St. Patrick</ENAMEX>. It is used for the inauguration of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.
        underground excavation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Defenses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> can
        stand in the dry bed of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moat</ENAMEX>, traverse imaginative gangways
        over the encroaching river (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poddle</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liffey</ENAMEX>), and view the
        stairs where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> once brought provisions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>. In the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restored Treasury</ENAMEX> (built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1715</TIMEX> and located in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lower Yard</ENAMEX>), browse
        in the bookshop or relax in the pleasant self-service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Vaults</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bistro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patisserie</ENAMEX>.
        The oldest remaining part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Record Tower</ENAMEX>
        (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1258</TIMEX>), visible as you leave the upper yard. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX>-revival
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Church</ENAMEX> of the Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Trinity</ENAMEX>, adjacent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>,
        has stone work by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Smyth</ENAMEX> and a fan-vaulted ceiling. The newest
        addition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle precinct</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chester Beatty Library</ENAMEX>, which
        moved here from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballsbridge</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christ Church Cathedral</ENAMEX> and Environs
        Farther up the hill on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Castle Street</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Gate</ENAMEX> is
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major cathedrals, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Christ Church Cathedral in</ENAMEX>
        Christchurch Place (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and admissions). Standing,
        like the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>, on an eminence, the cathedral rises on the site of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Sitric‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11th-century</TIMEX> wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. The foundations date back to
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1170s</NUMEX> when ‚ÄúStrongbow,‚Äù the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earl</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pembroke</ENAMEX>, had it rebuilt as a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stone</ENAMEX> structure. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1558</TIMEX>, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry VIII‚Äôs</ENAMEX> break with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, all the existing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> had become
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>).
        Unfortunately, the church <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was massively and
        unsympathetically restored in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1871‚Äì1878</NUMEX>, when most of the original
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interior</ENAMEX> was ripped out. However, there is still much to appreciate in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christ Church</ENAMEX>, including the impressive stonework, soaring nave, and
        the handsome <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">encaustic</ENAMEX> floor tiles based on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13th-century</TIMEX>
        pattern. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strongbow‚Äôs</ENAMEX> tomb is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>; and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loo</ENAMEX> is a somewhat macabre artifact, the embalmed heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence O‚ÄôToole</ENAMEX>, the influential <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archbishop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>,
        which is kept in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX> suspended on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> near the altar.
        The large, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaulted medieval crypt</ENAMEX> is the oldest structure
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>. In the crypt you can see a forest of heavy, rough stone
        pillars supporting the upper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, and displays that include stocks
        dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1670</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medieval carved stones</ENAMEX>, and an odd exhibit‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa
        mummified <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>, found in the organ pipes.
        In the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Synod Hall</ENAMEX> just across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cathedral</ENAMEX> (linked to it by a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>) you will find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublinia</ENAMEX>, a rather
        touristy sight-and-sound re-creation (in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> languages) of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> in
        medieval times; tableaux of medieval <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craftsmen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> cover
        events in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> invasion (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1170</TIMEX>) to the
        dissolution of the monasteries (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1540</TIMEX>). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open April‚ÄìSeptember</ENAMEX> daily
        10am‚<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Äì5pm</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">October‚ÄìMarch 11am‚Äì4pm</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10am‚Äì4:30pm</TIMEX>]; entrance fee:
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> IR¬<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">£4</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> IR¬<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">£2.90</NUMEX>. ) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Upstairs</ENAMEX> is a gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and the
        entrance to the connecting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">walkway</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">cathedral</ENAMEX>; you can climb the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tower</ENAMEX>, which has an interesting view of the surroundings.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fishamble Street</ENAMEX>, leading downhill to the river, a
        plaque commemorates the first performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Handel‚Äôs Messiah</ENAMEX>, which
        took place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Music Hall</ENAMEX> (now an old steelworks) on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 April 1742</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wood Quay</ENAMEX>, on the south <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> of the river (downhill from the arch and
        dominated by the featureless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin Corporation</ENAMEX>), is the
        site of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Viking</ENAMEX> settlement and its clever recreation, The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viking Adventure</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tuesday‚</ENAMEX>ÄìSaturday 10am‚<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Äì4:30pm</TIMEX>, closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> IR¬<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">£4.95</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> IR¬<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">£2.50</NUMEX>, family <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">IR¬£13</NUMEX>). Construction
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> obliterated much of the archaeological dig which had
        unearthed the original layout of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quay</ENAMEX>, but the Viking
        artifacts that were found are on view in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Museum</ENAMEX> (see page
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX>) and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking Adventure</ENAMEX> exhibit.
        A short distance from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">cathedral</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">High Street</ENAMEX> are the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Audoen‚Äôs Churches</ENAMEX>. The restored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland St. Audoen‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        is the older of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">c. 1190) and</ENAMEX> is the only truly medieval church
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tours July‚ÄìSeptember</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30am‚Äì4:30pm</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> only
        May and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, closed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">October‚ÄìApril; IR¬</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">£1.50</NUMEX>. ) Next door is the narrow,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lofty Neoclassical</ENAMEX> fa√ßade of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic St. Audoen‚Äôs</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1847</TIMEX>. Both
        churches stand beside what remains of the old city walls, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
        Audoen‚Äôs is the only surviving gate. In medieval times the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Cross</ENAMEX>
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> city, where decrees and notices of excommunication were
        read out, stood on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">High Street</ENAMEX>. Granite markers erected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>
        indicate the line of the old city walls.
        West from here in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thomas Street</ENAMEX>, a plaque on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">decommissioned</ENAMEX> and rather sad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Catherine‚Äôs Church</ENAMEX> (built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1769</TIMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX> the spot where famed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> resistance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Emmet</ENAMEX> was
        hanged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1803</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Street West</ENAMEX> turns into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">James‚Äôs Street</ENAMEX>, where the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guinness Brewery</ENAMEX> has been situated since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1759</TIMEX>, and nearby in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crane</ENAMEX>
        Street is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guinness Hopstore</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberties</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">area</ENAMEX> known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberties</ENAMEX> was so named because it was
        situated outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">medieval city</ENAMEX> walls and was run by local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>,
        free of city regulations on trade. Across from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Audoen‚Äôs</ENAMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> run off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">High Street</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Street</ENAMEX> is lined
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antiques</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, and in Back <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lane</ENAMEX> is a large covered market,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Redcap‚Äôs Market</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85</NUMEX>).
        Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back Lane</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An Taisce</ENAMEX>, an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gardens</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appropriately</ENAMEX>, its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is the delightful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tailors‚Äô Hall</ENAMEX>, the
        oldest guild <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, once used by hosier and barber-surgeons‚Äô
        guilds as well as by the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">tailors</ENAMEX>. It dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1706</TIMEX>, and is one of the
        few remaining original <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Anne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Liberties area</ENAMEX>, once a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">slum</ENAMEX>, is rapidly gentrifying,
        with new housing and restoration of the original small red-brick
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">houses</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Patrick‚Äôs Cathedral</ENAMEX>
        At the eastern end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back Lane</ENAMEX> and turning right, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas</ENAMEX>
        Street becomes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Street</ENAMEX>, and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Patrick‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patrick‚Äôs Cathedral</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>). This is the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> site in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dublin‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇSt</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick</ENAMEX> himself is reputed to have baptized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">converts</ENAMEX> on
        this spot (marked by a Celtic cross in the nave), suggesting that there
        has been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> here from around a.d. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">adjoining St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Patrick‚Äôs Park</ENAMEX> is a marker showing the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Patrick‚Äôs Well</ENAMEX>.
        The height and space of the cathedral are impressive. Note
        the carved helmets and swords set above the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">choir stalls</ENAMEX> and the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tiled</ENAMEX> floor, similar to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Christ Church</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>-m
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">300-ft</ENAMEX>) interior makes it the longest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>-m
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">141-ft</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> holds the largest ringing peal of bells in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>. Not
        much is left of the original construction of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1191</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Destroyed</ENAMEX> in a fire
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 14th century</TIMEX>, it was later rebuilt, and even includes some
        Victorian restoration work, though not as extensive as that in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">cathedral</ENAMEX> has had a varied and interesting history, and
        enjoys a lively, friendly rivalry with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Christ Church</ENAMEX>, only a few
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundred yards</NUMEX> away (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Patrick‚</ENAMEX>Äôs is the national cathedral of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1320</TIMEX>, until it was closed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry VIII</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick‚Äôs</ENAMEX> was the seat of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ireland‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>. Cromwellian
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> stabled their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> in the aisles.
        The great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Swift</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1713 to 1745</TIMEX>.
        He was much revered for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> and his championship of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
        cause. You can see his grave and that of his great love, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>, as well as the pulpit from which he preached. On the wall is
        his epitaph, written by himself.
        An interesting artifact from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">medieval chapter house</ENAMEX> is
        a door with a hole in it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hole</ENAMEX> was cut in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1492</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord Kildare</ENAMEX> so
        he could reassure his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archenemy</ENAMEX> Lord <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ormonde</ENAMEX>, who was under siege in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter house</ENAMEX>, of his friendly intentions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kildare</ENAMEX> put his arm
        through the hole, thus giving rise to the common expression ‚Äúto chance
        your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        Also in the close (left from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cathedral exit</ENAMEX>) is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marsh‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>, the first public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1701</TIMEX> and
        holding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 25,000</NUMEX> books. (<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open Monday</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wednesday‚</ENAMEX>ÄìFriday
        10am‚<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Äì12:45pm and 2‚Äì5pm</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30am‚Äì12:45pm</TIMEX>; free, but a voluntary
        contribution is appreciated; ring bell for entrance). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oak</ENAMEX> shelving
        is original, as are the metal cages in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> were locked so as
        to prevent thefts. The on<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">-premises</ENAMEX> bindery repairs and restores old
        books and manuscripts. Even if you aren‚Äôt a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>, do come here‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe
        atmosphere and beauty of the place is entrancing.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgian Dublin</ENAMEX>
        Much of the rich history and surviving architecture of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> comes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> period. It may seem somewhat arbitrary
        to designate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúGeorgian‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇGeorgian</ENAMEX> architecture
        is found all over; however, the harmonious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and squares lying to
        the southeast of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau Street</ENAMEX> truly deserve the title. In addition to
        the superb <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, there are several important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> and galleries
        to visit, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Canal</ENAMEX> provide <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">leafy</TIMEX>, shaded
        walks.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrion Square</ENAMEX>
        Clare Street, at the eastern end of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau Street</ENAMEX>, runs
        into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Merrion Square North</ENAMEX>, where you‚Äôll find some of the finest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>.
        The square dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1762</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> here were the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> of high society,
        including many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous artists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>.
        Look for individual details on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">houses‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe</ENAMEX> painted doors, the
        fanlights, and the door knockers, some in the form of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> or a human
        hand.
        Number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ireland‚Äôs Royal Institute of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Architects</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> displays a permanent exhibition of the best
        work of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>, as well as holding frequent temporary
        exhibitions on all aspects of architecture (open <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monday‚</ENAMEX>ÄìFriday
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30am‚Äì5pm</TIMEX>, closed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sat¬≠urday</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Architectural</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archive</ENAMEX>, a library of architectural materials, is at number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">73</NUMEX> on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">south</ENAMEX> side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>.
        On <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Merrion Square</ENAMEX> West is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>
        (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX>), which provides tickets for free <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">40-minute</TIMEX> tours of the
        restored Government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Buildings</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Upper Merrion Street</ENAMEX> (tours <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday</ENAMEX>
        only from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30am‚Äì3:30pm</TIMEX>; no pre-booking required). Refurbished in
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1990‚Äì1991</NUMEX> and housing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> of the Taoiseach
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>) and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>, the interior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>
        are a fascinating and tasteful combination of the old and the new.
        Along with the latest technology, the prime minister‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> has a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">superb Bossi</ENAMEX> marble fireplace, as well as a fine display of art and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crafts</ENAMEX>.
        A magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evie Hone</ENAMEX> stained-glass window adorns the
        landing in the main entrance; it is beautifully complemented by the
        carpet and balustrade designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>. There is some
        excellent contemporary furniture and a miniature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ois√≠n Kelly‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        sculpture <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Children of Lir</ENAMEX>. Outside, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> is paved in
        limestone tram-setts from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Dublin</ENAMEX>.
        Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Merrion Street</ENAMEX>, next to the front garden of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leinster House</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> collection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Natural History</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX>).
        Enter one of the many gates of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Merrion Square Park</ENAMEX> and walk
        along some of the secret, wooded paths to the immaculately groomed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gardens</ENAMEX>. Don‚Äôt miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Osborne‚</ENAMEX>Äôs statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Wilde</ENAMEX>, wearing a
        smoking jacket with red lapels and reclining on a rock in the northeast
        corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. At the height of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Great Famine</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1845‚</NUMEX>Äì <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1847</TIMEX>, a
        soup <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> was set up here to feed the starving. You‚Äôll want to
        return here to browse the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúBoulevard Galleries‚</ENAMEX>Äù of art set up around
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer weekends</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fitzwilliam Square</ENAMEX> and Ballsbridge
        Take time to stroll down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Merrion Square</ENAMEX>,
        which were laid out at the same time as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>. At the eastern end
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper Mount</ENAMEX> Street you‚Äôll notice the distinctive shape of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>-revival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Stephen‚Äôs Church</ENAMEX>, which dates back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1824</TIMEX>. For
        obvious reasons it is known universally as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúPeppercanister Church‚Äù</ENAMEX>;
        occasional events and concerts are held here. Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fitzwilliam Street</ENAMEX>,
        at the southeast corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Merrion Square</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electricity Supply Board</ENAMEX>. They tried to make up for the ugliness of
        their new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> by restoring Number <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twenty Nine</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>
        representing a typical bourgeois <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of the period (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> crosses Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Baggot Street</ENAMEX> and leads on to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fitzwilliam Square</ENAMEX>, which has a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> open to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> only. The last
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dublin‚Äôs Georgian</ENAMEX> squares to be built, it was completed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1830</TIMEX>,
        although the older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> date back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1714</TIMEX>. Here, as elsewhere in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgian Dublin</ENAMEX>, note the doorways and fanlights, and the ironwork of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">balconies</ENAMEX>.
        Back in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Baggot Street</ENAMEX> is the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> was named after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baggotrath Castle</ENAMEX>, which stood here
        until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 19th century</TIMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Baggot Street Bridge</ENAMEX> you will find the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bord F√°ilte</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Tourist Board</ENAMEX>). If you turn right
        along the towpath of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canal</ENAMEX>, you can chat to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Kavanagh</ENAMEX>,
        sitting on a bench: Actually, it‚Äôs a life-size bronze commemorating the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>, who died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Canal</ENAMEX> was begun in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1755</TIMEX>. The pleasant towpath
        walk, under a canopy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX>, goes past the gardens of terraced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">houses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, and apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. There are plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX>,
        moorhens, and swans and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canal</ENAMEX> is spanned by the very distinctive
        curves of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>. This is a good place to rest and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recuperate</ENAMEX>, and gain a different slant on life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>; you may
        come upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barge Caf√©</ENAMEX>, which travels up and down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canal</ENAMEX>, and
        serves breakfast and brown-bag lunches. If you want more information
        about the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canals</ENAMEX>, you can visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Waterways Visitor Center</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canal Quay</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX>).
        Beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Baggot Street Bridge</ENAMEX> to the east is the suburb of
        Ballsbridge, at the heart of which are the grounds of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Dublin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> where the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerrygold</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Horse Show</ENAMEX> takes place. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> was founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1731</TIMEX>, and established among other things, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Library</ENAMEX>. All sorts of events and
        concerts are held at the showground. On the corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elgin</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pembroke Road</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX>, a curious round <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>,
        conceived by an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North of the River</ENAMEX>
        Dublin north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liffey</ENAMEX> has its own atmosphere and, like
        the southern part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, some magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, and
        Dublin‚Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Crossing O‚ÄôConnell Bridge</ENAMEX>, there are fine views along the
        river: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Custom House</ENAMEX> is on the right and to the left is the equally
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">splendid Four Courts</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1790</TIMEX> and widened until it
        was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">almost square</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1880</TIMEX>. It is difficult to know which direction to
        follow from here.
        Turning left along the quays of the north bank towards the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Courts</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about11‚ÅÑ2 km/1 mile</NUMEX>), you will come to the delightful
        cast-iron footbridge, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ha‚Äôpenny Bridge</ENAMEX>, that connects <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Merchants‚</ENAMEX>Äô
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arch</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Liffey Street</ENAMEX>. It was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1816</TIMEX>, and its name refers to the
        toll once levied for crossing. Looking up river from here, you can see
        the green-topped column of the smock windmill (the largest in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>)
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guinness Brewery</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">spire</ENAMEX> and green roof of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Patrick‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christ Church</ENAMEX> will also come into view, as will the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Audoen‚Äôs</ENAMEX>; and no, you‚Äôre not having a vision‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthat really is a
        statue of a blue- and white-robed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> blessing you from a rooftop
        corner.
        On the corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Liffey Street</ENAMEX> is the sculpture locally
        known as ‚Äúthe hags with the bags. ‚Äù <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> doors down from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> is
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Winding Stair</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bookshop</ENAMEX> and caf√©, which is worth a browse.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Four Courts</ENAMEX> was designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Gandon</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1785</TIMEX> after
        the death of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>. With its magnificent Corinthian
        portico crowned with statues and its columned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is a
        majestic sight. It holds the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, together with
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> of law and a basement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Four Courts</ENAMEX> was damaged
        in the fighting of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX> and a terrific fire destroyed all the
        official archives, but restoration work (in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX>) has removed nearly
        all traces of the destruction. You can step inside when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are
        in session. At the far end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inns Quay</ENAMEX> is the site of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> bridge
        across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liffey</ENAMEX>, which was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1214</TIMEX>.
        Just beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Four Courts</ENAMEX>, turn north into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church Street</ENAMEX>,
        where you‚Äôll find the fascinating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Michan‚Äôs Church</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the
        oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>, it was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX> on the site
        of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chapel</ENAMEX>, but heavily restored in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Handel</ENAMEX> is
        believed to have practiced on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1724</NUMEX> organ here while composing The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messiah</ENAMEX>. The church‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> claim to fame, however, is its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vaults</ENAMEX>,
        which, because of their limestone composition, preserve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> buried
        there in a mummified <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. A few of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> are on display (tours
        Monday‚ÄìFriday <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:45am‚Äì12:45pm and 2‚Äì4:45pm</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10am‚Äì 12:45pm</TIMEX>;
        entrance fee, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> IR¬<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">£1.20</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50p</TIMEX>; go early to avoid group
        tours). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Emmet</ENAMEX> is thought to be buried in the graveyard of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parnell‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral service</ENAMEX> was held here. Afterwards, you
        may well want to drop in at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Old Jameson Distillery</ENAMEX> (see page
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX>) in cobbled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bow Street</ENAMEX>.
        If you turn right instead of left from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">O‚ÄôConnell bridge</ENAMEX>,
        you will come to one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs great architectural masterpieces, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Custom House</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visitor Centre</ENAMEX> open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-March‚</TIMEX>Äìmid-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monday‚</ENAMEX>ÄìFriday
        10am‚<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Äì5pm</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday 2pm‚Äì5pm</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wednesday‚</ENAMEX>ÄìFriday only).
        Built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1791</TIMEX> and designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Gandon</ENAMEX> as his first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">masterpiece</ENAMEX>, it has undergone thorough renovation and can perhaps be
        best appreciated from the south <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> of the river, though more detail
        can be seen from the closer vantage point on the north <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>.
        The elegance and grace of this building have something to
        do with its human dimensions, for although it stands <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">114 m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">375 ft</ENAMEX>)
        high and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">61 m</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 ft</ENAMEX>) wide, its height does not in the least
        overwhelm. The sculpture on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> (a personification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>)
        and the river gods (including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Livia</ENAMEX>, set over the main door) are
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Smyth</ENAMEX>, who was also responsible for the statues on the GPO
        (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX>). The original wax models of the river gods are on display
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Civic Museum</ENAMEX>. The north side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> has statues by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Banks</ENAMEX> depicting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
        Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and east along the quay is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Famine Memorial</ENAMEX>, a series of striking life-size bronze figures by Rowan
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gillespie</ENAMEX>.
        O‚ÄôConnell Street
        O‚ÄôConnell Street is a grand <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">boulevard</ENAMEX> with a wide central
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island</ENAMEX>, studded with monuments and statues. It runs in a straight line
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">north</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">O‚ÄôConnell Bridge</ENAMEX>, and the best way to view it is to walk
        down the central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>, making excursions to the left and right at the
        zebra crossings.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> was largely destroyed in the Rising (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>),
        but was restored by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 1920s</TIMEX> (plans for a new restoration
        are under way). At the foot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Foley‚</ENAMEX>Äôs monument to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel O‚ÄôConnell</ENAMEX>, surrounded by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> victory figures and peppered with
        bullet holes from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Livia Fountain</ENAMEX> (nicknamed the ‚ÄúFloozie
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacuzzi‚Äù</ENAMEX>) was unveiled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> as part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs millennial
        celebrations; it refers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Joyce‚</ENAMEX>Äôs personification of the Liffey
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Finnegan‚Äôs Wake</ENAMEX>, and across the way, in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Earl Street</ENAMEX>, his statue by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marjorie Fitzgibbon</ENAMEX> jauntily regards it. The memorial to working-class
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, orator, and socialist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Larkin by Ois√≠n Kelly</ENAMEX> is opposite the
        famous chiming clock of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clerys</ENAMEX>, the largest department store in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>. Farther up on the right is one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dublin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gresham Hotel</ENAMEX> which was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1817</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> before the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shelbourne</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> interior of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ground floor</ENAMEX> is worth a
        look.
        Perhaps the most memorable monument in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Post Office</ENAMEX> in the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">O‚ÄôConnell Street</ENAMEX> (open
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Monday‚ÄìSaturday 8am‚Äì 8pm</ENAMEX>). Built in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1815‚Äì1818</NUMEX> and one of the last great
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dublin‚Äôs Georgian</ENAMEX> architecture, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPO</ENAMEX> is justly renowned
        for its imposing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ionic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">portico</ENAMEX> (look for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet</ENAMEX> holes) with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
        fluted columns and figures sculpted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Smyth</ENAMEX>. It was here, in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1916</TIMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Connolly</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Padr√°ig Pearse</ENAMEX> barricaded themselves
        inside and proclaimed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irish Republic</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> was virtually
        destroyed in the fighting but has since been fully restored. The Rising
        is commemorated in the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> by a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bronze</ENAMEX> statue of the
        mythic folk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cuchulainn</ENAMEX>.
        Just off Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">O‚ÄôConnell Street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lower Abbey Street</ENAMEX> is
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Abbey Theatre</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX>). Founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.B. Yeats</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusta Gregory</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Martyn</ENAMEX>, the theater has been a showcase for
        great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> writing. The early works of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean O‚</ENAMEX>ÄôCasey and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Synge</ENAMEX>
        were written for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey</ENAMEX>. The present <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey Theatre</ENAMEX> dates from from
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>, since a fire in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX> destroyed the original <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North of the Abbey Theatre</ENAMEX> and parallel with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">O‚</ENAMEX>ÄôConnell
        Street in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Marlborough Street</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Catholic St. Mary‚Äôs Pro-Cathedral</ENAMEX>,
        the main <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> parish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> of the city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1816-1825</TIMEX>.
        Its somewhat forbidding classical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doric exterior</ENAMEX> seems to dwarf the
        street (it was designed originally for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">O‚ÄôConnell Street</ENAMEX>). The domed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> interior is in restrained blues and grays, and is curiously
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unadorned</ENAMEX>. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestrina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> that sings mass on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> is
        excellent, and attracts numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.
        Opposite the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">cathedral</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyrone House</ENAMEX> (not open to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">public</ENAMEX>), home to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Education</ENAMEX>. Built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1742</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle</ENAMEX>, the interior features work by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francini</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> (also
        responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newman House</ENAMEX>). Outside is a gift to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in gratitude for relief supplies
        during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>: a marble <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piet√</ENAMEX>† entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">La Deposizione</ENAMEX>, by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ermenegildo Luppi</ENAMEX>.
        It is worth making a detour on the pedestrianized areas of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Henry Street</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moore Street</ENAMEX>, to see their famous markets and hear the
        cries of the stallholders (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">83</NUMEX>). Expect some ribald remarks in
        broad <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> accents.
        At the northern end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX> monument to
        Parnell by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augustus Saint-Gaudens</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> anything odd? Yes, he is
        wearing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> overcoats (apparently he always did).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parnell Square</ENAMEX>
        Compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> squares south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liffey</ENAMEX>, the
        area around <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Parnell Square</ENAMEX> looks rather shabby, but once it was just as
        fashionable and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">affluent</ENAMEX>. On the south side of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Parnell Square</ENAMEX> are the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotunda Hospital</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate Theatre</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palladian</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rotunda</ENAMEX> was
        built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Castle</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1751‚Äì1755</NUMEX>; it‚Äôs Europe‚Äôs oldest maternity
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">chapel</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> floor, with stained-glass windows and
        Rococo plasterwork, has had a varied career as an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Assembly Room</ENAMEX> and a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cinema</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Dickens</ENAMEX> also gave readings here. What is now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gate</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX>) was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1784</TIMEX> and is probably the most
        beautiful stage in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater company</ENAMEX> was founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX> by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Micha√©l MacLiamm√≥ir</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilton Edwards</ENAMEX>, and is still going strong
        today, with an excellent reputation for international and innovative
        work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Mason</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orson Welles</ENAMEX> began their acting careers here.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Garden</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Remembrance</TIMEX> on the north side of Parnell
        Square is dedicated to those who lost their lives in the cause of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX> and features a cruciform lake and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Ois√≠n Kelly‚</ENAMEX>Äôs beautiful
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lir</ENAMEX>.
        Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Garden</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Remembrance</TIMEX> are the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Lane</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Municipal Gallery</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Art</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writers Museum</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> is set in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th-century</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charlemont House</ENAMEX>, built for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlemont</ENAMEX> by Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Chambers</ENAMEX>.
        Restored in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, this hand¬≠some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is worth seeing for itself
        alone, as well as for the splendid art collection. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writers Museum</ENAMEX>
        next door (also restored in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>) is an intriguing combination of
        Georgian exterior with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> interior. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> have
        good caf√©s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East of Parnell Square</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great George‚Äôs Street</ENAMEX>, is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Joyce Cultural Center</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX>), housed in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> dating
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1784</TIMEX> and run by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joyce‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX>. It has a full program of events,
        including lectures.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix Park</ENAMEX>
        On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liffey</ENAMEX>, just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 miles</NUMEX>) from the
        bustle of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">O‚ÄôConnell Street</ENAMEX>, lies the biggest urban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>,
        comprising <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">some 709 hectares</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,750 acres</NUMEX>) of landscaped gardens,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">woods</ENAMEX>, pastures, and playing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX> for all sorts of sports. The park
        is a graceful and elegant expanse with fine views of the mountains,
        much loved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dubliners</ENAMEX> since it was first opened to the public in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1747</TIMEX>. Self-guided heritage walks and several nature <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> are marked
        by black information plaques.
        The oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashtown Castle</ENAMEX>, a
        former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">papal</ENAMEX> residence which has been renovated to house the splendid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix Park Visitor Centre</ENAMEX> (open <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30am‚Äì 6:30pm</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> IR¬<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">£2</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IR¬</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">£1</NUMEX>; concessions; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled</ENAMEX> access), which presents a video and an
        excellent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-floor exhibition on the history and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wildlife</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> itself comprises <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an early 17th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower house</ENAMEX>, restored
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oak</ENAMEX> from the park which is held together without a single
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nail</ENAMEX>. Outside there is a young garden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">maze</ENAMEX>, marking the outline of the
        original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX>, and a restful caf√©.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> also boasts the tallest obelisk in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">67-m</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">220-ft</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wellington Monument</ENAMEX>, erected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1861</TIMEX> after the victory of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waterloo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wicklow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">granite</ENAMEX> is faced with plaques <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> from captured
        and melted-down cannon. Not quite as large is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papal Cross</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commemorating Pope John Paul II‚Äôs</ENAMEX> visit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> gathered to celebrate mass.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix Column</ENAMEX>, dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1747</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> near the
        natural spring from which the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> is derived (the result
        of an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> corruption of the Gaelic fionn uisce, meaning ‚Äúclear
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">water‚Äù</ENAMEX>).
        Occupying <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than 12 hectares</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 acres</NUMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin Zoo</ENAMEX>
        (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX>) was founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1831</TIMEX>, and has greatly improved in recent
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>; there are plans for a complete renovation. The landscaped
