
  
  
    
      
        WHERE TO GO
        Planning an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> vacation entails a series of difficult
        decisions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äú Doing‚Äù Italy</ENAMEX> is a lifetime job, and many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX> are so
        in love with the place that they won‚Äôt even think of an alternative
        destination. After a predictable <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> romance with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>, or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florence</ENAMEX>, they spend the rest of their lives systematically working
        their way through the small but wildly varied <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, region by
        region, visit after visit. If this is your <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trip, you‚Äôll do well
        to establish an overall impression. If the seduction works, and it
        usually does, you‚Äôll want to come back time and again.
        This section includes all the most important <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> and
        regions to help you make your choice. Each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> areas has a
        principal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> as a focus or starting point: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> for central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>,
        plus <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sardinia</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Umbria</ENAMEX>, and the Adriatic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seaside</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> to the east; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veneto</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolomites</ENAMEX>, and
        Emilia‚Äôs historic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parma</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ravenna</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lombardy</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riviera</ENAMEX> to the west; and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX> for the south
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sicily</ENAMEX>.
        Given the sheer and unrivaled richness of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, the
        selection of places within those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> areas is not in any way
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exhaustive</ENAMEX> (nor, by the same token, exhausting). Those who already know
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> will inevitably feel that a few of their favorite spots have
        been neglected (though they may also be grateful to not have their
        secret exposed), while they‚Äôll find others they never heard of.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Newcomers</ENAMEX> will have an embarrassment of destinations to choose
        from.
        Depending on how much time you have for that all-important
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> taste, we suggest you try to visit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX>, even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX>. Those with a passion for the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> can combine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rome</ENAMEX>
        with the artistic delights of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magical</ENAMEX> romance of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>. For many, the key to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Italy‚Äôs Mediterranean</ENAMEX>
        soul is to be found in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX> and the south. After the intense emotion
        and summertime heat spells (air conditioning is not always available),
        cool off at the seaside <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Riviera</ENAMEX> or any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gem</ENAMEX>-like
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">islands</ENAMEX>.
        The trick is in the mix. Not just geographically, in
        exploring the variety and contrasts of north and south, but in
        combining the attractions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and countryside and the resultingly
        different facets of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italy‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life. Nowhere is it easier or more
        delightful to overdose on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> and monuments than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>. A dear
        old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> returned from her first visit with the observation: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúItaly‚Äôs</ENAMEX>
        very nice, very nice indeed, but for my taste, much too much history. ‚Äù
        While it would be a crime to ignore the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, palazzos, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>
        chronicling the unparalleled glories of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italy‚</ENAMEX>Äôs history, the best way
        to enjoy them is also to spend plenty of time soaking it in from a
        front-row seat in a caf√©, or from under a canvas beach umbrella
        watching seaside life unfold. The siesta is one of the greatest of all
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, and the most important <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> expression you may
        ever learn is dolce far niente (the sweetness of doing nothing).
        Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> cannot manage to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> outside the major
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX> periods‚<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇEaster</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>. But if your options are
        more flexible, the most enjoyable (though equally crowded) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> are
        May, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">October‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇespecially</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX>. Certainly, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> can be almost unbearably hot and
        humid in most big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, but some find an odd, ghostly pleasure in
        being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferragosto</ENAMEX> (on and around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 August</TIMEX>) when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">abandoned ‚Äúto the cats</ENAMEX> and the crazy. ‚Äù And remember, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> make no
        bones about public <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">233</NUMEX>); they just close the whole
        country down.
        Getting Around
        Even the most free-spirited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> can use a little help
        occasionally. With the tourist industry such a vital factor in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> has an elaborate network of information <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bureaucrats being bureaucrats</ENAMEX>, efficiency and amiability vary from
        place to place, but the tourist information <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> all provide useful
        maps and brochures.
        For general information, the state tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> ENIT
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ente Nazionale Italiano per il Turismo</ENAMEX>) has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in major foreign
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> as well as regional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX>. When in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, look instead for
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APT</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azienda di Promozione Turistica</ENAMEX>) for more detailed regional
        sightseeing information; they occasionally help as well with hotel and
        camping accommodation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIT</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compagnia Italiana di Turismo</ENAMEX>) is a
        national travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> for transportation, excursions, and hotel
        bookings.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Travel Tips</ENAMEX> section at the back of the book (see page
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">217</NUMEX>) gives detailed practical guidance on the technicalities of travel
        through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, but here are some general thoughts to help you plan your
        trip.
        Major journeys from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to another,
        say, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> or down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX>, is most enjoyed by train
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> with plenty of time, patience, and curiosity. The
        uncertainties of schedules and frequency of strike action gradually
        disappeared in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, but the occasional wrinkle still needs to be
        ironed out. If you are making a long rail journey, don‚Äôt rely on the
        generally dreary dining-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>. Make up your own picnic hamper of
        cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meats</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> from the local
        market before you get aboard. Very often, you end up sharing it with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> who offer in exchange their own homemade
        goodies.
        The great breathtaking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> adventure remains the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>.
        The autostrada (toll motorway or expressway) runs the length and
        breadth of the peninsula, a challenge to the imagination and survival
        instincts of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> civilization. Only to the uninitiated do Italian
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> seem dangerous. Most of them are highly skillful‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthey have to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">be‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> proud of their reflexes. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX> to avoid: recklessness
        and excessive caution. Don‚Äôt try to match their improvisations, you
        will only raise their competitive spirit into the realm of high risk.
        They may be similarly provoked by indecisive and slow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>.
        Keep your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for use on the open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. In the overcrowded
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, just drop your bags off at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, and then park your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
        To see the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, you should walk, take a bus, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX>, or rent a
        bike. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> have solved the problem for you by closing off their
        historical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> (centro storico) to traffic: Consider that your
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rental</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> will cost you money while remaining unused albeit safely
        parked.
        Try to vary the kind of places that you stay in. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> has
        all types of accommodations available, so you‚Äôll have quite a few
        choices. Small family-run hostelries and country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">inns</ENAMEX> are charming,
        but, depending of course on your budget and personal preferences,
        consider indulging for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least one night</TIMEX> on the special comforts and
        pampering of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>. Look for converted monasteries and
        countryside farmhouses. In most cases the frugality has long gone, the
        heating is modern, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">medieval well</ENAMEX> has been replaced by a
        swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pool</ENAMEX>, but the setting is still memorable.
        Even if you‚Äôre a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">linguistic dud</ENAMEX>, try to learn a handful of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> words or expressions. The pronunciation is remarkably easy and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> are usually delighted by anyone making the effort. A
        cheerful buon giorno (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">good day</TIMEX>) or buona sera (good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>) can work
        wonders when entering or leaving a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>. In a land where
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">politeness</ENAMEX> is important, per favore (please), grazie (thank you), prego
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">don‚</NUMEX>Äôt mention it), and, when pushing through a bus or market, permesso
        (excuse me) will be greatly appreciated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find some additional
        phrases beginning on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">218</NUMEX>. Now enjoy it, buon viaggio!
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CENTRAL ITALY</ENAMEX>
        The center of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> is the cradle of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> civilization,
        one-time administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of that ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX> known
        as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>. Immediately surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, today‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lazio</ENAMEX> is the
        ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latium</ENAMEX>. On the eastern flank of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apennines</ENAMEX>, the
        Abruzzi region, of which the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molise</ENAMEX> is a recently created
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">offshoot</ENAMEX>, came under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> domination in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third century</TIMEX> b.c.
        First-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> will understandably want to spend most or all of
        their time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, but the area surrounding the capital makes a
        pleasant excursion within fairly easy reach of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> for those
        adventurers with wheels and extra time.
        The rugged island of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sardinia</ENAMEX> deserves <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a week</TIMEX> to
        do it justice, but you may want to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long weekend</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of its
        attractive little seaside <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>
        Crowning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> hills along the winding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">River</ENAMEX>
        Tiber, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> has numerous different personalities: ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imperial ruins; Catholic Rome</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vatican City</ENAMEX> and countless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>;
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baroque of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernini</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Borromini</ENAMEX>; and a modern metropolis of interminable traffic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jams</ENAMEX>, fashionable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX> and caf√©s, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> and
        characterless apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that make up the post-war eye-sore
        suburbs.
        None is easily separable from the others. The secret of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eternal City‚</ENAMEX>Äôs magic is that it lives and relishes all its ages
        simultaneously. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Churches</ENAMEX> are commonly built on the ruins of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> baths
        or pagan temples. The trendy caf√© <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piazza Navona</ENAMEX> draw natural
        inspiration from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernini‚</ENAMEX>Äôs grandiose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX> fountain.
        Ease yourself into this magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that has hosted
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> for millenia. To know its every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crook</ENAMEX> and cranny is a daunting
        challenge, but concentrate on the ancient city around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colosseum</ENAMEX> or
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican‚</ENAMEX>Äôs formidable complex, and come to know one age at a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>
        Make an early start with breakfast (or come back for a late
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon ap√©ritif</TIMEX>) on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piazza del Popolo</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caff√® Rosati</ENAMEX>, a veritable
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> and historical meeting-place of the city‚Äôs literary
        personalities. Its outdoor tables are a perfect vantage point for
        admiring the gracefully curving piazza, an exemplary piece of open-air
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> theater designed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1816</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuseppe Valadier</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX>.
        On the north side, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Maria del Popolo</ENAMEX> is
        important for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Raphael‚Äôs Chigi Chapel</ENAMEX>, exquisite frescoes by
        Pincuricchio, and, above all, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> profoundly disturbing early
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX> paintings by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caravaggio</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Conversion</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Paul</ENAMEX> and
        Crucifixion of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Peter</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cerasi Chapel</ENAMEX> left of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX>.
        Next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, an arched <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16th-century</TIMEX> gateway marks
        what was the entrance to ancient and medieval <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via</ENAMEX>
        Flaminia, leading from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rimini</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Adriatic</ENAMEX> coast. The obelisk in the
        piazza‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, dating from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rameses II</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13th century</TIMEX> b.c.
        ), was brought here from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circus Maximus</ENAMEX> and re-erected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sixtus V</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1589</TIMEX>. Rounding off the south side are the twin Baroque
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">churches</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Maria dei Miracoli</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Maria</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montesanto</ENAMEX>,
        completed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gianlorenzo Bernini</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlo</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fontana</ENAMEX>.
        Above the piazza to the east, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pincio</ENAMEX> gardens offer a
        magical view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, especially at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">sunset</ENAMEX>. (For the great art
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Villa</ENAMEX> Borghese park behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pincio</ENAMEX>, see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX>. ) The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ascending Pincio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promenade</ENAMEX> lined with umbrella pine <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> takes you
        past the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Villa Medici</ENAMEX>, home of many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> visiting on national
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scholarships</ENAMEX>, to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinit√† dei Monti</ENAMEX>.
        Its twin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">belfries</ENAMEX> loom over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> Steps (Scalinata
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">della Trinit√† dei Monti</ENAMEX>), eternal hang-out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rome‚</ENAMEX>Äôs golden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lovers</ENAMEX>, peddlers of trinkets and the occasional hustler. The pleasant
        daze induced on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-tiered travertine staircase, festooned in
        spring with pink azaleas, was celebrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Keats</ENAMEX> as a ‚Äúblissful
        cloud of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">summer indolence‚Äù</TIMEX> before he died here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1821</TIMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at
        the bottom of the steps has been preserved as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>.
        Named after a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> used as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX>, the
        famous steps and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piazza di Spagna</ENAMEX> are the heart of the city‚Äôs most
        fashionable and exclusive shopping enclave, leading to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via del</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corso</ENAMEX>. The piazza‚Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX> sunken<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-boat</ENAMEX>-shaped marble fountain,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fontana della Barcaccia</ENAMEX>, is by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">great Bernini‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. The nearby
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">venerable Babington‚Äôs Tea Rooms</ENAMEX> are a relic of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when Romans
        called the piazza the ‚ÄúEnglish ghetto. ‚Äù More <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quintessentially</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX>,
        on nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Condotti</ENAMEX>, is the city‚Äôs oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Caff√® Greco‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇpopular</ENAMEX>, as you‚Äôll see from pictures, busts,
        and autographs, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goethe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baudelaire, Liszt, Casanova</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fellini</ENAMEX>.
        This is the general area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trevi Fountain</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fontana di</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trevi</ENAMEX>) which benefited from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fellini‚</ENAMEX>Äôs keen sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baroque</ENAMEX> aesthetics
        when he dipped the dazzling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Ekberg</ENAMEX> in its legendarily purifying
        waters for his film <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">La Dolce Vita</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs been quite some time since
        anyone was caught romping in these waters reflecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicola Salvi‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        astounding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th-century</TIMEX> fountain. It is in fact a triumphal arch and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">palace fa√ßade</ENAMEX> (to the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palazzo Poli</ENAMEX>) framing mythic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> in a
        riot of rocks and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX>, with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rearing horse</ENAMEX> symbolizing the ocean‚Äôs
        turmoil and a calmer steed its tranquility. Tucked away behind narrow
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alleys</ENAMEX>, this recently restored extravaganza is out of all proportion to
        its tiny piazza and no amount of signposts leading to it can prepare
        you for the marvellous shock of discovery. Romantics go at the dead of
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, to be alone with its illumination. It‚Äôs a favorite haunt for
        local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX> looking for foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innocents</ENAMEX> abroad. Tradition dictates
        a toss of a coin over your shoulder to ensure a return trip.
        That other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">la dolce vita</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Veneto</ENAMEX>, has
        been deserted by its starlets and paparazzi and only the expensive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">caf√©s</ENAMEX>, once stylish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, and five-star <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> remain. Slowly, it is
        making something of a comeback in popularity.
        On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> hills of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fortress-like Palazzo del Quirinale</ENAMEX>, once summer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> to popes
        fleeing the malarial swamps of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> down by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiber</ENAMEX>, housed
        the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1870</TIMEX>, and since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> is the presidential
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">palace</ENAMEX>. The only embellishment on its formidable fa√ßade is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernini‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        graceful porch, but its piazza is worth the climb for the view over the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vatican</ENAMEX>.
        You couldn‚Äôt miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piazza Venezia</ENAMEX> if you tried‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand many do
        try, because of its endless traffic jams and the arguably ungainly
        white marble <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vittorio Emanuele Monument</ENAMEX>. The monument celebrates the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of unified <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tomb of the Unknown Soldier</ENAMEX>
        with inimitable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pomposity</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> of the monument, the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palazzo Venezia</ENAMEX> is a fine example of severe but elegant
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early Renaissance</TIMEX> architecture, now containing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> of medieval and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> arms, furniture, and sculpture. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX> had his office
        there and harangued his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> from the balcony.
        Beside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piazza Venezia</ENAMEX>, a steep staircase leads up to
        the austere <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Maria</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aracoeli</ENAMEX>, while another, more
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">graceful</ENAMEX> and gradual, takes you up between the statues of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castor</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollux</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michelangelo‚</ENAMEX>Äôs beautifully proportioned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campidoglio</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitoline Hill</ENAMEX>). This quiet traffic-free haven forges a
        superb link between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> and ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rome‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most sacred
        site, where sacrifices were made to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juno</ENAMEX>. The grand bronze
        equestrian statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus Aurelius</ENAMEX> that anchors the piazza‚Äôs center
        is a copy; the restored original from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second century</TIMEX> a.d. is
        sheltered within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palazzo Nuovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> to its left. Opposite stands
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palazzo dei Conservatori</ENAMEX>, and at the rear of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> is the
        handsome <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fa√ßade</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palazzo Senatorio</ENAMEX> (now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall</ENAMEX>). These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> palazzos house the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capitoline Museums</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX>),
        whose <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> collections provide an excellent introduction to
        the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Forum</ENAMEX> that spreads below it.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ges√π</ENAMEX>, severe and relatively discreet on
        its own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> west of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piazza Venezia</ENAMEX>, was a major element in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuits‚Äô Counter-Reformation</ENAMEX> campaign. Begun as their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúheadquarters‚Äù</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1568</TIMEX>, its open ground plan was the model for the
        Congregational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> that were to regain popular support from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> faith. While its fa√ßade is more sober than the exultant
        Baroque <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> put up as the movement gained momentum, the interior
        glorifies the new militancy in gleaming <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bronze</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, marble, and
        precious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX>. Perhaps inevitably, the church‚Äôs most elaborate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ornament</ENAMEX> is the altar of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Ignatius Loyola</ENAMEX>, covering the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> of the
        Jesuits‚Äô <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Spanish</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> in the left transept. Its profusion of lapis
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lazuli</ENAMEX> is actually a thin shell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fused</ENAMEX> to plaster stucco.
        In gentler contrast, the nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sant‚</ENAMEX>ÄôIgnazio
        stands in an enchanting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rococo</ENAMEX> stage-set of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>.
        Inside, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Pozzo</ENAMEX> (himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jesuit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">saint‚Äôs</ENAMEX> tomb at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ges√π</ENAMEX>) has painted a superb trompe l‚Äôoeil ceiling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fresco</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1685</TIMEX>) depicting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Ignatius‚</ENAMEX>Äô entry into paradise.
        The circular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pantheon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piazza della Rotonda</ENAMEX>) is the
        best-preserved monument of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals the Colosseum</ENAMEX> in its
        combination of quiet elegance and sheer massive power. Built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadrian</ENAMEX> around a.d. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX> on an earlier site destroyed by fire, it
        achieved a marvel of engineering with its magnificent coffered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX>:
        over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43 m</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">141 ft</ENAMEX>) in interior diameter (larger than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Peter‚Äôs</ENAMEX>),
        exactly equal to its height. Bronze that once embellished the entrance
        was carted away and recycled as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernini‚</ENAMEX>Äôs canopy for the high altar in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Peter‚Äôs.</ENAMEX> This ‚ÄúTemple of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gods‚Äù</ENAMEX> today contains the tombs of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael</ENAMEX> as well as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vittorio Emanuele II</ENAMEX> and his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Umberto I.</ENAMEX>
        Caravaggio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> will find some of his greatest
        masterpieces right in the neighborhood: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX> trilogy in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fine Baroque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Luigi dei Francesi</ENAMEX>, and the moving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pilgrims</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sant‚ÄôAgostino.</ENAMEX>
        Pause now at a caf√© in that most serene of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> squares,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piazza Navona</ENAMEX>. Nowhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> is the spectacle of Italian street
        life more pleasantly indulged, thanks to an inspired collaboration of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> across the ages. The elongated oval piazza was laid out
        around a.d. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">79</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domitian</ENAMEX> as an athletics <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circus</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agonalis‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa</ENAMEX> sporting tradition continued in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Middle Ages</TIMEX> with
        jousting tournaments and other events in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> that followed.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The 17th century</TIMEX> contributed its <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sublime Baroque d√©cor</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it is
        protected as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rome‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernini‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        Fountain of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Four Rivers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fontana dei Fiumi</ENAMEX>) celebrates the great
        rivers of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> continents: the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Americas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R√≠o de la Plata</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Danube</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ganges</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nile</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Romans</ENAMEX> who delight in
        Bernini‚Äôs scorn for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">the Nile god</ENAMEX> covers his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> rather than look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borromini‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sant‚</ENAMEX>ÄôAgnese in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Agone</ENAMEX>,
        and the river god of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Americas</ENAMEX> is poised to catch it in case it
        collapses. In fact, the fountain was completed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> before
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Borromini‚Äôs splendid‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand structurally impeccable‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇfa√ßade</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dome</ENAMEX>.
        A large and boisterous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>, vegetable and flower market
        takes place every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campo dei Fiori</ENAMEX>, overseen by the
        statue of philosopher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giordano Bruno</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counter Reformation</ENAMEX> burned
        him alive here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1600</TIMEX> for his preposterous idea that the universe was
        infinite, with many more galaxies than ours. An even more famous death
        occurred at the nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Piazza del Biscione</ENAMEX>, more precisely the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">restaurant Da Pancrazio</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cellar shelters</ENAMEX> ruins of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pompeii‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        Theater where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius Caesar</ENAMEX> was assassinated.
        Only with a special appointment can you visit the glorious
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palazzo Farnese</ENAMEX>, built by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio da Sangallo the Younger</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giacomo della Porta</ENAMEX>. Begun in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1514</TIMEX>, it now houses the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX>. Only the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rome‚</ENAMEX>Äôs finest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">palace</ENAMEX> is accessible to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, but its grand <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">portico</ENAMEX> and the
        handsome stuccoed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vestibule</ENAMEX> leading to it make it well worth a visit. A
        privileged few get in to see the ceremonial dining room‚Äôs fabulous
        frescoes by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annibale Carracci</ENAMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1871</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> pay a rent of one
        lira <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> and provide a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italy‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX>.
        Narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> southeast of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campo</ENAMEX> de‚Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiori</ENAMEX> take you to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ghetto</ENAMEX> near the ruins of the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Theater</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcellus</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teatro di Marcello</ENAMEX>), architectural model for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colosseum</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> have been a permanent feature of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> life for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 2,500</NUMEX> years
        but were forced into a ghetto in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX>. A small <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> still lives nearby around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via del Portico d‚ÄôOttavia.</ENAMEX> The
        hefty neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX> (inaugurated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904</TIMEX>), with a small
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> history next door, is by the river <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classical Rome</ENAMEX>
        The nucleus of classical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> is around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colosseum</ENAMEX>, with
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX> to the northwest and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baths of Caracalla</ENAMEX> to the south.
        Don‚Äôt be daunted‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇeven the best-informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> find the monumental
        relics difficult to decipher‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe mystery itself is more than half the
        charm of these vestiges of a vanished world. Take them in your stride,
        avoid the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midday</TIMEX> sun in the shadeless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>, and finish your visit with
        a picnic and siesta on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palatine</ENAMEX>. Even if you‚Äôre not an archaeology
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buff</ENAMEX> who wants to understand the meaning of every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>, it‚Äôs worth at
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">least an hour</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to stand among the debris of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> and wonder
        whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifth Avenue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Piccadilly</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Champs-Elys√©es</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Square</ENAMEX>
        will look any better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,000 years from now</TIMEX>.
        Of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rome‚</ENAMEX>Äôs countless inspirational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> and palazzos, it
        is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Colosseum‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwhat Byron</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúthe gladiator‚</ENAMEX>Äôs bloody
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">circus‚Äù‚Äîthat</ENAMEX> is the symbol of the city‚Äôs eternity. Built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 80</TIMEX>,
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-tiered elliptical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">amphitheater</ENAMEX> seated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectators</ENAMEX>.
        Flowing in and out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> arched passageways known as vomitoria,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aristocrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plebs</ENAMEX> alike came to see <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bears</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX>,
        and leopards starved into fighting each other and against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>,
        war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captives</ENAMEX>, and (according to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>.
        Gladiators, once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and slaves but later professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX>,
        fought one another to the crowds‚Äô cries of Jugula! (‚ÄúSlit his throat! ‚Äù
        ).
        For their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> and private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">popes</ENAMEX> and princes
        have stripped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colosseum</ENAMEX> of its precious marble, travertine, and
        metal. In the arena‚Äôs basin, they have left a ruined maze of cells and
        corridors that funnelled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX> to the slaughter. The horror
        has disappeared beneath the moss and what remains is the thrill of the
        monument‚Äôs endurance. As an old Anglo-Saxon prophecy goes: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚ÄúWhile</ENAMEX>
        stands the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Colosseum, Rome</ENAMEX> shall stand; when falls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colosseum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>
        shall <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX>; and when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> falls, with it shall fall the world. ‚Äù There
        is reason to believe it shall stand forever, a massive top-to-toe
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restoration</ENAMEX> completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> has it looking rejuvenated and
        soot-free.
        The nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constantine</ENAMEX> celebrates the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor‚</ENAMEX>Äôs battlefield conversion to Christianity. A
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cost-conscious Senate</ENAMEX> took fragments from monuments of earlier rulers
        Trajan, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hadrian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus Aurelius</ENAMEX> to decorate the arch.
        Immediately northeast of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colosseum</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domus Aurea</ENAMEX>,
        the fabulous villa with extensive gardens built by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nero</ENAMEX>,
        who spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just a few years</TIMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚ÄúGolden House‚Äù</ENAMEX> before killing himself
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 68</TIMEX>. It was reopened to the public in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> of
        renovation work. On a site once <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> times the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colosseum</ENAMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX>-room <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> can be visited, and by guided tour
        only.
        With an exhilarating leap of the imagination, you can stand
        among the columns, arches, and porticoes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Forum</ENAMEX> and picture
        the civic, commercial, and religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hub</ENAMEX> of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, the first
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> to house <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX>. Earthquake, fire, flood, and
        the plunder of barbarians and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> reduced the area
        to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">muddy cow</ENAMEX> pasture until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the excavations of the 19th century</TIMEX>.
        Today, a detailed map and portable sound-guides rented at the entrance
        (on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via dei Fori Imperiali</ENAMEX>) will make sense of the apparent
        confusion and help you trace the layout of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>, temples, and market
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">halls</ENAMEX>.
        Part of the brick-built <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Curia</ENAMEX>, home of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Senate</ENAMEX>,
        still stands. Steps nearby lead underground to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lapis Niger</ENAMEX>, a black
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marble pavement</ENAMEX> laid by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius Caesar</ENAMEX> over the presumed grave of
        Romulus, the city‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>. To the south of it are remains of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Basilica Julia</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rostra</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">orators‚Äô platform</ENAMEX> from which
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Antony</ENAMEX> informed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesar‚</ENAMEX>Äôs assassination. Countless
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baroque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sculptors</ENAMEX> have drawn inspiration from the
        friezes on the triple <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Septimius Severus</ENAMEX> (honoring a
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> who died in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, the northernmost
        boundary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX> doubled as state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">treasury</ENAMEX> and center
        of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">debauchery</ENAMEX> known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturnalia</ENAMEX>, pagan precursor of
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. In the circular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple of Vesta</ENAMEX>, the sacred flame
        perpetuating the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> was tended by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vestal Virgins</ENAMEX> who, from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">childhood</ENAMEX>, observed a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year</TIMEX> vow of chastity on fear of being buried
        alive if they broke it. At the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Sacra</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titus</ENAMEX>
        commemorates the sack of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> in a.d. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>.
        Most impressive monument of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Imperial Forums</ENAMEX>, built as
        an adjunct to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Forum</ENAMEX> in honor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius Caesar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augustus</ENAMEX>,
        Trajan, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vespasian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domitian</ENAMEX>, is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>-m- (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100-ft-</ENAMEX>) high Trajan‚Äôs
        Column (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">a.d. 113</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebrating Trajan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs campaigns against the Dacians
        in what is now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Romania</ENAMEX>, the minutely detailed friezes spiraling around
        the column constitute a veritable textbook of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> warfare utilizing
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 2,500</NUMEX> figures. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Peter‚</ENAMEX>Äôs statue on top replaced that of the
        emperor‚Äôs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1587</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South of the Roman Forum</ENAMEX>, a slope leads up to the Palatine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rome‚</ENAMEX>Äôs legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> a romantic garden, dotted
        with toppled columns among the wild <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and spiny acanthus <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">shrubs</ENAMEX>.
        Only rows of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cypress trees</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pavilions</ENAMEX> remain from the more
        formal botanical gardens laid out here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX> by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farnese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. A small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> reopened here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. From its grassy
        knolls, enjoy the fine view back over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colosseum</ENAMEX> or southward over
        the great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circus Maximus</ENAMEX>, where chariot races were held for crowds of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 200,000</NUMEX>.
        A <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kilometer</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about half a mile</NUMEX>) south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colosseum</ENAMEX>, the
        huge <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Baths of Caracalla</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terme di Caracalla</ENAMEX>) were built
        for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to bathe in considerable style and luxury. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX>
        and gymnasia were of alabaster and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">granite</ENAMEX>, decorated with statues and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frescoes</ENAMEX>. Public bathing was a prolonged social event as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> passed from the calidarium (hot <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>) to cool down in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tepidarium</ENAMEX> and frigidarium. Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> the stage for spectacular
        open-air operas in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>, the calidarium was vast enough for the
        unique setting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Verdi‚Äôs ‚ÄúAida‚Äù</ENAMEX> and its processions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX>,
        camels, and endless cast. Rumors persist that the performances will
        resume again: stay tuned.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX> begins the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Appian Way</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Appia</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antica</ENAMEX>), built in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">312 b.c.</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legions</ENAMEX> who marched to coastal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brindisi</ENAMEX> to set sail for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Africa</ENAMEX>. On either side
        lie the ruins of sepulchres of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of patrician <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The 17th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">chapel of Domine Quo Vadis</ENAMEX> marks the site where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>, fleeing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nero‚</ENAMEX>Äôs persecution in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, is said to have encountered
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>. Farther along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Appia</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rome‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most celebrated
        catacombs, including those of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Callisto</ENAMEX>, the largest of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 50</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">underground Christian</ENAMEX> cemeteries.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>
        The power of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> endures both in the spirituality evoked
        by every stone of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Peter‚Äôs Basilica</ENAMEX> and in the almost physical awe
        inspired by the splendors of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vatican City</ENAMEX>. At their best, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">popes</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cardinals</ENAMEX> replaced military conquest by moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and
        persuasion; at their worst, they could show the same hunger for
        political power and worldly wealth as any caesar or grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duke</ENAMEX>. A visit
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> is an object lesson for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sceptic</ENAMEX> alike.
        Named after the hill on which it stands and which in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Middle Ages</TIMEX> was surrounded by a malarial swamp, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> has been a
        papal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 600 years</TIMEX>, but a sovereign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> independent
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> only since the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Lateran Treaty</ENAMEX> signed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>.
        If you have the time, try to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Peter‚Äôs Basilica</ENAMEX> and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vatican Museums</ENAMEX> on separate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> to avoid fatigue and visual
        overload. Check opening times: it is anyone‚Äôs guess if the generously
        extended <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jubilee Year 2000</ENAMEX> will be kept in effect.
        To appreciate the unique <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">panorama</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Peter‚</ENAMEX>Äôs Basilica
        and its <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 sq km piazza</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.4 sq mile</NUMEX>), approach it by foot as history‚Äôs
        countless pilgrims have. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX> at the beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sant‚ÄôAngelo Bridge</ENAMEX>, one
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> crossing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tiber River</ENAMEX>. Adorned by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> angel sculptures by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernini</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, it arrives at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castel Sant‚ÄôAngelo</ENAMEX>,
        originally built as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hadrian‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a.d. 139</TIMEX>. Its name derives
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope Gregory‚Äôs</ENAMEX> vision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archangel Michael‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇnow</ENAMEX> represented
        by a statue on top‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇheralding the end of a plague in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">590</TIMEX>. It was
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixth-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barbarians</ENAMEX> who commandeered the massive round brick pile
        as a fortress, using ancient statues as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> to hurl on the heads
        of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> below. Linked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> by a thick-walled
        passage, it served as a hideout for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">popes</ENAMEX> in times of danger, notably
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pope Clement VII</ENAMEX>, who holed up here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> during the sack of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Habsburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1527</TIMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Papal Apartments</ENAMEX> are a
        strong contrast to the dungeons, both open to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, where
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">philosopher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giordano Bruno</ENAMEX> and sculptor-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">goldsmith Benvenuto</ENAMEX>
        Cellini were once imprisoned.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Peter‚Äôs Square</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Piazza San Pietro</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernini</ENAMEX> has
        performed one of the world‚Äôs most exciting pieces of architectural
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">orchestration</ENAMEX>. The sweeping curves of the colonnades reach out to the
        unending stream of pilgrims from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> itself and the whole world, urbi
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> orbi, to take them into the bosom of the church beyond. In a rare
        opportunity for concentrated effort by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on such a gigantic
        project, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernini</ENAMEX> completed the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">284</NUMEX> travertine columns, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX> pilasters,
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140</NUMEX> statues of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just 11 years</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1656 to 1667</TIMEX>.
        Stand on either of the circular paving stones set between the square‚Äôs
        twin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX> fountains and the red granite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> obelisk to
        appreciate the harmony of the quadruple rows of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doric</ENAMEX> columns, so
        perfectly aligned that they seem like a single row. The purity of
        Bernini‚Äôs work here refutes the popular conception of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baroque</ENAMEX> as being
        nothing but overblown extravagance.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Peter‚Äôs Basilica</ENAMEX> is the largest of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">churches</ENAMEX> and by any standards a grandiose achievement, but it
        inevitably suffered from the competing visions of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>
        called in to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">collaborate‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇBramante</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliano da Sangallo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baldassare Peruzzi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giacomo Della Porta</ENAMEX>, Domenico
        Fontana, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Carlo Maderno‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇeach adding, subtracting, and modifying,
        often with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> looking over his shoulder.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1506 to 1626</TIMEX>, it changed from the simple ground plan
        of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> cross, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> arms of equal length, as favored by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bramante</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch-enemy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>, to the final form of
        Maderno‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> cross extended by a long nave, as demanded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">popes</ENAMEX>
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counter-Reformation</ENAMEX>. One result is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maderno‚</ENAMEX>Äôs porticoed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fa√ßade</ENAMEX> and nave obstruct a clear view of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michelangelo‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">square</ENAMEX>.
        The church‚Äôs dimensions are impressive: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">212 m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">695 ft</ENAMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exterior</ENAMEX> length, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">187 m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">613 ft</ENAMEX>) inside length; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">132 m</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">435 ft</ENAMEX>) to the
        tip of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> (diameter <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">42.45 m/139 ft</NUMEX>).
        As you go in, notice the keys of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Peter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">inlaid</ENAMEX> in the
        doorway paving. Set in the floor by the central door is the large round
        slab of red porphyry where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlemagne</ENAMEX> knelt for his coronation as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 800</TIMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find the basilica‚Äôs most treasured work of art,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Michelangelo‚Äôs sublime Piet√†‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇMary</ENAMEX> with the dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> on her lap‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇin
        its own chapel to the right of the entrance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Florentine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> was
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just 25</TIMEX>, and justly proud enough to append his signature (the only
        surviving example), visible on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madonna‚</ENAMEX>Äôs sash . Since a religious
        fanatic attacked it with a hammer in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, the statue is protected by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bullet-proof glass</ENAMEX>. But reverence can also cause damage: on the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13th-century</TIMEX> bronze statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Peter</ENAMEX> near the main altar, attributed
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Florentine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect-sculptor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnolfo di Cambio</ENAMEX>, the lips and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fingers</ENAMEX> of countless pilgrims have worn away the toes of its right
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">foot</ENAMEX>.
        Beneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernini‚</ENAMEX>Äôs great baldacchino (canopy),
        cast out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bronze</ENAMEX> beams taken from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pantheon‚</ENAMEX>Äôs porch (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX>),
        soars above the high altar. It was built right over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Peter‚Äôs</ENAMEX> tomb
        and reserved exclusively for the pope‚Äôs mass. In the apse beyond, the
        Baroque <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> gives full vent to his exuberance with his bronze and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marble Cathedra</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Peter</ENAMEX>, throne of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostle‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX>.
        It should come as no surprise that, as the greatest patron
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX>, sculptors, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> have ever known, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> should <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, one of the world‚Äôs richest
        collections of art. The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 miles</NUMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican Museums</ENAMEX> are made up of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostolic Library</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borgia Apartments</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael Stanze</ENAMEX> (or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rooms</ENAMEX>), and the incomparable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sistine Chapel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Shuttle buses</ENAMEX> run
        regularly from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Peter‚Äôs Square</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> entrance and back,
        otherwise a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20-minute</TIMEX> walk.
        If you want at all costs to avoid the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sistine‚</ENAMEX>Äôs day-long
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crowds</ENAMEX>, go there first thing in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> (don‚Äôt forget your
        binoculars for details on the ceiling). In any case, you can‚Äôt miss
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">it‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇarrows</ENAMEX> indicate color-coded itineraries within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> that
        showcase the myriad marvels to see en route, a remarkable degree of
        which is overlooked by time-restricted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> on a mission.
        With the booty from the ruthless dismantling of ancient
        monuments to make way for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th century</TIMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pio-Clementino Museum</ENAMEX> has assembled a wonderful collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> art. Most celebrated is the tortured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laoco√∂n</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhodes</ENAMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">century b.c. ‚Äìfirst century a.d.</ENAMEX> ), only recently returned more
        closely to its pristine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> by the removal of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> statue‚Äôs
        outstretched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> added by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-zealous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">‚Äúrestorers‚Äù</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope Julius II</ENAMEX> took a calculated risk in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1508</TIMEX> when he
        called in a relatively untried <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26-year-old</TIMEX> to do the interior
        decoration of his new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>. The result was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael Rooms</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanze di Raffaello</ENAMEX>). In the central <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stanza della Segnatura</ENAMEX> are the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> masterly frescoes, Dispute over the Holy Sacrament and the famous
        School of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>, confronting theological with philosophical wisdom.
        The Dispute unites biblical figures with historical pillars of the
        faith such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope Gregory</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Aquinas</ENAMEX>, but also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fra</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angelico</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">divine Dante</ENAMEX>. At the center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael</ENAMEX> is
        believed to have given the red-coated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plato</ENAMEX> the features of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo da</ENAMEX>
        Vinci, while portraying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX> as the thoughtful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heraclitus</ENAMEX>,
        seated in the foreground. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raphael</ENAMEX> himself appears in the lower
        right-hand corner.
        In stark contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raphael‚Äôs</ENAMEX> grand manner, seek out the
        gentle beauty of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fra Angelico‚</ENAMEX>Äôs frescoes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas V</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cappella del Beato Angelico</ENAMEX>). The lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
        are depicted in delicately subdued pinks and blues.
        The richly decorated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borgia Apartments</ENAMEX> contain
        Pinturicchio‚Äôs frescoes with portraits of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borgia Pope</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexander VI</ENAMEX> and his notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucrezia</ENAMEX>, and
        leads into the collection of modern religious artwork opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul VI</ENAMEX>. The latter includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rodin</ENAMEX> bronzes, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso ceramics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matisse‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> sketches, and designs for ecclesiastical robes and, rather
        unexpectedly, a grotesque <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Bacon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>.
        But nothing can prepare you for the visual shock of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sistine Chapel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cappella Sistina</ENAMEX>), built for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sixtus IV</ENAMEX> in the 15th
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>. Restored to its original colors after a controversial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten-year</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restoration</ENAMEX> finished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, the brightness and freshness of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frescoes</ENAMEX> is overwhelming. Despite the distraction of the constant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crowds</ENAMEX> (quiet is requested), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> seem to yield to the power of
        Michelangelo‚Äôs ceiling, and his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Judgement</TIMEX> (restored in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>). The
        other wall frescoes by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Botticelli, Pinturicchio, Ghirlandaio</ENAMEX>, and
        Signorelli are barely given attention. In this private papal chapel,
        where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cardinals</ENAMEX> hold their conclave to elect a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>, the glory of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> achieves its finest artistic expression.
        The chapel portrays nothing less than the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, in
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> parts: from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Noah</ENAMEX>; the giving of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Law</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>; and
        from the birth of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Judgment</ENAMEX>. Toward the center of
        Michelangelo‚Äôs ceiling, you‚Äôll make out the celebrated outstretched
        finger of man‚Äôs creation, filled out by the drunkenness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noah</ENAMEX>, the
        turmoil of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flood</ENAMEX>. But most overwhelming of all is the impression of
        the whole‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbest appreciated looking back from the bench by the
        chapel‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exit</ENAMEX>.
        On the chapel‚Äôs altar wall is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michelangelo‚</ENAMEX>Äôs tempestuous
        Last <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judgment</ENAMEX>, begun <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23 years</TIMEX> after the ceiling‚Äôs completion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1512</TIMEX>,
        when he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> and imbued with deep religious soul-searching. An almost
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">naked Jesus</ENAMEX> dispenses justice more like a stern, even fierce Classical
        god-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> than the conventionally gentle biblical figure. It is said
        that the artist‚Äôs agonizing self-portrait can be made out in the flayed
        skin of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Bartholomew</ENAMEX>, to the right below <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>.
        Amid all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican‚</ENAMEX>Äôs treasures, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Picture Gallery</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinacoteca Vaticana</ENAMEX>), in a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">palace</ENAMEX>, get short shrift. This collection of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> centuries of
        paintings includes important works by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giotto, Fra Angelico, Perugino</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raphael‚Äôs Transfiguration</ENAMEX> (his last great work), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo da Vinci‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unfinished St. Jerome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bellini‚Äôs Piet√†</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Caravaggio‚Äôs Descent</ENAMEX> from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX>.
        The neighborhood south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trastevere</ENAMEX>,
        literally ‚Äúacross the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiber,‚Äù</ENAMEX> has long been renowned as the most
        popular quarter of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>. Here, ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that consider themselves
        the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> uphold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age-old</TIMEX> traditions and customs (much like
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cockneys</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>). It is good to wander among the narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>
        and markets to sample the authentic life of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, highlighted by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Noantri (‚ÄúWe Others‚Äù</ENAMEX>) street festival of music, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fireworks</ENAMEX>, during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two weeks of July</TIMEX>. Another sort of festival
        atmosphere prevails every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Porta Portese</ENAMEX> section of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trastevere</ENAMEX> hosts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rome‚</ENAMEX>Äôs liveliest and largest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">flea</ENAMEX> market. The stalls
        are filled with everything from vintage clothing to the occasional
        valuable antique.
        Inevitably, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúpopular‚Äù and ‚Äúauthentic‚Äù</ENAMEX> became chic and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ambience</ENAMEX> is now somewhat contested by higher rents and the change in
        character that guarantees. But the true Trasteverini hang on, mainly in
        the area immediately around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Maria</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trastevere</ENAMEX>, reputedly the
        oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> may date back to the third
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, but the present <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> is the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope Innocent II</ENAMEX>,
        himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trasteverino</ENAMEX>, around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1140</TIMEX>. It is known for its wonderful
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX>-influenced fa√ßade and the interior‚Äôs pavements and mosaic of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> enthroned with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> decorating the domed ceiling of the apse. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liveliest fruit</ENAMEX> and vegetable market is to be found on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piazza di San</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cosimato</ENAMEX>.
        Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museums</ENAMEX>
        The largest collection of Etruscan art in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> can be
        found in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Villa Giulia</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northwest</ENAMEX> area of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Villa Borghese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. Room after room is filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> from the
        tombs of this little understood pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>: shields, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chariots</ENAMEX>; exquisite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and silver jewelry; and decorative ceramic
        works. The museum‚Äôs highlight is a life-size, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixth-century</TIMEX> b.c.
        terracotta sculpture of a reclining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> that was used as the lid of
        a sarcophagus.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borghese Gallery</ENAMEX>, opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> after an extensive
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year</TIMEX> renovation, is housed in a handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baroque villa</ENAMEX> inspired
        originally by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadrian‚Äôs Villa</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tivoli</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">69</NUMEX>), but with its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> formal gardens now transformed into an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>-style landscaped
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">park</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italy‚</ENAMEX>Äôs loveliest and most important small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, its
        highlights include some outstanding sculptures by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernini</ENAMEX> and Canova
        (whose portrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> as a reclining <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Venus</ENAMEX> is arguably
        the museum‚Äôs most famous attraction), as well as paintings by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael</ENAMEX>,
        Correggio, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titian, Caravaggio, Botticelli</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D√ºrer</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cranach</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capitoline Museums</ENAMEX>, in the twin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campidoglio</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>), have extensive collections of sculpture
        excavated from ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, particularly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palazzo Nuovo</ENAMEX>. In the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palazzo dei Conservatori</ENAMEX> is the most celebrated piece, the superb
        Etruscan bronze <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capitoline She-Wolf</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lupa Capitolina</ENAMEX>), symbol of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. The wolf dates from around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fifth century</TIMEX> b.c. , but the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">little Romulus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Remus</ENAMEX> that she is suckling are actually <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>
        additions by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollaiuolo</ENAMEX>. The top-floor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitoline Picture Gallery</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinacoteca Capitolina</ENAMEX>) has important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venetian</ENAMEX> works by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellini</ENAMEX>,
        Titian, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tintoretto, Lotto</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veronese</ENAMEX>, as well as a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubens</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romulus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Remus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caravaggio‚Äôs St. John the Baptist</ENAMEX>.
        Alternatively known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palazzo Barberini</ENAMEX> or the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery of Antique Art</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galleria Nazionale d‚ÄôArte Antica</ENAMEX>) (on
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via delle Quattro Fontane</ENAMEX>), another architectural battleground for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch-rivals</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borromini</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernini</ENAMEX>, is worth a visit as much for its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">splendid Baroque</ENAMEX> d√©cor as for its collection of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13th‚Äì17th-century</TIMEX>
        paintings. They come together in the palace‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salone</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Hall</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pietro da Cortona‚</ENAMEX>Äôs dazzling illusionist ceiling fresco, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Triumph</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Divine Providence</ENAMEX>. Notable in the collections are a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Fra</ENAMEX> Angelico
        triptych, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raphael‚Äôs La Fornarina</ENAMEX> (though the authorship is disputed),
        and works by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titian, Tintoretto</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Greco</ENAMEX>.
        New on the scene is the vast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palazzo Doria Pamphili</ENAMEX> off the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piazza Venezia</ENAMEX>. The private collection of the important <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doria</ENAMEX> family
        includes a number of masterpieces by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 15th</TIMEX> to the 17th
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Annibale Carracci and Brueghel the Elder</ENAMEX>.
        Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Churches</ENAMEX>
        It‚Äôs impossible to even count all of the delightful
        churches worth visiting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> (unofficial counts hover at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">250</ENAMEX>), many
        of which are commonly stumbled on by accident. We suggest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just three</NUMEX>
        within easy reach of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Cavour</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">thoroughfare</ENAMEX> leading from the main
        railway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stazione Termini</ENAMEX>).
        Originally built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth century</TIMEX> on the Esquiline
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> site of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Maggiore</ENAMEX>
        is the largest and most splendid of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> dedicated to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgin Mary</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas time</TIMEX> is especially popular here when pilgrims
        come to admire relics of the holy crib from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth¬≠lehem.</ENAMEX> In the Oratory
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crib</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oratorio del Presepio</ENAMEX>) are the moving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13th-century</TIMEX>
        sculptures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Kings</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ox</ENAMEX>, and the ass, by Arnolfo
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">di Cambio</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16th-century</TIMEX> additions). The
        most spectacular art treasures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> are its gorgeous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX>
        mosaics, glittering <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Testament</ENAMEX> scenes high on the walls (don‚Äôt
        forget the binoculars), and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">triumphant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> enthroned in
        the apse over the high altar. The coffered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> ceiling glitters
        with the gold of the first shipments from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World</ENAMEX>.
        In a nearby side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Prassede</ENAMEX> is unprepossessing
        from the outside but enchanting in the intimacy of its interior. The
        delicate <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mosaics</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> angels make the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Zeno</ENAMEX> the city‚Äôs most important <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> monument. To the right
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">chapel</ENAMEX> is a fragment of rare jasper said to come from the column
        to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> was tied for his flagellation. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice the</ENAMEX> fine mosaic of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jerusalem</ENAMEX> over the chancel.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">San Pietro</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vincoli</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Peter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Chains</ENAMEX>) might not
        attract a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> look if it didn‚Äôt contain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the greatest of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michelangelo‚Äôs</ENAMEX> sculptures, his formidable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>. Intended for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter‚Äôs Basilica</ENAMEX> as part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michelangelo‚</ENAMEX>Äôs botched project for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius II‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX>, the statue of the great biblical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> sits in
        awesome majesty. You can imagine how grandiose the original plan must
        have been when you realize that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> was supposed to be one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
        figures adorning the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúhorns‚Äù</ENAMEX> on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> continue a
        traditional medieval mistranslation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX> for halo-like rays of
        light. On each side, the comparatively passive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacob‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>, a prayerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel</ENAMEX> and melancholy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leah</ENAMEX>, were the last completed
        sculptures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Lazio</ENAMEX>
        The excursions to be made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lazio</ENAMEX> hinterland
        around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> are those that ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Romans</ENAMEX> themselves made to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>
        homes by the sea or nearby lakes.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tivoli</ENAMEX>
        Follow the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> chariot <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> (repaved) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via</ENAMEX>
        Tiburtina <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">19 miles</NUMEX>) east of the capital to the haunting ruins of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadrian‚Äôs Villa</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Villa Adriana</ENAMEX>), near the picturesque <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tivoli</ENAMEX>,
        at the foot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabine Hills</ENAMEX>. Sprawling across <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">70 hectares</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">173</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acres</ENAMEX>), this retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hideaway</ENAMEX> of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor-builder</ENAMEX> was
        designed to recapture some of the architectural marvels of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>,
        especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> he loved above all else‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇa travel notebook for
        his old age. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barbarians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators</ENAMEX> have removed most of the
        villa‚Äôs treasures, but a stroll through the remaining pillars, arches,
        and mosaic fragments in gardens running wild among the olive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>,
        cypresses, and pines can be marvelously evocative of a lost world. To
        get a clear sense of the original, start with the villa‚Äôs excellent
        scale model. The monumental <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX>, separate <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> theater, temples, and pavilions together make up the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who drew no distinction between the pleasures of mind and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. In
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, the enchanting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Villa ¬≠dell‚ÄôIsola</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> surrounded by
        a little reflecting pool and circular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">portico</ENAMEX>, epitomizes all the magic
        of the place.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tivoli</ENAMEX> itself, overlooking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> plain, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Villa</ENAMEX>
        d‚ÄôEste is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>, celebrating all the extravagance
        of the late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Renaissance</TIMEX>. From the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cardinal Ippolito d‚ÄôEste</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> can look down at the terraced gardens, the real reason for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tivoli‚Äôs</ENAMEX> fame and your visit: <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> of cypresses and soaring fountains
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500</ENAMEX> in all, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernini‚Äôs Bicchierone</ENAMEX>), grottoes, waterfalls,
        reflecting pools, and everywhere the cool sound of rushing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alban Hills</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castel Gandolfo</ENAMEX>
        The region immediately southeast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> is known locally
        as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castelli Romani</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman Castles</ENAMEX>) for the fortified hilltop
        refuges built during the medieval civil wars. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it‚Äôs just the
        summer heat that drives the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> out on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>-trips to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">vineyards</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alban hills</ENAMEX> and lakes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country villages</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frascati</ENAMEX>,
        Grottaferrata, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marino</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocca di Papa</ENAMEX> make delightful stops, not
        least of all for a cool glass of their white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, especially during
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX> grape-harvest festivals. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> has his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> palace at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castel Gandolfo</ENAMEX>, on the shores of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Albano</ENAMEX>. As his health is
        failing, his usual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> blessings from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-July</TIMEX> to
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early September</TIMEX> are no longer guaranteed.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarquinia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Lazio</ENAMEX>
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">A12</NUMEX> autostrada and the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Via Aurelia</ENAMEX> (which ends up
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arles</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Provence</ENAMEX>) take you to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarquinia</ENAMEX>. Most important of
        the original <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Etruscan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">confederation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> dominated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> in its heyday of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixth centuries b.c. Today</TIMEX>, the
        paintings and sculptures found in its necropolis of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 5,700</NUMEX> tombs
        provide fascinating evidence of the brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Etruscan</ENAMEX> civilization for
        archeology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX>. Visits to the tombs outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> are organized
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Museum</ENAMEX>, housed in the fine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15th-century</TIMEX>
        Gothic-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance Palazzo Vitelleschi</ENAMEX> as you enter Tarquinia. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX> exhibits sarcophagi, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Etruscan</ENAMEX> and imported <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> vases, and some
        of the best wall<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-paintings‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇall</NUMEX> in reconstructed tombs. Displayed in a
        room by itself, the prize of the collection is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winged Horses</ENAMEX>
        sculpture from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarquinia‚Äôs Ara della Regina Temple</ENAMEX>.
