
  
  
    
      
        Where to go
        Where, indeed? This subcontinent is so rich and varied that
        the choice of what to see on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> visit can be daunting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don‚Äôt</ENAMEX> even
        think of ‚Äúdoing‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ‚Äúdo‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. With some judicious
        selection from among the places we suggest, you can most certainly get
        a pretty good feel for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks</TIMEX> that most people
        devote to a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trip.
        Even if you have a distinct taste for improvisation and a
        horror of schedules and detailed itineraries, you must accept from the
        outset, if your time is at all limited, that travelling around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
        will demand a certain amount of planning. Remember, there are over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">844</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> out there, and a lot of them will be on the move at the
        same time as you will be, therefore competing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> seats and hotel
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>. So you will need to make at least some advance reservations for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotels</ENAMEX> in principal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and especially for your major <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> or train
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journeys</ENAMEX>. This will still leave you plenty of room for getting off the
        beaten track and staying overnight in new and unexpected places.
        Putting Together an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itinerary</ENAMEX>
        We have divided the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">regions‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇnorth</ENAMEX>, west,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>, east, and south.
        In each of the regions, you‚Äôll find a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>,
        Mumbai, or Chennai which you can use as a starting point, and which
        would also be the best place for phoning home and making other
        practical arrangements. Equally important, each area includes a place
        where, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hallowed</TIMEX> and sensible military phrasing, you can go for rest
        and recreation. In this case, you‚Äôll find a beach <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX>, nature
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reserve</ENAMEX>, or one of the old hill-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Raj</ENAMEX>, each being
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ideal</ENAMEX> for a change of pace or climate. It‚Äôs easy to overdose on the
        many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">temples</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. They are all worth your
        attention, but do take plenty of time to relax, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">too‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇyou‚</ENAMEX>Äôll be
        surprised at how much more you can see and appreciate if you‚Äôve had
        enough rest.
        If your budget allows you to fly around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, you can
        design a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúsmorgasbord‚Äù</ENAMEX> of places to see in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX>, since you will
        not be able to do all of them exhaustively. In any case, we recommend
        that you choose from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> of them, ideally <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, when planning
        your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúmenu</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Information</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> can be very helpful. You will
        find their guides are much more reliable than those outside the temples
        or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>, but one word of warning: different tour guides will give
        contradictory explanations about the significance of statues as well as
        many different versions of legend and historical ‚Äúfact. ‚Äù It would be
        easy to dismiss these explanations as being nonsense, but you‚Äôll
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">understand India</ENAMEX> better if you can appreciate that what each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> is
        saying may in its own way be true. When it comes to ideas, there is no
        more tolerant land on earth.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Practical Hints</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Handy Travel Tips</ENAMEX> section at the back of the book
        offers details on how to handle the practical side of your trip, but
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">it‚Äôs</ENAMEX> worth keeping a few points in mind when deciding where you‚Äôre
        going in the time you have available.
        The climate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">235</NUMEX>) imposes its own
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">imperatives</ENAMEX> and restrictions on your itinerary. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern India</ENAMEX> is
        simply impractical in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> unbearably hot in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, and
        trains uncertain in the monsoon. Think of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three seasons</TIMEX>, cool, hot, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wet</ENAMEX>, emphasized here because they take on a particular meaning in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> context.
        The cool <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> is from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October to March</TIMEX>, the ideal time
        for seeing most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> (‚ÄÇexcept in the northern hills and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX>,
        where it‚Äôs bitterly cold). Cool means it is pleasantly warm by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>, and
        fresh enough for a sweater in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>. The temperature begins to
        rise by mid-February. Hot, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April to June</TIMEX>, is hot as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> only
        rarely experience it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and plains in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX> are
        definitely a bad bet, but the hill-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> will be at their best. From
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-June to September</TIMEX>, wet means monsoon-wet, not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day every day</TIMEX>,
        but torrential <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rains</ENAMEX> occur often enough to make travel uncertain and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mosquitoes</ENAMEX> and other bugs a real nuisance. However, during this
        time the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is at its most green, and the monuments, especially
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj Mahal</ENAMEX>, take on a glistening beauty.
        With regard to your health (see also page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">241</NUMEX>), two
        attitudes herald a miserable time: carelessness and hypochondria. Take
        elementary precautions by sticking to bottled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> and freshly cooked
        food, and you won‚Äôt have any serious stomach problems. An occasional
        touch of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúDelhi belly‚Äù</ENAMEX> is unavoidable when you‚Äôre not used to the spicy
        food, but nothing to worry about; take it easy and drink lots of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liquids</ENAMEX>, and it‚Äôll pass. If you are on a short trip, you may need to
        take a quick-acting remedy to keep you on your feet, but if you load up
        with antibiotics and a host of other patent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX>, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> will
        never build up resistance, and the next attack will just be worse.
        There is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> essential: protect yourself from the heat.
        Save your sun-tanning for the beach or the hotel swimming pool.
        Otherwise, stay out of the sun. Wear a nicely ventilated hat and keep
        to the shade in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. Try to do your open air sightseeing in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning and late afternoon</TIMEX>. Take a siesta after lunch. Drink plenty of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liquids‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇin the heat, dehydration is more of a risk than an upset
        stomach.
        In all senses of the word, stay cool. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first few days</TIMEX>
        jet-lag, acclimatization, and culture shock may lead you to lose your
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temper</ENAMEX> when you see the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railways</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> not organized in
        a way you‚Äôre used to, but don‚Äôt <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">forget‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇJohn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Galbraith</ENAMEX> called
        it a functioning anarchy. Count to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>, and, like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> belly, it‚Äôll
        pass. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Airports</ENAMEX>, railway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> can be a pain anywhere in
        the world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> are mostly cheerful, responding much more
        readily to a smile than a scowl.
        The red tape can at times seem like barbed wire, but this,
        too, can be handled. Part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India‚</ENAMEX>Äôs legacy after several centuries of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> (don‚Äôt just blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> civil service‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit began long
        before) is an inordinate respect for the written document and the
        rubber stamp. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don‚Äôt</ENAMEX> knock it‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇuse it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vouchers</ENAMEX>, passes, letters of
        introduction, and printed business cards all work like magic when a
        ‚Äúconfirmed‚Äù reservation has become ‚Äúunconfirmed. ‚Äù
        If you should be travelling by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">253</NUMEX>) and
        rate comfort above improvisation, go <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indrail Pass</ENAMEX>.
        It saves you time in queues and gets you preferential treatment with
        reservations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Airlines‚Äô Discover India</ENAMEX> plan offers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 days</TIMEX> of
        unlimited travel and is less economic than single tickets, but buy them
        en bloc with confirmed reservations that you should reconfirm at each
        new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>.
        Echoing around every office you will hear the cheerful
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sentence: ‚</ENAMEX>ÄúNo problem. ‚Äù Though it rarely means exactly this, interpret
        it as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">meaning ‚Äúno catastrophe‚Äù</ENAMEX> and have a good time anyway.
        THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORTH</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> embraces the government
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">capital‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthe heart</ENAMEX> of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mughal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agra</ENAMEX>, and the nature
        reserves of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corbett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bharatpur</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayan</ENAMEX> mountains there is
        the hill-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Simla‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwhich</ENAMEX> once served as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> summer
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">capital‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇand the magical but dangerous region of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Delhi</ENAMEX>
        On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yamuna</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jumna</ENAMEX>) river at the western end of the great
        Ganga valley, the capital seems to have been a coveted place for
        India‚Äôs conquerors. Though they each very often destroyed the work of
        their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">city</ENAMEX> remains a fascinating
        compendium of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India‚</ENAMEX>Äôs imperial history.
        Recent archaeological findings suggest that a site on the
        Yamuna river may have been the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mahabharata</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yudhishthira</ENAMEX>,
        dating back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> b.c. A rock inscription from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashoka</ENAMEX>
        indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> was a major point on the trade route between the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">northwest</ENAMEX> frontier and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengal</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third century</TIMEX> b.c.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomara Rajputs</ENAMEX> made it their capital in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">736</TIMEX>, with the
        name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dhillika</ENAMEX>, and it was a focus of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX> wars until the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>
        conquered it and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qutb-ud-din Aybak</ENAMEX> set up his sultanate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1206</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Delhi</ENAMEX>
        was dismantled to make way for new monuments which then suffered from
        the devastating passage of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Timur the Lame</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1398</TIMEX>. He took away <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>-loads of building materials and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stonemasons</ENAMEX> and sculptors to build his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samarkand</ENAMEX>. With the
        advent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughals</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1526</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> alternated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agra</ENAMEX> as the
        capital, and each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> asserted his particular taste in architectural
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">caprice</ENAMEX>.
        Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> took a back seat to the ports
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calcutta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bombay</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madras</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX>, when it became once more a
        proud imperial capital. No less vain than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughals</ENAMEX>, the new
        conquerors all added their own architectural tastes, which were a
        tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India‚</ENAMEX>Äôs past but unmistakably <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> in overall conception,
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX>.
        Today, a tour of the capital takes you through a mixture of
        imposing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX>, modern office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>,
        and along the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Delhi</ENAMEX> of vibrant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>
        crowding in on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughal</ENAMEX> monuments. For more orientation, visit the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Information Office</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Janpath</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delhi</ENAMEX> of the Sultans
        Start at the southern end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qutb Minar</ENAMEX>,
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islam‚</ENAMEX>Äôs impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. Begun by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delhi‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first sultan</ENAMEX>,
        Qutb-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ud</NUMEX>-din, and completed by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iltutmish</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">73</NUMEX>-m
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">240-ft</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> was erected to celebrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> conquest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> comprises <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> stories, each a tapering cylinder with angular
        and convex ribs, separated by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">balconies</ENAMEX>.
        The top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> is off limits, due to dangers inherent
        in the narrow staircase that leads to the look-out point, so the best
        bet for a panoramic view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is the top floor of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">taller</ENAMEX>, more recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>.
        The ruins of the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quwwatu‚</ENAMEX>Äôl-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islam</ENAMEX>-Masjid
        (which means ‚ÄúThe Might of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islam‚Äù</ENAMEX>), was built with the might of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX>. With no skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> labor at his disposal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qutb</ENAMEX> called on
        local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craftsmen</ENAMEX> to build the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> from the ruins of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> and Jain
        temples, demolished by their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX>. You can see the results of
        this construction method in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>-pillars set on top of one
        another. Sculptures have been plastered over, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> carving
        remains. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> architecture shows in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> characteristic peaked
        arches of the prayer-hall screen, but even here the decoration, which
        includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> lettering, is naturalistic and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> in style.
        In the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mosque‚Äôs courtyard</ENAMEX>, there is a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7-m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>-ft) Iron
        Pillar, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth century</TIMEX>, brought here by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajput</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> of
        Dhillika, but nobody knows from where. Without rust after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1600</TIMEX> years
        worth of monsoon, this monument to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu god Vishnu</ENAMEX> is said to have
        special properties: if you stand with your back against it and
        completely encircle it with your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">arms‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇno mean feat‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇgood</ENAMEX> luck is
        yours for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rest of the day</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> of the Mughals
        Due east of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Delhi‚Äôs India Gate</ENAMEX> the much-plundered
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Purana Qila</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Fort</ENAMEX>) stands on an ancient mound, now
        believed to mark the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Indraprastha of the Mahabharata</ENAMEX> epic.
        The earliest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Qal‚Äôa-i-Kuhna-Masjid</ENAMEX>,
        with its minutely detailed molding of graceful peaked arches,
        represents an important transition from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turco</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> to the
        sophisticated style of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX>-influenced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughals</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> was
        built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1541</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sher Shah</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babur‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Sher-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mandal</ENAMEX>, the octagonal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> due south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>,
        served as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">General‚Äôs pleasure-palace</ENAMEX>, but it was to be the death of
        his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humayun</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX>).
        From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humayun‚</ENAMEX>Äôs death came the splendid monument located in
        Nizamuddin, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomb of Humayun</ENAMEX>, which was built by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> Haji
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Begum</ENAMEX> and the inspiration for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj Mahal</ENAMEX>. It is set back on a raised
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">terrace</ENAMEX> in a set of walled-in tree-shaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX> surrounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hedges</ENAMEX>,
        but without the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> once running in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> (‚Äúrivers of life‚Äù),
        or the rectangular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> that were to be the perfect setting for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taj</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humayun‚Äôs Tomb</ENAMEX> has a remarkable charm of its own, a site for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">repose</ENAMEX> and serenity made from a delicate combination of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">materials‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbuff</ENAMEX>-and-red sandstone and smart, grey-trimmed white
        marble. With a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">majestic dome</ENAMEX> uniting the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> octagonal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX> over the
        terrace‚Äôs latticed arches, this is the first fully-realized masterpiece
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mughal</ENAMEX> architecture. The numerous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-pointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> set in the
        abutments of the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arches</ENAMEX> are not the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Star</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> but an
        esoteric emblem that you‚Äôll see all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
        Dominating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Delhi</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lal Quila</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Red Fort</ENAMEX>) was built by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shahjahan</ENAMEX> when he transferred the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Agra</ENAMEX>.
        Behind its ramparts, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> citadel is more a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> than a
        fortress, with white marble preferred over the region‚Äôs red sandstone.
        It‚Äôs thought he used the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> who worked on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahal</ENAMEX>.
        From south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort</ENAMEX>, notice the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monumental elephants</ENAMEX>
        outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Delhi Gate</ENAMEX>. Part of the original design, they were
        destroyed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aurangzeb</ENAMEX>, who refused images susceptible to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">idolatry</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Viceroy</ENAMEX> Lord <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curzon</ENAMEX> had these replicas installed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903</TIMEX>.
        Enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">fort</ENAMEX> on its west side at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lahore Gate</ENAMEX>, and you find
        yourself in a vaulted bazaar <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, an idea <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shahjahan</ENAMEX> borrowed from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>. Imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajput</ENAMEX> princes riding on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX>
        through the arcade as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naqqar Khana</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drum House</ENAMEX>), where the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imperial</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> played and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> were obliged to dismount.
        Pass with the ghosts of these nobles and commoners through
        the drum <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diwan-i-Am</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of Public Audience</ENAMEX>). Here, under
        a baldaquin with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> pillars, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> sat cross-legged on his
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">throne</ENAMEX>, the ‚ÄúSeat of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shadow</ENAMEX> of God. ‚Äù He held <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, surrounded
        by nobles, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midday</TIMEX>, while common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">petitioners</ENAMEX> attended in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> below. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>, you can admire the inlaid stone panels
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> at the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>.
        Entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Diwan-i-Khas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of Private Audience</ENAMEX>) was
        for the privileged, by ticket only. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">You‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find it on the left, among
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace apartments</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yamuna</ENAMEX> river. Beautiful as it is, with
        carved designs on the marble columns and cusped arches, imagine it in
        its full glory before the ravages of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nadir Shah</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1739</TIMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> chipped the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> out of its pillars and inlay off the ceiling,
        and then carted away the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">fabulous Peacock Throne</ENAMEX>. Above the arches
        you‚Äôll see the inscription:
        ‚ÄúIf paradise on earth there be,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äò Tis</ENAMEX> here, ‚Äòtis here, ‚Äòtis here! ‚Äù
        The last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> to enjoy it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George V</ENAMEX>, for whom a
        painted wooden ceiling was installed.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the few surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace apartments</ENAMEX> is the principal
        harem, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rang Mahal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palace</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Color</ENAMEX>). The walls‚Äô paintings have gone and
        water no longer flows in its indoor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nahr-i-Bihisht</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">River of Paradise</ENAMEX>),
        but mosaics made of mirrors ornament the ceiling and walls of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
        boudoirs, making a galaxy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> when candle-lit (strike a match).
        Southernmost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace buildings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mumtaz Mahal</ENAMEX> was part of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imperial</ENAMEX> harem and is now a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mughal</ENAMEX> artwork.
        To the northwest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Diwan-i-Khas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Moti</ENAMEX> Masjid
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Mosque</ENAMEX>) is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> contribution to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shahjahan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aurangzeb</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Each evening</TIMEX>, a sound and light show at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fort</ENAMEX> tells its story; details can be obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Bureau</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandni Chowk</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fort‚Äôs Lahore Gate</ENAMEX>, was
        once an avenue for processions. Today, it is the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">thoroughfare</ENAMEX>
        linking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delhi‚</ENAMEX>Äôs bazaars, which sell jewelry, clothes, and traditional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sweetmeats</ENAMEX>.
        On an outcrop of rock southwest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Fort</ENAMEX>,
        Shahjahan‚Äôs other great construction, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jama Masjid</ENAMEX> (the great
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">congregational ‚ÄúFriday Mosque‚Äù</ENAMEX>), is the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. The
        inadvisability of a mo rning or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late afternoon</TIMEX> visit on hot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> will
        become apparent when you see the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pyramidal flights of stairs to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">gate-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100-sq-m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,076-sq-ft</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> is enclosed by
        long colonnades with a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> at each corner. The prayer hall
        highlights the emperor‚Äôs aesthetic, in the lotus calyx on the gateway‚Äôs
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> lantern shafts, the delicately flaring <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">balconies</ENAMEX> on the minarets,
        and the stripes to emphasize the bulbous marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">domes</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raj Ghat</ENAMEX>, the simple memorial to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahatma Gandhi</ENAMEX> overlooking
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yamuna river</ENAMEX>, is far in spirit from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughals</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">an integral</ENAMEX>
        part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Delhi</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX> planted with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> donated by visiting
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads of state</ENAMEX>, a square of marble marks the place where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cremated</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> has an inscription recording his last words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H√</ENAMEX>©
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ram</ENAMEX> (Oh, God), and nearby, a sign declares that most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>
        talisman: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúRecall the face of the poorest and most helpless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whom
        you may have seen and ask yourself if the step you contemplate is going
        to be of any help to him. ‚Äù There is also a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> recording the
        highlights of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gandhi‚</ENAMEX>Äôs life.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX>
        Those nostalgic for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Empire</ENAMEX> please note: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clive</ENAMEX>
        Road has been named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyagraja</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Victoria Road</ENAMEX> has become Rajendra
        Prasad, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Curzon</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasturba Gandhi</ENAMEX>. Though the statues of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have also disappeared, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> remains in the city‚Äôs
        planning. Faithful to the policy of separating the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> cantonment
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">railway</ENAMEX> as the barrier, the new city
        built for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Empire‚Äôs Indian</ENAMEX> seat of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is separated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> by the line running from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amritsar</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agra</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Neo-Classic</ENAMEX>
        architecture here is mixed with elements of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX>, and Mughal
        past, and the geometry of its plan exudes the self-confidence of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>. As a visiting statesman once said of it: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúWhat splendid ruins
        it will make! ‚Äù
        The commercial pivot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX> is the circular arcade
        and bustling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roundabout</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connaught</ENAMEX> Place. With cinemas, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, travel
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and the better craft emporiums, it‚Äôs a place
        whose new name, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indira Chowk</ENAMEX>, does not seem to catch on. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connaught</ENAMEX>
        Place straddles the northeast‚Äìsouthwest axis which links the Jama
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masjid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Delhi</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India‚Äôs parliament</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sansad Bhavan</ENAMEX>.
        Designed by the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Baker</ENAMEX>, the rather too massive,
        colonnaded rotunda of the parliament <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is at its best
        illuminated at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Viceroy‚Äôs Residence</ENAMEX>, now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rashtrapati Bhavan</ENAMEX> has wings radiating from the great grey-blue <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> of
        the central block and the tranquil <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX> of its gardens, and
        so bespeaks the grandeur of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britain‚</ENAMEX>Äôs heyday. It looms from an
        artificial hill along the processional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rajpath</ENAMEX> (once <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingsway</ENAMEX>),
        which is flanked by parklands, where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> holds its marches on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic Day</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26 January</TIMEX>. At the other end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajpath</ENAMEX> stands <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
        Gate, the war memorial designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutyens</ENAMEX> in the style of a triumphal
        arch that pays tribute to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> who died in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">War I.</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jantar Mantar</ENAMEX>, set south of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connaught</ENAMEX> Place, is perhaps
        the strangest monument in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX>. It is difficult to believe that
        these bizarre shapes, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">staircases</ENAMEX> going nowhere, and windows in walls
        without <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> were built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1724</TIMEX> by a serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, rather than in
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last century</TIMEX> by some deranged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>. It is in fact the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">astrologico‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇthat</ENAMEX> is, the astronomical <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">observatory‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇof Rajput prince</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jai Singh II</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaipur</ENAMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>). Its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centerpiece</ENAMEX> is the
        right-angled triangle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samrat Yantra</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Instrument</ENAMEX>), with a
        dome acting as a sun-dial, ‚Äúaccurate to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. ‚Äù In addition to
        this structure, he built <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> more‚<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇin Ujjain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Varanasi, Mathura</ENAMEX>, and
        his native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jaipur</ENAMEX>.
        Near here, surely the liveliest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> of all,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanuman Mandir</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Monkey</ENAMEX> God) is a theatre where you can
        witness the joyous atmosphere of popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hinduism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanuman</ENAMEX> is a
        beneficent deity predating classical <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinduism</ENAMEX>, and the reason why no
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> would dream of harming the little lemurs (monkeys) running around
        here.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Museums</ENAMEX>
        In what is artistically a predominantly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mughal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Museum</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janpath</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queensway</ENAMEX>) just south of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajpath</ENAMEX>, is worth
        a visit for its collection of old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> sculpture, in particular those
        from medieval <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vijayanagar</ENAMEX>.
        Railway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX> will surely enjoy the display of the
        country‚Äôs early steam engines at the open air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rail Transport Museum</ENAMEX>. It
        is situated in the diplomatic neighborhood of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chanakyapuri</ENAMEX> (behind the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhutan Embassy</ENAMEX>). Adventurous as rail travel in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> still is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
        one exhibit belongs hopefully in the past: the skull of an elephant
        that nearly derailed a mail <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1894</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nehru Memorial Museum</ENAMEX> is devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Independence</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">life of India‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first Prime Minister</ENAMEX>. It is located in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> which
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nehru</ENAMEX> inherited from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teen</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murti Road</ENAMEX> (it also houses a planetarium).
        Agra
        Location of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj Mahal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agra</ENAMEX> is the most popular sight
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. Even if the place had nothing else, it would be worth the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trip</ENAMEX>, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj</ENAMEX>, as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> calls it affectionately, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúsight‚Äù</ENAMEX> that
        awakens the wonder and enthusiasm of the most blas√©, world-weary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">traveller</ENAMEX>.
        But there‚Äôs plenty more. Agra was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akbar</ENAMEX> the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>, the site of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">fort</ENAMEX>, of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sikandra</ENAMEX>,
        and, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several miles</NUMEX> west at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatehpur Sikri</ENAMEX>, of the marvellous deserted
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> he built to celebrate the birth of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and which he abandoned to
        fight on the northwest frontier. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Heirs</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craftsmen</ENAMEX> originally
        brought here continue a tradition in jewelry, brassware, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ivory</ENAMEX>, and
        inlaid marble.
        The first historical mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agra</ENAMEX> is in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1501</TIMEX>, when
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sultan Sikandar Lodi</ENAMEX> made it his capital. Babur captured it along with
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Koh-i-Nur</ENAMEX> diamond now in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> crown jewels. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akbar</ENAMEX> chose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agra</ENAMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th century</TIMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jahangir</ENAMEX> made it a major focus of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> world. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> Shahjahan
        lost his taste for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agra</ENAMEX> after finishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj Mahal</ENAMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mumtaz-Mahal</ENAMEX> after she had died. He moved the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>
        again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1648</TIMEX>, leaving the city‚Äôs treasure to vandals (including the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>) after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1857 Mutiny</ENAMEX>, until the viceroys organized its
        restoration. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it is the effects of pollution that are taking their
        toll on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agra‚</ENAMEX>Äôs monuments.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj Mahal</ENAMEX>
        This is truly a monument for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all seasons</TIMEX>. There are those
        who swear by the sight on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj Mahal</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharad Purnima</ENAMEX>, the
        first full moon after the monsoons, a cloudless <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>
        when the light is at its clearest and also most romantic. Others love
        to see it in the middle of the heaviest monsoon, its marble
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">translucent</ENAMEX>, its image blurred in the rain-stippled water channels of
        its gardens. But its magic is strong at any time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, and any
        moment of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dawn</TIMEX>, its color changes from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> to
        rose-pink, and at sunset it is golden. Observe it, too, in the
        brilliance of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midday</TIMEX>, for then it is utterly, dazzlingly white. On
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> with a full moon, the grounds stay open till <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>.
        The gateway to the gardens of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum</ENAMEX> can be admired
        as a masterpiece in its own right, with noble marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arches</ENAMEX>, the domed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kiosks</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> corner turrets, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> rows of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> small chhattri
        (umbrella-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">domes</ENAMEX>) just above the entrance. It provides <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> with the
        perfect frame for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> view of the ensemble. You will find that
        long-range photography is allowed, but it is forbidden to take pictures
        inside the monument.
        The chharbagh (foursquare) gardens are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">an integral part of</ENAMEX>
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj Mahal</ENAMEX>, both spiritually, as the symbol of the paradise to which
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mumtaz-Mahal</ENAMEX> has ascended, and artistically, to enhance the color and
        texture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum</ENAMEX>. The dark cypresses heighten the brilliance of
        the monument‚Äôs marble, and the water <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>, meeting at a broad
        central viewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>, not only provide a perfect <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> image, but
        also, with the reflection of the sky, add at dawn and sunset a subtle
        illumination from below.
        Exquisite harmony and refined symmetry are the keynotes of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum</ENAMEX> itself. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> is clad in miraculously white
        marble from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajasthan</ENAMEX> quarries of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Makrana</ENAMEX>, achieving a magnificent
        texture with the subtly alternating broad and narrow slabs. Standing
        protectively at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> corners of the raised <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX>, the minarets
        are, deferentially, slightly lower than the sublime central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cupola</ENAMEX>.
        Inside, the octagonal cenotaph-chamber contains the ceremonial marble
        coffins of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mumtaz-Mahal</ENAMEX> and also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shahjahan</ENAMEX>, while, as was the custom of
        that time, the actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> are entombed in another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> directly
        below. You‚Äôll need to light a candle or use a flashlight in the
        cenotaph-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> because daylight barely filters through the beautiful
        marble trellis-screens.
        Sadly, vandals removed all the tomb‚Äôs spectacular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">treasures</ENAMEX>, but they did leave the gentle beauty of roses and poppies in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> inlaid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> of onyx, green chrysolite, carnelian, and variegated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum</ENAMEX> is flanked by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> almost identical red <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>,
        to the west a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>, to the east a guest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇeach</ENAMEX> is a perfect
        viewing-point. Try the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> at sunrise and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">sunset</ENAMEX>.
        But go around the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj</ENAMEX>, too, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX> which overlooks
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yamuna</ENAMEX> river. This boasts a view as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Agra Fort</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agra Fort</ENAMEX>
        Built by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akbar</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1565</TIMEX>, a more embattled period than during
        Shahjahan‚Äôs construction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Fort</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Agra Fort</ENAMEX> was
        conceived as a citadel with a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moat</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> and a river on the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>. Pleasure <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> were a secondary consideration, and were in
        fact mostly additions by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akbar‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX>.
        The entrance from the south, at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Amar Singh Gate</ENAMEX>, takes you
        up a ridged elephant‚Äôs ramp, sloped to slow down any potential
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attackers</ENAMEX>. Pass into the long quadrangle of the pillared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diwan-i-Am</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of Public Audience</ENAMEX>). It was here that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain William Hawkins</ENAMEX>
        handed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jahangir</ENAMEX> a special letter of introduction from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James I.</ENAMEX> Due north is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shahjahan‚Äôs Moti Masjid</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Mosque</ENAMEX>). Climb the
        narrow staircase to the roof of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> for a fine view of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">fort</ENAMEX>.
        Just off the northeast corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diwan-i-Am</ENAMEX>, the harem
        had its very own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nagina Masjid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>, and between the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> a bazaar where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> sold silks and jewels. Near the hammam
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Diwan-i-Khas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of Private Audience</ENAMEX>) has rich carving
        and inlaid marble. The crack in the marble throne came from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cannonball</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1857</TIMEX>. As in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi‚Äôs Fort</ENAMEX>, most of the private palace
        apartments face the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yamuna</ENAMEX> river. Among the most charming are the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arcaded loggia</ENAMEX> and the gilt-roofed pavilions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Khas Mahal</ENAMEX> or
        Private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Palace</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A minute</TIMEX> staircase led to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Musamman Burj</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pavilion</ENAMEX> of the emperor‚Äôs chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. It is also popularly known as the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúPrisoner‚Äôs Tower‚</ENAMEX>Äù for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aurangzeb</ENAMEX> imprisoned his father <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shahjahan</ENAMEX> here,
        allowing him a view of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj Mahal</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palace</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jahangir</ENAMEX> is built around a square <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arches</ENAMEX>. There are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> motifs on the ceiling in the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>, and in
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the west side: peacocks holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX> in their beaks, for
        example.
        Other Sights
        On the river bank opposite the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">fort</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomb of</ENAMEX>
        Itimad-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ud-Daulah</ENAMEX>, overshadowed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj Mahal</ENAMEX>. This was built <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years earlier</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jahangir‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nur Jahan</ENAMEX>, for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, who served
        as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mughal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>. There‚Äôs a fragile elegance to the white
        marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion‚Äôs graceful silhouette</ENAMEX>, with a cupola and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> octagonal
        turrets, and topped by domed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX>. The fine lattice-work on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arches</ENAMEX> and windows is superb, but its outstanding feature is the marble
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inlay</ENAMEX>, which is even more abundant than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj</ENAMEX> and better
        preserved.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Akbar‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum</ENAMEX>, located at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sikandra</ENAMEX>, is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 miles</NUMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">north of Agra</ENAMEX>. The best view is from the top of the gateway. On the
        cenotaph are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99</NUMEX> names of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allah</ENAMEX>.
        Fatehpur Sikri
        In a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of crowded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, it makes a refreshing
        change to travel <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">37 km</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">22 miles</NUMEX>) southwest to an outcrop on which
        stands the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citadel of Fatehpur Sikri</ENAMEX>, briefly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akbar‚</ENAMEX>Äôs imperial
        capital.
        Fatehpur, planned as a capital with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agra</ENAMEX> as a fallback
        position in case of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">attack</ENAMEX>, is protected on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> by ramparts
        measuring <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 6 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 miles</NUMEX>). On the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> side is an artificial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">lake</ENAMEX> stretching <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 miles</NUMEX>) to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rajasthan</ENAMEX> border, never
        sufficient, apparently, for the needs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citadel</ENAMEX>, and so one of the
        probable reasons why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akbar</ENAMEX> did not settle here permanently.
        Built by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> working on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Agra Fort</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">citadel</ENAMEX> adds the darker red stone of the mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ridge</ENAMEX> to the usual
        pink sandstone.
        Entering via the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Agra Gate</ENAMEX>, at the northeast corner, one
        passes on the right the karkhanas (workshops) where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpenters</ENAMEX>,
        weavers, and stonemasons worked.
        In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diwan Khana-i-Am</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> used for public
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akbar</ENAMEX> dispensed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> while attended by an executioner
        with instruments of torture and death. The sight of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them was
        felt to be an effective means of getting at the truth. At the foot of
        the colonnade is a big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone tethering</ENAMEX>-ring for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX> whose job
        it was to crush capital <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> to death.
        Go through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daulat Khana</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abode of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX>) on the south side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> of which the most
        striking feature is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> nature of its decoration: carved
        pedestals with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stylized elephant</ENAMEX> heads as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX> and sculpted stone
        screens.
        In the southeast corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sultana‚Äôs House</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hujra-i-Anup Talao</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of the Peerless</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Pool</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> covering every wall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> and pillar create the illusion
        of woodwork rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatehpur</ENAMEX> is the subject of many colorful
        stories in which it isn‚Äôt possible to establish a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">historian‚Äôs ‚Äútruth</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        For instance, in the center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pachisi Court</ENAMEX>, a
        huge chessboard for the game of pachisi, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akbar</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
        are said to have used human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúpieces‚Äù‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇ</ENAMEX> each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> using a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave-girls</ENAMEX> in different costumes.
        Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akbar</ENAMEX> is said to have come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astrologer‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pavilion</ENAMEX>, in the northwest corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> dose of
        forecasts from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>-esoteric. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> is known to have
        consulted a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">astrology</ENAMEX>. Just behind this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Treasury Pavilion</ENAMEX>, where you can
        imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Akbar</ENAMEX> seated on cushions under the arches and counting the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imperial</ENAMEX> money. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> was known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ankh Michauli</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blind Man‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buff</ENAMEX>), because it was where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akbar</ENAMEX> was thought to have played
        ‚<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Äúhide-and-seek‚</NUMEX>Äù with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>.
        The purpose of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Diwan-i-Khas</ENAMEX> is hotly disputed; it is
        not necessarily the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> of private audience that its name implies. It
        is dominated by a great central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pillar</ENAMEX> supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> to a balcony.
        Some claim it was here that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akbar</ENAMEX> held his famous debates with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuits</ENAMEX>,
        Brahmins, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parsi Zoroastrians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sufi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mystics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jain</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monks‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇthe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sages</ENAMEX> arguing while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akbar</ENAMEX> sat listening atop his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pillar</ENAMEX>, or
        Akbar striding majestically around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">balcony</ENAMEX> hurling his
        questions at his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX>. Others insist that it was just a storehouse
        for jewels. Truth in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, even more than beauty, is in the eye of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beholder</ENAMEX>.
        Walk across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> to the beautiful <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-tiered
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Panch Mahal</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian</ENAMEX> system of ventilation known as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">badgir</ENAMEX> (wind <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>): without walls on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX>, it is open for the
        breezes to sweep in. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> is supported on columns diminishing
        from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84</NUMEX> at ground-level to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> on the roof. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> that no two columns
        on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ground floor</ENAMEX> are alike. Be careful on the steep climb to the
        top, but you‚Äôll find it is well worth it for the wonderful view across
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citadel</ENAMEX>, particularly the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> of the imperial harem to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southwest</ENAMEX>.
        The harem‚Äôs principal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jodh Bai‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Palace‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇbuilt</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Akbar‚Äôs Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, the first royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> not
        required to convert to her husband‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">faith‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akbar‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        favorite residence at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatehpur</ENAMEX>. It has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side screening out the
        summer heat while the other is open to the cooler breezes. Its most
        cherished feature is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">turquoise ceramic tiled</ENAMEX> roof in the north and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">south</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatehpur‚Äôs Jama Masjid</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friday Mosque</ENAMEX>), at the south
        end of the citadel up on its mountain<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-ridge</ENAMEX>, was the very first of the
        open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>-style mosques to became characteristic of all Mughal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice the</ENAMEX> carved central mihrab (the recess marking the
        direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mecca</ENAMEX>). The jewel of the red stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX>, however, is
        the marble-clad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaikh Salim Chishti</ENAMEX>. Its fa√ßade features black
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">calligraphy</ENAMEX>; in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cenotaph-chamber</ENAMEX> there are pretty painted <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>.
        Originally a more simple monument, its white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">marble ‚Äúskin‚Äù</ENAMEX> was the
        addition of a very grateful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jahangir</ENAMEX> who, without the mystic Shaikh
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salim Chishti</ENAMEX>, might never have seen the light of day.
        Bharatpur
        Strictly speaking, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bharatpur</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rajasthan</ENAMEX>, but
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">proximity</ENAMEX>, just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">42 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">26 miles</NUMEX>) due west of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agra</ENAMEX>, makes it logical to
        include here. The marshes of the bird <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keoladeo-Ghana</ENAMEX> offer
        a welcome change of pace. Even if you‚Äôre not an avid <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watcher</ENAMEX>,
        you‚Äôll enjoy the gentle walks in the woodland, with the chance of
        seeing exciting <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herds</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">nilghai antelope</ENAMEX>, blackbuck, and cheetal
        (spotted <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX>). A good time to visit is just at the end of the monsoon
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">October‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇwhen you can see flocks of storks, egrets, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cormorants‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇand it is ideally combined with a full-moon trip to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taj</ENAMEX>, but there‚Äôs plenty to see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> round.
        Among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 300</NUMEX> different species of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> here,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">you‚Äôll</ENAMEX> find eagles, cranes, pelicans, snakebirds, kingfishers, and a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX> and geese, as well as a flock of rare <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wintering</ENAMEX> Siberian
        cranes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between January and March</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maharaja of Bharatpur</ENAMEX> used to
        organize formal annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>-shoots here for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> viceroys and other
        top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> as well as for fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princes</ENAMEX>. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> hunting is
        strictly banned. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bharatpur</ENAMEX> is only for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corbett Park</ENAMEX>
        Among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">India‚</ENAMEX>Äôs nature reserves, this is the best known
        because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Corbett</ENAMEX>, the audacious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-eating tigers
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kumaon</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> was established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX> and was given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corbett‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        name after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> became independent.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>, this lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> of forest and meadows
        by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramganga</ENAMEX> river in the foothills of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayas</ENAMEX> remains a home
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tiger</ENAMEX>, leopard, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cheetah</ENAMEX>, sloth bear,
        wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX>, jackal, and hyena. The river abounds with mahseer and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX>,
        as well as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds of crocodile and the occasional blind freshwater
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dolphin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> should look out for stork, red jungle-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fowl</ENAMEX>, and
        black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partridge</ENAMEX>.
        The forest is thick with sissoo and tall <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">sal trees</ENAMEX>; their
        timber is prized for ship-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>-ride, which allows you
        to swing through the jungle and grassland while reclining on a
        cushioned howdah, is a great joy. Rest at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midday</TIMEX> in the lodge at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dhikala</ENAMEX> and watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> head down to the river.
        Be sure to plan ahead through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourist Information</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, because admission to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> is by
        permit only. Permits are easy to obtain, however, and reserved
        accommodation can be booked either in the lodges or in the official
        campgrounds
        Chandigarh
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab</ENAMEX> is just a stopover en route to
        Simla, or a half-way point en route to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>. It‚Äôs well worth
        visiting this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, which was planned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Corbusier</ENAMEX>, invited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to create a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for
        the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Partition Punjab</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">windy</ENAMEX> plain at the foot of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayas</ENAMEX>. With <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxwell Fry</ENAMEX> designing most of the
        housing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Corbusier</ENAMEX> created the leading public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and laid out
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of spacious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">boulevards</ENAMEX> and sweeping tree-lined <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX>, inspired
        at least in part by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutyens‚</ENAMEX>Äô ideas for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX>, and blessedly
        uncongested by growing traffic. He planned the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> on the principle of
        the human body, with the government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> and
        university at its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, the commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>-center at its heart, and
        the outlying industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> as its limbs.
        In the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Assembly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secretariat</ENAMEX>
        administrative block, the vaulted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Court</ENAMEX>, and the smaller
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Governor‚Äôs Residence</ENAMEX>, you can see huge slabs of concrete like weathered
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">granite</ENAMEX> from the nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> boast both geometric
        and amorphous shapes, with bright colors visible behind the sub-breaker
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grills</ENAMEX>. Take a walk through the nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock Garden</ENAMEX> of large concrete
        blocks, or, to the east, take a rowboat on the artificial Sukhna
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX>.
        Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> visit the holy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amritsar</ENAMEX> for its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Sikh Shrine</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sikh</ENAMEX> architecture may also be appreciated at the
        nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Durgiana Temple</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jallianwala Bagh</ENAMEX> is an important monument to
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyrs</ENAMEX> who dies in an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Amritsar</ENAMEX> massacre in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX>.
        Simla
        Similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandigarh</ENAMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, which is now capital of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Himachal Pradesh</ENAMEX>, was built back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early years of the 19th century</TIMEX>
        when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> were desperately searching for
        refuge from the heat of the plains.
        At an altitude of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,130 m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6,755 ft</NUMEX>), this was once the
        place where a religious ascetic offered cool spring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to the
        numerous weary and thirsty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> coming out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayas</ENAMEX>. Some
        of these trekkers were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> returning from the war with the
        Gurkhas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1819</TIMEX>. They came back to build mountain retreats, as
        well as regular little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cottages</ENAMEX> or perhaps an occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>. From
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1832</TIMEX> onwards, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor-general</ENAMEX> Lord <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bentinck</ENAMEX> spent a happy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">summer</ENAMEX> here, it became the most prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">hill-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>. The viceroys,
        including the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mountbatten</ENAMEX> (who pondered the last details of
        Independence and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partition</ENAMEX> here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>), made it their summer
        capital.
        The old reasons to head for the hills still make a trip to
        Simla more than valid, even if the old viceregal glamour has gone. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">air</ENAMEX> here is sweet, cool, and clear, and the pleasure of the quaint and
        tranquil <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> village atmosphere remains, along with some lovely
        walks into the surrounding mountains. You should, however, acclimatize
        to the altitude before attempting any long hikes.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> can retrace the favorite promenades
        along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mall</ENAMEX> and see the old administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ridge</ENAMEX>. The
        place at which these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> meet is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kipling</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">‚ÄúScandal Point</ENAMEX>. ‚Äù
        At the eastern end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mall</ENAMEX> you can see the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gaiety Theatre</ENAMEX>, one-time
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Simla Amateur Dramatic Company</ENAMEX>, which is famous for its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">productions</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> drama and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edwardian</ENAMEX> operetta.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ridge</ENAMEX> leads past the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Neo-Gothic, Anglican Christ</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>, where the bells are made from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX> of cannons captured
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sikhs</ENAMEX>. At the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ridge</ENAMEX>, you‚Äôll find the baronial pile
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viceregal Lodge</ENAMEX>, nowadays used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute for Advanced</ENAMEX>
        Studies. You can imagine rickshaws pulling up onto the grounds of the
        ivy-covered grey stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> for one of the viceroy‚Äôs banquets. Peer
        into the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>, which has an elegant fireplace, a coffered
        ceiling, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">majestic staircase</ENAMEX>. Then continue to the top of Jakko
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>, where you can see a fine view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and valley.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kashmir</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vale</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,700 m</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5,000 ft</NUMEX>) above sea level,
        has historically offered much-needed respite for conquerors and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> alike. Passing through the deserts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sind</ENAMEX> and the hot and
        dusty plains of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ganga valley</ENAMEX>, they have heard tell of its blessed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">meadows</ENAMEX>, forests, full fruit orchards, and lakes. It remains the
        undisputed treasure of the entire subcontinent. Unfortunately,
        continuing tensions between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> have
        rendered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kashmir</ENAMEX> a dangerous place for travellers.
        In accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. State Department‚Äôs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        Foreign Office‚Äôs travel advisories, as well as warnings issued by most
        other foreign consulates, we do not recommend <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kashmir</ENAMEX> as a tourist
        destination. The following information is provided only for the sake of
        background on the area.
        Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the past, particularly during high <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>,
        made <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kashmir</ENAMEX> the principal destination of their visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>,
        combining it with perhaps just brief outings and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>-trips in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agra</ENAMEX>. Those making more extensive tours of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, planned to see
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kashmir</ENAMEX> at the end, with the intention of relaxing in a houseboat on a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">lake</ENAMEX> or going on a refreshing hike in the lush surrounding
        mountains.
        Travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kashmir</ENAMEX> used to require bookings and
        preparations far in advance of visiting. But since the increase in
        eruptions of violence over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past ten years</TIMEX>, foreign travel to the
        region has greatly decreased. During <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Kashmir‚</ENAMEX>Äôs height of popularity as
        a tourist destination, one of the area‚Äôs most alluring features was the
        unique accommodation on houseboats. Travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> can reserve a
        houseboat for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX>, allowing travellers to change around
        once they‚Äôve fully settled in. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> important and major advantage of
        advance reservations is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> will be met at the airport
        straight away by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of the houseboat-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">owner‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇit‚Äôs</ENAMEX> not
        easy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> to find their way among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>.
        Houseboats are a beautifully preserved tradition of the
        heyday of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Raj</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> was the
        most exotic hill-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> of them all, the maharaja forbade the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
        to buy land there, so they then hit on the brilliant alternative of
        building luxuriously appointed houseboats moored on the lakes near
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Srinagar</ENAMEX>. Equipped with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> upper-middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> comforts
        the colonials were used to, the more maneuverable, smaller houseboats
        made their way to other lakes for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>-shoots or just for the pleasures
        of the cruise, while the larger ones stayed languidly put.
        With so many new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> having been built in the same old
        style, boasting lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kashmiri</ENAMEX> carvings on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> and decks, many
        are too heavy to move around the waters. But the traditional comforts
        are the same: wood-burning stoves, plush armchairs in the living room,
        warm carpeting in the spacious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX>, superb personal service, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fine Kashmiri</ENAMEX> cuisine you can enjoy on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deck‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇnote</ENAMEX> that you can arrange
        with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> what you want to eat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>, Western or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
        style.
        Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">houseboats</ENAMEX> are moored on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dal Lake</ENAMEX>, but for those
        seeking seclusion, there are others on the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nagin Lake</ENAMEX> to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">west</ENAMEX>. They are well serviced by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">shikaras‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇgaily decorated</ENAMEX> and roofed
        canoes somewhat reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Venetian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gondolas‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇplying</ENAMEX> their way
        around the lake, ferrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>. There is also a floating market
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>. The shikaras will also show you carpets, silks,
        shawls, brassware, jewels, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carvings‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇand tailors‚</ENAMEX>Äô establishments
        with names like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savile Roy</ENAMEX>, recalling their old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> allegiance.
        Srinagar
        Srinagar, like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jammu</ENAMEX> and the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>, is still
        considered a dangerous place for foreign travellers. There is a strong
        military presence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dusk-till-dawn</TIMEX> curfew is often in
        effect. The heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir‚Äôs</ENAMEX> capital is built along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">serpentine Jhelum</ENAMEX> river on the southern shore of the lakes. The many
        bazaars, busy tailor‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, and government-operated emporiums are
        fascinating places to observe the style, panache, and never-ending gall
        of that charming and often shameless scoundrel, the Kashmiri
        merchant.
        Few monuments have survived <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kashmir‚</ENAMEX>Äôs troubled history,
        but the city‚Äôs beauty lies in its numerous tranquil lakes and gardens.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dal Lake</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adjoining Nagin</ENAMEX> offer leisurely cruises, with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers lounging</ENAMEX> on the cushions of a shikara. Lovely floating
        gardens growing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">melons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX>, cucumbers, and lotus root in a mesh
        of reeds and mud floating in the water and moored in squares by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poles</ENAMEX> stuck in the lake bed, add to the tranquil beauty of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">lake</ENAMEX>.
        On the western shore of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dal Lake</ENAMEX>, is the large white <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX>
        and minarets of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazratbal Mosque</ENAMEX>, famous for its relic, the hair of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beard of the prophet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed</ENAMEX>.
        There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> small squares of land that rise up out of
        the lake: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sonalank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Akbar‚Äôs Golden Island</ENAMEX> to the north, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruplank</ENAMEX>,
        Silver <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX>, to the south.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> hills, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hari Parbat</ENAMEX> to the north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shankaracharya</ENAMEX> to the east, offer pleasant walks‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇwith the reward of a
        magnificent view over the lakes and the whole Vale of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">134 km</NUMEX>
        long and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 km</NUMEX> wide (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">82 by 25 miles</NUMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mughal Gardens</ENAMEX> are on the eastern shore of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dal Lake</ENAMEX>.
        For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jahangir</ENAMEX>, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> idea of paradise had any meaning, it was
        here, amid the staggered terraces, tranquil <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX>, waterfalls, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, looking out over the lake against the backdrop of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himalayas</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, there‚Äôs a sound-and-light show at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jahangir‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shalimar Bagh</ENAMEX>, laid out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1616</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> are able to relax
        here as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> did, by lingering on the terraces to take in the
        changing scene that surround them. The white marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> on the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX> was used for public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> was a private
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pavilion</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">third‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇmade</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">black marble‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇaccommodated the harem,
        and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> was strictly reserved for the emperor‚Äôs private use.
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three km</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 miles</NUMEX>) to the south, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nishat Bagh</ENAMEX> was laid out
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1633</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asaf Khan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jahangir‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. It is the largest
        of the gardens, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> terraces and lined with fine cedars and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cypresses</ENAMEX>. It offers a magnificent view of the lake beyond.
        Tucked away in a small fold of the hills is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chashma Shahi</ENAMEX>,
        the smallest but in many ways most exquisite of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughal Gardens</ENAMEX>,
        drawing its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> from a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> that runs directly down the adjacent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mountainside</ENAMEX>.
        Excursions from Srinagar
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pahalgam</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 95 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60 miles</NUMEX>) east of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Srinagar</ENAMEX>. The route there runs through groves of willow, used for the
        local <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">cricket</ENAMEX>-bat industry, and fields of saffron. If you‚Äôve ever
        wondered why saffron is so expensive, it‚Äôs because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX> of these
        purple or white crocuses (only the stamen is orange) are necessary to
        make up a single kilogram (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2 pounds</NUMEX>) of saffron proper, the stuff that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flavors</ENAMEX> and colors those famous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paella</ENAMEX>.
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> is the only other place in the world apart from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> where
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">saffron</ENAMEX> is grown extensively. )
        The most popular journey from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pahalgam</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">45 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">27 miles</NUMEX>)
        up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Amarnath Cave</ENAMEX>, which has an altitude of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 3,895</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,742</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ft</ENAMEX>). Sacred to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hindus</ENAMEX>, it is a destination of devout pilgrimage on
        festive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> for the sight of the imposing stalagmite called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shiva‚</ENAMEX>Äôs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lingam</ENAMEX>; this phallic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX> stands for the god‚Äôs fertility, power, and
        creativity. Just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">22 miles</NUMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pahalgam</ENAMEX>, one trek, the most
        strenuous by far, leads to the spectacular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kolahoi Glacier</ENAMEX>.
        Gulmarg, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">52 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">32 miles</NUMEX>) west of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Srinagar</ENAMEX>, is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2,653</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8,622 ft</NUMEX>) above sea level. It is currently developing its winter
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sports</ENAMEX> in addition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf and tennis</ENAMEX> already provided. There is
        wonderful hiking here, too, through pine forests and meadows carpeted
        with wildflowers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>.
        THE <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WEST</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> is, above all, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rajasthan</ENAMEX>, land of the great
        maharajas, with its desert and lake <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>, but it‚Äôs also the bustle
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mumbai</ENAMEX> and the splendor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cave temples</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ajanta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellora</ENAMEX>.
        There is also the great bonus, further down the coast, of the stunning
        beaches of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goa</ENAMEX>.
        Introducing Rajasthan
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajasthan</ENAMEX> is undoubtedly one of the most romantic regions
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. Known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rajputana</ENAMEX>, and stretching from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pakistani Sind</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punjab</ENAMEX>, this land is where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rajput warriors</ENAMEX>
        erected their desert and mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">redoubts</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>-fortresses were
        built with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">granite</ENAMEX> from the surrounding hills, and with the same
        dazzling marble used for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Taj Mahal</ENAMEX>.
        The great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaisalmer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jodhpur</ENAMEX> are on the
        ancient caravan routes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indus Valley</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Thar Desert</ENAMEX>, for
        this is a land of cattle-herders too. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of their most spectacular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monuments</ENAMEX> is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">market-festival</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pushkar</ENAMEX> held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> (see page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209</NUMEX>).
        Probably descendants of the invading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scythians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huns</ENAMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajputs</ENAMEX> were a formidable opposition met by the waves of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invaders‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚ÄÇTurks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghans</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughals</ENAMEX>. Despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rajputs‚Äô ‚Äúforeign‚</ENAMEX>Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">origin</ENAMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">claimed ‚Äúdescendancy‚Äù</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aryan</ENAMEX> dynasties of the sun
        and moon was accepted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brahman</ENAMEX> priesthood and they were duly
        inducted retroactively into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kshatriya</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior caste</ENAMEX>, a caste to
        which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajputs</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> continue proudly to belong .
        While the nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malwa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gujarat</ENAMEX> came under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> rule,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajputana</ENAMEX> remained <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX>. Towns with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suffix -pur</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>;
        -abad is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> suffix. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rajput</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princes</ENAMEX> pursued an independent
        line. Others sent their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> to the harem or their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> to serve
        as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>. They enjoyed a privileged position
        during the time of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Raj</ENAMEX>.
        Jaipur
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rajasthan</ENAMEX> was built according to
        astrological precepts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raja Jai Singh II</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> who
        dotted northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> with his collections of instruments for observing
        the heavens, chose an exact date for moving his capital from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Amber‚ÄÇ‚Äî‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇ17
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1727‚ÄÇ‚</TIMEX>Äî‚ÄÇas auspicious. He then laid it out according to the
        disposition of the stars and planets.
        But let‚Äôs begin at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amber</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9 km</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 miles</NUMEX>) northeast of
        Jaipur, high up on a hill commanding a gorge, which offered military
        advantage but was not right for the expanded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> he wanted for his
        capital.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber</ENAMEX> takes you through classical
        Rajasthani landscape, its parched hills embracing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Maota</ENAMEX>, where
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water buffalo snooze lazily</ENAMEX> in the sun. You may also pass an occasional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camel</ENAMEX>, that time-honored vehicle of transport known as the ‚Äúship of the
