
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi there my name is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scott</ENAMEX> where you calling from
 	
 	
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget</ENAMEX>
 		i'm calling from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> where are you calling from
 	
 	
 		i oh i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> yep but i had i'm out of breath because i had to run to find my card because i didn't remember my PIN i haven't done this in a while it's been probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three three or four months</TIMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		oh do you
 		oh really
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah well we  we we got on it um a long time ago but then it was down so much of the time you kind of got out of the out of the habit
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so anyway so what are we supposed to talk about
 	
 	
 		i think we're supposed to talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> magazines
 	
 	
 		okay okay so what so what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> do you take
 	
 	
 		um i don't take any do i need to push one first okay hold on
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well now if you don't take any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> why would you why would you want to talk about magazines
 	
 	
 		i didn't i said it i called in and it told me to talk about i don't subscribe to any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> do you
 	
 	
 		i subscribe to lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> yes my family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well well</ENAMEX> we're we're kind of renowned for being big magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you really
 		really so how come you like subscribing to them
 	
 	
 		well because i i i have a lot of interests and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> have a lot of interesting articles and
 		and it's just my way to keep up and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s sitting here telling me it's because i'm a bookworm  uh so she calls it a true bookworm no i like to read and so i take a lot of magazines
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> do you get
 	
 	
 		well let's see i get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Economist</ENAMEX> get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX> i get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harpers</ENAMEX> um we get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i get um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fine Woodworking</ENAMEX> um what else do we get here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um let's see then i get a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes i</ENAMEX> also oh i get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Republic</ENAMEX> here at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> as well i read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh goodness</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i don't know we i'd probably some and sometimes i take them for a while and then sometimes i i you know i'll let them lapse and then i'll get something new
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> so you get a well you get a lot see i'm in college so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i usually get mostly business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> so so all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> i ever see they're just advertising so i don't ever subscribe to them so but that's good though
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		do you are are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> out at at out at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> really which year are you in out there
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i'm gonna i'm a senior yes i love it
 	
 	
 		do you like it
 		well how'd you get on this uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> thing then
 	
 	
 		see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and they started in and they sent it to me and so that's how i got started
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so i thought well i can do this you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's not too hard but i i've called in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> times but then like i said it was down so much that i got out of the habit and then i'm not usually home so i'm not usually here when when when when they try because i don't i haven't done it very often
 	
 	
 		when they try and call yeah
 		yeah i just started so i'm always like now what do i do i'm always like what
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't
 	
 	
 		but didn't you have to fill out a form where it said that you would check off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and stuff on it
 	
 	
 		yeah but i didn't know they'd ask me if i subscribed to them i can talk about magazines
 	
 	
 		well now what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> do you like to read
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um hm</ENAMEX> see i really i mean i don't even read i don't even grab <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> or even look at them
 	
 	
 		well if you had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> bucks and you couldn't do anything except spend them on magazines what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> would you would you get would you would you buy
 	
 	
 		well i think right now i'd buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bride</ENAMEX> because i just got engaged so i'd buy that
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> are like phone books aren't they they're like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX> pages of advertising uh uh of ads or something in them
 	
 	
 		i know they're huge
 		i know i think i'd buy like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home and Gardens</ENAMEX> and stuff like that yeah i like stuff like that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really really
 		really
 	
 	
 		i used to get like a horse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and stuff i used to show horses so yeah
 	
 	
 		really that's neat
 	
 	
 		so you see a lot of horse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> but that was quite a while ago
 	
 	
 		there so did you did you uh um uh uh ride them and stuff what do they call it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dursege</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah i used to ride them English uh-huh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter jumper</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum  well that's good
 	
 	
 		so i used to get lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> for that but every since i stopped at that and went to college and i really haven't got any more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> for that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum um-hum my
 	
 	
 		but those are probably the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> i'd get
 	
 	
 		well you could buy an awful lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bride</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> i don't know it it
 	
 	
 		i know that's right
 	
 	
 		we have some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsstands</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> you know that have like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and i could buy a lot i could buy a lot of magazines
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you get a lot of them that's great though
 	
 	
 		well there's more that i could get
 	
 	
 		that's great though because especially with business though because i know like with business stuff because when they first asked me this i was like well God i they're like why do you like articles or or
 		why do you not like magazines i was like because it has so many advertising but business ones don't really and they're really informative
 	
 	
 		um-hum well they have a lot of they i don't know they have a lot of different different kinds of ads and stuff in them
 	
 	
 		yeah but they're very they're very informative informative i think that's great
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 		i guess so what are you majoring in out there
 	
 	
 		um i major in psychology in family studies yeah
 	
 	
 		really
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		i like it a lot
 		i love it up here i like it better than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you you you like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> better than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> why
 	
 	
 		yeah uh because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are so much nicer yes
 	
 	
 		really <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are nice here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh  it's just a different atmosphere i think
 	
 	
 		you don't think so huh
 		where'd you go to high school
 	
 	
 		i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birkner High School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richardson High School</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	