
 
     		
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy</ENAMEX> have you had any uh experiences with your nieces in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> to indicate that something's wrong with the school system
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well they they don't seem to discipline the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> like they used to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when i was in school i'm i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only twenty nine</TIMEX> and i i hadn't been out of college that long but when we were in grade school
 		we you know if you got in trouble you definitely got paddled or you know something something was done and now they can't touch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah do you think that's the fault of the school system or society or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it's really a combination the fact that so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> refuse to let the school discipline their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and the fact that they let
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> file law suits for one thing i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and she says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> can hit you kick you stab you and you can not touch them and if you touch them then they can sue you and they can sue sue the school system
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so it's really no more a failure of society
 	
 	
 		i i think so i think so and and i you couldn't pay me enough to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> in a bad in a bad city
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no
 	
 	
 		and and and our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> where you know maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there's not a problem
 	
 	
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> school  the stories she tells oh yes
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah
 		it's unbelievable the things and and of course the sweet little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		within
 		well the neighborhood that she's in is is very economically deprived and that is reflected in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> abilities i mean they have no support at home
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so for if you casually looked at it you could say maybe the test scores in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> are bad and and therefore there's a failure of the public school system
 		but when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are not interested or don't have the resources or
 		can't even read themselves
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that sort of thing it it's bound to affect the education of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well yeah and the fact that they're not putting enough money
 		into the schools
 	
 	
 		oh well
 	
 	
 		you know and they don't even have adequate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		i just wonder where all the money goes i mean my
 	
 	
 		well isn't isn't that the truth
 	
 	
 		
 
 		my taxes are exorbitant
 		and  i i i don't think you solve problems too much by throwing money at it i think you have to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> interested and have to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> support and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum and and let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> give them a little more you're right give them a little more support and a little more to work with
 		and as these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get older it's it's even harder yeah because then you know their minds are made up as to what they're gonna do by then
 	
 	
 		oh i'm sure it is i'm sure it is
 		well yes and if you don't develop an interest in reading at an early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> it gets awfully hard a lot later on
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah they see no point you know we've gotten away with it this far
 	
 	
 		that's right but again society's uh influences i think can affect how well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> perform more than this than what the public school is or is not doing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean certainly  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and and peer pressures of that sort
 		can again make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> fail and therefore look like that there's something something deficient about the public school system
 	
 	
 		yeah and it just frightens me when i think about  having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and sending them to school where they're they're selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in in grade school
 	
 	
 		
 
 		isn't that scary
 	
 	
 		i can't imagine i mean we wouldn't even have known what they were talking about let alone take something or you know sell it buy it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i i just can't imagine that it has has come so far
 		that there's little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> dealing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> dealing to the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		that's right but then then again that's something that that's very difficult for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to try to control
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		this principal i know does the best she can in terms of dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> this is a grade school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		yes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who carry <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> to school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX>  and when we were little when we went to grade school we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waxahachie</ENAMEX> and little bitty town you know little bitty school
 		and there was i i i just  it is beyond my comprehension
 		to imagine grade schoolers with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's just you might as well just have a police file on them
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		you know because you you know you you learn who the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are and you know what they're doing and it's you can't do anything to them
 	
 	
 		that's right but when there are disruptive influences like that in the school i think it makes it especially difficult for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who want to learn
 	
 	
 		it really does
 		because even even the ones that are that want to will let the other ones bully them out of it
 		
 		
 	