
 
     		
 	
 		have any great vacation spots to share with me
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh  well most
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> most of my big vacations i think are probably in the past i've been you know to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> a couple of times and
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		and to
 	
 	
 		where in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rio huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> did you go
 	
 	
 		oh okay uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holland France</ENAMEX>
 		uh one of the interesting most interesting ones was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> we were there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> and this was back in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX> before you know the wall came down
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so that was very interesting to go into
 		you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and all that course it's kind of laughable now but you know that's the way it was then
 	
 	
 		that's not
 		you say you were there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> i'm
 	
 	
 		oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX>
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so we were visiting them
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry i interrupted you you was always saying also saying that you'd gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah uh another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>  all my  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> used to live in all these interesting places uh they're all retired and back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> now but one lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rio</ENAMEX> and that was
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		we went there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about ten days</TIMEX> and that was quite a beautiful place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so
 	
 	
 		so a lot lot of your big vacations have been international
 	
 	
 		to
 		yeah and to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> worked lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> so we went there you know for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> so uh
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		do you like to travel domestically as well do you do you take vacations around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		uh yes uh-huh in fact that's probably where we'll go in the remaining <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> we'll probably just stay right here in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for some we i think we could afford more back then than we can now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we're caught in this economic crunch
 	
 	
 		yes i can relate to that
 	
 	
 		we also had a time share condo if you're familiar with those so we used and it was our home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vail Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		and then if you didn't want to go there you could switch and go actually anywhere anywhere in the world and
 	
 	
 		did you ski when you were there
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vail</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah a little but we waited we were too old when we started going to really learn the you know like our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> learned well and skied well but you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you that's something you really i think should learn when you're younger
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know you wait until you're forty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and start learning to ski well then you're afraid you're going to break something
 	
 	
 		it's true it's true
 	
 	
 		now i've done all the talking you tell me what you've done
 	
 	
 		yours are much more exciting than mine um i think probably finances have limited us um primarily my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> um
 		because i'm the oldest when i left
 		um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> went on some really fun vacations so it's more the things that i've done with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and and more recently our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that uh
 		that we that i could probably talk about
 	
 	
 		well you're much younger what age are you
 	
 	
 		well i'm not actually i just started my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> younger  i mean started my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> later um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty six</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s only
 	
 	
 		well that is young go ahead
 	
 	
 		my
 		well but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> so  at my age i think that my my mother
 		i mean when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was my age i think that i was probably twelve or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah but but that was the trend back then you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you had your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early twenties</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		it
 		right
 		at any rate we've really enjoyed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">camping</TIMEX> vacations i think that that's probably the thing that we've uh done most <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> we'll take short short little vacations maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and there's so many places in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Francisco Bay area</ENAMEX> that you can camp that you don't really have to go very far you can drive as little as an hour and get into a redwood forest and feel like you're just
 	
 	
 		oh and such beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> up around you
 	
 	
 		it is really nice to have that very close
 		um there are some places up the coast near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mendocino</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX> that have what they call environmental cabins so
 		you can rent them fairly inexpensively and stay <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple nights</TIMEX> and feel like you have a little beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> getaway
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so we've done that a few times too you know it's very rustic you don't you bring all your own things and you bring your your your cooler almost as if you were camping but there's a stove and there's a
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		a table and and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX> for your bed mattress and that sort of thing so it's somewhat set up
 		those we've really enjoyed i think what i'd like to do when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s a little older
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and if we have other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> its uh the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">med</TIMEX> vacations that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i enjoyed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> because there's so many different activities
 	
 	
 		um-hum and and they you can take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> now can't you
 	
 	
 		yes they call them club <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah okay i knew i knew something about that uh-huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes they have all kinds of art activities and sports that are tailored for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and babysitters if you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that are you know infants
 		
 		
 	