
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		you think health benefits probably the the most important
 	
 	
 		yes for because most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are aging getting older and the benefits uh the benefits are going up i mean the price is going up
 	
 	
 		that's true that
 	
 	
 		everything seems to go up
 	
 	
 		that that's the case or the problem i have i'm getting older and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and uh we
 		use the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> more have um more health problems and that is a very important benefit that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah see here where well here where i live all the benefits have been going up lately up on health and there are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> that have we have a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one cent</NUMEX> tax and then
 	
 	
 		what
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is coming up with this health plan so i don't know much much about it then
 	
 	
 		no i've i haven't really studied that too much but uh that is one of the benefits that uh
 		that i feel that uh is real good
 		with uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i work for so far but uh it it's uh
 		you know what's gonna happen their costs keep going up as you say and it's uh it could wipe a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> out or uh all your savings and everything <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> serious illness
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> illness will do it
 	
 	
 		i think that's uh one of the benefits that we really need to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> need really need to take a look at because there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> that are not covered at all that's uh
 		quite a situation i think the other thing uh security and that that's getting pretty tough now a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a job with security
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh especially if you're in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> of defense or you're in the auto industry been working for fifteen or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> and all of a sudden uh
 		because of changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> this uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays holidays</TIMEX> so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are losing their jobs and uh i don't know how you can as as a benefit how you could have have security as one but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like to have that security in their jobs
 	
 	
 		yeah i would i would think so well that's one of the main main i would think one of the main securities that you would need is health benefit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i'll say yeah it really is and uh it's uh you really feel sorry for those who don't have it or they have a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uh cancer</ENAMEX> or something real serious that uh could runs up their uh transplant heart transplant or something runs up into
 		uh um  <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of thousands of dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		that could wipe you out in a hurry
 	
 	
 		well we i have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> died and she had some benefits that helped through her well they had her hooked up and everything but that helped her helped us through it
 	
 	
 		good good good a good thing that uh they she had those i think there's other uh
 		well there's other benefits that uh kind of or look at i guess uh need a vacation once in a while most jobs do that
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		uh give you some time off and uh that's something that uh
 		each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s a little different on that but most of them are pretty good on those uh those type of benefits i think
 	
 	
 		um-hum just just with the benefits going up it's just there's not a whole lot you can do about it really
 	
 	
 		no there isn't and another one i think is uh quite important of course is retirement system that they they have
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and uh with social security and uh the way it is if that's all you got is social security by then
 	
 	
 		you're not gonna make it very far
 	
 	
 		right by the time i get up there uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> and uh draw social security with the cost of living uh that benefit is just really not gonna help very much
 	
 	
 		no i don't think that would
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh the older the older you probably you would probably need more help
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> don't have the money and the ones that do well they have insurance so
 	
 	
 		no
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		it's it's just a i think it they need to extend them
 		because we're we're paying here a lot
 	
 	
 		um-hum yes
 	
 	
 		and
 		i think the elderly needs it more than anything
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's true and uh it seems like it goes up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> you have no control over the the cost to you and that just takes away your buying power also and uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of course i can see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s side uh too because uh they have to pay uh an a proportion of whatever the
 		the health cost is and it gets to the point where uh they're not uh making money and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it uh
 		i don't wanna see us to go socialized medicine like they are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> or places like that
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		but still uh i i hope that this plan that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s come up with uh is gonna help all those or help some way
 		bottom line though who's gonna pay for it
 	
 	
 		really have they got it have they already signed that or that's not signed yet is it
 	
 	
 		no no he he just uh proposed it and uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republicans</ENAMEX> are saying hey it's a great plan the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> say it's no good so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well they
 		
 		
 	