
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		have you snow had any snow up your way
 	
 	
 		no we haven't had any since uh oh just before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
 		and uh we got a lot before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> the ski <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> were really excited and uh but now uh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		we have we've had fog for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days in a row</TIMEX> and temperature inversion so but no uh no snow
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX>'s all melted off the mountains uh
 	
 	
 		well i talked to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who lived up in the hills uh mountains in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		guess this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> and she had uh quite a bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> on the ground her way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i guess there there's different parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> that that that does have some but uh not usually we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to a hundred</NUMEX> and fifty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">inches</NUMEX> up at the ski <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX> and they're down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between thirty eight</TIMEX> and uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> inches
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		this time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> and uh we've been in a drought for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five years</TIMEX> this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> year
 		and it's getting quite serious as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well the weather uh here is always a topic of conversation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		we have wide variations and have
 		warm weather when most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have cold weather but we have our share of cold weather as well the uh temperature <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> was right at freezing it didn't stay there but it was
 	
 	
 		oh well that's that's different isn't it
 	
 	
 		right at
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		we usually have some of our coldest weather toward the uh
 		end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> it wasn't bad at all i guess that's because we had so much rain
 	
 	
 		i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was telling me about the rain down there he said yeah well it just  and we read in the newspaper southern part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		flooded out
 	
 	
 		well my uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and they uh
 		the river there was uh in the flooding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> near where her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> lives and that uh
 		caused some uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> of course
 		they have a uh lake <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> and uh their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX> was completely under water on the lake
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		so we really had a lot of rain
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> he lives fairly close to there's quite a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wash</ENAMEX> that goes down uh through Plano
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh there's walking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> on both sides a walking path and uh when i've gone down to visit him i've gone on that but uh that was clear full and up to up to some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> i guess it just gets
 	
 	
 		yeah we had a lot of flash floods in the area we had a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who ran into uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and a few fatalities just uh just uh a few not more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's funny that uh we can't have it in moderation instead of having either a drought or having too much
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		seems like
 	
 	
 		well the uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there's an old profane
 		expression about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> weather it's always too damn cold too damn hot too damn windy
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's uh interesting uh i'm going down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh i was wondering what the weather was but i imagine that if it's that cold in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Paso</ENAMEX> won't be cold
 	
 	
 		it's not a doesn't get that cold i guess huh
 	
 	
 		no it's it's quite southern and it's it's rare to get real cold in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX>
 		the uh
 		you'll be flying in there
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		well uh take off is uh fun from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX> because you normally the way the winds are you take off right toward the mountain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockies</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and they're towering above you and so you circle back over the air and then make a circle around and come back over again
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah we're kind of used to that here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> of course there are mountains and i fly into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> a lot and we have a
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX> are are really uh high and a lot of places we go into you just kind of uh it's in the little valley but
 		and i uh sure hope we we really need the moisture i hope we can get uh get some there's supposed to be a storm but it split went down through uh northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> and southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		they're not predicting any for the next uh week anyway up here so
 	
 	
 		well i noticed on the weather map on uh cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> that
 		there was supposed to be a storm front moving into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and on down your way but i guess it didn't pan out huh
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's that's what the  went above uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		some of it went to the south and some to the north up into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> so that just left us we got a high pressure
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		system that's just been sitting in here and uh we broke the record for the amount of fog that we've had uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>'s been shut down uh till <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about noon</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday</TIMEX> and they they seed the clouds or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX> the fog to try to
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> in and out
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well we uh had a bad siege last uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas a year ago</TIMEX> we went up to visit my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> who lives in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calgary Alberta Canada</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	