
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well so you you don't know too much about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Mavericks</ENAMEX> this this
 	
 	
 		no what where they at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> uh they win in their division
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no they are uh only just a slightly a bit better than uh the other expansion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> they're they're they're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in disarray right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh do you do you have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> pass you go watch them or
 	
 	
 		actually i used to and i gave it up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> because i thought well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Tarpley</ENAMEX> wasn't going to make it and sure enough <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> after i decided not to buy my ticket he went down with his uh his drug problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and uh boy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> just is going into a tailspin since then
 	
 	
 		yeah that's too bad i'm i guess i'd be most familiar with uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i've never watched them but uh interestingly enough i i i got to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Malone</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're kidding
 	
 	
 		huh-uh uh well it  i live <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about forty five miles</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackpot Nevada</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how'd you manage that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's a town it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> where they uh have uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> and so forth
 		and i guess that's one of his pastimes i caught him down there and he was playing the slot machines and uh yeah you know would you know it somebody like him
 		he hit a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five thousand dollar</NUMEX> jackpot and then he turned around hit hit another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX> dollar jackpot
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and they came and took his picture and you know got the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> forms and stuff and he sat there and put all the money back into the machine lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">every penny</NUMEX> of it didn't bother him a bit
 	
 	
 		sound sounds like a real game huh
 	
 	
 		just yeah just doing it for enjoyment
 	
 	
 		well he must he must be a pretty big guy
 	
 	
 		it was incredible when he stood up he just towered he was a good foot above anybody in there
 	
 	
 		gee
 	
 	
 		and uh everybody everybody was uh kind of excited to see him and he's he oddly enough he was uh very friendly and cordial and stopped to sign a few things and
 	
 	
 		well it's it's it's nice to see those those you know those kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> when they get paid all those big bucks to uh you know to be halfway friendly
 	
 	
 		so it was it was neat
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i know what you mean about talking about being big i mean that's when i was in high school
 		i got i went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland Cavaliers</ENAMEX> game i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>
 		and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine runs or used to run the clock down on the floor so he'd let me get down on the floor at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> time and i stood by these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> they all walked out and and gee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX> they're just monsters
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> foot doesn't sound that tall but boy when you stand next to one  it it is real tall
 	
 	
 		yep yeah i hear you so
 	
 	
 		so if you you don't you don't get down to uh basketball games very often then
 	
 	
 		i don't no we've got a small of course this isn't professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> but uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSI Golden Eagles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know if you've heard of them they're they're number they're the number one junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> excuse me
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and uh so they're here and they're kind of fun to go watch but uh uh that's that's the the most closest i get to in fact i've only seen one professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> game uh
 	
 	
 		so you didn't watch the all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> game uh yesterday
 	
 	
 		i kind of watched it on television parts of it i didn't i didn't see the whole thing
 	
 	
 		yeah i i got out the weather was so nice here that i got out and didn't didn't see any of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh yeah well well what do you think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Johnson</ENAMEX> should he play or should he
 	
 	
 		well that's uh you you talking about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> is uh what they
 	
 	
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> is his next thing
 		well i really you know it's it's his choice to play but there's a lot of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s choice not not to play against him i think he's gonna find a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just say well heck i'm not going to worry you know i'm not gonna mess with that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh-huh yeah well i don't i think they that they'd feel that way too interestingly enough they've kept a seat a seat open
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and he may even play in the in the tournament games for uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		are you serious
 	
 	
 		i'm serious i heard that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> on a sports
 	
 	
 		how can how can they do that if he doesn't played the whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i don't know i don't know i guess the roster's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> you know there's a hole there still
 	
 	
 		oh unless they yeah unless they're just carrying a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> odd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> instead of carrying the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> that they carry just carry <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> less
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		that's what they've done
 	
 	
 		well i you know i didn't watch the game but a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine was telling me that he you know he played a lot but he he played then he'd sit down then he'd play and he'd sit down and it wasn't like he was out there for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty or thirty minutes</TIMEX> at a at a go
 	
 	
 		and there's
 		yeah
 		no he wasn't and the the the part i saw is he he made the last shot of the game off balance three pointer and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i guess so
 	
 	
 		yeah once once uh he starts losing that weight and can't keep it on you know he'll have to slow down and not not do that kind of stuff that that's got to be awful tough awful tough on his body
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well when's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mavericks gonna</ENAMEX> do something
 	
 	
 		oh gee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX>  the the they are
 	
 	
 		they need more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they need a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> what do they need
 	
 	
 		they need <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and and they need a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front office</ENAMEX> that that can judge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> we've traded away so many good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX> and got nothing for them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and drafted so many bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and you know they haven't turned out
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		it's uh it's very frustrating we had we had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> where we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round picks
 		and we picked uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> by the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Wittington</ENAMEX> uh who's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> foot center a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uvay Blob</ENAMEX> another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> foot white center
 		and they are both okay but i think both of them are playing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and they you know they they traded away <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Aguirre</ENAMEX> and got nothing for him
 		i mean he had to go but they they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	