
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we're talking about taxes
 	
 	
 		taxes right you think you think you pay too much
 	
 	
 		all right well you
 	
 	
 		is what they said and do you think you'd get what you pay for
 	
 	
 		that's hard to say you know i think it take a lot for granted you know and it's the the quick answer i think would be that you pay too much taxes you know but but i think if you think about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> we have all the uh federal programs we have whether they're good or bad um
 		sure seems like you do get a bang you know it seems like a lot of stuff's going on even though every paycheck a lot of money's coming out
 		um i don't know i don't know it seems like so i used to think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> spent too much and they probably do but
 		you know when you go to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s private also and uh they're gonna charge you a good buck for whatever they're doing also so well what do you think
 	
 	
 		right
 		well i really feel in some areas that uh i agree i don't think any of us like paying taxes i think in some areas we could do better in a private sector
 		i think it just i've done some reading on this and some and in some of the areas you know you're lucky to get back a a dime on a dollar on some programs
 		uh but i also know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to me won't do what they should do to help each other and they wouldn't have so much government if we did
 		and uh we get you know gets forced into it i think socialized medicine's coming which i hate to see but i think because there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> without insurance that's what's coming you know it's coming
 	
 	
 		yeah it's needed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so uh
 		but no i don't probably feel like i get back what i pay now you do you pay state income tax in
 	
 	
 		yeah i i pay actually <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state city</ENAMEX> and federal
 	
 	
 		yeah see here a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we're lucky because we don't pay um state income tax but they get us in other ways you know
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah well i i just figured it out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i get uh i think my my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two week</TIMEX> pay is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen hundred</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> dollars or something like that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen sixteen</TIMEX> something around there and my
 		take home after taxes is about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 	
 	
 		so <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX> every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> comes out you know and obviously if you make
 		you know <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty thousand dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> you're paying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten thousand</NUMEX> in dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in taxes and everybody who's in that type of income is paying that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think that's another problem
 	
 	
 		you know plus sales tax right
 	
 	
 		uh yeah well that's where they got us here you know every time they need something they up the quote user's fees or the sin taxes you know on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and such
 	
 	
 		
 
 		sure sure and plus you pay if you buy cigarettes you pay tax on that if you buy beer
 	
 	
 		yeah so just because we don't have a state income tax they get us proportionately higher in other areas
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so i don't know
 	
 	
 		you
 		you don't have a state income tax in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		that's so yeah that's not so bad but they still have to get the money somewhere to
 	
 	
 		they get it somewhere and and the problem is with that if you have a state income tax you can take it off you federal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so we can't take our any of our sales taxes or anything off anymore because of the reform
 		but that's what they up it they up it on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX> they up it on um say <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and cigarettes uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>'s fee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license license plates it all just keeps going up and up and up and they tell us it's not really taxes
 		you know you know but
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it is and uh no i don't know i don't know what the answer is to all this i think uh
 	
 	
 		same difference
 		
 
 		what
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		i i think it's a i i don't know i i think i think it's like private like you said privatization is good because
 		you know when the profit uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> good thing that could be said for the profit motive is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't going to run a business at a loss i happen to work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of New York</ENAMEX> and uh that's the attitude that uh at least my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> takes
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know they they when they take the attitude that uh this is a business
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and and if you're not going to run it profitably then you're going to be out of business because they are going to privatize it so in that sense you know at my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and and it's unique i think for government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> is revenue producing
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and we make more money than we than we cost so uh
 	
 	
 		well that's really unusual
 	
 	
 		so nobody's ever going to question my salary or anybody else on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> uh especially my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> because my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> is a revenue producing unit uh there are other
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know things that that may i mean look at that i was talking to my father <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> program
 		you know he thought it was kind of ridiculous we spend all this money to send these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rocket ships</ENAMEX> up into space and stuff but yet then again they come up with all these scientific discoveries that may help save us sometime i mean i think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		that we've learned a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah you do learn a lot so you're not you you know you're paying all this money but you're getting something back for it uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know military spending is the same thing whether you agree or you disagree with building all these bombs and stuff which i happen to have a tendency to disagree with
 		uh you know we are buying protection you know we are protecting ourselves from from uh from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that we may be afraid of whether it's right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		
 		
 	