
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		so what do you think
 	
 	
 		i figured you were going to ask me <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> here i was going to ask you first this is a difficult one i mean unfortunately the first thoughts are sort of negative
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but then when i give myself a chance to think about it a little bit more i recognize the positives as well uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		positives for sure are technology and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um some of the changes that the computer age has brought i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> growing up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are just
 		uh very much more facile than i was as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in terms of the use of computer technology and you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right that's true i mean i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty six now</TIMEX> and i came through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> with about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> that had computers in the classroom
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and all that and it certainly has been good for me
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so i see myself
 		you know when i learn a new system a new program or a new computer language that it's much easier for me than for let's say
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> who are a lot older but just as intelligent and whatever
 	
 	
 		um-hum and the earlier you learn
 		yes the younger you are probably the easier it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		some of that i think probably we take for granted you know the changes have happened so rapidly that it's it's easy for us to forget how quickly it has changed
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		i think probably the other thing i that came to mind is is the increased awareness on our part of the the criminal element if i can put it that way you know you don't
 		you don't uh casually let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> play in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> or you know ride their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> if you're in an area where you're at all concerned about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and what do you think that's just a question of becoming more aware or has it become less safe over the years
 	
 	
 		abduction
 		i think it's changed i think that in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last twenty</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX> there's definitely been an increase in that type of crime
 	
 	
 		yeah i would agree with you
 	
 	
 		and i'm not sure why you know uh certainly a question that we could spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> on you know whether whether there is a change in
 	
 	
 		um that's right
 	
 	
 		in the way a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> grow up whether or not there is you know more mental illness or something that causes that sort of
 		thing to go on uh i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i don't know i think a lot of what causes it is just economics
 		naturally
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but you know kidnapping is a strange thing you know what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> today are not nearly as free as i was when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in terms of just being able to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> by myself or riding my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> around the neighborhood or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		being being informed at a very young age about uh going to a shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and what to do if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX> approaches you i mean i never had a concept of that as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> so that's certainly changed a lot in the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i suppose it has uh
 	
 	
 		anyway what are some positives that you could  you've thought about besides  spending too much time on the criminal element
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right uh it's
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		well let's see i think that the mass communication that we have in the world now is in general a good thing and i think it has its good points and
 		bad points but in general it's pretty positive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it really does bring us together as a global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX> doesn't it
 	
 	
 		uh more or less yes i mean it is we have the
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		global village you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maclean</ENAMEX> was saying but it doesn't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't think that it really means that we have a sense of community yet as a world
 	
 	
 		uh that's a good point
 	
 	
 		which
 		which hopefully maybe coming we'll have to see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i think that's something that uh is a political influence as well you know probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel it on a personal level more than they might
 		um on a on a global level you know just being informed about what other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		other cultures are doing
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		in a way that we might not have been informed before but yet politically uh their activities aren't aren't
 		influencing how our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> direct
 		legislation as as much as they could
 		it's still really focused on our interests you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		well yeah that's definitely right i mean and when we're
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		right well with things like the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> we were
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		dealing with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s affairs for our own interests certainly is what i believe
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> uh
 		burning up the uh
 		the rain forests in order to have more <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> grazing so that  somehow that's something that's not going to work out in the long term in that kind of a cycle it's going to catch up to us at some point
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what else has changed social changes uh i think that there's probably a greater awareness sensitivity on the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to to what the other
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> is adjusting to in life
 		
 		
 	