
 
     		
 	
 		okay this subject is magazines what do you like and what do you dislike about magazines
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i like them because i can read them at my convenience and i don't like a lot of the ads i get in them especially those stupid cards that fall out of them all the time
 	
 	
 		that's my main complaint on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> too and i get magazines  some of them are just pictures and advertisements
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
  
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Life</ENAMEX> magazine is like that i quit subscribing to that it's just uh magazine i mean pictures and um
 		advertisements what is your favorite magazine
 	
 	
 		oh i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> like uh the home remodeling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Decorating</ENAMEX> and Remodeling things like that because you can see what other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are doing with their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and maybe you could do it in yours
 	
 	
 		
  
 		um-hum you like to do remodeling in your home
 	
 	
 		yeah we've learned how to do a lot of things on our own
 	
 	
 		for instance what are you doing now anything in particular
 	
 	
 		uh no not right now um i haven't gotten any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> that have shown me anything lately
 		what other kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> do you like
 	
 	
 		well i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Digest</ENAMEX> we get that and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> subscribes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientific American i</ENAMEX> think he's a frustrated doctor
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because he uh reads constantly we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in our area
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		that uh his little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> was diagnosed as as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal</ENAMEX> and uh he came across an article about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX> so he had me fix up the
 		make copies of it and give it to them and tell them that there's hope for her and all this
 	
 	
 		hm how many different kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> do you subscribe to
 	
 	
 		well right now i i dropped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> but we have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better Homes and Gardens Scientific American</ENAMEX> and um
 		uh what's the other one i think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladies' Home Journal</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redbook</ENAMEX> something like that
 	
 	
 		i used to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> but it cost too much so i had to quit taking it
 	
 	
 		did you enjoy it
 	
 	
 		uh sometimes they'd have good articles but a lot of it was kind of uh
 		a lot of fluff and not a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> and it and it like i said it cost a lot of money because i think they came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> or something like that so it was a lot higher than the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> magazines
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> likes to read sports and fishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> all the time that's pretty boring to me
 	
 	
 		
  
 		do you get those as subscriptions
 	
 	
 		oh he gets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to uh fishes hm what's it called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stream Field</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stream</ENAMEX> that's what he gets
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but that's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> but he'd get more if he could
 	
 	
 		when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was younger he liked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outdoor Life</ENAMEX> he thought that was a pretty good magazine
 	
 	
 		i don't think i've ever seen that one i don't know if they still do it or not
 	
 	
 		i don't know my
 		it might not be because it's been a while
 	
 	
 		you know what i really hate about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> is those smelly cards that have perfume or cologne
 	
 	
 		what's that
 		with the scratch and sniffs
 	
 	
 		the well the ones aren't they're not scratch and sniff anymore the the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kind i'm talking about you open it up and
 		the fragrance is just there it's like a fold that's glued shut but usually
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		when you get the magazine the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>  smells like that fragrance and you can't get the smell out and it and sometimes it makes you have a headache because it's so strong
 	
 	
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> are those i don't know if i've ever seen one in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> or not
 	
 	
 		well they came in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> and a lot of times if you buy like the fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cosmopolitan</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Glamour</ENAMEX> or or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elle</ENAMEX> those type have have them in
 	
 	
 		oh i don't get those
 	
 	
 		i don't get them on a regular basis but sometimes i've bought them
 	
 	
 		hm
 		do you have any pet uh magazines
 	
 	
 		no we we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> but no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> come in  uh regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> at all
 		
  
 	
 	
 		do you like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Digest</ENAMEX> when the in their uh theirs they're kind of interesting they have the uh
 	
 	
 		i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Digest</ENAMEX> but i usually borrow my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' of that because they get it so i didn't have to subscribe
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 		so you get away easy huh
 	
 	
 		yeah well a little bit
 		but i like the they're interesting and plus i like to read through the in the anecdotes and the jokes and things on those
 		sometimes the book excerpts are good too but mostly i like the other articles
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i like the vocabulary section in that
 	
 	
 		yeah i like that too sometimes you can get a pretty good uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		and sometimes the  real definition is something totally of opposite of what you thought it was
 	
 	
 		yeah doesn't that blow your mind away when that happens
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's something
 		and
 	
 	
 		sometimes i like the true to life stories but sometimes they get too melodramatic
 		
 
 	
 	
 		like what do you mean
 	
 	
 		it seems
 		
 		
 	