
 
     		
 	
 		go now what kinds of things do you like to listen to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		good
 		well my uh uh my interests lie mainly in classical music
 	
 	
 		is that right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh uh uh although i wasn't raised with opera it's something that i've i come to enjoy how about yourself
 	
 	
 		well actually i kind of like those same things myself and um uh i did uh study some music in school although i'm not um
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> i just took it kind of as an avocation and i sing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookhaven</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> over at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookhaven College</ENAMEX> you must be familiar with that name living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right absolutely
 	
 	
 		and uh they have um a lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> over there who um teaches singing and um
 		has a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> class as well as private lessons and uh we go and we sing for some retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Botanical Gardens</ENAMEX> and things like that and uh
 		really very very very enjoyable and i do try to get down to the symphony <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least a couple of</NUMEX> times a year and i didn't get down to the opera this year though but i have in the past um
 		but anyway i do enjoy listening to especially the classical music that has some kind of a story line or a theme like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pastoral</ENAMEX> and things like that where you can
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		follow um through some of the mood of the of the melodies and not just have um you know a kind of mathematical arrangement of the notes which is
 	
 	
 		sound
 	
 	
 		also fascinating many times but i like that break of a kind of a story line sometimes what kind of uh pieces are your favorites
 	
 	
 		well i uh i tend to shy away from anyone who uh uh is born later than nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		other than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Copeland uh Aaron Copeland</ENAMEX> i enjoy
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh-huh
 		uh-huh what about Gershwin
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gershwin uh Gershwin</ENAMEX>'s uh i i i uh
 		i i haven't uh quite found jazz to be enjoyable and and and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gershwin</ENAMEX> has a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a some</NUMEX> of some of his work is a little uh has has has a touch enough enough of jazz uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that uh that uh is not particularly enjoyable for me to listen to the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh like i i i suspect my favorites uh are in the uh seventeenth and eighteenth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> uh uh musicians uh i'd
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the uh oh there's one uh uh i guess more recent one with uh Copeland uh is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Raspegie</ENAMEX> who uh i was always amazed that he was uh so contemporary uh contemporary
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but i uh
 		uh i our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> gets down to uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myerson</ENAMEX> relatively frequently it it's our uh uh our one enjoyable uh if if we can make it to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> uh everything's okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's uh it's a relatively busy uh activity we uh one uh very nice uh uh opportunity that we've had is the is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber Orchestra</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		that has uh uh uh actually it's it's it's wonderful they they have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> matinee that uh uh if you buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> tickets the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go free
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh that gives us an opportunity to uh
 		uh to take the to uh uh make sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh get uh get dressed up and and go to the symphony whether they want to or not and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh and they uh their they oblige us by falling asleep so least that's pretty good
 	
 	
 		
 
 		how old are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven nine</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> which is and it's it's nice in that uh
 	
 	
 		oh isn't that wonderful though
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in that uh their their you their they you can get real close to the uh to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber orchestra</ENAMEX> and see the music and watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> it's uh it's a very intimate setting and the the music's really very good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i bet it is now i have never heard them um that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myerson</ENAMEX> auditorium is really is really quite acoustically beautiful i i have to admit that um
 		i had the privilege of going to the uh piano concert that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yefgenya Chessum</ENAMEX> who is a young uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> gave i guess it was just before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> time
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i'm telling and and it was no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra orchestra</ENAMEX> or anything it was just he
 	
 	
 		it was just a recital
 	
 	
 		and yes and i'm telling you the sound the sound was so
 		so perfect uh i i had heard you know the orchestra the symphony and we went for the toy symphony and the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s um uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMU</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh um-hum
 		right
 	
 	
 		several things down there this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i just heard like one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	