
 
     		
 	
 		and how's your weather been
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well my weather right now is rainy uh this is the most rain i think we've ever seen uh over a twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX> period of time since i moved to to uh to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> area
 		um i was uh i've seen  climates both rather arid and and and complete and total uh tropical so i've seen kind of the gamut but this is starting to lean towards the uh the tropical end how about you
 	
 	
 		well this is getting to be uh similar to the reason i moved away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> all these gray gloomy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">rainy days</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		oh my uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but uh i've been here for about uh well it's going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> now and this is definitely the rainiest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January February</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh this is this is a neat year you missed the nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eighty one</NUMEX> uh uh mess
 		the nineteen eighty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> that about roasted everybody and then the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> that uh where practically every lake in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North North Texas</ENAMEX> overflowed
 	
 	
 		well i thought it was bad enough <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years ago</TIMEX> when we had the was it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four years ago</TIMEX> when we had the big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> storm
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i mean we
 		oh yes <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ma'am well</ENAMEX> that was that was pretty good uh however the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy nine</TIMEX> and uh and uh seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> uh dwarfed that one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you've been here a while then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yes ma'am</ENAMEX> since uh you know i have been well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> i am with uh i've been with them them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty three years</TIMEX> so and they are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Texas</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		yeah i have seen quite a bit of of weather uh patterns of course like i say uh when i was in the service i got to see plenty of um
 		different uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> as far as wet and dry uh climates and uh
 		uh i was kind of like you i'm i didn't want to go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> because of the different because of the tremendous weather we had
 	
 	
 		
 
 		gosh i think you're the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> i have ever heard that didn't say oh it's wonderful it's so dry here
 	
 	
 		um no no no
 	
 	
 		well this actually isn't far enough south for me
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i would like to get down to oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa</ENAMEX> some place like that where
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at least yes
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well let's see my in-laws uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> in uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Leesburg</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		is that down the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it's uh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa Saint Petersburg</ENAMEX> is not that super far away
 	
 	
 		no i think it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple hours</TIMEX> drive if i
 	
 	
 		yeah something like that i think we made to from their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gardens</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ninety minutes</TIMEX> that day
 	
 	
 		uh you may have been speeding a little bit though
 	
 	
 		no no no no no no no not not at that not down that uh uh tollway they've got
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		they're they're smokies you think our smokies are bad with with uh uh our uh little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mustangs</ENAMEX> that are hot rods they got them there too oh yeah
 	
 	
 		is that right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i know we uh were uh
 		over run by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in uh  we went down for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and we were cruising cruising along in our little rental car and uh this this this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> comes over the hill and  pass me and it was one of those
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX> and he was flat moving
 	
 	
 		do they arrest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there uh unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah he's he he pulled one  he pulled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> over and was uh steady having a little chat about something other than the weather that's for sure
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because i mean he didn't look happy when we went by
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i don't know maybe it was uh
 		who knows but anyway this weather here is is certainly evolved from a from a dryer hotter uh nineteen eighty
 		to uh the present the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last summer</TIMEX> we had i think we barely what cleared <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe
 	
 	
 		i think that was stretching it
 	
 	
 		well uh i'll tell you i will definitely take the hot summers
 	
 	
 		oh well believe you me i'm not not advocating cold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> no no no no no no no wrong wrong wrong but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> of nineteen eighty we saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred fifteen</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one hundred sixteen</TIMEX> and i was running a little heating and air-conditioning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> at the time
 	
 	
 		no kidding
 		i'll bet you just did all kinds of business
 	
 	
 		well uh
 		what happened there was that most of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> everybody's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> uh down here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about April</TIMEX> start to call call everybody you know call their their local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we go out and tune up the systems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we are normally expecting some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred hundred</NUMEX> degree days so we tune for that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we had everybody nice in tune when the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred and fifteen</NUMEX> degree weather hit
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and so what the only thing that got replaced were the weak systems
 		you know that would barely make it at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> but when the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred and fifteen</NUMEX> degree <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> hit well it just couldn't couldn't handle the load and they then they then the compressors blew like popcorn
 	
 	
 		oh i'll bet
 	
 	
 		i mean just this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pop</ENAMEX> pop bang bang
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	