
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 		my name's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's nice to meet you are you ready for me to push one
 	
 	
 		nice to meet you
 		i think so
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 		okay do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no uh luckily i don't i just rent them
 	
 	
 		you do
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm a i'm an assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout master</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy scout</ENAMEX> troop
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		yeah it's
 		it's it's it's so much better to to rent
 	
 	
 		a little easier
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well what would you think if they were going off to college
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		that's uh let's see i i used to be able to do this quite well but that was when i was in college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> that i've got that that i went to was pretty good which was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cal Poly</ENAMEX> in Pomona
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh  you know it was a regular it was a state university and it seemed to be pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah because i'm in college right now i thought God this is a good question
 	
 	
 		oh really which one
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i was like because i i know how my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> when i was looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they didn't really say anything i mean they didn't say you know i want you to go here or you know they left it up to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i thought it was real interesting because i picked where i wanted to go and then afterwards my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was like oh i really kind of wish you would have gone there and i didn't even know that she'd even you know liked another place or anything
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		but i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> could make that decision for you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> wanted me to go to uh community college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i ended up  getting into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> and they never really said anything about it until
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> went to college and they they went to the community college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s going jeez it it it uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		costs a lot more or just as much to go to community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and you aren't getting as much you know so
 	
 	
 		yeah definitely
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because i know people
 		i know some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> really wanted them to go somewhere so they did and they hate it you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		or that they don't do good and they fail out and it's like because i know one person
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> wanted him to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMU</ENAMEX> really bad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he went and he doesn't like it i mean he wouldn't admit to you that he doesn't like it but it you know he's not doing good and he never is excited about it or anything and he won't tell his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> i was like well why don't you transfer you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh well because his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> gave him the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to go there  well you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean i really the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> wouldn't get it because i just think that's sad i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> can can make that decision for you i you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you if they let i think you should choose and you know work something out between y'all God
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's that's the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> are right now anyway is they they have a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> come down they say hey you wanna be here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah oh i know
 	
 	
 		it's it's so it's pointed towards you
 	
 	
 		yeah see
 	
 	
 		and if they sell you well enough there ain't nothing that's going to change your mind
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right that's definitely true
 	
 	
 		we're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> in society
 	
 	
 		yeah sad as long as i just think as long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are happy so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will go some place and transfer or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's like you got to find where you fit in best
 	
 	
 		yeah you got to
 		got to find the good classes and things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah really i know i have some hard classes now that i'm just like uh
 	
 	
 		i i well i can imagine that i i started off the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> at high school said oh you wanna do this well then go into aerospace aerospace
 	
 	
 		stuff like that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i went and my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first day</TIMEX> of enrollment in college i walked around i go into the aerospace building they give me the curriculum and it's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty four</NUMEX> units a quarter
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and you're like uh i don't think i want to do that
 	
 	
 		yeah and average is like you know it's supposed to be like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen eighteen</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know this is like i don't want to be a doctor
 	
 	
 		yeah you're like i i really didn't want to do it i was just kidding you know i just  thought i'd come try it out
 	
 	
 		yeah  yeah i happened to be walking down the hall turned into some some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and said help me  and he sold me on his program
 	
 	
 		yeah really
 		yeah you can't have someone can't choose that for you that's why i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people people</ENAMEX> i know that stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so long it's because they can't figure out what they wanna do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like what you know and they start with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> major and they go through the certain you know classes you have to take for that major then they change their mind
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's like oh you got to start all over because you lose all the classes you just took  that's crazy that's like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they need to hire someone to help you and everyone should have to take like a test or something of what you might want to do because i think that's so sad because people
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		well they there there's some tests like that now but they're kind of strange some of them you know it's like you you you should be a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cement mixer</ENAMEX> or something like that you know
 	
 	
 		yeah there are
 		yeah
 		yeah i know yeah i know they have better ones yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> walked in going yeah but i wanted to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah you're going you should be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> you're like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> what
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah i know we took those in like high school those are stupid
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they ought to tell you mine is psychology
 	
 	
 		what's what's your major
 		
 		
 	