
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		what product did you have returned
 	
 	
 		i had to uh i had to return a
 		that recently i've had to return uh uh a cassette recorder
 		um
 		my feelings about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> made in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> uh recently is they are getting worse
 		uh in fact i am kind of disappointed in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> made things uh
 		how about yourself
 	
 	
 		well i'm kind of confused about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isuzu Mazda</ENAMEX> engines
 		and they're considered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> products
 		so i don't understand if we are supposed to not buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazdas</ENAMEX> because they are foreign
 		or if we are supposed to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> because they're foreign but they are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> you know what i am saying
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i just don't understand that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it seems that whenever you do have a product
 		parts of it are both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and overseas that it creates a problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		both in uh the product
 		and in the
 		overall warranty or lasting
 	
 	
 		have have you recently bought a car
 	
 	
 		yes i did
 	
 	
 		what what did you buy
 	
 	
 		i bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">New Yorker</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plymouth Sundance</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they are pretty much <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> made aren't they
 	
 	
 		no uh i was surprised yes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> has some of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parts</ENAMEX> built overseas also
 	
 	
 		or you know is that right
 	
 	
 		and i thought that was totally American
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and uh that's why i stayed away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> and find out that the same thing happened to me anyway
 	
 	
 		i am really surprised to hear about uh i i haven't studied <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> probably as closely as you have
 		um i was really surprised that you mentioned uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> no it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> that are um using <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> motors and
 	
 	
 		and engines that's true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it seems that they're quote unquote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> made where was your VCR
 	
 	
 		um it
 	
 	
 		what was it and what went wrong with it
 	
 	
 		yeah let me see it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd</ENAMEX> and um it it continually i don't know if i think it is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd</ENAMEX> is made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and uh it it was eating my tapes
 		and uh
 		i don't know i am totally uh totally confounded about uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh American</ENAMEX> made and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> and
 		i'm not sure which is the best
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Digest</ENAMEX> a lot to decide what i want to buy
 	
 	
 		yeah i do too i don't read it but sometimes i  did you know that Fitzhugh
 		is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and they deliberately make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> and parts wrong so you will have to buy them
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and it cannot be repaired and that upset me when i found that out
 	
 	
 		huh
 		do you own a computer
 	
 	
 		no i don't but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> does and she worked with a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that uh serviced them
 		and she is the one that told me about that because uh we were we are thinking about buying a computer we haven't done it yet
 		and uh since she works for this computer computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i asked her what she thought was best cause if <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> was using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> clones and this type of thing
 		and uh
 		she was saying that she didn't know which one was the best because of the way they're put together and then she was telling me about this uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> computer
 		boards just put in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> number of uh
 		computers and then they last for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX> to no longer than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and then instead of repairing them you have to buy a whole new board
 	
 	
 		i didn't realize that i work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and we have a lot of computers in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and uh the computers we use mostly are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX> computers and they are manufactured down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		by whom
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Dell Computers Dell Corporation</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell Corporation</ENAMEX> where do they get their parts from Fitzhugh
 	
 	
 		uh uh
 		uh i i don't know ma'am uh i wouldn't be surprised if most of them aren't <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> parts but uh we've had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX> computers for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> now and we we're really happy with them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		are you
 	
 	
 		and we use them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> we use them probably <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours a day</TIMEX> on the average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> so they get a lot of use
 	
 	
 		well maybe you're
 		well you're probably fortunate you've probably got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the better ones
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		so you work part time with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		i i'm full timing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX>'s office
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 		
 	