
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay what are you are you doing anything in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> on recycling
 	
 	
 		well in uh our particular area uh we're not other than uh
 		they have a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> that you can take uh
 		bottles and
 		cans and different things to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in their parking lot and uh
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> we haven't been doing that but uh
 		they don't uh
 		that's about all they're doing
 	
 	
 		is it a small town
 	
 	
 		yes it's a rural area
 	
 	
 		that makes a difference uh here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> they're trying to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to start some curbside recycling i think they're doing a test uh personally my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i do plastic and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and cans but we have to uh take them you know to
 		to areas and the problem that i'm finding is that uh a lot of the places i've been taking things have now discontinued the recycling policy like it's hard to find a place to take newspapers anymore
 	
 	
 		um-hum yes so that's uh that's basically what happened up here and then uh with all the recycling the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> cans went down
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah it used to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about sixty cents</NUMEX> a pound and so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were collecting them and taking them in to recycle
 		uh to get money for them now it's down to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about nineteen cents</NUMEX> a pound
 	
 	
 		well i noticed a difference uh we go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kroger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> uh here to take our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> cans and i noticed a difference you know i'd be getting perhaps a dollar for whatever i took in and i think the last bunch i took in which i didn't think was much smaller was maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty six</TIMEX> cents
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's what's happened and i don't know if that's from recycling i i understand it is but
 		here uh we do we do recycle our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and give them to the scouts
 		and they uh they're able to make some money
 		uh
 		that way
 		but i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> who uh
 		they pick it up they have a  a recycling uh garbage uh pick up where they have different
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> receptacles where they put it in
 		they have some for the cans some for the bottles and newspapers
 		and then they have the regular garbage and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this truck comes before the garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and picks uh
 		and has separate bins to put all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and the plastic and all that in
 		that seems to be working quite well there that's uh in uh  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well you know what is so sad is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are finally i think willing to do something about this and then all of a sudden uh the the demand isn't there you know it's too expensive to recycle but i personally feel that we're going to have to
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pay the price you know whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> subsidizes it and i'm you know i sorry to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government government</ENAMEX> get involved in too much of anything else like that but something has to be done we're just uh we're using our natural resources we're filling up the dumps and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		well i've that's what they in the local the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> here they were talking about that uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half about half</NUMEX> the uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> in the dumps is newspapers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they could recycle that uh more than they do then uh
 		um
 		we'd be able to save a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and everything else so i've been i i i'm all for it i just don't know uh
 		i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> where he has this they have uh
 		uh they have to pay extra to have them pick it up even though and and so that's kind of a a burden on my uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> even though they they put it in different containers they still have to pay extra money to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well and i know uh too my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> lives in a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> also and it she would have to go like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> miles to recycle anything and so course so of course she she doesn't and plus uh it's difficult for her to
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		um
 	
 	
 		drive around just all that much so in a case like that you know they have to make it a little bit easier for people
 	
 	
 		yes they do
 	
 	
 		to do that
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		and um i'm hoping that they do this curbside recycling i'll be willing to pay a little extra you know if they'll go ahead and pick it up quite frankly it'll save me money in gas running around all over town
 	
 	
 		right
 		yep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>  that's true
 	
 	
 		and i take my uh paper i always get paper bags and i take them back to the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and use them again
 	
 	
 		hm right
 	
 	
 		so you know little bit here and little bit there i guess it all helps
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it it really does if we could just get uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh
 		all over to do it now i know in uh south of us about a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundred miles</NUMEX> south in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> they do have a uh area where
 		uh they bring all the garbage in and they uh they do have places to recycle and they really encourage this and uh you can bring it and you have different areas
 		um that's a small yeah well it's next to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Provo Utah</ENAMEX> i don't know if you're familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> at all but anyway
 	
 	
 		not a lot but i've heard the name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Provo</ENAMEX> before
 	
 	
 		it's where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham Brigham Young University</ENAMEX> is uh this
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh there they seem to be having success and but it is a uh
 		it's done by the
 		it for profit making for these people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they of course are
 		
 		
 	