
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you feel you're paying too much in tax
 	
 	
 		oh i always feel i'm paying too much for everything  that's part of my problem
 		i wonder if we wouldn't be better off um
 		you know with a little more free enterprise than having the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> do some much for us
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's what my i don't know those are some of my feelings i think free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> does it for a better price
 	
 	
 		i think you're right there uh it might be a little more ruthless uh to go with the free enterprise system the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has a sort sort of a habit of investing in things that don't pay much return
 		and into getting into projects that uh there is no yield on the investment so it's all money down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> hole
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it doesn't it doesn't seem like we really get our uh i don't know i i don't think we get the best for the buck if that's if that's a good way to put it but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um  uh do you now do you live close to uh uh you know to a government installation of any kind or
 	
 	
 		no i'm uh sort of in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax County</ENAMEX> working for uh one of the uh free loaders on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uh government contract uh group uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh okay so you know it from the contract side
 	
 	
 		so you know somebody once accused uh accused us of uh uh being a welfare program for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> worked uh for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uh
 		here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hill Air Force Base</ENAMEX> where i mean you know that was the occupation that he had all the time i was growing up and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we got a good living out of it but i know just from talking with him there were it was like you said there are a lot of things that go on that just just make you wonder
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that they don't really even get the best out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are working for them so it makes me wonder where we're where we're going with that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> went through his life saying that he just keeps paying taxes and paying taxes and paying taxes
 		and he never got anything out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well they uh uh yeah they they they provide a lot of services that we don't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you you know that we don't really see or notice i guess but it just seemed like if if we had you know some kind of a private enterprise system
 	
 	
 		well the welfare is a good example that uh
 		you know if if welfare is handled at the local level by small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> and some of the organized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> that that get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved directly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh then the money gets right straight to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and there's a lot of volunteer work and and supporting that type of operation
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> handle it and next thing you know you're spending <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> just to administer it
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 	
 	
 		and it just seems like nothing gets down to the people
 	
 	
 		i think i think that's a really good point  because i i i think you know welfare is one of the one of the big problems
 	
 	
 		
 
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and it it's interesting that in
 		uh in a way it's interesting to me that that like in the foreign in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and those kind areas where they're having their struggles right now you know they're gonna have to have a welfare system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in order for in order to improve their life over there and i i hope they don't pattern theirs after our
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah well i'm afraid they may have a more bureaucratic system than we do
 		uh i think one of my biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> on taxes is uh real estate uh taxes down at the local level the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> seems to be pretty stable you know you can figure out what they're gonna charge you next year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh since i moved into this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX> the real estate tax has doubled
 		and i'm just afraid that by the time i'm ready to retire and uh the mortgage is paid off on this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i won't be able to afford the taxes on it
 	
 	
 		um
 		your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> taxes will be as high as your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> payment
 	
 	
 		yeah well that was true on the last house i bought i got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty year</TIMEX> mortgage on it and by the time i uh sold it the the tax payment was a bigger part of the uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that is the
 	
 	
 		of the mortgage payment  yeah
 	
 	
 		hm that that is scary because that really makes you wonder what they're doing with that i
 	
 	
 		and i figure it just says that uh when i'm ready to retire i'm gonna have to move out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax County</ENAMEX> and get out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> some place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and there's no control over it uh the accessors just come around and say okay you're assessment just went up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thirty</TIMEX> percent and uh
 		you know there's no recourse
 	
 	
 		and what what do you think you get out of your taxes your property taxes
 	
 	
 		well the property taxes are supposed to pay for education and some of the county services
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i i hope that some of that is working efficiently we have a pretty good school system
 		i'm a little concerned that there's too much paper work there for them
 		
 		
 	