
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay we have uh we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every summer</TIMEX> and uh we different uh sides of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> take turns on planning it sending out the invitations and
 		and then uh the activities that we have we kind of get together and have a luncheon or a lunch or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a cookout or barbecue or whatever
 		and uh and get to know so all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> get to know each other and
 		we really enjoy our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> uh get togethers and family reunions so to speak
 		are you able to do that
 	
 	
 		yes we have ours <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every three years</TIMEX> and uh we have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brownsville Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania Ohio</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia Virginia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> so we've got them everywhere <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and that's why we only have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every three years</TIMEX> so that everybody can get together and we uh have one from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early morning</TIMEX> it starts at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it goes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> and we just had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year and a half ago</TIMEX> we have it every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> in a
 		place called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bare Rocks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		its a  it was a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> and it was catered and um
 		i hadn't seen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> that i hadn't seen for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and others that are new in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> from marriage or
 	
 	
 		well that's really great and uh they're able to come from long distances like that we we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> and uh all over but uh
 		they get to some of them but this is uh the ones that live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and but it it's sure great uh those family reunions are really something but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		aren't they wonderful
 	
 	
 		at uh
 	
 	
 		uh it's a shame that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't get together like that more often and and uh
 		have a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> tie
 	
 	
 		it really is because that that really helps and like say to get to know each other and the background and we uh we the one that we have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> uh we go up to uh
 		go up into the canyon and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> out for uh over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> and uh it we
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bonfire</ENAMEX> and uh sit around and in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> and uh around the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pine trees</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pine trees</ENAMEX> in the mountains and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the atmosphere's just really nice and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get to play with each other and it uh it's a super thing uh
 	
 	
 		that sounds like fun we only have ours for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that one day</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then we make plans who's going to have the next one where it's going to be and all that and the next one i believe is going to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> next year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um
 		do you have a large family
 	
 	
 		uh we have uh there's probably about uh
 		our own own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> there is we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but we have uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is the one that we go up to uh
 		Idaho up in the canyon and uh there's probably about uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there
 		and uh total and then we do have another get together at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas time</TIMEX> on my side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and uh this last one we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to that one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's good how many was in your family
 	
 	
 		uh we have uh i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and one sister
 		and then on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> she had uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so we're kind of from large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and then they're all married and all have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they come and uh so it's it's really quite a get together we've been doing this uh up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> out for
 		uh we're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty nine years every summer</TIMEX> we've done this and we do it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second week</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty fourth of July</TIMEX> which is a holiday here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		what's the holiday
 	
 	
 		it's uh when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX> came into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and settled uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Brigham Young</ENAMEX> came in on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty fourth of July</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and when they came across they came from the east in the covered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagons</ENAMEX> and uh settled or started the settlement of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX>
 		so
 	
 	
 		is there a special uh type of festivities for that occasion too
 	
 	
 		yeah uh they have uh we have uh a large parade in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> it's probably the one of the biggest parades in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> it goes for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about three or four hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh of course uh it's a state holiday
 		and so we uh
 		we have ours between that and uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> between those <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the fourth and twenty fourth and</TIMEX>
 		so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> we know
 		
 		
 	