
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		well are you there
 	
 	
 		yes i'm here
 	
 	
 		okay well i just bought a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that's why i checked um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		uh what kind you get
 	
 	
 		it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tercel</ENAMEX> i love it it's really nice yep
 	
 	
 		how do you like it
 		well that's good
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um wife</ENAMEX> just got a new car a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic</ENAMEX> so i think i think it's my turn
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well a CRX not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic</ENAMEX> i don't why i said <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		oh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRX</ENAMEX> that's what i was looking at
 	
 	
 		yeah she liked it and it's been pretty good so far she's had it about um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um it's been a really good car
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i don't know i think she when she got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> i should get one so i'm looking although slowly right now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are thinking about getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Camry</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are thinking about getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Camry</ENAMEX> because they're supposed to be i think i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toyotas</ENAMEX> are really good cars
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah just about everybody i've never had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but everybody i know who has they don't have too many complaints which is can't be said about a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i don't know i think i want a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Blazer</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GMC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jimmy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> is what i'm looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon</ENAMEX> type of deal
 	
 	
 		yeah those are nice
 	
 	
 		it'd be good i look was i looked at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4-Runner</ENAMEX> actually it's the same type of deal but smaller kind of like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>-10s
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevys</ENAMEX> and i don't know i like i like the bigger ones better than the small ones if you're gonna buy a truck you might as well buy the real one instead of a toy truck
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> has a my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> just bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> truck and he loves it course and he's into the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> and all and the stereos
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		uh that sounds pretty good i used to have a an S-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> a little truck i don't know was it was more like having a car than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> so i decided this time i'll get a big one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> used to have a big full size <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GMC</ENAMEX> and um he just bought a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S-10</ENAMEX> and now he hates it he wants a full size again yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		he wants a big one again yeah
 	
 	
 		he's so used to driving a big truck
 	
 	
 		that has a lot of advantages and i'm up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> so up north with the snow and everything it's a a big advantage to us
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> by the way yeah yeah most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i talk to on this are from down there i'm one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New East Coast</ENAMEX> people
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well that sounds pretty good do you shop around pretty much when you were looking for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yep
 		i didn't do not much at all i went and looked at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GMC i i</ENAMEX> went and looked at a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> because i just i don't need you know much more and um
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i went and looked at it and it was just i couldn't afford it or anything
 		so and i was just looking for a little stripped down
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they just wanted way too much for it so i was kind of looked around and i was going to look at a
 		mainly the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> but i also looked at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sentra</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then i went and i looked at the um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tercel</ENAMEX> and i ended up getting it because i really liked it i test drove it and i just love it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		are those um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cylinders do you know or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> cylinder <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cylinder
 	
 	
 		mine's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cylinder
 	
 	
 		yeah you get pretty good gas mileage like
 	
 	
 		yeah really good
 	
 	
 		around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or more than that even or
 	
 	
 		it's about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> i think it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and uh like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> out on the highway it's really good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's a that's about what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> gets
 		little bit over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> which is pretty good i can't complain right now i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Escort</ENAMEX> which is the terrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but it gets good gas mileage so i can't complain too much but it's ugly and you know it's not real comfortable or anything but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i bought it used after i graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and it's getting the job done but it's nothing that i really enjoy
 	
 	
 		yeah i used to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick Skylark</ENAMEX> an eighty one
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> used to have one of those
 	
 	
 		really mine was  not a good car  i bought it used and it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and then i had a lot of problems with it it just made me so mad that because i had to pretty much go out and get a new car
 	
 	
 		yeah lot of time in the shop
 	
 	
 		yeah most of the time or sitting out front  yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i know about that i had a i had a
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thunderbird</ENAMEX> for a while and
 		fixed or repaired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> is the joke about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and it was pretty accurate with that car i swore up and down i never own another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> as long lived and i ended up anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah  yep
 		yeah
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s pretty much against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fords</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		oh i don't think i'll ever have another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> after this one but so far it hasn't too mean to me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		um do you test drive a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> before you um bought them
 	
 	
 		not really i only i test drove mine the one that i got now and um that's the the only one i went and when i looked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRX</ENAMEX>'s uh i just looked at them and they had the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX> that i went to the close
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	