
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">afternoon Doug it</ENAMEX> certainly is uh going to be a pleasure to chat with you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm uh certainly was surprised to uh to hear from you normally i talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah me too
 	
 	
 		how did you get on this list
 	
 	
 		uh through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Dalgren</ENAMEX> she um
 		she had somehow gotten the information from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and was distributing it around
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		all righty well now what would you say about these everyday
 		invasions of our privacy do what ideas do you have on that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um see i'm not sure that
 		i don't think they're necessarily widespread in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but i think that the opportunity is definitely there for um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to invade your privacy when they want to i think it's um
 	
 	
 		in what in what manner
 	
 	
 		well it's certainly not that difficult to tap a phone it's completely trivial to for instance
 		listen in on someone's car phone or walk around phone since they're just radio signals  it's um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		let's see
 		well what's the first thing that comes to your mind
 	
 	
 		well the thing that i thought they were uh concerned about was was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> calling calling on the phone from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to sell you something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in reality in many cases they knew or they had information about you that was purchased from some other
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> and i thought that was uh beginning to invade the privacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because
 		the things about where you live and and maybe what you purchased in
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past months</TIMEX> is then put down and sent to someone else in the same business and they in return come back and try to sell you something with this uh
 		additional knowledge to me that's an invasion of privacy
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree with you there for sure
 		um
 		and i think that all that information is quite easy for anyone to get you know it's possible for
 		almost anyone to get information about your credit history for instance if they just um
 		twist the right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> or claim to be from the right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> when they're calling the credit company
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's you know possible for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a thirteen year</TIMEX> old
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacker</ENAMEX> with a modem to find out almost anything about your personal history not to mention change it if he wants to
 	
 	
 		you mean your history in regards to uh the charge card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		well um
 		well yes well for instance yes um and they'll probably goes into
 		other things like you know your records with
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or utility <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> or anything
 	
 	
 		do you consider these serious uh problems
 	
 	
 		since
 		um uh not
 		not yet anyways because i don't think they're widespread enough but i think they have the potential of becoming serious problems
 	
 	
 		um-hum well what should we do about it or what could be done about it do you think to correct it
 	
 	
 		um i'm not really sure because
 		the
 		i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> is going more and more electronic and there are certainly benefits to its doing so
 		and it's hard to hard to say whether the um risks have potential of outweighing the benefits or not
 		and i'm not sure
 		what can be done to ensure that they don't um
 		uh why do you see any out for us
 	
 	
 		well i would think that uh information held on records uh by any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or charge card <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> or or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> should be absolutely private private and
 		and not be allowed to be uh to given out by those companies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean it it should be made a a uh national or a state law to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so that uh you would then feel more free to deal direct with these companies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in other words if you call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> yourself directly uh and then know that what you tell them will be on their records but will not be available to anyone else uh you know from the outside so to speak then you'd
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you'd feel more free to uh to go into detail with them
 	
 	
 		yeah i suppose
 	
 	
 		but but we have no control of that now and then uh you you're when you're talking with them you really don't want to tell them everything that's on your mind because you you feel that it someday might be used against you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	