
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well uh what is your favorite kind of music
 	
 	
 		well i have to say my favorite type of music would probably be uh classical music
 	
 	
 		oh same here yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really what type of music do you like in the classical area or what era do you era do you like the most
 	
 	
 		oh well i guess i like a wide range uh everything from uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Baroque</ENAMEX> through at least some modern music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i these days are especially into opera we've been sort of opera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		um do you go to the operas that they sing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> or go to the ones that they sing other languages
 	
 	
 		well we uh generally the places we've gone they sing in the original languages
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Opera</ENAMEX> here normally does i guess
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah i i haven't gotten into that too much because i  uh if i don't know the story line and um i don't speak the language then i have difficult time
 		comprehending what's going on
 	
 	
 		well one thing that's helped us a lot is that uh you you know you can buy a lot of these operas now on video cassettes uh video tape
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so we have quite a collection of those and you watch them at home and they have subtitles so you you figure out what's going on after a while and then you can enjoy it in the uh theater
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but you know the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> opera now has uh super titles on on all their performances i think
 	
 	
 		what is that
 	
 	
 		well they they give an uh an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> translation on a on a screen up above the stage
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that can help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like me
 	
 	
 		
  
 		in fact they even do that for operas sung sung in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> because it is hard to understand the words some times
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i can understand that
 		so i'd say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vivaldi</ENAMEX> is probably my favorite uh composer
 	
 	
 		yeah well i really like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vivaldi</ENAMEX> uh he's uh definitely uh one of the one of the top of that era
 	
 	
 		yeah i like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baroque</ENAMEX> music i like full body music uh with the uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh with brass and winds wood winds instruments uh course i like uh also string instruments and i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> string instruments in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> uh instrument players
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> play string instruments <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> plays a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cello</ENAMEX> and the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> plays the Viola
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i get to go to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least four or five</NUMEX> concerts a year
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh-huh how how old are they
 	
 	
 		uh one is thirteen and one is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they're doing this in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or what uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes sure
 	
 	
 		well you've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a string quartet there
 	
 	
 		yeah we're on our way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh um i try to enjoy all of it
 	
 	
 		well since you seem to like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> music have you ever uh gotten into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gabrielli</ENAMEX> or anybody there in that era the uh
 		uh period right before actually before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vivaldi</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		um a little bit but um a lot of the um music i don't know about uh as far as the titles and i have to listen to it and and figure out what i'm listening to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i do belong to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Musical Heritage Society</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		do you belong to that
 	
 	
 		no i don't but i think i know what it is isn't that a uh uh see can't you get records through that or something recordings
 	
 	
 		you can get recordings uh they now have them on compact disc or uh or cassettes or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LP</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they do their they do a lot of original recordings themselves
 	
 	
 		yes yeah i think uh
 	
 	
 		uh but they also uh they also uh go to the different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> or the different i guess uh what do you call them
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that orchestrate
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		the conductors the conductors yeah they go to conductors uh and and they actually have them perform the music and they record it
 	
 	
 		uh yes right
 		so they're actually commissioned performances
 	
 	
 		sure a lot of them are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or they will know find out when they're performing and they will uh record the music at that time  and so uh it is uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh high quality grade music and of course now they're getting in they also have a jazz section and they also have a uh more contemporary and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> section
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i have good heard good things about the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music Heritage Society</ENAMEX>
 		but if i get involved in one of those things i end up spending all my money on the on the music or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well you can control it uh
 	
 	
 		almost uh almost uh bankrupted myself out of college as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> when i got into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Record Club</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah my room <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> signed me up he got a bonus record and i got a lot of bills
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		so we have to watch that
 	
 	
 		huh well that's good
 	
 	
 		uh do you play an instrument yourself
 	
 	
 		yes i i play guitar and and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years</TIMEX> played saxophone
 		
 		
 	