
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Bill um</ENAMEX> as you think over the plans and so forth that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you're working with now who do you work with this time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i own a company
 	
 	
 		you own the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> alright
 	
 	
 		i'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of the company
 	
 	
 		my goodness
 	
 	
 		so uh i guess uh i determine what the benefits are
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess you do
 		hum
 	
 	
 		but uh you so what are you asking me what  what benefits i think are most important
 	
 	
 		well what what do you think of the let's put it this way what do you think are the most important benefits for those working for you other than other than their present salary
 	
 	
 		um i'd say in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s economy uh besides basic benefits uh such as um health insurance and life insurance and the uh some type of retirement plan
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'd say that uh most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> uh um
 		that we have really like a a profit sharing plan
 	
 	
 		a profit sharing plan that's interesting um-hum
 	
 	
 		they like to participate in the profits of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> like they're part like you know because they feel like well we're contributing to it so we'd like to participate in it
 		and so that means i make a little bit less but the thing is that really you make a little more because everybody has a interest in in it working
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes because they  they have a specific reason to do so because they themselves benefit from doing a better job
 	
 	
 		right
 		i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh don't want money um it's been my experience most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want uh to feel like they're participating in something that uh
 		that is not a drudgery you know that they can enjoy and that they can get some benefits out of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		and it's a contribution
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		well Bill uh that idea fits me exactly i just retired from uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> here and that's been the goal of my life was to
 		contribute and um to the work that i was doing in my research and that's what made me happy
 		and uh that's the type of goal i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ought to look for and i'm sure a lot of them don't you can't stand in front of a counter and
 		do that kind of stuff <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> and feel like that you're contributing something to a scientific level of knowledge or so forth
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get a lot of satisfaction um we're a financial planning firm
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you're a financial planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> how many uh
 	
 	
 		uh yes so you said you retired i just happen to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that i happened to do some planning for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> but anyway uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we do we deal with a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are uh retired or trying to
 		retire
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh
 	
 	
 		and uh it's real important uh that their benefit plans that they get from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and from their work that where they were that uh
 		um that it take care of them they don't none of them really want to be rich but they like to have enough to be comfortable
 	
 	
 		well what what changes would you have have you considered uh in in doing it to your to your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that might benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> or perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> itself better
 	
 	
 		well um we considering instead of tying a profit sharing plan to a a salary
 		is uh is tie um
 		uh a percentage
 		um of business that uh that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would participate and bring into the company
 		uh pay them uh based on the percentage of business they bring instead of based on their salary and the result
 	
 	
 		when you say bring in do you mean that they negotiated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to to come in and uh ask for your support
 	
 	
 		no not necessarily um it can be in house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who help you handle <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> amount of dollars
 	
 	
 		oh okay um-hum even though they didn't bring it in they help it once it's there
 	
 	
 		right well see we have different we have marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and then we have uh financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh then we have uh staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> and administrative assistants
 		and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> and administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> um you know that if we don't have their cooperation and they're not participating in the profit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> they they can get very dissatisfied very quickly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so uh we're thinking about paying them instead of a percentage on salary paying them a percentage on the business they handle so
 		administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> that would handle <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two million dollars</NUMEX> worth of business is a lot more valuable than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that handles a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX> worth of business
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yes but it it might not be necessarily because he did a good or bad job but it might be whether the locality locality there those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want that kind of support
 	
 	
 		well and and and but to see the thing is that they give support to the financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planner</ENAMEX> that they're the assistant to
 		or that they usually have several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they report to that you know that they work together with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it encourages them not to uh complain
 		when they realize that they get a part of the of the action based on their efforts not based on being sitting back saying well make me do it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		see we don't want anybody around here that says make me do it i don't think anybody any i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		lack a better terminology terminology they want to be self employed but they don't want to take the risk in other words they like to control their own future but they also want to be somewhat content to go and come as they please
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		without some real strict adherence which that's what we have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	