
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> the subject is almost laughable is there such a thing as an honest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that's uh debatable if if you read the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>  looks like there's a new scandal breaking ever ever minute uh
 	
 	
 		oh i agree with you
 		it's amazing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Rogers</ENAMEX> who was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the twenties</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> if you hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that gimmicks him and uses his same material it is pertinent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as it was then
 	
 	
 		yeah it is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that does the traveling show that's that's on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> and everything now
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's supposed to be great i don't know as long as there <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> making up the majority of the state legislatures and the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't see a lot of change happening
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> yeah did you catch that the defensive driving course you can take to get out of a ticket was recently changed from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> to once every twelve months
 		it was also noted in some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> that the percentage of ownership of the driving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislatures</ENAMEX> has greatly increased
 	
 	
 		isn't that funny how that just happens to be a correlation
 	
 	
 		yes yes they're not down there to to live off the salary of uh what they're paid
 	
 	
 		i'm afraid not unfortunately
 	
 	
 		and course you know the  the famous joke is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> does so good in business because they only let <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> graduate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> and that's if fifteen had died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right i saw a
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> joke book <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and it and the title of the joke was skid marks  and of course there's a major joke about skid marks and lawyers
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 		uh
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't know it just it's pretty disgusting every time you
 		it it's not just the unethical part of it it's the self-serving part of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that bothers me about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> they're all out
 		either for a particular controlled interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of some kind or maybe several uh and rather than really honestly decide issues on the basis of what is good for the country
 		everybody decides them with this the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> in mind or or afraid that they're gonna hack off the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> or the other vote wise
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and won't get reelected
 	
 	
 		and yeah exactly and so we if we just limited terms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> especially
 	
 	
 		i agree with you a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		and even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> this appointing them for life is just absurd they wind up senile old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> making decisions at eighty years old
 	
 	
 		oh i think all the way
 		uh
 		all the way down to dog <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catchers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> yes sir limited turn
 	
 	
 		just just say that the most you can serve is a couple of terms and then get in there and then you could get in there and do the best possible job that you really feel like you should be doing and then you're out of there and go on to something else instead of this
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two two</TIMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you go to  you know get elected to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and let somebody else pay you
 	
 	
 		because this exactly well at least you'd decide things you'd decide things from the stand point of what's best hopefully for whatever agency you're representing
 	
 	
 		uh you seen the benefits that
 		yeah
 		the benefits legislatures uh state and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">senate</ENAMEX> and uh
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislatures</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warshin</ENAMEX> get after they've been there a few terms is unbelievable they get their salary for life health benefits for life
 	
 	
 		yeah i know
 	
 	
 		oh uh uh have have you ever noticed when
 	
 	
 		i just i just think we ought to we limit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> why not terms of the others and give there's plenty of other qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to run
 	
 	
 		what
 		right
 		they tried that in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> or was it or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was from there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if approved it he would not have been eligible to continue representing and being speaker
 		and so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters voters</ENAMEX> kicked it said no we we since we're the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with the with the gun right now we're not gonna vote out having the gun control having the power
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so when i i don't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX>'s a perfect example of how somebody can be broke and get into politics and come out rich as yeah
 	
 	
 		that's right and above nothing either  starting with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Duvall County</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		well they they used to say in advertising that the textbook example of good competitive advertising advertising is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hertz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> rent a car commercials number one number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> has to be a textbook example of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> without any morals
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah that's that's probably true
 	
 	
 		i don't think one of the question question was could they legislate laws to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> honest my opinion no because they won't pass laws against themselves
 	
 	
 		i haven't
 		yeah i don't
 		well that's it when the very <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> making the laws are gonna be the ones who would have to pass those uh against themselves it it sort of uh
 		goes without saying that it'd be awfully awfully tough unless you could get the best thing that could happen uh to the state legislatures would be to be full of just
 		independent independent independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> or just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> working for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that could somehow get their salary made
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		let them
 	
 	
 		uh  justified you know or brought up to whatever over the state salary level uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	