
 
     		
 	
 		have you recently bought a car <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well well i didn't buy one i just changed jobs changed jobs and got a work <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> car and uh they bought me a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontiac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Grand Prix</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've been yeah i've been pretty happy with it i i've been driving just a little little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic</ENAMEX> and stuff so it's a bigger car but i've been pretty pleased with it you know i uh
 	
 	
 		that's a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> isn't it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was it's you know got a lot of nice gadgets and stuff but i gosh it's been nice so far i can't say that it's put it through all the loops
 	
 	
 		can you use it for personal too to
 	
 	
 		yeah i can use it for personal and
 	
 	
 		so so you buying a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to you right at this point anyway isn't a a big deal
 	
 	
 		no not really i although we my other we have a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and it's getting a little bit old it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an eighty five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic</ENAMEX> and so we're thinking in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two</TIMEX> we might have to but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i i kind of i just like to keep up i you know don't uh don't plan on buying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> like i say for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two</TIMEX> but sooner or later i'm going to have to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		we we just bought <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> we just bought a a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plymouth</ENAMEX> Voyager
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's been great we've got family a a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and that's the only way to travel as far as i'm concerned the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i bet
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> can get up and move around and you can
 		get them things
 	
 	
 		now is that a is that a full size van or
 	
 	
 		it it's not it's a it's a minivan
 	
 	
 		minivan
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and it was the best rating out of the consumer reports and things
 	
 	
 		oh was it
 		it you do so do you shop the consumer reports when you buy a car then or do you
 	
 	
 		i do i do and
 	
 	
 		do you find that works out pretty good for you
 	
 	
 		yeah we've only bought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> i bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sentra</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that um and i really liked it too didn't have any problems with it
 	
 	
 		did you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and this one has been been an exceptional vehicle we've really enjoyed it especially for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's good to hear yeah that's good to hear some good news about some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i uh i really believe they're getting better and you know i i i looked around and seen some of those new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturns</ENAMEX> and stuff and they seem to be a really nice car
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		well actually my philosophy about i mean if i was going to buy something for me like
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i'd drive around  unfortunately i'd still get a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> makes uh like you've got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accords</ENAMEX> are very very well built i also really like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> Camrys
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they're just not practical if you have kids
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		you can't um
 		well if they get older i guess you can take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but when they're small you got to get up and crawl over the seat and you know which doesn't work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah what we found just even going down to our inlaws overnight uh uh this little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic</ENAMEX> there's just not enough room we i've just got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> by the time you put the car seat and a couple of bags i mean we're just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know we we uh we were having that problem that why there's just not enough room those small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> any more we couldn't go camping because we couldn't put a tent and a cooler in it you know it was so small
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>'s started doing some nice things with their with their warranties and things i've got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven year</TIMEX> seventy <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousand mile</NUMEX> warranty on the drive train
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six six thousand mile</NUMEX> on uh i think it's a pretty that's pretty well bumper to bumper
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		but the drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven seventy</TIMEX> and that's i think that's one of the well i kind of think that the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> are now uh bumping it up to meet it but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to do that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 		yeah
 		they've had that for a while yeah
 		well it says something they're willing at least put something behind it you know they're they feel like turning out a good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> and they're at least
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that warranty stuff that's uh i did have to take this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> car in and the cassette jammed all of a sudden
 		and it was nice to know that you know that warranty it was still under its warranty and they just took it and took care of it right on the spot but that's definitely something i think i'd shop for i'd want as much warranty as i could because
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		it's expensive to get the things fixed anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if it's not covered
 	
 	
 		and i'm thinking about getting a used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with my next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> trying to see if i can't take some of the
 		depreciation off i don't know they're still danger expensive you know i'd you know only i only want to buy something like maybe twenty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousand miles</NUMEX> on it they they don't go down much you know unless they're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years old</TIMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		to buy it
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no they don't you know they
 		yeah if you get something that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one or two years old</TIMEX> uh you can usually knock i i worked at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> as a loan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> and so i could you know i got into that a little bit you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> financing and stuff but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> makes a huge difference you know they say and it's pretty much true that you drive off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX> and you lose at least a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> as soon as you take that thing off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX> in value and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hondas</ENAMEX> and some of those they don't depreciate as much but you can still get them a little bit cheaper
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i tell you what it's kind of scary uh we bought our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> car through an auction a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> auction and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> they they get those things for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> of what they sell them
 	
 	
 		yes
 		you're kidding me
 	
 	
 		i couldn't believe it i uh we stickered the car i got this <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Grand Prix</ENAMEX> was stickered at uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen thousand</TIMEX> it was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety one</NUMEX> and had uh had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousand miles</NUMEX> on it but we ended up getting it for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about ten</TIMEX>
 		and i mean they bought it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten</TIMEX> they'll sell it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen seventeen thousand</TIMEX> i could not believe it had just if you know somebody that's the way to go but unfortunately only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> can get in  but uh
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yeah
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i tell you i i've been real happy with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hondas</ENAMEX> actually we had a have a nineteen eighty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX> too
 		
 		
 	