
 
     		
 	
 		a tough one
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes it is  i know well i i believe in it
 	
 	
 		would you like to begin
 		uh-huh do you feel like there should be any kinds of restrictions on when it's
 	
 	
 		i think
 		uh yes i do think that but i do think that i believe in it whole heartedly i really think that a lot of crime we have the criminal
 	
 	
 		obviously
 	
 	
 		you know element is just unreal i work in a high school here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it just boggles my mind what's happened over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		really do you mean even with adolescents
 	
 	
 		you know i've been there fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen years</TIMEX> and just watching the mentality of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> and and this tough stuff that's going on now you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do you feel that it should be applied to them as well then same kind of laws or
 	
 	
 		i uh well i think that they should tougher laws for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> yes i do believe that not but not the uh capital punishment for them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really don't feel that but i do feel tougher laws but some way i feel they have to uh revise our criminal system
 	
 	
 		you think it's too lenient over all
 	
 	
 		um-hum i really do and i think that the um oh rehab is terrible
 		you know they put them in there and there's too it's just because of numbers though i understand the rehab is so big that they can't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but any way back to capital punishment i do believe in it for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> and and especially um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you know when they actually thinking about it
 		is that number one manslaughter something like that
 	
 	
 		oh premeditated you mean versus uh uh-huh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i i don't know i'm not real sure premeditated right murder definitely of course i do feel that and then these
 	
 	
 		at this point most capital punishment is really uh related to murder though right i mean there's no capital punishment unless a life has been lost
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think i think that's the right
 	
 	
 		right right
 		and um
 	
 	
 		i wonder something i mean i believe as you do that something needs to change but i wonder sometimes what what makes an impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> that do this kind of a crime i mean it it almost seems like
 		they either don't believe it'll ever be them that's caught or if they do they don't really value their lives enough to care if they would lose their lives
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		it's it's i i'm not even sure i i feel uh in between i guess i'm i'm not sure that i have a strong commitment either direction because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know enough about what what would motivate these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know i do think that they are some times um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		put in a rehabilitation program when there's really a very small chance of rehabilitation that that they're coddled for too long and they get the kind of courtesies of our society that that
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX> would love to have you know something's wrong here
 	
 	
 		yes yes that's right that's for sure
 	
 	
 		but
 		it's a tough one
 	
 	
 		well and sometimes the uh on the rehab uh i've just from being around the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> that i'm around they know how to talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>
 		they know exactly what to say to anybody in a
 	
 	
 		in in what respect
 	
 	
 		uh they know the right answers you know
 	
 	
 		like what's within their legal rights or do you mean how to manipulate the system
 	
 	
 		right what's well what's within their legal rights and how to manipulate them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and how to manipulate them just just they they answer to authority and to people
 		to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and that type of thing that they have to answer to or even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> do in to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that count the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and that type of thing you know they they usually answer to them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in a way that like i said manipulative they just manipulate they've manipulated manipulated so long so this is
 	
 	
 		so they feign for example that they're really are um apologetic or what ever for their crime but they're
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right and sorry right and very very sorrowful and then when they get out then we run into the problem of getting right back into a routine again of the same thing
 	
 	
 		but but you know that they aren't
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i'm sure that's easily learned if they don't get it from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> they get it from going through the system one time being in juvenile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> or what ever
 	
 	
 		so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you know if there's much of a difference between the law i'm i'm embarrassed to say i don't know between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> what what difference is there
 	
 	
 		i really don't myself i really don't i know they permit it here but i don't know you know the difference in it actually
 	
 	
 		hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in fact we just had um a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> put to death uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three weeks ago</TIMEX> was in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and i forget for the reason now oh it was for the uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX> that he murdered he murdered a uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a uh
 		it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> i believe he murdered
 	
 	
 		oh my uh-huh it is interesting to look at other cultures other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and see how different their rates are you know you look at even um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> where there's a lot of emotion and sometimes an
 		
 		
 	