
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		all right
 	
 	
 		okay so what do you think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> they got uh i probably didn't get into <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> until maybe
 		maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four three years ago</TIMEX> really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh but i i i just like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> i don't i don't know why i really got into them i read uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Dreveki</ENAMEX>'s book his autobiography and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah wasn't that something of him
 	
 	
 		yeah that that was incredible
 	
 	
 		yeah that's really a really proud of him though the way he's you know
 	
 	
 		the way he handled that entire situation yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah really you know
 	
 	
 		but
 		i just think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> have a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> they they got all you know they're they're real they're real balanced out they got real good pitching and they got the hitting to go along with it so
 	
 	
 		yeah i just don't understand why they're not right up there on the top you know
 	
 	
 		yeah they just they need that i think they just need that one one element to push them over the top you know i don't really know what it is but but every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that's that's really good seems you know like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX> had they had they just had it all that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah um i was mostly an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> you know i had been to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> games at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX> than i have in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because uh i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> you know for some time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i still like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> though you know
 	
 	
 		yeah if you if you're a fan you got to stay with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> any way you know you good and the bad but
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's it's kind of hard i still well
 		basically the the me and all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> around here since we don't have anywhere i mean we can go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astros</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> but since none me or none of me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are really really like either one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> so we uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		about the about the most most baseball we get is either TV or we play it on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> we play RBI <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> so so that's just you know that's small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> trying to make it through the
 	
 	
 		yeah right right
 	
 	
 		through the lull not being around it really but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah right well i prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball uh football over baseball</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah so do i but <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> is still
 	
 	
 		yeah it's
 	
 	
 		you got you got to do something when <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> ain't on so
 	
 	
 		so add hot dogs <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> and apple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly this this is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah um so what do you think's gonna happen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but
 		uh i don't know it's hard to say i haven't really really you have to just keep up with everything in the off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> it's kind of hard to do at least you know you have to read the paper and
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Illustrated</ENAMEX> and everything to keep up with who they traded and who they picked up and and all that but like i say if they can if they can get that one element that they were missing i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> can do it
 	
 	
 		yeah well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		they just i don't you i don't really know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX> i don't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX> uh matter of fact i can't stand the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oakland A's</ENAMEX> just because they have that you know they've got their
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Canseco</ENAMEX> and and all the attitude that goes along with that you know the kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah makes you sick doesn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah you hear what you hear did you hear what he did he ramming his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and i i was like yeah see that's just
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 		
 
 		he's like a little bitty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		yeah he's just a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> with a lot of money so that's just you know but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> or might move away from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> it sounds like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i've heard i've heard talk about that
 	
 	
 		you know uh they won't be that far away but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> it'll be hurting anyhow
 	
 	
 		yeah they're not gonna be happy about it
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		but i hope they can do good i mean that's just
 		i think they're a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that just need that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one little</NUMEX> thing to push them over i don't know
 		exactly what it is they got they're pretty balanced out all the way through it just might be the drive you know more than anything else they just they probably just need something to push them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i that's that's the only thing i can see that's holding them back is the ambition to do it or somebody basically maybe they just need everybody to tell them they can't do it
 		maybe that's what you know that's what some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> need
 		look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins</ENAMEX> going from worst to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> so
 	
 	
 		i know isn't that something you couldn't believe that huh
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>'s a my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> forever forever so he had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his year this year</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah i just it
 	
 	
 		we we got quite preoccupied we we got into that a whole bunch that was a that was a series to remember for sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all seven</NUMEX> games of that so that was definitely worth watching
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah i couldn't believe that you know i don't uh there was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> in that chanting that they have that would drive you up a wall
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah they every every every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> been doing that now and it and it i can't figure out why i've yet to figure out why they're all doing that i'm like it doesn't work it's obvious it doesn't work because the you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you know God
 		yeah well you're right
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> didn't win so uh why why keep on doing something that didn't work but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know i was i was kind of surprised that  we're gonna talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> and i get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s voice i was i was i was thinking uh-huh i talked to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vinny</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> about fixing your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah i got i called got a call <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> about about fixing your automobile up so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball baseball</ENAMEX> it's it's kind of i don't know it's kind of odd that they'd do you pick the topic or does the computer
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		no uh they give you a list of things that you want to talk
 		
 		
 	