
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think the first thing they said i've written this down so it would is it possible do you think it's possible to have honesty in government
 		or an honest government
 	
 	
 		okay you're asking what my opinion about whether it's possible to have honesty in government  well i suspect that it is possible uh i think it probably
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is more likely if you have a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government unit</ENAMEX> where everybody knows everybody
 	
 	
 		right that's a good point
 	
 	
 		but um
 		other than that i think maybe it just depends on how you define honesty
 	
 	
 		that's an interesting yeah that's interesting i had read something one time and it was just applying to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> in general it was written <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX>
 		it said that is impossible to have
 		a completely honest system of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who choose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for their positions are power seekers
 		and i thought that was interesting
 		it wasn't just talking about our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> it was just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in general from times past you know on and
 	
 	
 		um-hum so they're saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> would tend to be power <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		right and that would be a next question to ask how many do you think are in there for public for but because they wanna be of service to us
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		or are they in there for their own gains and personally i feel it's probably there's probably some of each
 	
 	
 		right yeah but i think maybe a lot of them um say the more honest ones who are still looking out for themselves it may be more a matter of
 		not what can i steal while i'm in office but how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> can i make while i'm in office and  you know how good a name can i make for myself and so forth
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		so i guess it would be like anything else the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> probably has the same
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 		and they talked uh the other let's see <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> question was how much how much self-serving for their own gains do you think goes on then they that's hard to answer i'm sure there's a lot but i agree with you there's a lot in business i think that's just
 		i think that's very normal
 	
 	
 		i think i'm
 	
 	
 		that we should not expect i mean i think we put too much on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> we expect them
 		to only be there to serve us you know
 	
 	
 		i think a little more honesty in campaigns would be more to the point if you knew what you were getting when you voted uh  yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		that's a problem isn't it
 		it's interesting because i'm taking a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> right now and
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things i always realize it's so easy to blame them to blame a lot of times i think it's our own fault
 		they lie to us because we don't wanna hear the truth and if
 	
 	
 		yeah they say you get the government you deserve
 	
 	
 		if they tell us the truth we don't elect them and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		especially with all this front cover stuff coming up here lately
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s past and i don't know why anybody would wanna get under that scrutiny anymore
 	
 	
 		it's hard to imagine
 	
 	
 		because it's i think it's gotten just careless well we're not talking about issues we're talking about somebody's personal life and
 		and we're getting away from what we ought to be looking at
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah and it almost seems like in order to avoid uh some of this scandal you would have to have the kind of life that you would only find in a say in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bobsy Twins</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		right
 		you know i also think it'd be funny if we could know know everything about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were in there and threw them out i don't think there would be too many left you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		so you're taking a government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> at what at the university
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh at uh it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCJC Texas Tarrant County Junior College</ENAMEX> yeah and it's really it's really enjoyable i like it
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and they also you know ask can we eliminate do you think we could make laws to eliminate all corruption and i don't think we can make laws to eliminate anything anyplace totally
 	
 	
 		you can make laws against corruption but that doesn't eliminate it does it
 	
 	
 		yeah but that doesn't mean i don't think making laws will
 		stop it
 		i mean i don't know how many laws you'd have to have i mean you know
 	
 	
 		well they've got laws against cannibalism cannibalism but that didn't stop that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> did it
 	
 	
 		no sure didn't did it
 		so no i think you can legislate but i think there's no way that you'd eliminated all by legislating and we'd end up with so many more laws that
 		you know i mean i just think that's human nature that you're gonna have corruption
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in business personal life i mean you know
 	
 	
 		actually i think other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> may have it worse uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is always having a some kind of a scandal usually involving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> very close to him it's so uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 		yeah i still believe i get very fed up with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> sometimes but when i think about where i'd wanna go
 		you know this is still the best or i can
 	
 	
 		yeah i've been around to a few other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and i uh i i have not found one yet that i would rather live in i think uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah at it's worst i think we've got the best
 		
 		
 	