
 
     		
 	
 		talk in the background  she's i don't know what she sees outside well what kind of music do you like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh well
 		
 
 		well mostly rock
 	
 	
 		rock
 	
 	
 		yeah what about you
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh everything um
 	
 	
 		well i like well i like different you know different things but uh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		primarily you know rock and roll
 	
 	
 		what era of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> and roll or whatever did you prefer
 	
 	
 		oh you know well you i i really like more of the modern stuff you know but i like the oldies you know they're okay
 		but i you know i listen mostly mostly to the you know the modern stations
 	
 	
 		um
 		um i guess we listen to a lot of things um i grew up with the with rock and roll and older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and sisters
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so i would i remember always being kind of ahead of my
 		peers just because
 		um you know in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade i was listening to to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and stuff that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graders</ENAMEX> usually aren't interested in music by that time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think now i listen we listen to a variety of stuff um jazz or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western or
 	
 	
 		see now i don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western uh
 	
 	
 		do you not i don't i don't like the old the old
 	
 	
 		i don't like most you know most of it i don't like but i recently saw that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> show
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i thought he was terrific and i really thought i mean i thought he was a great you know really wonderful entertainer the way he um he you know he he was very good
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 		i there
 		i think country music i don't like the real old twangy stuff like the
 	
 	
 		i don't like twainese no i non't
 	
 	
 		you know but that it has undergone undergone a lot of change and there's a like there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyle Lovett</ENAMEX> that he could be considered
 	
 	
 		oh he's really not that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i mean i've heard him sing stuff that really doesn't sound too you know
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah see he does it's more what do they call it
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		sometimes i've heard it called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rockabilly</ENAMEX> where it's like rock and roll and or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but um but they refer to him you know as a country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> but a lot of his stuff sounds really jazzy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah right i  yeah i have heard him and uh i didn't think he was a country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> you know i
 	
 	
 		um they i mean they they term him as that but i i know well i've watched like the music awards or the country music awards before and they had him on as a new up and coming country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh well
 	
 	
 		so it's kind of i mean but there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kind of like that that
 		they're they're playing they're right on the line and you know the
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		at the the i guess the rock and roll side might be so saturated that
 		you know they're trying out this and and we've gone <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western dancing before and
 	
 	
 		oh you really
 	
 	
 		but and it when i don't i don't dance i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> dance that well but
 		you know just watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when they get out there is when they start playing the rock and roll music while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>'s taking a break
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know i mean they get out there and jitterbug and or you know whatever you want to call it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so i think there's there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there now that aren't aren't just <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Johnny Cash</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> or or you know or um
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i don't even know what the alternative
 	
 	
 		well you know i said let me watch this and see what all the fuss is about i mean everybody's raving about this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you know
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is i have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> he's uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four and</TIMEX> of course he hates country music and he said ma i can't believe you're gonna watch that i said i have to find out
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> said she likes him i said i if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> likes him i said he's gonna not he he couldn't be all wrong you know i mean he's there's got to be something good about the guy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so i watched it and really i i just thought he was terrific
 	
 	
 		i saw previews of it and it looked more like a rock and roll concert than a
 	
 	
 		i don't know but i mean and his songs uh uh were you know i liked them uh were they weren't that silly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> western stuff that you know they used to do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> you know with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dopey</ENAMEX> lyrics you know very simple lyrics
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		and there's still some out there like that too
 	
 	
 		uh you know they're
 		yeah oh there are but uh uh yeah i think as a whole it's gotten more definitely more sophisticated in the you know in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i do too i do too
 	
 	
 		you know but then i wouldn't listen you know listen to it uh you know steadily uh you know i wouldn't listen to it at all actually  you know i just don't really care for it any you know it as a whole but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> do you listen to radio
 	
 	
 		i usually listen to either the uh classic rock it's uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX> or or uh one oh two
 	
 	
 		yeah i switch around
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> loves the oldies you know every time he he gets in the car the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> he sticks on the oldies station
 	
 	
 		well it's funny because my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> um i'm youngest of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and we all
 		play some type of music interest instrument instrument and i had a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> that were in rock and roll bands and
 		so forth so you know he was constantly having to grow up with us so at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> or his birthday we're always buying him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		tapes you know to keep him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	