
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridgette</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Bridgette i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's nice to meet you
 	
 	
 		and nice to meet you are you um
 		where are you from
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and what's that where's that
 	
 	
 		it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">west Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin Kenosha</ENAMEX> yeah i'm not very familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm far
 	
 	
 		well is that where you are right now
 	
 	
 		yeah i i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenosha Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh i didn't know i'd get someone that far away
 	
 	
 		yeah i i've gotten a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and they're always like wow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know that's i was like oh my gosh so we're supposed to talk about music okay i'll push one then
 	
 	
 		uh-huh okay okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		all right ah what kind of music do you like
 	
 	
 		um i listen to all sorts of music really i think uh i like a lot of country
 	
 	
 		oh yeah is that really popular in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> or is that just like a stereotype because it's the south
 	
 	
 		um
 		i think it's pretty popular  i mean it is probably like a huge stereotype but i think it's pretty popular too what kind of music do you like
 	
 	
 		is it
 		oh
 		um well i used to not really like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that much but i think but what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> really likes it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i used to listen to that and the older i got the more it you know i i can listen to it but um i prefer um  um hm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like i like um Firehouse
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slaughter</ENAMEX>  and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um Scorpions um the Scorpions</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so you like more hard rock yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah but i also like the top <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> too and i really like the oldies <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> like um fifties music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">and um The Doors</ENAMEX> are pretty good too i can listen to them and The Who i i really like all kinds i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's how i am too do you like any rap music
 	
 	
 		um no that's about the only kind i don't get into is like rap and like classical and um
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't either
 	
 	
 		jazz is all right but um like the blues and stuff like that i i like to dance and if it's like a upbeat you know good song then then i'll listen to it and if i'm out you know dancing then makes it better to listen to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so you like mostly like uh do you like hard rock the best
 	
 	
 		yeah um there's this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Blaze</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and that's my favorite  because they yeah they play um all different kinds of um harder rock
 	
 	
 		really
 		uh-huh well i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh i've been there hm um-hum
 	
 	
 		have you they have hard rock <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> there i don't even think they have a hard rock <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> i pretty sure they don't if they if they do i've never come across it
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they only have i mean they don't have really it's really small and uh  they don't have that really many radio you know like top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forty stations</ENAMEX> even
 	
 	
 		oh really uh oh yeah oh that's neat uh-huh me too  yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it's more like a college <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> so yeah because i'm in college
 		
 
 		cool so um i mean i  don't think gah they had a i don't think they do have a hard rock <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		see you don't here very often and you  never have like bands come you never have them like come up to we're up here you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really we get a lot like at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> because um we have a lot of like bands that form by themselves like from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> trying to get started you know to the big top and yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		see that's great you would never see that here no i don't think you would
 	
 	
 		oh really uh-huh
 		i think a lot of music has to do with like you know the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you hang around with and especially your environment like you know the settings like the bigger cities you get more variety i think you know
 	
 	
 		yeah see yeah see i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> up here being it's so far like in the panhandle of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		uh i've gotten to like um a couple of songs from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you i know he's great i like him a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah i i just um heard of him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend um</ENAMEX> he uh likes some types of country music and he was listening to that and it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		see i only know very few too even i mean i only know like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> and like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Straight</ENAMEX> and a few of the top the really good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> i really like him he's really good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah i i've liked most the songs i heard so that was good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you have to kind of get used to it though because i didn't like country western really for a while and even when i came up here i didn't listen to it until like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> then i started listening to it a lot and then then you like it a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah same here
 		oh yeah
 		uh i just started um listening to it too because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> but yeah after i heard it a while at first i didn't like it and then i heard it and then i'm like oh this isn't so bad you know it's it's
 		you know upbeat and
 		you know i got into it and i saw on TV <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time um they were playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> and they were um showing how to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> dance to it and it looked so fun because like i say i like to dance and it was just really neat
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah you would like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stepping then
 	
 	
 		yeah it it looked fun i'm like oh i wanna learn now
 	
 	
 		i know i wanted to i wanna learn to because we can do it but we're not very good
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		we're just like oh yeah we kind of fake it you know so i wanna take lessons because i think that'd be so fun i think
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	