
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay well why don't you start because it said i was suppose to ask you what do you
 	
 	
 		do you have any elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> currently in uh in a nursing home now
 	
 	
 		yes i do
 	
 	
 		do you i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and two</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		she'll be a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred and three</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we decided not to put her in a nursing home
 		she lives with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> who also live here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> takes care of her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she even though she is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and two</NUMEX> she still has all of her faculties
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		she still has her snap she takes care of her own business this is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> that she has gotten weak and actually has to have a little walker
 		but with somebody that needs around the clock care i have seen my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> age
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i've seen them in the she's been there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> now and i have seen them age <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> in the time and and with the expense and everything i think i still think it is worth it if you if you had a good nursing home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they needed some quality care i would put someone in a nursing home
 	
 	
 		right
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> finally they had to make a family decision there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and fortunately <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of them live in the same home town
 		and she has <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> it was getting where she was
 		getting things dangerous i mean letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> in and things like this but they were very fortunate it's a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she happens to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s and then she's got a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> there and that go and see her all of the time but she really doesn't nobody thought she would adjust but she's adjusted beautifully
 	
 	
 		oh well that's good
 		oh that is great
 	
 	
 		but then i am also facing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> who is very sick and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> reside in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> she's been taking care of him i don't know how much longer this can last
 		and at that point because he requires round the clock he can't do anything without her he doesn't know when to take his medicine
 		and it's really sad and i have thought if something would happen to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> for
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s are not interested in helping me so i would have to move him down here that way i want to see the nursing home if i have to put him into one
 		you know where i can go see it i i'd be very uncomfortable with him being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
 		and
 	
 	
 		why yeah i'm sure you have got some really good nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes and some of them are limited care too where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can do uh like they have apartment styles but that wouldn't work for him i think he's beyond that
 		where if you need help you can get it but basically <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kind of have a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s are available if they need them and allows
 	
 	
 		um-hum i i i know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> that lives in a place similar to that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well the only problem with these are that they are very expensive of course i guess all nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> there is
 	
 	
 		where
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		and the bad thing about it before you can get any kind of government help you just practically have we have to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pauper</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it it takes every <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">penny</NUMEX> they want you to spend every dime you have before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will pay for your your care and that's the sad part about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		yeah i see uh yeah and i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do it now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> it's interesting i talked to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> they allow you sixty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five thousand dollars</NUMEX> and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and your home
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> could make it on that what she probably would do is disburse the money to me and then i would send it back to her so that's probably what would happen
 	
 	
 		um-hum i think that's what most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do you just have to give it everything away
 	
 	
 		yeah it's unfortunate
 	
 	
 		i i i work at a brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and i have seen so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that just have to gift
 		you know their belongings as much as they can each year in anticipation of having to move to a nursing home
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah it's frightening and i guess uh i don't know how old you are i'm <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty six</NUMEX> you know we're the generation moving into this and i don't know how our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are gonna take care of us
 	
 	
 		i can't imagine i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty nine</TIMEX> and everybody in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s always had we don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> everybody that has has them later in life so my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> are in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their late sixties</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i mean they're not  that far away
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		i also fill in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> a squeeze between
 		looking to having to help my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and still having to help my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> because things are so rough out there job wise and he's still living at home and i don't know how he's ever going to get on his own the way things are
 	
 	
 		oh i know
 	
 	
 		and so it's kind of squeezed you feel squeezed in the middle of having both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> but it something will have to change as more and more of us get older uh luckily if we could be like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>
 		i uh you know i would love to live to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and two</NUMEX> if i were okay
 	
 	
 		it but yeah most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't
 	
 	
 		but you see these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in their seventies yeah most aren't that's the problem
 	
 	
 		and that's the bad thing i would hate to have lived so long she lived by herself
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> passed away before i was born so she lived by herself up until she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety ninety one</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's incredible
 	
 	
 		and just did everything and it but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't like
 		
 		
 	