
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX> whenever you get around to purchasing your next new car
 		what are going to be the chief considerations
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the main considerations is safety and quietness and um economy what about you
 	
 	
 		uh i'm interested primarily in reliability
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well i have found most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> now are pretty reliable um
 		i haven't found any that have left me down yet what are your specific requirements <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> or foreign
 	
 	
 		well
 		well uh let me give you a little history on that i drove i drove uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> for a long time
 		and in fact i had a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> and it ended up costing it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only about five or six years old</TIMEX> and i was paying on the average a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> a month in repair bills on that thing
 		and i just couldn't handle that so i took a deep breath and bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX>
 		and have lived happily ever after since then yes yes i've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> small problems neither one of which left me by the side of the road
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		uh with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five years</TIMEX> and and when i was buying that i was concerned primarily with reliability reliability
 		and but i also wanted a hatchback
 		because you know you you sometimes you have to carry bags of fertilizer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		so
 		well it is a sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that i got which is my first probably my last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> because
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">comfort</ENAMEX> is not
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		high on the list when you get a sports car
 	
 	
 		do you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> for comfort or
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		just you
 	
 	
 		just me
 	
 	
 		well i had the same problem whenever i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> car i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		just me
 	
 	
 		it was constantly giving me valve problems i had this constant ticking of the valves and uh i switched over to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Plymouth</ENAMEX>
 		and i haven't had a lick of problem
 	
 	
 		does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> have an air bag
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		it does
 	
 	
 		but just on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s side
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i wish they would come out with them everywhere on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> side too
 	
 	
 		yeah i suspect they probably will
 		and i think on my next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i'll be concerned i'll i think i will want antilock brakes
 		i've heard good things about them it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> it was offered on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Supra</ENAMEX> when i bought mine
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i was a little nervous about some new technology i mean i'd got to where i had real this real hate relationship with anything that looked like service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> at a dealership
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i found out they're pretty good whenever uh especially on weather like we're having <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> are so slippery
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the antilock brakes are one of the better ones to have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think i'd i'd like that i don't know i i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who drives an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acura</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Legend</ENAMEX> which is very comfortable car
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it it makes me more aware of how uncomfortable mine is every time i ride in his car
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> has a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civic Honda</ENAMEX> and that's a real comfortable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to sit in yeah which surprised me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh is it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> now i just bought and uh it's real comfortable
 		and i'm very happy with it but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> has a good warranty that they have to stand behind so i haven't had any
 		worries about that that's one thing i go for in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is their warranty and uh
 		what does and doesn't come under that warrantee but they have the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seven thousand uh seven thousand seventy thousand miles</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> i believe
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh bumper to bumper and i have no complaints
 	
 	
 		well that's great
 	
 	
 		so far with mine
 	
 	
 		that's great
 		so if you had to do it again you'd buy another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> do you think would you
 	
 	
 		i sure would
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge Plymouth Chrysler</ENAMEX> something in that line
 	
 	
 		that's
 		yeah that's interesting because i mean i i was hearing a just on on the way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> i heard something on the news about the trade deficit for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> the figures were some some very large number
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was thinking golly and and you know it's partly my fault i mean not in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i i really have a problem buying <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> things and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> i bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 		and i don't know i hope by the time this car wears out and i hope that's not for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another five or ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		i hope that i can get an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> one at that time
 	
 	
 		well that's another fallacy because uh so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say that's a requirement has to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 		but uh did you know that my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> has foreign parts in it and so does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> and so does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh sure it
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so um i often hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saying well i want to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> or i like the foreign something and uh
 		they're built right here like the foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are even built over here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Datsun</ENAMEX> has a
 		
 		
 	