
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well what do you think about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> providing health insurance for everybody i think they should i know i had a job until let's see
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago this past December</TIMEX> i was working for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PIE</ENAMEX> and they closed and naturally while i was working for them i had health insurance
 		but um for me to try to get it now uh it would cost me like over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three hundred dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> with the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that was providing health insurance at at pie
 	
 	
 		good grief that's just almost unaffordable isn't it
 	
 	
 		right it really is and i think you know i think the God the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should come up with some kind of a health plan or stop these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> from having their prices so high
 	
 	
 		well i wonder if they couldn't just provide uh interim health insurance for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are between jobs like that that might be a step in the right direction i don't know
 	
 	
 		well the thing is you know jobs are so hard to find you know and then what you can get out here in anyhow in the valley where i live at now they don't wanna pay anything for health insurance at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		no benefits you know
 		um yes i mean you get a job now and
 	
 	
 		you mean the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		the wages are really low and uh
 	
 	
 		because everybody's competing for jobs
 	
 	
 		yeah and they don't want uh to pay any benefits
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so you just you know pray to God that you don't get sick
 	
 	
 		well i used to think that universal health insurance was probably the right thing to do i I have to think about it some more now because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> is uh actually he's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh he told me that there're a lot of uh lot of counts against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> system which is basically the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are talking about for here i don't understand the arguments exactly he says it restricts your choice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and and so forth i'm not quite sure i understand why government health insurance would restrict your choice any more than private insurance does
 	
 	
 		no i don't understand that either
 	
 	
 		i mean we're on a private insurance plan right now uh actually uh i have my own business and and we uh our health insurance is through my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s employer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> we get another list of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s we can go to and where we can buy or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and
 		and uh it changes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> it's always so confusing so uh
 	
 	
 		yeah well i know the plan that i had with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PIE i</ENAMEX> could go to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and i could go to any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and get my prescriptions filled you know then i just sent cards in and then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they would have like a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollar deductible per year for my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and then they would just send me a check for what was ever over that you know
 	
 	
 		well yeah
 		of course the restricted choice in this case is because only certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> agree to accept the uh the limits of uh compensation but of course that is restricted choice so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't think that the restricted choice really uh
 		has to do with the difference between uh public and private health insurance i think it has to do with the the the uh attempt to limit cost doesn't it and uh everybody agrees that we need to limit cost some way so
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah that's true that's true there
 	
 	
 		well um i guess the most sensible thing i've heard about this is they they say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are trying you you you have to recognize that if you're going to
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		have the very best health care possible and uh available on demand whenever and wherever you want it then it's gonna be expensive
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		and if you wanna pay less then you're gonna have to settle for a health system that is not quite that uh lavish
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		but there's just so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that can't afford to pay anything you know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that's on unemployment
 	
 	
 		yeah well what happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s safety net anyway did he take that back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> with him
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 		
 
 	
 	
 		using it for a trampoline now
 	
 	
 		yeah probably so i don't know but it is it does seem to be a big problem
 		you know i don't know what they're gonna come up with but um
 		i sure wish they would come up with with something
 		and uh like i say and and i'm at the age too where the i'll be fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't wanna hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> this age any more
 		and i worked for my previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty six years</TIMEX> you know so
 		it's kind of hard you know so
 	
 	
 		yeah they'll be needing you in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> because they're running out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> down there at the other end and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah they'll be calling at my door huh  but any how
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well if they're smart
 	
 	
 		yeah now i I do think the government though is gonna have to do something uh with this problem because it you you know even to go to a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> out here just to ask him anything costs you forty bucks
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know just for the visit
 		and then he then that's not counting what medicine you're gonna buy and everything else you know and he might tell you well you know now you're gonna have to come back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and then that's another forty bucks plus whatever else he decides to do to you
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		
 		
 	