
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Janet</ENAMEX> do you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have a family budget
 	
 	
 		
 
 		we try to  like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> i'm sitting i'm right <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this minute</TIMEX> dishing up cheap spaghetti which is one way we try and keep within a budget
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it's probably why we're participating too right
 	
 	
 		although i'm trying to raise money for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy scout</ENAMEX> cause
 		um actually how we do it is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i both work and we try very hard to live on his salary and my salary goes automatically into a savings
 		account which we try not to use too much although from that we both definitely we typically pay our credit cards from that account
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's the that's the uh our household expenses are pretty well covered because they're pretty much the same every month
 		but it's our credit card spending that it's always the problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> is the cost of living uh high down there is it tough to
 	
 	
 		i don't know what to compare it to i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> but i was a student then and you know when you're a student things don't mean much um i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is um
 	
 	
 		i know it's just a
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		relatively high priced <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> but then there's not
 		i think energy and some of the other things aren't quite so high
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i my my gestalt is that our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX> are sort of intermediate there're not as bad as i have seen in big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> areas
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		um the cost of living here is cheap in in fact it's really great we've got a
 		a quite a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> we've got a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom home home</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> in it and it cost me through let me see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX> it cost me fifty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five thousand</NUMEX>
 		so it's great i mean uh uh
 	
 	
 		that is
 		where are you from originally
 	
 	
 		right here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> in law in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano Texas</ENAMEX> and that's how we got hooked up with this uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> deal but it's
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i don't know anyone from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um</ENAMEX> and i have a great love for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		would go back in a minute if i could but i married a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they don't always tell you that they have a homing instinct
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i our home uh we have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom home um</ENAMEX> but it's more in the range of with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">around two hundred forty thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four and a half</NUMEX> times your home i'm sure they're probably quite comparable
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or maybe i don't know ours is nice our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is nicely located but i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> itself is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well i i wouldn't uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>'s not nicely located i probably got a bargain i think more
 	
 	
 		particularly extraordinary
 		how about budget wise how how do you do a family budget are you married
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes i am and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is very meticulous about budgeting she has a computer program in fact i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> i'm a CPA
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm calling you from work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> uh but uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> runs every single check she spends through a computer
 		and she can tell me on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> basis and she's more interested not me in fact i only look at it once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> when i do our we do our taxes
 		but she can tell you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> exactly what she's paid for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX> and uh utility bills and for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and everything she's uh
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> tries very hard to do that for us and we used the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Managing Your Money</ENAMEX> software package with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Tobias</ENAMEX> he is familiar with that one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		yeah i'm not i'm not uh-huh
 	
 	
 		well i mean now i'm sure there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> software packages but um he tried very hard and we were all computerized and we
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		our regular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> checks we printed you know um and i hated i did it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> and hated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every minute</TIMEX> of it  and still founded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> of our checks
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 	
 	
 		maybe a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> i still hand wrote because it would be like in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> parking lot or
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yep
 	
 	
 		you know at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s skating lesson or something like that so we had to come we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> checks two sizes of checks
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um
 		excuse me  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth</ENAMEX> right there
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> wants to know where the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spaghetti cheese</ENAMEX> is um so we we tried and it was pretty nice one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> mistake i think we made in that is that um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		for budgeting purposes in terms of putting it in a budget we must have had eighty different categories and so they they became sort of nonsensical instead of i always said if we had redone it we should have just put big categories like utilities
 	
 	
 		yep
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you know luxuries and entertainment that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about twenty five</NUMEX> categories is all probably and we write all of our checks out of the register we don't try to do any through the computer and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> just sets down when she's got <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX> and just keys them all in
 		and it's really not you know that bad it um
 		well i don't know it might it might've been tough for you but she enjoys it and that's another thing too she really enjoys it
 		she uh
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well i see  i suppose that's the key um
 	
 	
 		just gets a thrill out of seeing where her money went i guess
 	
 	
 		do you does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> work outside the home
 	
 	
 		she does she's she teaches at um a small <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> college here she's uh teaches uh business communications
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness well with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPA</ENAMEX> and a business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you should be organized
 	
 	
 		and
 		uh yeah uh i don't know no we still have problems with money like everybody else
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	