
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh just the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> screamer
 	
 	
 		okay  How old how old i is uh he or she
 	
 	
 		he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX> today
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> and a half
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		huh yeah and he's um he's discovered pens and that you lick the backs of stamps
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's what he was screaming about  i just uh
 	
 	
 		well i would suppose a lot of your time is spent with yours then
 	
 	
 		yes i i'm a full time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and i spend all day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes and i spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> with the baby
 	
 	
 		uh-huh How how do you see most of the world now uh uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> spending time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see a real growing trend for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> going back into the home
 		where a lot a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if they really can can make a a tight budget they're going back to where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		and not working so much to
 	
 	
 		and not working and not
 	
 	
 		live live in the fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and drive the nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i personally see that happening maybe i'm not in the right neighborhood but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really do see it a big trend toward that and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> even not waiting as late in life as they had been
 		i know for a while that there were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> waiting to have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and i think that trend is is slowing down
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh i i'd have to agree with you that's what's happening back here in the west more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
 		are just saying it's not worth it and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and spending more time at at home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i know it's tough for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to do that i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh my oldest one is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only six</NUMEX> but she's still in dance and kindergarten and you know she's got a bunch of things going on and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i my it's a good thing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> she she does work a little bit she works part time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> she at a junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> here but she has time to go to all of her uh dance concert <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">recitals</ENAMEX> and things and and it just means so much and i i try to be there but i don't get to go all the time
 	
 	
 		ah uh-huh
 		yeah
 		well i agree it
 		it's really important to me to support my family
 		to support my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> without support are really they're missing out a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah my you know when when i was growing up my i i played high school sports
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> rarely missed a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> game my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> both but mostly my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> rarely missed a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football game</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> game even if we had to travel away from the local area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he would always go and uh i remember that and i'll never forget that you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh and it
 		well it obviously made a really good impression on you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		and that's something that i'd sure like to do with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> when they
 	
 	
 		yeah well i agree i'm i'm even considering putting my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in a tumbling class
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know going and maybe staying with him during most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and then going to see what he does and all that
 		because i really i think it's important for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to be around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but i also think it's important for there to be a tight nucleus at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i'm
 		trying to think of what else what was the other part of the topic
 	
 	
 		um trends and uh
 	
 	
 		trends
 	
 	
 		we've talked about trends um you're you're talking about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> does your do you find your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has a hard time spending time with the child
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes
 	
 	
 		it's tough isn't it i sure have a hard time see i still at work now
 	
 	
 		well
 		oh are you
 	
 	
 		yes it's uh it is sure tough for me
 	
 	
 		well he
 		he has a tendency um
 		to leave it to me since i'm with him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's really hard for me to let go too
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		i feel very attached to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and i i'm sure it would change if i had another one
 		but um
 		i just don't think that
 		i don't know i i don't see much of a change happening there i wish they would spend more time together
 		but
 	
 	
 		yeah what line of business is he in
 	
 	
 		we'll uh we'll see how that goes
 		he's um a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 		So he's part of the study here then almost isn't he
 	
 	
 		well it's um it's not the speech study but it's a different kind of study i mean he he works
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in uh laser he's a laser physicist
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's a completely different line of work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		than uh than the speech program but
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		anyhow
 	
 	
 		well i i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> and i know it takes it's it takes a lot of lot of time away from the home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so uh i just don't i the only time i get a lot of time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> is when
 		
 		
 	