
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 		to face the situation where you were looking at putting a loved one in the nursing home
 	
 	
 		well i we're sort of in the middle of it um
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last February</TIMEX> we brought my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> to us here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and so far she has been with us but
 		i really look to the future that it may be occurring um i don't know what i'll do i i'm almost inclined to hire somebody um to be in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with her rather than have to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		put her somewhere you know but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you don't feel as though that that's a decision you're comfortable with because
 	
 	
 		well i think  partly and it's not me it's the it seems to me the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and my in-laws
 	
 	
 		you'd be
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um you know the stigma used to be you went there and and you died and so they have all kind of
 	
 	
 		you feel as though they are being abandoned if you leave them somewhere
 	
 	
 		right
 		you know it just um
 		and you try and say you know they're nice now or or nicer and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know i wouldn't want her in one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> because i couldn't check on her but if she were in one near here i i would probably be there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know several times per <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> and i would
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		stand up and scream if i saw things that were you know  improper or or uh you know her care was not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it's difficult boy i really
 	
 	
 		have you had that experience yet
 	
 	
 		can appreciate
 		no i haven't but um
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		i i work in a hospital and we see patients
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are just not able to care for them once they've left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and so they have to make that decision often when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s still in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		it's uh well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> and that was you know he had <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and
 		eventually the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> comes and says you know your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> uh care you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> says he doesn't need the level of care to be hospitalized so you are going to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		eventually they'll come and tell you you will have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX>  to you know move him somewhere else and and that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and i needed to think what do we want to do at that point we did because he was
 	
 	
 		so then you begin right
 	
 	
 		not yet comatose but real close and he lived <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> in the nursing home so we did do that but um at at that time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three and a half years ago</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was in such a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		state of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> i didn't think she could handle even if we had full time around the clock care i didn't think
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		emotionally she could handle him being there it  well it yes that too you you know there is no question that uh
 	
 	
 		yes it's a challenging job physically
 	
 	
 		just moving them about is um difficult but it really is and it's just uh and i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> whose we're all in the age <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> where
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		were thinking about some of these things for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and it really is uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes
 		what are some of the things that you have looked for for example with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> what what helped you identify an appropriate
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">placement</ENAMEX> was it was it geographic was it how close it was to you or
 	
 	
 		with
 		well of course this again was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> actually the level of care and in fact <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that we looked at were you know they were all in mauve and blue and very elegant looking and
 	
 	
 		oh that's right
 	
 	
 		and so on but i didn't like the fact that they had you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> for one uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> or one care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giver</ENAMEX> and the one we selected was not nearly as
 	
 	
 		care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giver</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		uh up to date however it was clean  and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were well cared for and i like it because it had a level of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five to one</NUMEX> and i felt that  that would be
 	
 	
 		yes
 		
 
 	
 	
 		better care for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> uh and but several of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> oh but you ought to i said i know but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we're making this decision and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> basically let me make the decision so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and she was pleased with it because he did get um
 		you know just wonderful care
 	
 	
 		that's a pretty important factor too that really influences the degree
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely i don't care what you know one of these had a little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream parlor</ENAMEX> and i looked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> i said my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> you know will never get out of a bed i don't care about a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> parlor
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know if you went there and you were in your seventies and well you just went there
 		to a you know retirement center yes you could do all that good stuff but this was
 	
 	
 		more a transitional setting
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i wanted him cared for and and not left uh you know if he spoiled his linens or something i did not want that
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		you know there what do you do in a hospital work with okay all right
 	
 	
 		my job is as occupational therapist um
 		a lot of what we are looking at are are skills that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is gonna have to be able to perform to be able to live independently once they leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and we sometimes help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> make that decision if it looks like they're gonna be able to
 		get in and out of bed or on and off the toilet with just a little bit of help then that's something that they can manage but
 		you you're talking about an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> and when it involves quite a bit of assistance and lifting you don't want the other person
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	