
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um what type of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		we take several at home i i take um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skiing Magazine</ENAMEX> and i take uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover Magazine</ENAMEX> and also uh CD and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stereo Review</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geographic</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		oh that's a
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boys Life</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh good that's a good one i'd like to get  um so i take it that you like to ski do you um do you um
 		receive a lot of information on skiing through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skiing Magazine</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i presume that i do uh i suppose that puts me on some mailing lists and so forth because i do get things from ski <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> and things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh at during the year
 	
 	
 		oh uh and do you receive discounts and things like that do you think or
 	
 	
 		uh not so much that i uh more likely to see those at a ski show or something but um  i just enjoy reading about the resorts and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		where you can go and and new equipment that's come out and so forth some fashions are always in there too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so with this vacation you're taking did you receive the information from your skiing magazine
 	
 	
 		probably not uh we already knew we wanted to take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and we just started looking around
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i may have referred to a couple of them but we went to the ski show and looked at all of the resort information and picked up a lot of brochures
 	
 	
 		oh
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and just decided to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Crested Butte</ENAMEX> we hadn't been there before
 	
 	
 		um that sounds nice
 	
 	
 		it's kind of away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> that's why we chose that one it's supposedly low lift lines but i haven't skied <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> yet but i want to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		huh that's
 		oh well you need to come out
 	
 	
 		like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sundance</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park City</ENAMEX> and some of those i understand <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Deer Valley</ENAMEX> is nice too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Deer Valley uh</ENAMEX>-huh yeah
 		they are it's wonderful snow
 	
 	
 		well how about you what what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> do you have at home
 	
 	
 		uh i am currently taking <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Decorative Woodworking and uh Country Living</ENAMEX> and let's see we do have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geographic</ENAMEX> and then we have some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> magazines
 		but i really enjoy the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Decorative Woodworking</ENAMEX> i'm heavy into woodworking and tole painting and things like that so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Decorative Woodworking</ENAMEX> has just been a great great help
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		does it have uh articles on how to do things as well as equipment that you can buy and so forth
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh they do have uh mostly they have the the ads on the equipment but the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is just filled with
 		uh pictures and projects that you can make yourself and then it has all of the patterns and the instructions that you would need to make a wood project and
 		and then how to paint it with the tole paintings and so it's really a fun one i like that
 	
 	
 		well that's good it's good to get use out of one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure that um in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geographic</ENAMEX> i mean i read it but then they just sort of gather dust for a long period of time but then eventually there'll be a school project or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> will need to refer back through
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty eight</NUMEX> back issues to find you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> or something or whatever it is he's looking for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh  yeah</ENAMEX>
 		yes i've i've noticed that too but they have been nice to have around every once in a while they come in handy
 	
 	
 		i used to take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian</ENAMEX> too and i liked that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> but it was i was just found myself not ever getting around to reading it you get so many coming in and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hm oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		by the time the next round comes in i'm still not through reading the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round
 	
 	
 		oh that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientific American</ENAMEX> comes to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> too i forgot that's mostly my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s but he but i do read it too and so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 		well that sounds
 	
 	
 		and he takes <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Games Magazines too Games</ENAMEX> Magazine which has puzzles and things that he likes to solve
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know crosswords and various logic puzzles and things like that and he likes to to try that and so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he does but  does get to be a lot of paper though after a while  if you don't keep them weeded out they almost take over
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		they do they can do that i found that they've been fun for my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years old</TIMEX> and they like to go through and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they're just kind of getting started now with there
 	
 	
 		uh-huh  they like to cut the pictures out and paste them on and so we've found good use for those
 	
 	
 		mine is a senior in high school so he's we're kind of at the end of that trail you're just sort of beginning to think about <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade
 	
 	
 		oh oh uh-huh  yeah it's fun well i do have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in junior high too so
 	
 	
 		oh okay so you've got a little bit of a gap there between the little ones
 	
 	
 		so we're kind of running the gamut  yeah but they do it
 		
 		
 	