
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		what do do you do artistic painting
 	
 	
 		um i do tole painting
 	
 	
 		oh you do
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i really love the tole painting um
 		i haven't done any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> or watercolor i would like to learn that some day but right now my passion is tole painting  uh-huh
 	
 	
 		do you do a lot of it
 		yeah i i took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> about i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four years ago</TIMEX> and i've done a little
 		um but it takes a lot of time
 	
 	
 		oh
 		it does it is real time consuming and
 	
 	
 		do
 		do you sell your projects
 	
 	
 		uh mostly i have just given them away as gifts um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've done uh perpetual calendars and
 		cookie jar lids and oh on and on you know just things like that but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i would eventually like to make enough to sell and quit my job
 	
 	
 		where do you work at
 	
 	
 		i just work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stop</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shop</ENAMEX> out there in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ogden</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		now do you ever send any of your stuff to the boutique
 	
 	
 		no i've wanted to do that uh but just haven't just haven't mass produced enough to do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of my own so it's
 	
 	
 		that keeps you busy
 	
 	
 		they they keep me busy and tole painting's just a you know something i do in my spare time so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> have you tried any of the well do you cut out your own projects
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh i have my own saws and so i really enjoy doing that
 	
 	
 		huh
 		do you um ever spray your projects with uh i mean a base coat <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> or do you brush it all on
 	
 	
 		i brush it on yeah i haven't tried a a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX> varnish
 		i use just a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> sealer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		i just bought a spray gun one of those airless um not airless high volume low pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and i do a lot of wood working and that's what i bought it for
 	
 	
 		do you oh
 	
 	
 		but i haven't used it yet
 	
 	
 		oh well that's that  probably give you a smoother finish wouldn't it oh now what type of wood working do you do
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		um fine uh furniture type stuff yeah
 	
 	
 		oh do you
 	
 	
 		that's why i brought bought the sprayer is to finish my projects that's my worst
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		worst part of my wood working i get so sick of making it
 	
 	
 		oh  but it's hard to finish it huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but spraying does put on a nicer finish
 	
 	
 		oh well that is interesting so what kind of equipment do you have
 	
 	
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> working um let me see table saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scroll</ENAMEX> saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> saw lathe routers and that's about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		boy it sounds like you're really into it that is nice
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		yeah i i just have a scroll saw and a jig saw and i am really anxious to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> saw and a router
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> saw's really nice i have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inca</ENAMEX> i don't know if you've ever heard of those
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but yeah it's nice to have the right equipment
 	
 	
 		yeah that is that makes it easier doesn't it well have you sold any of your furniture or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just
 	
 	
 		um not mostly i do like you do give it away as gifts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh making my own furniture
 	
 	
 		well
 		oh well that's interesting do you uh did you take classes to learn how to do that
 	
 	
 		um just in junior high and then i just kept on through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> and then bought my own equipment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		kept up with that
 	
 	
 		oh so yours is mostly just a hobby too then oh well that's interesting oh i would i really would love to go take a class in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> working and learn how to
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know if i necessarily wanna do furniture but mostly uh
 		just do more uh-huh the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> working
 	
 	
 		like the shelves and
 		for your  tole painting
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah so it's fun
 	
 	
 		good
 		well i guess i'll let you go now
 	
 	
 		well they come on we're supposed to talk until they come on and tell us  yeah  well it's it has been really fun i've enjoyed this um
 	
 	
 		oh they do
 		oh okay so this is my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one you're probably a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> at this
 	
 	
 		like i say i've made a couple of calls to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and just talked to all different kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so i think you'll enjoy doing it it's fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah sounds fun where do you buy your tole painting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">paints</ENAMEX> at around here
 	
 	
 		um you know there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX> that i really love um and it's there by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Copper Mill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> used to be the Hayloft
 	
 	
 		oh i'm not familiar well we live in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX> but we haven't is it on nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh um let's see i'm trying to think of the name
 	
 	
 		i know where fifty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six hundred</NUMEX> south is
 	
 	
 		uh i don't not right off
 	
 	
 		is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben Franklin</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Franklin</ENAMEX> okay
 		
 		
 	