
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i uh i that's kind of a controversial issue here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capitol i think we're becoming known as the murder capitol
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so there's a lot of of emphasize on gun control
 		uh i'm not exactly sure where i stand because uh
 		i feel that it may be necessary with the crime coming out this way that we'd be allowed to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities necessary facilities</ENAMEX> to protect ourselves
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i do know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX> has a gun control law and it seems that the number of shootings has gone up since they invoked the law
 	
 	
 		it
 		oh i see
 		yeah well i
 	
 	
 		but the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> all have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		right
 		well they they can get them one way or the other i i think it's uh i probably rate it maybe on the scale of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> maybe uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
 		uh i think well the automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and these assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and all of these things that uh i think that is something that
 		uh
 		really be limited but like you say if they take uh if they have gun control control then they take away uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> right to protect themselves
 		and we live out in the west where uh of course i have a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and we go hunting quite a bit for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> and
 		and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pheasants</ENAMEX> and things like that and uh they impose a gun control law that would really be disastrous i think because because i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> will get <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> no matter what
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where if we were restricted from having them
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or registering them all so that everybody knows who's got them i i don't feel i think that would really take away from our
 		our uh rights and freedoms as as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to to bear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and protect ourselves if necessary
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well we have uh
 		well in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax county</ENAMEX> it's against the law to discharge a firearm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in fact i think it's against the law to discharge a bow and arrow
 	
 	
 		oh my God
 	
 	
 		uh
 		but the uh they don't have any real strong gun control law
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh whereas just over the border in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX> they they have a real strong gun control law
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fairfax</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">County</ENAMEX> is fairly peaceful and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX> is averaging <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two</NUMEX> murders a day
 	
 	
 		oh boy yeah that i i've read about that that is really tragic i don't know how you could stop that i
 		it  that would be terrible
 		i mean you you don't even know whether you want to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well we i fortunately fortunately work out in the suburbs
 	
 	
 		with
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i just don't go downtown at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		and uh a little bit reluctant to go in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> time
 	
 	
 		no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there've been a few occasions uh i can remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX> i was downtown
 		and uh
 		toward quitting time i decided since i was there i'd go visit one of my favorite stores
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six thirty</TIMEX> when i left the uh store
 		and i was walking back to my car
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i tell you i got spooked
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh there were you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> making noises at you and
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lying around in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and it was dark and
 		and i i just got scared  i wound up running back to the car
 	
 	
 		yes
 		you would
 		well i know out here uh apparently they've kind of uh uh well they  excuse me in the  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> area they have
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> they had a uh hostage situation at uh one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alta View Hospital</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> where uh a fellow came in with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and he uh killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> and
 		and held the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> till they finally finally got him but
 		uh so what they're saying now in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> that there has been uh uh big increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> that are buying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> to protect themselves
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because of this situation that happened and it doesn't happened hasn't happened very often but uh
 		again that's it you hate to to do that but uh
 		we're starting to get some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> uh they're coming out here and there's been a few shootings drive by shootings and these
 	
 	
 		yeah we've we've had a lot of uh drive-by shootings we have a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> arrested for it going out and shooting just because they felt like killing somebody
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just shooting at random i'm kind of sorry to hear that that it's happening in nice rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> because uh
 	
 	
 		well it's it's not bad yet but uh there's there it is happened we we we had one of our uh football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> that uh
 		i guess they were out on the practice field uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> and a couple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> were involved and they shot him in the leg
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and uh it's
 		it  the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> of course are are quite
 		
 		
 	