
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		okay uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> has a a good school system where uh
 		as far as i'm concerned i can't really
 		see the difficulty uh or any problems that we have other than
 		they keep saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ACT</ENAMEX> scores were a little low
 		or lower than well we're above above the national average but
 		they're talking in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> all the time that we're not doing as well as other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in science and math
 		which i think there's been an effort to to increase that so
 		i don't see that there's serious any serious uh problems with our
 		school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 		uh what about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i'd say uh we probably have what could could be described as serious problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from uh
 		gun toting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to uh
 		low grades on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> test
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well i hate i hate to hear it
 	
 	
 		they got a pretty much of a handful of
 		problems to deal with
 	
 	
 		huh
 		where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are kind of controlling the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> then in some areas
 	
 	
 		well i don't know if you could say that but they're uh
 		are having to uh
 		put in
 		metal detectors and
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah that's not good uh i'd hate to teach under those situations
 	
 	
 		indeed
 	
 	
 		well well that hasn't got here yet i hope it it doesn't but uh
 		it i know we're we're starting to have a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> here
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with the schools
 	
 	
 		yeah that's bad news i tell you they uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but that's where it begins i guess
 	
 	
 		course it always sounds a lot worse than it is i suppose but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		but at least uh
 		i i go into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> quite a bit in my occupation
 		the different high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the
 		in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that i
 		i work in
 		and uh
 		generally from what i can see the uh
 		we don't really have that type of problems in any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> yet
 		but i know talking to my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> back east that they're
 		they have uh security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> that patrol the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallways</ENAMEX> and
 		and that's not a good learning situation if you've got to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> there to
 		keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in class and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it sound like that's it's kind of getting to that point in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in at least where you're at
 	
 	
 		yeah they uh
 		i don't know i think they uh
 		they need to uh
 		get back to the basics i think we
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		throwing a lot of money at the problem but it hasn't uh seemed to
 		do what's necessary yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's true and i i think that uh
 		in in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> we
 		we've kind of reversed going from the social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> back to
 		a lot of the academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> that uh they feel is necessary
 		and i think that is that's a good change to
 		to get back instead of so many uh
 		off the wall classes that have nothing to do with academic education
 		you know education
 	
 	
 		i think learning social interaction is good too but uh i think it has to be a balanced curriculum
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yes there does uh you can't uh
 		go from one extreme to the other and
 		there there has to be a balance there's got to be both there but i think it should be a little stronger on the academic uh portion
 		in order to prepare them for the society <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with the technology that we have they've
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		they've got to have a good math an english background in order to compete
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't think uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in general are uh
 		coming up to where they should be
 	
 	
 		no they're talking about uh in some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> back here are going <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two hundred days a year</TIMEX> instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and eighty i don't know what your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">school year</TIMEX> is there but
 	
 	
 		they're talking about going to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> they're actually testing out we just had it on the news tonight about the uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they go for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> and then take a month off or something
 	
 	
 		
 
 		we have a a there's a little of that going on here but it's all in the elementary grades it's not in the upper uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in the secondary area
 		but i it's there's some test cases to see uh if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are able to if they don't lose as much uh
 		they're able to retain more where they're only out for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> instead of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> and they have to go
 	
 	
 		exactly i think that was the uh thing they mentioned too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so it sounds like uh
 		in your area and this area too that they're trying to work on the problem that they see as a problem
 		to correct the some some some of the situations uh
 		
 		
 	