
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so you think uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>'s a threat anymore to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i was i was thinking about that while i was waiting for the connection i i think uh you know it's uh uh a military threat certainly i don't feel like it's like it was back in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> whenever <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kruschev</ENAMEX> said he was going to bury us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh at the same time i i think they may still be a threat in a different sort of a way in that uh the situation over there is so unstable
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and and the especially the economics uh uh ramifications of whatever is going to happen over there i mean they're like a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX> of the land mass of the earth
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and and if things don't get straightened out over there it it will impact us one way or the other i think
 	
 	
 		right right
 		i think i'm just afraid of uh what they're going to do with their nuclear warheads that they already have right now that uh they said you know they're open to uh anybody who's willing to pay the money i think uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX> said that you know if you've got the money for it we'll give you the warheads
 	
 	
 		is that right i hadn't heard that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and uh i'm just afraid you know some some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sadaam Hussein</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah or or any one of the other uh nuts that are running around yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i mean
 		you could get someone like you know  the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who uh who negotiates <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> you know you know he buys them out sticks them in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX> and starts selling them to everybody in the world
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well it's uh i don't know it's it's amazing to see uh the kind of changes that's happened just in the past uh you know not even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> or even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> it's just awesome
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 		well you know it's i guess the break up it's self was was uh kind of unusual and then now all of a sudden
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> who was uh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>'s pocket pretty much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is now gone you know and now we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin uh Yeltsin</ENAMEX> who seems like he's a little bit of a hard ball typical
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		typical communist
 	
 	
 		yeah but even so he seems to be a much more reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> than than you know previous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah doesn't
 		right right that's true
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		you know it's just uh uh you see this the uh you know on television the the uh shows uh on the news with the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> waiting in line
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they had last night i think it was on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> where some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> had gone on strike because their uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> salary was about enough money to buy them <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six pounds</NUMEX> of sausage with you know the new increase in prices
 	
 	
 		right hm
 	
 	
 		which is you know of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> over there aren't held in the same rare high esteem that they have here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum well
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		the other thing was uh like nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> over there were being uh taken in by you know other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because i mean like you said they're not being paid very much over there and and whereas they can command salaries of you know twenty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> a month
 		in uh you know these middle eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that you know oil bearing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> you know
 		and i saw that they uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> had offered uh twenty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> to nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> i mean
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		who wouldn't want that kind of money
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you know i i would even consider moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> for that i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah really
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well anyway it's
 	
 	
 		but i mean and and these and these are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that couldn't eat you know so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well as a matter of fact i know that uh you know they they were concerned about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> brain drain because there're so many of their top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just uh like you say they they
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		you know are are being given offers elsewhere and some of them i think are even coming to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> if we can get them you know rather than let them uh go to one of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">third</NUMEX> world countries
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum well i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> is eventually going to have to step in i mean you've got this you know big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that's now
 		uh pretty much uh in chaos because uh i mean the all the things that's split up and they've got the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX> to you know pretty much eliminate the rest of the world
 		and uh they've asked for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> support and i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> is going to have to give in
 	
 	
 		well i'm all for them  providing as you know as much support as we can at the same time you know it's time for us i think as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to run us you know the rest of the world really is not our responsibility
 	
 	
 		because
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's good for us to look after our own best interests even in uh you know an international way but at the same time we i don't think that we have the resources to bale out the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no i don't think as far as bail out goes i'm thinking more on the sense of uh um helping them take the infrastructure they have
 		and putting it to use i mean they've got a good infrastructure there i mean they at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time were you know they they were a threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> i mean they had the weapons ability they had the manufacturing capability
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think it's all kind of disorganized right now
 	
 	
 		you know the amazing thing about about it is how these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've been operating for you know seventy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> under a uh uh
 		you know the the protectorate protectorate of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> over them that they really don't even have a concept of what capitalism is
 	
 	
 		right
 		um-hum yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and and and as a matter of fact i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks ago</TIMEX> and i asked him what it was like and he said you know he said they start drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vodka</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten o'clock in the morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah i wish there was that kind of uh stuff over here it'd be great
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		but uh anyway it's uh uh i don't know there there just
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		they've got a really uh different outlook and a different mentality than uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than have anybody that has been accustomed to living uh under any form of capitalism and it's going to take quite a while for them to to realize that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm um-hum
 		yeah yeah
 		
 		
 	