
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hobbies</ENAMEX> tonight okay well let me go ahead and press one
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah sure
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Leslie</ENAMEX> i'd like to find out a little bit about your hobbies what do you like to do in your spare time
 	
 	
 		well and when i have my spare time  i do enjoy
 	
 	
 		that's a cherished commodity now days huh
 	
 	
 		that's right um i do enjoy uh sewing uh hand you know i do some needlepoint
 	
 	
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		and i i've been doing a a picture for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> that if i i ever get enough spare time he might see it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and and some other things i like to do are is music and um  also reading
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		what kind of music
 	
 	
 		so well i enjoy singing yeah
 	
 	
 		oh okay well great i enjoy music too and i uh one thing that i like to do uh is sit down and and play the piano i can't play that well but
 		i uh sit down and enjoy playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">musical</ENAMEX> selections that i familiar with
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		my famuel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s familiar with i enjoy that uh couple of hobbies that i also have is uh i enjoy i really enjoy bike riding
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the biggest hobbies i have right now are my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and whatever they're involved in
 	
 	
 		yes hm yeah
 	
 	
 		like my uh oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> is involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> so we go out and play kick the soccer ball around or play uh throw the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and uh
 		they also like to ride <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX> so we're riding <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX> and so a lot of the hobbies that i have right now are are centered around my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and also things that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i like to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		together and uh so personally  lot of the hobbies that i had when i was growing up um in going to college and so forth are have changed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really enjoyed uh mountain climbing i really enjoyed skiing um
 		and a lot of outdoor activities and uh there's not a whole lot of mountains here in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i can go skiing with that right now but hopefully i'll be able to get back to the slopes someday so
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		yeah i i've not had the opportunity to to go skiing but
 		i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> which had some mountains around it but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		never did get out and ski
 	
 	
 		you didn't
 	
 	
 		no i never did didn't have the i guess i didn't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> out there saying hey let me take you skiing and of course i was at that you know stage of my life where i had to be taken places places i couldn't go by myself but
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		and then of course then once i got to the age where i could've done it myself i had other interests i guess so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i guess that for me it was very helpful my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> were very interested in skiing
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and so we we went quite often and uh in fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> still does a lot of skiing and when i lived around in that area my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> would fly in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and we would we would go skiing and enjoy that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so but uh luckily it's it's kind of unusual because hobbies
 		it's a it's a nice thing to have and it's it's good to fall back on those hobbies when you have time but like you mentioned and i am finding out a lot of the spare time that i had isn't there
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		it's uh it's uh taken up by activities with uh work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> with um civic and church responsibilities for me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah i i find that if i i make i have to make myself to realize that it's important to get out there and not you know just even to go for a walk is good recreation for me
 	
 	
 		oh yes oh yes oh yes
 	
 	
 		yeah and my youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is gonna to be starting up soccer so she's real excited about doing that so we'll we'll be busy with that again
 	
 	
 		well great
 		what again so you've participated that in the past
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 	
 	
 		have you participated participated in that in the past
 	
 	
 		well i did with my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and she was in it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> but she's got so many interests herself that we had to start eliminating and  that was <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to go she still likes her piano
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she's in band so
 		so she's got lots of hobbies or uh activities going on
 	
 	
 		sounds it sounds like her life is full too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i imagine your life is full  taking them around all over the place
 	
 	
 		very much keep that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		all right all right well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leslie</ENAMEX> it's been very nice talking to you is there anything else that you'd like to mention <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		um no i think we covered it pretty good thank you for calling
 	
 	
 		okay great well thank you and you have a nice <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> bye now
 	
 	
 		you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	