
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 		all right well we're supposed to talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that uh probably the kind we'll get next and
 		i uh
 		i do a lot of driving commute uh i have about uh
 		fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> miles one way to commute here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> but it's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeway</ENAMEX> and it's not bad but uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> i've been getting i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		gosh
 	
 	
 		it's economical now i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> now and um and it's a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five</NUMEX> speed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and for the all the driving i do that uh is the kind i
 		i think i'd probably look at next i'm not sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i'll probably look for a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> type vehicle like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van mini van</ENAMEX> or something because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i just uh i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young ones so we're we're looking for something that's more family oriented yeah something bigger that we can carry
 	
 	
 		i see
 		a little bit bigger  yeah
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s gone we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time but they've uh they're all gone and so we we can go to the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> now but we did have to have back then it was station wagons
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		as for a family uh when you start taking much with you or going any place you really need a little more room
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano Texas</ENAMEX> who has uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and he got a
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> and he really enjoys it
 	
 	
 		hum that's that's right near me
 	
 	
 		is it
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few miles</NUMEX> north
 	
 	
 		oh okay well he uh i know i've had several from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		who who does he work for
 	
 	
 		he works for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JC Penney</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		oh really corporate office
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yes uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh uh i've got a i'm taking a class and uh one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that's in my uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		yeah he
 	
 	
 		we're doing a group presentation he works for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JC Penney</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum well good yeah he uh he's been down there going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three three years</TIMEX> now i guess uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> they're moving their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> to to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> right right now
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh they closed at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> i think and uh they're moving but it's uh
 		so in fact i was just down there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX> and then i had a layover <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">couple hours</TIMEX> uh at at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> airport
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">airport</ENAMEX> and they come out and got to visit with them for a while i got i got a new little brand grandbaby and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i've seen him
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		well that's great
 	
 	
 		i don't know i looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> you you they say buy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> but i  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i've talked to that uh
 		seems like they get a lot better mileage i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and eighty thousand</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> that i had in eighty and that thing i hadn't had any problems at all it was just going strong when i sold it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but uh i guess it's just it depends there's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lemons</ENAMEX> in all of them i guess but uh
 	
 	
 		that's super
 		yeah well <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are
 		hopefully they'll i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> really screwed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> up they uh
 	
 	
 		i do too yeah
 	
 	
 		you know the the price of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are just more than incomes are  because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that work at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> make well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		or yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> that they have down here that they're thinking about closing
 		uh the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> there makes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty two dollars an hour</TIMEX> and that's you know that's more than a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> make salary you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> make
 	
 	
 		oh wow i've been yeah i've been working
 		well i that's it i've been working for uh
 		oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five years</TIMEX> for the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and think i've got a pretty good job but i don't make that much
 	
 	
 		yeah i didn't either
 	
 	
 		and i've got uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		a a degree and everything else you see and i and i don't know hopefully you you'd think that if they were making that kind of money they would try to have a little pride in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in uh the product that they put out so it is a good car but
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s bought uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> bought uh a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick</ENAMEX> paid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> for it she's had nothing but trouble with that thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know you pay that kind of money you should uh it should be trouble free at least for fifty fifty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seventy thousand</NUMEX> and then
 	
 	
 		sure
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh she's had it in the in the shop <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> and shop and she called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and said oh it's uh leaking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> out of the head gasket she's only got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about twenty thousand</NUMEX> on it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so she's got to take that back in and have them work on it but and i and i think it from what i can hear it's just because they uh
 		they don't take the pride that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> do or something in in their work or workmanship that when something comes out and their name's on it they want it to to be the best and so i I hate to stay away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	