
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hi this my name's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridgette</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Bridgette this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi nice to meet you um do you know what we're supposed to talk about
 	
 	
 		yeah if there's something wrong with the school system
 	
 	
 		yeah so are you ready then okay
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		i press <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> don't i okay i've never done this before so  okay
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you there okay
 	
 	
 		uh-huh okay so what do you think is wrong with the school system
 	
 	
 		well you know i was listening to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> i think the other night they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Rooney</ENAMEX> on there  and one of the comments he was making is that um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know part of the problem is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and um
 		their lack i guess of uh interest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and he said do you know basically until we change that
 		uh we're not gonna have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh get any smarter because um you know they're not encouraging their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to do well in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		otherwise we're not gonna ever achieve a good education system unless we really get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> involved
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree with that but that's  coming from because i'm in college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and seeing how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> are my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> that's very hard to do in some areas you know it's like they sent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i know where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> teaches you know and she teaches in like a lower class
 		part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> and where it is is they just send their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to school and you know they don't care if they do their homework if they don't do their homework whatever
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so she says it's very hard from that aspect i mean she'll call the parents and they you know they're like well you know that's not my responsibility it's yours
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and i know she gets real frustrated being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> that she feels like you know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> aren't willing to do that which is very scary i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		another another thing i think though is uh i know now because i'm getting ready to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of mine that are getting teaching degrees are um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that aren't getting a master's are having an easier time uh getting a job because they can get paid less
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and it seems like they're just compromising good qualified educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> just for someone they can pay less and they get they don't get paid much now and i think that's really bad
 	
 	
 		yeah it's kind of a shame that um we don't put emphasis and money where we really should i mean we've never really paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> real well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we've never paid um other public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and such very well it is kind of a shame um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there are some times i think that uh you know the quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> may be improved upon i think what they did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> was kind of a joke about testing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and all
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh i think it was
 	
 	
 		um i think that  i think that they're made some changes you know into um
 		the the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> that should be involved in education curriculum and um trying to improve improve upon them uh somewhat but
 		um they've never really paid you know real well and and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to  pick a an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX> that's gonna support themselves it can't be all sacrifice and no you know salary  you got to live on something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		i think it's hard though because even like the like in high school and stuff you take the standardized tests and stuff and i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know are like dyslexic i mean i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in college that are like dyslexic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		that i wonder how they pass through all their school you know all their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and pass through all the tests that they had to pass through and so forth to get to college because they have the hardest time you know  things like that always make me wonder too i mean they make all these tests but are they really proving anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah true and you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are much better test <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">takers</ENAMEX> than others um
 	
 	
 		yeah that's definitely true
 	
 	
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know um just really clam up when it comes to a test and they're so nervous about well is there a is this a trick question and instead of being real straight forward and just trying to answer it they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um give themselves you know worse grade because they were so anxious about it
 	
 	
 		see yeah
 	
 	
 		and then other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know aren't that upset about it and they test very well so there has to be
 		different ways of of testing sometimes you know because um that isn't always a real good reflection of if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s learned it or not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i agree i think there's just so many problems now with  just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know younger <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> and
 		all the problems they have and all the problems like in general in the world like with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> and stuff just being brought into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is making it worse i think that's not even helping at all
 	
 	
 		yeah you know uh  i i wouldn't wanna be back in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> now i think it uh it's a real challenge and you know um i think maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> need more um
 		i don't know counseling or or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> or just you know talking about how to get along in life if they're not getting that so much from home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	