
 
     		
 	
 		that's it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 	
 	
 		what do you think are possible changes in the uh the way trials are conducted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> do you like the way some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in there for instance really take over and uh
 		we have no way of knowing whether they're legitimately right or wrong so forth
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what do you think about these things
 	
 	
 		well as i look at our trial systems i think they've gotten to be quite a joke the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can appeal and file for mistrials and they've taken a lot of the things that that were set up to make it be a fair system
 		and used it to their advantage
 		i think that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> should listen to the court
 		uh to to the hearings and to everything but i think they should only weigh fifty percent of the decision
 		i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> should hold the fifty or maybe even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty nine</NUMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> should be able to rule one way or the other
 	
 	
 		you you're so you're saying you you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> should actually have the final say
 	
 	
 		i think he should and i think that there should be more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> there should be maybe two
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		at least that sit in and listen so that there's no way that you could have
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		like a crooked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> do you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		yes i know what you mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i think that there it's important to have a jury
 		but i think the way that they go through so much time to get a a fair one that's okay too as long as it's not used to delay the trial so much
 		they need to have a fair jury but they only would you know would cover
 		fifty forty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nine percent</NUMEX> of the decision or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fifty percent</NUMEX> and then the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> would go ahead and make the final decision
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		how do you feel about that
 	
 	
 		i hadn't uh thought of it from that point of view before i have been in a fairly important trial
 		and uh what bothers me is
 		i was concerned of the ability of some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> to adequately understand
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		what was being presented so that they themselves could make a proper and uh accurate decision
 		that's the part that bothered me about it
 		um i really think that the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> ought to have more say so in the selection or in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of whether they're guilty or not but i also think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> should be
 		uh very very uh carefully more carefully selected to make sure that they are entirely intelligent intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and that they understand some of the details that are involved so that they can make accurate accurate decisions
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i hate to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> brought in who basically have lived out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and don't know much about any of this stuff and
 		and they just make a decision based on whether they like the dress she wore <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> or whether that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> smiled or growled all the time that's no way to make a decision on some terrible problem
 	
 	
 		right
 		right well what if they used you know i just had a thought come as you were talking what if they used law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 		and had that be credit <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> to sit in trials
 	
 	
 		that would be certainly nice shit let's say we we would have fifty percent of them law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at any rate yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah at least at least on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and that would give them experience in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> and it could count as some aspect or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> going into their major
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's a very neat idea and they would learn a lot about being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> later in life when they see what it is like to be in the jury side of a trial
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's right that would be a really good thing to do
 	
 	
 		that would be a a really good thing to do
 	
 	
 		i i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> that just went through a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year</TIMEX> trial
 	
 	
 		so that's
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and what happened was her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was um
 		involved in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> accident where a drunk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> ran the stop light and ran into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but the reason the actual reason that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> person her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was killed was because his brakes
 		went out on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> he was just taking it home from the place it was brand new and his brakes did not work
 	
 	
 		for goodness sakes
 	
 	
 		and this expensive big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that owned these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycles</ENAMEX>
 		um railroaded this into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> worth of trials for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> and she had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that was just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two years old</TIMEX> when it happened
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they were following him home in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> saw the whole thing happen
 	
 	
 		oh they saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> get
 	
 	
 		that's right they were following him home from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> shop
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they railroaded this whole trial into mistrials um this and that and the other every time she'd get a verdict that would be in her favor of a of a settlement
 	
 	
 		they'd find something wrong with it
 	
 	
 		until finally they won and said that it was the drunk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s fault and she would have to sue him
 	
 	
 		did they really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which i would think it would be some his fault but i just felt like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> wasn't served because they had the money the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and she didn't
 	
 	
 		that is a shame you'd think there would be enough uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who saw the accident other than his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		to to also uh make statements and they have nothing to gain one way or the other so if they say a certain way then why not believe them
 	
 	
 		right and i don't know all the details on that but i certainly think that we've come up with a good idea with the
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> coming into the jury
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i don't think that it would be such a bad idea even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> didn't have the final say
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	