
 
     		
 	
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi hi i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX>  this is a riot  i i'm making money what are you doing
 	
 	
 		oh bull is this Mrs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slaubacher</ENAMEX>  what are you doing
 		the same thing okay hold on
 	
 	
 		push your <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and let's get with it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay  so what do you think about raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you don't know anything about this
 	
 	
 		well i don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so it's kind of hard to say
 	
 	
 		it is kind of hard for you
 	
 	
 		but i think that i mean i think it's kind of sad that like they're talking about like what the trends are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i think it's kind of sad that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are so uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		involved with their careers and stuff that they don't take time for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i think it's really sad i think they should reevaluate their priorities
 	
 	
 		i do to
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		because i was waiting to get someone that would say yeah well you know it's hard to spend time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i was just gonna be like gritting my teeth  hoping not to say something i didn't mean to
 	
 	
 		right right but i i think you need to take that for the little bit of time it takes like for or about
 	
 	
 		but i think it's really sad
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> out of your life of really being around them when they really need you and their younger ages it's worth that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> and it pays off i think
 	
 	
 		yeah see
 		see i do too i agree
 	
 	
 		because the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> isn't long till you can work on your career and then you have <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> more to do your career
 	
 	
 		no
 		
 
 		i know if you don't if you wanna have a career that's fine but i don't think you should have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know or wait till you're
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		ready to give up some of it
 	
 	
 		that's true what well you know some of the um
 		i see it with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> that have waited for it till they're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty four thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh really
 	
 	
 		and they have that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> you'd think they were the only ones that ever had kids
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		they and yeah they really love it
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		i think they're kind of sorry then they didn't that they waited that long because they really enjoy them a lot
 	
 	
 		that they waited
 		
 
 		see  i know
 	
 	
 		and i see that a lot with the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> that think that's all they wanted was careers and then when they hit around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty four thirty five</TIMEX> they decide well the really want to try motherhood
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh that happens but i agree if they if they want a career though i think they should go with the career and forget the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> when
 	
 	
 		and
 		
 
 		see i see too i mean i it sounds bad and i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would totally disagree and say it shouldn't have to be a choice but for the welfare of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> i think it is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah right
 		right are you at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> now are you that's a riot yes
 	
 	
 		or at least it uh-huh  yep i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 		that's hilarious must have been right when you said something i knew that was you i was like oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		um what are some of the things you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> should do with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		God anything i mean take them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> or God i mean even if they say they don't have time for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they should sit down and eat dinner with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that would take all of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah see i think that dinner time is real important with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that's when a lot of things would come out
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that if you and you'd make i know that when they're all going all different directions but i used to at least make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> out of a week they had to be together
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i kind of insist on it and they were pretty good about it they hated to miss it because they'd hear about the good time we had if they weren't around
 	
 	
 		yeah i just think it's important
 	
 	
 		yeah i do too because that's when i don't know why but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> start talking when you're when you're around a dinner table and all they start telling all the things
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah especially you had so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> too though so you get to hear the whole scoop on everyone because everyone would know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh but i think any any entertainment that you can do with them is fun though when when you know we always loved to go camping
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's great even even now we go camping in fact we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> set up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you really
 	
 	
 		and the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> come now it's the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i mean we started out when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were young doing this and now they bring their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies um</ENAMEX>  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks old</TIMEX> when we took her
 	
 	
 		oh
 		how cute
 	
 	
 		we took him and uh we start them out real young even and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> we just take electric blankets and put them on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		really see that's great
 	
 	
 		they and they love that outdoors
 	
 	
 		i'd love to do that
 	
 	
 		yeah and they go fishing from the time they're little and uh the daddies take them out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> it's fun
 	
 	
 		
 
 		see this is important i know i i get engaged and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s like so how long you think it'll till you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i was like God i'm not married even yet uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		don't start saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i'm not ready
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i think any any outings with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> is wonderful makes you get to know them better and another thing i like is um just making sure you have time with each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> alone
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's of important
 	
 	
 		yeah even you you know no matter how many you have you should take a special day a special time for one
 	
 	
 		for each so they don't feel like there isn't singled out
 	
 	
 		yeah and make <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> for shopping or going out to lunch or just taking them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> alone and you'd be surprised what they'll talk about when you're just sitting there on a swing talking
 	
 	
 		
 
 		see
 		
 
 		yeah just as long
 		
 		
 	