
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i think that
 		i think it should be done
 	
 	
 		you think that that spot testing for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is is well like it said
 		you think it should be done permissible and where do they draw the lines
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh well i think at some places like
 		not necessarily at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> at bigger companies
 	
 	
 		what's really bad is you know that i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI and TI</ENAMEX> does it
 		that's no problem i'm i don't take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> anyway i don't have any problem with that but
 		our own defense system doesn't do it
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> doesn't do spot testing for not only for you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and defense systems and everything else but they impose it upon the on the
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		standard public and i
 		i really don't care one way or the other i think it it prevents a lot i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> aren't so willing to take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> at work anymore or do <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and go to work but
 	
 	
 		but there's a lot that do
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah there well there even at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> there was there was quite a change when they come out with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> testing i think it's a great deterrent
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that works for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Town and Country</ENAMEX> and she had they just they go around and they just pick a store
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> a month and they go down and do drug testing on all of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> all the way down
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so there's no discriminating there you know they're not they're and even like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> now <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> if you go out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they test you positive for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> first they send you to drug rehab they don't just throw you out the door and fire you so you know they're not out hunting heads
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i think it should be done
 		across the work spectrum i don't i don't disagree with it i think it's a good thing to have but i think it should be done across the whole work spectrum i don't think that one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> should do it and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> not
 		i don't think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> should necessarily need to do it when the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> doesn't
 		you know it it it ought to be standardized somewhere somebody has to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and and they we got into a big discussion about it at work about
 		against being against unconstitutional and against somebody's privacy rights but that you know i don't want some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> hopped up on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> next to me working on a machine i might get my head cut off
 	
 	
 		true
 		yep
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		that's why i think it's good to do  testing not only when they get hired but also  along the line sometimes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will
 		have have ways of like faking the test or you know they just don't do it for a while to take the test to get the job and then they'll start up again
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i seen that too
 		but i agree with it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i think it should be done i think it should be done everywhere i don't think it should just be done at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or another
 		you know like you said not at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> but you know there's nothing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> except
 		a deep fat fryer full of grease that somebody can stick their hand into or you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> have if if
 		i have no qualms if they wanna take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that's their problem it's not mine but i don't want them around me or near me or working with me or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know not while they're hopped up i don't want a drunk there either
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't want some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in there that's
 		drunk
 		working next to me either so
 		and they're all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		i agree i think it should be done i think it should be done
 		all the everywhere i don't think it should be done in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place and not another i think it should be done i think it should be done every time a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> needs to
 		well you know changing jobs you have to to get into <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> you have to take a urines urine test anyway and they won't hire you if you test positive but once you're there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they they they test you positive they'll at least send you to drug rehab or some kind of counseling anyway
 		and i think it's working i think it's doing pretty good job
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i went down to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> to try to see about a job and they wanted me to take a drug test
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah most of your major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> do now
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well that's good you know i
 		it prevents a lot it's a great deterrent whether or not it
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		helps in the long run nobody knows but
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		it works pretty good
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		well thanks for talking sorry to wake you up it sounds like i did
 	
 	
 		uh-huh nice to talk to you
 		yeah it woke me up but that's okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yep
 		okay
 	
 	
 		see you later bye bye
 	
 	
 		bye bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	