
 
     		
 	
 		that proposal
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well actually i've i you know it kind of caught me by surprise i haven't ever really thought about
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh you know mandatory public service i obviously believe in public service and you know think it's a good idea i i i i'm not sure if they would get
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the service they anticipate if they force it do you understand what i'm saying i mean you know you're gonna get a lot more commitment a lot more desire a lot more uh
 	
 	
 		that's a good yeah good point
 	
 	
 		maybe quality time effort energy from somebody who really truly wants to be there so although i believe in it i'm not sure requiring it would be the way to go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you know what i've noticed at least in our in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> that that works is to require before a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can
 		enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> program that they do a number of volunteer <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> in that field or in in an environment that's related to that field and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that might be more motivating um in relation to what you just mentioned if it were somehow of interest to them
 	
 	
 		that's true if there were enough opportunities
 	
 	
 		i suppose uh that would really require a lot of
 		participation on the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to require a certain number of
 		community uh community service <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> in their area  that's
 	
 	
 		well that or have something available in that field you know and and when you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> then is it really a public service
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		thing or more of an internship you know i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i really like the idea of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting a chance to
 		to do something of a volunteer nature maybe in another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but that that's difficult for a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i guess financially to
 		to manage but it would certainly i think contribute to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s responsibility and and sense of maturity um to recognize what other cultures and other countries
 		go through in terms of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their day</TIMEX> to day existence if you're working in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> for example you're really gonna be able to learn those things
 	
 	
 		i i definitely agree and i i had you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that did serve in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> and i i always thought it was a wonderful thing
 		um i i do think that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have the opportunity to do it it's something that you know they won't forget it enriches your life and gives you like you said a a good understanding of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well what do i wanna say we take so much we we take what we have for granted you know we're very blessed in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and and we take so much for granted because we really don't realize uh
 	
 	
 		yeah we really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		how other cultures and other other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> live so i i definitely agree that it's it's good i just you know it i i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		to to require it i think would take a lot of forethought and planning if you wanna get the type of service you know that you're anticipating that you're hoping for
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 		it's a little challenging <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> too to think about being in another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where there's
 		uh potentially political or  military problems that are gonna effect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is volunteering
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's one thing because they recognize there's a minimal danger where where they might be but if you're
 		expecting that they have to do it then you you you perhaps the whoever the whoever the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is requiring it does assume some responsibility too
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		that's true and then i guess i can look around you know i i automatically when the uh
 		switchboard suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> i kind of like you i thought international or going out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and i i look around though and there's an awful lot of public service that could be done within our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> and our own
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know a lot of times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say i don't wanna go somewhere else i wanna help my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United United Way</ENAMEX> i want my dollars to work here something like that so that might also be a motivating factor then
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i i think it's terrific to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> involved in community services and i really like the idea of avoiding jail time for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are just um um
 		paying if you wanna call it that for minor offenses having them do something in the in the community
 	
 	
 		minor offenses yeah
 		i agree i think that's a very good idea
 		what you said the field you're in what field are you in does it apply
 	
 	
 		i i'm an occupational therapist and so it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> work that um i know this is true in occupational therapy as well as physical therapy there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are applying to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		that they require that you do <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> number of volunteer hours i think it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred or so</TIMEX> before you can even be accepted into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> program to become a therapist
 	
 	
 		okay
 		so you have to do it in that field actually
 		like if you like you
 	
 	
 		i believe you do yeah you have to volunteer in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> that that provides occupational therapy or physical therapy if that's the
 		the area you're pursuing i'm sure that there are other reasons for them wanting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do that because a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> may actually get into the program and not have a very good idea of what
 		it is to be an OT or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PT</ENAMEX> and having been a volunteer they'll certainly see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the job and recognize well this is really what i wanna do i wanna spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four years</TIMEX> getting this experience
 	
 	
 		yes
 		that's true well and it might also make them realize jeez this isn't what i thought it was i don't wanna do this that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		exactly which which is which is definitely the case in
 		
 		
 	