
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well the topic's about government um  i'm not altogether sure that that's my best topic um
 	
 	
 		i thought it was kind of a strange topic about corruption in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and um how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are self-serving
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean that you i i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tend to think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is not corrupt  and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't self-serving
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean that's what i would like to think
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i think that the last uh part of that question was particularly interesting um  about um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh uh</ENAMEX> can all unethical behavior or how much unethical behavior can be made illegal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because it it it seems to me that when  uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or public service of any kind degenerates so much that  you have to have so many explicit ethical
 		codes um parallel to the legal codes  that uh we're focusing on the wrong thing  maybe
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		maybe maybe that's what is happening maybe so many things have become public with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> over the past  you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> that uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it becomes more evident perhaps things that we didn't think of before and just concentrated on the lawmaking or the results that would be seen in public works or bills that are passed or you know etcetera like that  and we
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we're just not exposed to the personal lives of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> and i couldn't help thinking when that last question it was a funny question  when that last part of the question came about how how many
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		things can we um actually put a legal code on  that um uh how how much um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		should it be our  uh prerogative to see into the private lives of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know um
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that makes sense because you pry start prying in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s private lives you ruin their lives as well as and sometimes you know i don't even know how much of a difference it really makes you know i mean i guess in some cases sure we care about what they did in the past but uh
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sometimes i don't know it i think it gets in the way of the better judgement i mean just because he did something in his past doesn't mean he's not a good enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i i i agree with that and  um and also that if the  results that they are putting out and what they actually seem to be accomplishing by legitimate means is what's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know going to the public  then um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then they'll pay for their private life in their own private conscience  and uh uh you know when it becomes public though it becomes scandalous
 	
 	
 		that's right um-hum
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">the</ENAMEX> that's that's the thing that  um it it things that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you don't know uh do do do not worm their way around then and influence other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or perhaps lead other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> astray <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could say oh they do it so  i guess you know but as soon as things do get public
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um there there is that terrible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> so sometimes i ask myself what are  um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doing that are in the media
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when somebody you know comes up to office it seems that one of the first thing that's done is to dig up any kind of a thing they can on them and get it all over the headlines
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah  it's i guess it's what sells newspapers you know
 	
 	
 		it's a very low way of living um so and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">and and and as far as um</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know myself having any particular personal uh knowledge or insight into
 		politics or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> it i'm not
 		terribly involved in it just in a very cursory way i vote and i  you know try to do whatever i can on a little local area but i i it it just is not one of the things that i have uh placed um
 	
 	
 		um-hum right
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and uh a lot of my particular time and effort into so i i always feel very
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		outside this kind of um  this kind of an issue but um um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i'm kind of the same way i just kind of read the paper follow-up on people i mean just you know keep an eye on what's going on but i don't really play an active role in any kind of politics
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum um-hum yeah right yeah uh um um-hum i'm not i'm not in there i'm not one of those uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> that's there at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> and
 		whatever um although i admire the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that do that and they certainly do get inside information and um of course the better you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that might be affiliated with that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		the more you can trust their their judgment and their insight but the media insight as you said i just kind of read and
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		kind of be aware and then uh i don't like to make a whole lot of um judgment my myself unless things are so absolutely out of whack that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	