
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so you have a son
 	
 	
 		i have a an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> yeah he doesn't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> yet though
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty seven</TIMEX> and i don't know if he's ever going to have any or not but i do have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor kids</ENAMEX> lots of little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that i go out and uh i play ball with them
 		you know it's because like this one that lives right next door her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> does some work at home on computers and it just seems like she doesn't have any time for them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is kind of sad you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are kind of hungry for someone to play with them so i will go out and play catch with them or you know we have let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> outside and they will roll around on the ground and play with the dogs
 		but uh actually i do think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> should have you know a little bit more time to spend with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i would think so when you when when your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was at home did you um working did you work or were you able to stay at home with him
 	
 	
 		no when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was at home i i did work and then he went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX> that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> had about uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that she baby sat
 		you know but we always had our days off together and we went camping on vacations so we had a lot of time together that way you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> uh when i was growing up my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> worked too but she worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> and so she was always home for us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i always i really appreciated that having her there when i was you know when i came home from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and when i worked
 		but now when i look back at it it must have been a really difficult thing that she did for us
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well i am sure it was you know but uh
 		i don't know what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are really going to come to nowadays because they just there just doesn't seem like they do have time for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> because most most of them the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and the mother both work
 		you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's really rough um i have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> that's uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is a fireman
 		and he works like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> on and it seems like he is suppose to come home for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four days</TIMEX>
 		but he can't make enough as a fireman to support his family you know so he's got a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> job
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so he's you know he's not home very often
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i know miss that you know
 	
 	
 		they really do uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> without a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is it's a it's a really hard thing
 	
 	
 		yeah you know and i don't know i i suppose they are trying to get through to them that well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> is not home because
 		you know he is out working trying to make some money for you know we can buy you this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> and that toy and so forth you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i think would much rather have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> there than the toy anyway
 	
 	
 		oh i'm sure they would you know
 		so  are you planning on to having any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh yeah our uh-huh but we're um we just got married like like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> so we're going to wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and then we will try
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um yeah well that's good yeah that's
 		that's what my uh daughter-in-law had told me that they were going to have kids
 		probably after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> of marriage
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they will be married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years  this year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i don't know she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> you know and uh she has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> that has got lots of little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so maybe they just decided that uh
 		if they wanted to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> they would just you know call one of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> up and tell them to send the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> over for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a possibility yeah well we really want to have a family we feel like that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		you know but uh
 	
 	
 		you're not giving enough of yourself and you should you should be sharing your family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		and giving your values to you know making something better of the world by raising up good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and letting them know they're loved and stuff give them give them an edge but
 	
 	
 		right
 		right right
 	
 	
 		we feel like like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> needs to be devoted to uh making the the family the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> strong and secure in their love for each other
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but then a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is is definitely a high priority
 	
 	
 		yeah uh do you plan on staying home after you have your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or do you do you work or what
 	
 	
 		well i um i'm in a different situation i am a missionary
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm home on on furlough it's called like i've worked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> and i come home for a year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then we go back for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i will do the same job and we'll be living in in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> and we'll be working together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh we will we will share the job of raising the family i mean as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> i'll have certain responsibilities that he might not necessarily have but still we'll share that job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we have then we have decisions that we have to make that are hard about schooling like do you want to home school your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> on a computer program
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or do you send them away to boarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and if you do that when do you do it and that's a
 		
 		
 	