
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um have you ever had to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> in a nursing home
 	
 	
 		no but we're getting pretty close to it my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s uh uh stepfather uh is in the hospital right now and hopefully we can pull him out uh back home but we don't know yet
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		how about yourself
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty five</TIMEX> and she's which i feel is you know quite young still but she's not in the greatest of health and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so recently she has been talking a lot about what we would do if we had to put her in a nursing home
 		she's adamant that she does not want to live with any of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and put that burden on us
 	
 	
 		yeah so so is uh so is our uh my  my uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s parents
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> are dead
 	
 	
 		uh-huh but their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are still alive oh my goodness wow  oh
 	
 	
 		um-hum <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> and eighty
 		
 
 		yeah see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four one</NUMEX> eighty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh we've been looking into it and uh course nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> i think uh you would find that uh you would want uh one close to home
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and one that has a pleasant surrounding
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and one that has good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> that uh you know will take care of you and treat you you know like a a like an individual
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		and look after your every needs i know down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we've had a lot of problems with nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> that uh that don't uh take care of their people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they've gone in they've closed down a lot of them and they put new regulations on some of them
 		you go in you find an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with a bed sore because they haven't been turned or haven't been cleaned
 	
 	
 		oh oh dear
 	
 	
 		so uh all of that uh you know i think someone needs to know uh about uh the qualifications of a nursing home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the staff
 	
 	
 		now  how do you go about finding out things like that you
 	
 	
 		well let's assume that uh you wanted to take your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to a uh nursing home there locally in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ogden</ENAMEX> i'm sure you've got some that's close by
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it would it what would be real nice is find one around the corner that you could visit that you could go in and uh talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk to some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s uh uh siblings
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's right
 	
 	
 		or uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children children</ENAMEX> and uh find out how they like it you know course one of the most important things is is uh can you afford it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's true
 	
 	
 		and uh down in some small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it's about fifteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> over here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it's closer to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three thousand</NUMEX> if you really wanna get super care you know you can pay anything you want to
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		oh my
 		
 
 	
 	
 		course we haven't even mentioned Medicaid uh which and uh which uh would take care of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> who is destitute
 	
 	
 		boy
 		well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and course there's a lot to be said about uh making a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> destitute
 	
 	
 		oh well
 	
 	
 		as opposed to uh paying for it yourself because the government you know uh provides for a destitute person
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s been saying you know she's been just saving her money and not paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a penny</NUMEX> of it
 		but she says my little bit of savings will probably pay for a nursing home for maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and then i'll be on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> anyway so she said
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		why don't i go out and and enjoy life while i can
 		and you know  when i get to that point of being in a nursing home then maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> will just have to take care of me but why don't i just enjoy life now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well yeah and that's true because uh after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s gone all of her savings are going to be eaten up and if she owns her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure about the total rules on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> but i assume that you'd have to sell the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and those proceeds would go to pay for the nursing home
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think so
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and anyway it's while it's unlawful
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 		there's nothing wrong with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> gifting everything she has to uh to
 		uh to an individual like uh like like you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then uh from there on out uh saving that money uh so that uh you could supplement her income after she goes under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do that
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and most one of the most important things uh about sending a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to uh the nursing home is is the burial provided for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		see that should be provided for before she ever goes out of her monies or otherwise you know the the uh the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have to provide that
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh you know i sure you've thought of all this
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's
 		it's kind of a sad thing to think about isn't it
 	
 	
 		oh yes it's very sad we had a discussion with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who is uh is eighty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old this past weekend</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		
 
 		hm
 		
 		
 	