
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello yeah</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> yeah
 		yeah well i uh on capital punishment here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> it uh
 		we do have the death penalty for murder
 		and uh
 		the
 		uh
 		the either the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> can make that determination depending on the crime the seriousness of the crime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's been uh uh
 		it's been uh oh it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five years ago</TIMEX> since uh someone was actually uh put on death row well there's some quite a few on death row but uh before one was executed
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the same way it is here
 	
 	
 		and it uh we've got some that uh have been there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten or fifteen years</TIMEX> and
 		i don't know my opinion on on uh the death penalty i think it's uh
 		personally i think it would be a deterrent if uh they were able to carry this out without many appeals
 		but they appeal and appeal and uh it just goes on forever but
 	
 	
 		right right it's just nothing but cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> lots of money huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it really does and uh uh i i have i've always felt that uh
 		if they murder someone in cold uh in cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> they know what they're doing and uh
 		that they should be uh
 		pay made to pay for it but if we don't have a deterrent of some kind then it just gets to the point where
 		and if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it's just if they want to do it they do it and then they they think well i'll be out in uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years</TIMEX> and a lot of them are
 	
 	
 		yeah and then they end up doing it again
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 	
 	
 		no i think that's very very very wrong
 		um i'm with you i think if they if they've killed somebody they should they should pay for it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know period no you know none of this going on and on and on and on
 	
 	
 		right
 		what if the
 		where it's so clear cut we've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> cases here where they were actually caught and they uh and they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> where they had killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> people
 		and there was one that they thought they'd killed but they hadn't and they had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> and
 		and uh they did all kinds of things to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and this one they thought they had killed him but uh they hadn't and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> were able to get them but they they did uh were able to uh have the one uh
 		executed but the other one is still appealing and uh
 		it's uh
 		it's really a sad thing especially for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of those that were involved
 	
 	
 		yeah you know i don't in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i don't think they do that if someone does something bad like that they just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do it right now you know
 	
 	
 		right and and they don't have the crime rate that we have here i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> uh was over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> but he was over there during the war and he said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> somebody over there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh they they kill someone and the and uh that's it they're killed or they
 	
 	
 		yeah they pay for it right now yeah
 	
 	
 		right and so he says you really don't have that he could see the crime rate was very low over there because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> knew the consequences
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but here it's got to the point where i think it's gone too far the other way
 	
 	
 		yeah you know like like you say you know anything they do they don't care they could go out and rob somebody if they get caught they know they're just going to be out in just a little while anyhow
 	
 	
 		uh
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		so it's the same thing you know but uh i just don't think that they should let it go on and on and on like they do
 	
 	
 		well i know made in the point you made about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> paying for it when you start considering the cost of fifty to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">sixty thousand dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to keep them in prison
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		plus all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> costs  all of that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> pay for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> they don't get anything other than just the heartache and going through this and going through it appeal after appeal and i don't know i
 	
 	
 		yeah they make it wait for so long and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> forget actually what did happen you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and then they find some little glitch uh in the law and uh you either turn them loose or
 		or put them in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for life and then maybe after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> they're paroled
 	
 	
 		yeah right right
 	
 	
 		so i don't know it's it's uh quite a situation i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i wish they'd get back to that but uh every once in a while there was a fellow that was executed in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> the state next to us
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month ago</TIMEX> and uh of course he he said he wanted to be because he he had done the you know he he admitted to it and everything he said i just don't want to stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> couldn't do anything to stop that one  but anyway it's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it makes you wonder how they can live with themselves when they do something like that huh
 	
 	
 		i
 		well it does and then you try to teach your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh respect for for uh
 		
 		
 	