
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hi i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Linnstaedter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where you calling from
 	
 	
 		uh i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay all right so am i
 		
 
 		okay you understand the topic
 	
 	
 		uh yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		okay i'm going to go hit the button
 		
 
 		so what do you think about the death penalty
 	
 	
 		uh well
 		i've mixed feelings i guess you'd say
 		it's it's not something that uh i mean uh you know it doesn't make me happy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		on the other hand you know the present alternatives at least in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> are not real good i mean it's an all or nothing proposition you know you either you either uh give somebody a death penalty or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> in a very short time to uh have have a repeat performance of whatever they did um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i guess uh you know i guess i should mention i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and i used to do some criminal work and um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		hum
 	
 	
 		as long as it's reserved for
 		special purposes and as long as as uh you know the judicial process that's afforded to someone pretty much
 	
 	
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychopathic killers</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		you know makes you feel good about that you've got the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> then i guess i i can live with it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum well what'd you think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Dahmer</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		uh i haven't been keeping up with that i've been in and out of of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and i haven't kept up with it what's happening to him
 	
 	
 		well
 		well he got fifteen life sentences
 	
 	
 		um-hum uh so they went ahead and ruled him uh at least legally sane to stand trial
 	
 	
 		for uh
 		sane
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well okay so i see he can get up to fifteen life sentences
 		and uh i he with no chance for parole
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		see we don't have that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that's the problem
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		is is you can't give somebody life without parole at least at this point
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well huh that's not very good
 	
 	
 		no i mean you know uh a life sentence
 		they get time and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> for um time served and uh if they get made a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trustee</ENAMEX> they get good time um which is like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two two days</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> they serve
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they can really be out or eligible for parole in a fairly short space of time
 	
 	
 		now what's uh what is a life term if someone gets a life term what's the earliest they can get out
 	
 	
 		i want to say
 		uh you know they've changed things since i used to since i used to practice that kind of work but i think that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		somebody told me that  within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten</TIMEX> or twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> they would be um eligible for parole
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		i mean it's not very long
 	
 	
 		um-hum well now i know in uh
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> i i think it's about the same i want to say each life term you're eligible for parole within fifteen years
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i knew um
 	
 	
 		well see also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it's real unusual for them to do what they call stack them stack the penalties
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they they will they will cause the penalties to run concurrently
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah see they should make consecutively i don't like this concurrent stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean on on something like a like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Dahlmer</ENAMEX> or somebody like that you know that definitely i mean you know why go through the farce of having a parole hearing
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		you know what's going to happen if you let him out i mean we and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> too i mean i smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> uh and places like that have some real innovative
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		rehabilitation type activities that they can do in their penal system and in a in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we don't have that
 	
 	
 		right
 		hum
 	
 	
 		they get down there we are warehousing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> basically
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they go down there and they maybe pick up a few tricks you know how to be worse and uh and then you turn them loose on society and i just don't think that that's i don't think that's right i don't think that's fair
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		see that's what what i don't like is warehousing you know i mean if you make them useful you know put them in jail and make them do something you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know make license plates you know
 	
 	
 		something yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean it to me uh for me to pay i mean what does it cost uh per year to uh to keep uh an inmate i think they said it's something like eighteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> per per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is is what we were paying per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX> that's a lot of money
 	
 	
 		uh it's a lot
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i mean some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't even make that much money <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that's free
 	
 	
 		well and and if you consider the fact that with with all the the federal lawsuits that went on and all the standards that there are for how you can and cannot treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> and and what they're entitled to have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		frankly you know it's it's considered cruel and inhumane for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> at the state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">penitentiary</ENAMEX>
 		to live in conditions that would look pretty attractive to some of the homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have not committed a crime
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i mean we just our system is is is kind of skewed somehow or another
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and like i say i mean you know i can't i can't tell you i feel good about the fact that we put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to death
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean i really uh you know deep down i guess that bothers
 	
 	
 		well
 		
 		
 	