
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		well i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> they are all grown but i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> that live very close by that  i spend a lot of time with
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's great
 		that's good how old are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh see oldest one's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> then the youngest one is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		well good my we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and our oldest one uh will turn uh fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX> and the youngest one uh will turn
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight the end of April</TIMEX> so they're about the same uh range as your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> um-hum uh and so uh they're pretty busy right now we  the oldest is in uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> grade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> here uh the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one is in uh junior high <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> one is in uh what they call it intermediate school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fifth</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grades
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are in uh an elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and it looks like uh we're gonna have them in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least four</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> for uh you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three more years</TIMEX> so that keeps us busy running around some times
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		are your are are yours in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> near there your
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes they are in fact you know i pick them up from school their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is also going to school she's in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and ought to be finished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> so that leaves me a lot of time with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum what kind of things have you done with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well like they are in dance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and things like that and i pick them up from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and i take them there um
 		which it's all right for one of them i think  because she enjoys it and seems to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> for it but the other one i wonder about i think she's just pushed into it
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's possible for now
 	
 	
 		to have something to do  and uh are
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess that trade off between uh
 		you know letting them just do the things they enjoy doing or pushing them kind of just a little bit of a nudge so that they they uh
 		you know get into something far enough that they do enjoy it by themselves you know is is a tension for most parents
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh well i i can can sympathize i know i
 		i would go when <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> were growing up uh from one extreme to the other you know either i we didn't do anything or we did too much  it's it's hard to decide and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah right right
 	
 	
 		decide when they're old enough to make their own decisions that uh you are i wanted them to have the opportunities to do what they wanted but
 	
 	
 		that's right we
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wasn't sure what that was
 	
 	
 		yeah well we found out particularly with piano we wanted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to take piano for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> you know and i said well you need to take it for
 		for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least six</NUMEX> so that you know whether you wanna do it any more you build up enough enough skill that you can you make a a reasonable choice
 		so we pushed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> but then uh then we moved and and dropped it i hope some get back into something into something
 	
 	
 		well they may pick it up a little bit later and uh
 	
 	
 		i hope so
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all that but uh i know my oldest one he is well he's an honor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and just
 		wins all the awards at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but he's not really outside of school involved in anything other than the church activities so uh he's not a baseballer or anything like that but he seems very well adjusted and
 	
 	
 		well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		most of our focus is either on some school activities or going to or our church activities and they uh we just moved here uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> and so we uh we're sort of getting into things uh they've got a
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		good number of of activities and uh we enjoy you know transporting them to that because we really hope there's gonna be some benefit from those things you know and uh
 	
 	
 		oh right yes that's that is good
 	
 	
 		so they're they're doing that  we uh
 		uh haven't gotten into too many civic activities where we were before they were playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		did a little bit of gymnastics uh things like that uh here we haven't really gotten into it too much
 		uh we may later on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sometime</TIMEX> if you know they show particular interest
 	
 	
 		yeah i imagine
 		imagine it takes a while to settle down and let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> settle in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		find out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and what what it is they're wanting to do
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well i uh
 		i don't know about the time we spend with them it seems like we're with them all the time  if we're not here you know not working you know uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but um i'm sure they'd like more and it's hard for us it's hard to balance it you know there's some that
 		sort of uh i don't know about demand but you know sort of just take up more time just by their nature and uh we we struggle to uh i do any way not to work so much that i i don't give them time you know being with them and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		oh yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		uh sometimes it'd be just nice to come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and and work straight through without you know uh spending time with them but i like you know i like to spend time with them and and be with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and all like that i
 	
 	
 		well yeah well it's
 	
 	
 		uh
 		do you take them over say to see
 		
 		
 	