
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay well in the organized  i'm with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> and uh we have random drug testing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last couple of years</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have really you just accepted that of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> and then uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> they haven't done the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> yet but
 		personally i don't think see anything wrong with it uh i think it's a protection to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> and to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and everybody else if
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah the in my mind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that say that it's in violation of their privacy it's
 		it's actually a violation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they work with if uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's not fair to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working around you that uh could cause accidents or harm to yourself
 	
 	
 		you bet
 		i really like it the way they do it in the in the military they go by social security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">numbers</ENAMEX> and they take the last number and uh
 		so it uh
 		and it it or or just pick a last number social security numbers uh and that's the way they do it and it works really well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i work with recruiters a lot and they have uh
 		they have it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> with recruiters
 	
 	
 		is that mandatory for the recruiters
 	
 	
 		uh no no uh they do it that way but uh well it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every three months</TIMEX> excuse me every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>
 		and they have uh we have about um oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and fifteen</NUMEX> recruiters in our area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they have  a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> of them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every three months</TIMEX> they on a random basis
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		has
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		has your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> come up
 	
 	
 		no no hasn't come up i don't know i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's fine if it does i  the only thing you have to be careful if i know all those who join the service
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		uh it is mandatory that they're tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh if <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are found uh in the system
 		then uh they're barred for enlistment for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> and then they can come back once and test again and if it's uh still positive then they can't join
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		they've really cracked down on that and uh i think that's that's good because the source of the bad crime of reputation for for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it's surprising uh since they've been on well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first couple of months</TIMEX> this has been around for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX> and a half
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first few months</TIMEX> there was quite a few that were disqualified and uh since then you just never hear of it i guess the word got out and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> know that if they want to commit and and join then uh they have to be straight
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		the only thing that's kind of scary if you eat one of these buns with cinnamon with these uh poppy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX> on it
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and that would show up
 	
 	
 		you're kidding
 	
 	
 		no  no it's it's uh
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		it's kind of strange uh but uh yeah they they tell them that if they uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		if they're going to if they come into the motel to stay overnight
 		prior to being physical and tested and then so forth they tell them not to eat anything with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poppy seeds</ENAMEX> on it a hard roll if they're having lunch or something or dinner but
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well what does it test uh for
 	
 	
 		well i'm not sure and it just shows that they're uh uh
 		but they they specify that or just tell them that they'll have to kind of be careful well and it's the same with alcoholic beverages they they test for that too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i think it's great i really do i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but in the work place i i feel that it it should be uh something that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> have the right to do if they want
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to protect everyone concerned and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the the only problem i can see and i've heard is the the fact that if they uh
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		if the test whoever runs the test they've got to make sure they run it correctly so it's not a a misreading on it or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that that's happened in some instances i guess
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		i think they're pretty well i've heard what i've heard and especially the ones that that test the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> they uh
 		they make sure they they run them correctly and uh have the right right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with right sample and everything but
 	
 	
 		um-hum my my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s small enough here that uh
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		in fact i don't know of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> right around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Twin Falls</ENAMEX> area that's testing i'm sure they're here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i certainly wouldn't be opposed um is is it hard for you to tell people that are on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i mean
 		and i don't know how you can confirm that or not but uh
 		uh i'd really be surprised if someone in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> now it doesn't mean they're that they're not there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and maybe the testing wouldn't you know show that they were there
 	
 	
 		yeah i especially the the uh alcoholic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> part of it uh that's a that's a thing that uh
 	
 	
 		but
 		you can see that pretty easy can't you
 	
 	
 		yeah right you really can you can and uh
 		
 		
 	