
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fisher person</ENAMEX> are you
 	
 	
 		yes i love to fish
 	
 	
 		what kind
 		great what kind of fishing do you do
 	
 	
 		well it's mostly from the rivers and lakes
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and yes and from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> i don't like to go out on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> do they have in your neck of the woods
 	
 	
 		well it uh down here we usually catch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bass</ENAMEX> stripped bass you know where i <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> up at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Shasta</ENAMEX> when i go up there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but i like it all except uh really i don't i don't really care that much for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> i think i had rather have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> than i would a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well  i i don't blame you
 		i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX> and uh grew up <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish cat</ENAMEX> fishing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Little Blue River</ENAMEX> and
 		then uh we moved to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> and uh did a lot of walleye fishing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Missouri River</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh now that we are down here i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do some uh bass fishing and striped bass fishing but uh i still uh i am sort of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> at heart
 	
 	
 		i see well uh like in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX> those little bullheads they look just like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yep yeah they do
 	
 	
 		you know that's what i mean cause i am from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		you know we use to catch those little bullheads and that's they look just like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">baby catfish</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know uh did you get to go fishing very often
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i like to fish the only problem is i just moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so it's been a little over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> now but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i am not quite sure what residency is for a fishing license here and i so really i haven't gone fishing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's driving me crazy but uh one of these days i will go over to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Louisville</ENAMEX> or uh  what is it uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Hubbard Lake Ray Hubbard</ENAMEX> and
 		get some fishing in and get it out of my system for a while
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well uh you like to eat them after you catch them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well yeah sure you bet
 	
 	
 		because there's are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that like to go fishing but they don't like to eat them
 	
 	
 		well most yeah most of the time uh if we catch something we'll take it home and eat it um
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		and you're right i mean i like to fish for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> and they are really uh uh good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> but uh if i went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> that probably wouldn't be the first thing i would order if i had a choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> on the menu
 	
 	
 		yeah i know if i go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> and order fish it's usually either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salmon</ENAMEX> or uh red snapper
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well uh so do you just uh uh skin your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> or do you fillet them out how do you how do you
 	
 	
 		we skin skin them yeah yeah yeah just cut their heads off and skin them and then i just uh flour them <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> and pepper them and cook them
 	
 	
 		do you okay
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't put that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn meal</ENAMEX> on them
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		you know uh
 		that's the way my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> taught me to fry them so
 	
 	
 		well that's how we do it too uh although we uh use to set some uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> lines out and we've caught you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fifteen pound catfish</ENAMEX> and sometimes those are good to uh do on a barbecue grill
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and just uh leave the skin on and uh do it with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> on uh on on tin foil
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then the skin just basically scrapes right off and uh we're and it really tastes pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah well you know i don't think i've ever tried cooking those uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> quite that big
 		uh most of them are just the small you know pan frying ones
 	
 	
 		there uh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		well i am hoping one of these days i'll have the opportunity to catch a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> like that on uh a rod and reel but uh so far it's just been on uh on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> lines so
 	
 	
 		um
 		
  
 		
  
 		wouldn't that be something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's a thrill when you get a big fish though isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh well and up in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> on the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Missouri River</ENAMEX> there we've uh tied into a few northern pike and uh
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		they really uh in in when the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is cold they are very slow moving fish but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> time they'll uh give you a run for your money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so when you were when you did go fishing where did you go you moved there from where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it was just like the rivers and uh and the lakes i suppose huh
 	
 	
 		in
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh yeah most of the time uh we just fished uh in the river although there were a lot of sand pits and things like that that we could fish in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a lot of them ended up being close to the river so if the river ever uh flooded you know then obviously they would dump some <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bass</ENAMEX> and stuff into the into the ponds and the sand pits
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we'd do a lot of fishing there too but uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> didn't really have much for
 		
 		
 	