
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh the question is concerning the changes in the roles of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the past several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> and you know the in their in the society we live in what do you think has occurred there
 	
 	
 		well i think one of the major changes is the whole attitude towards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the work place and the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in doing jobs outside of the home
 		that's probably even one of the major changes i see over the last period of time
 	
 	
 		um-hum but uh are are they being given the full uh honor for the work they're doing and for the um
 		oh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gosh</ENAMEX> can't think of the word but for the what they have to accept well that's that they're responsible for it absolutely responsibilities is what i'm trying to say
 	
 	
 		oh i don't think so i think it's come a long ways in terms of giving them equal opportunities but i still think in lots of job markets they're not treated as equals in the words in some in some respects the other direction that in some job markets they really don't wanna be treated as equals
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		by the same token most in in most cases <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have the jobs with the same responsibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who been there before but at lower lower salaries is is that right wrong
 	
 	
 		yes i think that's generally speaking pretty true and i think that's what we really ought to look at that going is if they're gonna do equal work they ought to get equal pay
 	
 	
 		is that
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and that uh they ought to have equal opportunities to advance to those positions and i don't think we've gotten there yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah what changes do you think are most significant over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>
 		any individual thing or is it just a general switch over
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 		i think it's generally that switch over and i and i think that switch over has been more in the work force i don't think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are treated as equals in the home as much as they are in the work force
 		i think those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who are out working are probably still expected to carry more responsibility at home that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s having them on the other side of that coin picked up as much responsibility at home so they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three quarters</TIMEX> jobs now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and a quarter</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have a feeling that biness with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> working out at the same level of responsibility as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
 		sort of tears into their social or their loving relationship in that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the the lady
 		stand wants to stand up for what she has made and her own rights and has every right to do so and this upsets the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> because uh we've always been built to think that we were sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the household
 		so do you think that is gonna be uh difficult saying as far as uh marriages and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> enjoying each other in the future years
 	
 	
 		yes yeah and i think also in terms of parenting i think there's gonna be some increasing problem because i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are expecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> to do more parenting and i'm not sure they're becoming any more skilled at it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i think it really has put some additional additional stresses on family units
 	
 	
 		well do you have any opinion of potential changes that may occur occur in the next generation specifically
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i i think one of the things that always happens is i think we'll swing to one end whereas you know where were moving at to the end where a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> will be at work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then i think we starting to see now some tendency of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> at  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid thirties</TIMEX> and so i was saying you know this career thing isn't all it's cracked up to be and i wanna go back and do something else so i think we'll probably see this swind pendulum in terms of the work force swing back a little bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		although so much of it's driven by economics right now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have gotten out and gotten use to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> incomes coming in
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well i actually most lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are being hired now instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> because they can be brought in at lower salaries because that's what everybody else assumes they're gonna get
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> well how do you feel about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in uh armed services
 	
 	
 		well i think they ought to have the right i i have some problems with my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> thinking about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> going to combat and or my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> or my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s going into combat but i have problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> doing that and i guess if they want to they ought to have the right to do it it's nothing i'd be greatly enthusiastic about pushing for
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 		yeah i somehow can't do that i well i was brought up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> were kept home safe secure and made happy and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> went out and took the responsibility of earning the money
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		bringing in whatever they needed and and protecting the household and it and it really still bothers me and i spent plenty of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in the service
 		but it still bothers me to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> out in combat or actually out in places where there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> of them there and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> around them and how are they gonna protect themselves so to speak
 	
 	
 		i agree
 	
 	
 		it puts them in a very bad situation i i i really don't go for that
 	
 	
 		well i think one of the other things that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> has concerned me a little bit and i think i see some change in attitudes there my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> happens to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> who's chosen to stay at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there's a a tendency has been a tendency over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX> to treat her as though she was somebody who didn't have much intelligence because if she did she'd be out in the work force uh and fulfilling herself
 	
 	
 		yep
 		well that's not fair because i tell i can tell you one thing stay home sometime and start uh
 		doing some of those jobs that she's been handling and you're gonna learn there's a lot of responsibility in just keeping a home going
 	
 	
 		and i hope we reach the point where whatever women <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> chose to do that's acceptable if they chose to go into the work force that's okay if they choose not to that's acceptable
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		and if they go in the work force they should be treated as nicely as as well as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> or any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and uh not
 	
 	
 		as equals
 		
 		
 	