
 
     		
 	
 		well do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that uh go to college went to college are about to go or anything
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
  
 		yeah i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> go through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> we've put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> through college uh-huh
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness oh where did they go
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> A and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh oh my goodness well you are a very experienced person
 	
 	
 		right so
 	
 	
 		uh i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the present moment</TIMEX> who is a senior in high school
 		and uh he has uh made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> applications to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that give a double degree program because that's what he wanted to uh take
 		so he applied to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh he's waiting at this time uh to uh see what kind of uh acceptances and money grants might uh come in for him
 		so um i i think that uh it became very evident in the beginning of senior year
 		when he actually had to sit down with the applications he had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that he was interested in
 		but he really decided that he wants to take engineering but he also wants to keep a liberal arts
 		degree and actually get both of them  and not all that many places actually give you two degrees
 	
 	
 		right right
 		right
 	
 	
 		so he he weeded out the ones uh that did not offer that kind of thing and just really wound up making <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> applications  so um
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's probably your best bet because you know you narrow it down you're better off i think on that and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		uh-huh right well yeah and and as i saw the fall progressing and um
 		and his viewpoint it really became more evident that uh
 		he this is what he wanted to do and he didn't just want to get involved in the sciences without having the leeway of the liberal arts and i don't think he'll ever be a um
 		you know a kind of a research dedicated a test tube <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> so um
 	
 	
 		right right
 		is he going on for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s in his the engineering
 	
 	
 		i think he might wanna go to law school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh use the engineering background maybe in patent law or  yeah
 	
 	
 		you almost need a master's in like if he's in engineering in his major right now one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> anyway right now to do anything with it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		oh yes that's right yeah what uh kinds of fields did your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> study in
 	
 	
 		no matter what field you're in
 		uh well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> uh both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> let me see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was in uh business
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and business degree  and then the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was in a special ed degree
 	
 	
 		oh wonderful uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and lives and worths works with autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> um-hum and then the other one was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> director
 	
 	
 		is that right
 		uh-huh oh my
 	
 	
 		uh down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> for um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years seven years</TIMEX> and then uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is a CPA
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and another has a business degree and then the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> one is he was hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> but actually he's in the sign business now and making signs
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		oh gee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX> isn't that wonderful uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh likes that and has kind of hit on a nice setup with that so
 	
 	
 		is he uh local here in town or is uh-huh
 	
 	
 		he is local right here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> and he really loves it um-hum and it's just you know
 	
 	
 		oh good for him
 	
 	
 		that signs the type of signs they do is new in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five years</TIMEX> it's the latest thing in signs it's the type that you put on the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		put on windows and it peels off type and it looks like it's painted on
 	
 	
 		oh yes i've seen those they're remarkable because they come right off
 	
 	
 		yes and he
 		yeah
 		right he has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas um  Furniture Mart um Clothing Mart</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade World Trade Center</ENAMEX> all tied up in that he has
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 		oh good for him
 	
 	
 		so yeah so it's a nice deal for him yeah he has he's just starting in it but it seems to be a real up and coming thing
 	
 	
 		oh they've done well uh-huh oh yeah
 		oh yes that is terrific
 	
 	
 		because everything's so portable anymore i mean you know things are not stable and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are renting places for a short times and they don't want anything permanent anymore so
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right uh-huh
 		that's right you just use it when you need it and uh then it's you know gone and it it sure is very effective and then you can move into the next necessary thing that is uh right
 	
 	
 		it works out quite well
 		right
 		right
 		um-hum or on to a larger place and not put that much into anything permanent so it it works out pretty well for him
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		it's amazing isn't it amazing everything they do these days
 	
 	
 		it is it's wonderful it's wonderful
 	
 	
 		uh uh-huh it i i think it is too it really moves you from one thing to the other without  having to hassle and uh you know even like with you said with the signs have to you know to change
 	
 	
 		so
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		everything and uh you know
 	
 	
 		yeah  the have your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> have your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> a lot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> section
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for scholarships
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> both did that and they they came up with some of the you know you would never think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">applying for</ENAMEX> and they would apply for them well nobody else did and so they would get some
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh really
 		
 		
 	