
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what kind of music do you like
 	
 	
 		well i i like uh i guess it would be easier to say tell you what kind i don't like i don't like hard rock
 		uh
 		but other than that i i like just about every kind i
 		i'm not real crazy about modern uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western i i like the old uh
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> western songs that i grew up with uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rose</ENAMEX>
 		and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sons</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pioneers Cool Water</ENAMEX> and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		oh now that i don't know
 	
 	
 		well see you're not as old as i am
 	
 	
 		
 
 		either that or i didn't listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sons of the Pioneers</ENAMEX> i've heard about
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		in fact i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who uh plays hammered dulcimer and sings uh yodel cowboy yodeling songs and she talked
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		talks about
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patsy Montana</ENAMEX>
 		i think you know who that was
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		no
 		well that she she
 		that was
 		i gather an old
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowgirl</ENAMEX> who used to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sing songs like that
 	
 	
 		yeah and i i like the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Williams</ENAMEX> songs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh the modern kind it seems to me it all sounds just pretty much alike
 	
 	
 		pretty much like like rock
 	
 	
 		um yeah well
 	
 	
 		or or
 		or just too similar to each other
 	
 	
 		it's hard to tell one song from yeah it's hard to tell one song from the other
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		too too be truthful with you i'm sort of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bach</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i like all of that i like classical i when i look at my tapes it's hard to tell i like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Celtic</ENAMEX> music i like classical
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like uh some of the new age music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like uh blues uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muddy Waters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that i like uh
 		uh
 		what else do i have
 		folk music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like folk music a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah i have a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> she's been in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> oh about twelve fifteen years
 		and uh uh
 		she gave me a tape uh of some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> music
 		oh what is that dance
 		with the ladies in the long dress and the fans
 	
 	
 		uh oh you mean uh flamenco oh yes that's beautiful
 	
 	
 		yeah flamenco
 		it's modern day flamenco music
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">flamenco</ENAMEX>'s beautiful
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's really different and it's really pretty
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		well that that i like and i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> so i like i like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> music to a certain extent just because because it reminds me of that time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then uh um
 		do you play anything
 	
 	
 		well there're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of thought on that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you mean yours and everyone else's
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i i played in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> in in college i played the clarinet B flat clarinet
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then uh i took a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semester</TIMEX> as an elective i took a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semester</TIMEX> of class piano and i have a piano and an and an organ not a very fancy organ
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		but it's an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hammond</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		and uh i i can sight read most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> hymns
 		and uh
 		oh the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Movement of Moonlight sonata</ENAMEX> that goes of course very slowly
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and do you do it do you play
 	
 	
 		no not as on a regular basis
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i
 		that's going to be my retirement
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		activity if i can ever ever retire
 	
 	
 		well i
 		and get back and get back into trying something with music huh
 	
 	
 		yeah i i do sing in my church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh well that's great
 	
 	
 		yeah so so i i i do keep up to that extent
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		do do you play any instruments
 	
 	
 		no well i played the piano you know as a child uh
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and then quit and then kind of enjoyed it and took the guitar and
 		played the guitar a little bit and i can sight read uh and we have a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		piano my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was a percussionist and so he has we have a marimba and a drum set if i were to take anything i think i would take drums i just loved it when he did that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in in fact one time uh i bought a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a two hour</TIMEX> session with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> for a
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> who said she would had always wanted to go and just play all of those percussion instruments that you see including the gong the big big gong
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so he let us into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">percussion room</ENAMEX> and we got to play on every single instrument
 	
 	
 		listen let let me tell you what my uh my retirement job's going to be
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		uh i've just been to the Meyerson <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part was oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schubert</ENAMEX> and you know the usual stuff and then there was this very modern day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		piece that had no rhythm no tune and just sounded like a bunch of racket
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in the the middle of the stage was this box about oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> covered with black black what i have no idea
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	