
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		my name's Brigette
 	
 	
 		and i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		nice to meet you
 	
 	
 		and where are you
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> okay i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		are you okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um do you know what we're supposed
 	
 	
 		i'm never am ready  with that number i have to go flying around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to find it anyway
 	
 	
 		do you really do you know um what we're supposed to talk about
 	
 	
 		
  
 		vacations that we like to take and we're suppose to talk each other into a place we haven't been am i right
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay so you ready
 	
 	
 		okay so we're uh and we're not suppose to talk about what we're talking about you're going to press the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and then we just start talking
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		i think so
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i've only done this once before
 	
 	
 		oh yeah okay
 	
 	
 		have you ever done it where you call in
 	
 	
 		i haven't called in i keep getting called
 	
 	
 		oh do you okay because i called in and i was wondering i put in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> and i don't know if i was suppose to put like my area code or what or
 	
 	
 		i thought i don't know i've never done it
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay well i'll push one then ready
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay so you can go first
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		what kind of vacations do you like to take
 	
 	
 		um i like taking i like going like on vacations to um usually like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> somewhere place where it's sunny and stuff
 	
 	
 		sunny you like to like do you like to swim
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		do you do would you do you like going to tropical places
 	
 	
 		yeah i use to uh and i and i love the Virgin Islands it's a place i've been and i and and i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> although the last time we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau and</ENAMEX> and uh
 		uh the weather wasn't good and it was mostly gambling and that really wasn't what we were there for so
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		but um
 		but that's been a while now where i like to go is is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albuquerque</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		skiing
 	
 	
 		no no uh really just uh the weather there and the beauty and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">and</ENAMEX> and driving out in nature and that sort of thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> that kind of thing do you like that kind do you like
 	
 	
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah uh-huh i've been um i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Albequerque</ENAMEX> quite a bit just because i live close to there to go skiing and stuff and i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like both of them a lot
 	
 	
 		you you like both of them what about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have not been there i'm going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> in um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		you are
 	
 	
 		yes and i'm very excited
 	
 	
 		well that'll be fun
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean i've i've been when i was a lot younger but i didn't really remember it but i'm going in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> but i'm real excited about that
 	
 	
 		that'll be
 		yeah
 		well
 		the southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> are pretty different except that once you're on the coast of course it i mean being on the coast is just beautiful
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 	
 	
 		but
 		but i but i suggest some time you try to get up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> it's just incredibly beautiful that whole area
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and driving if you drive if you go from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and drive north up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh coast that way up to up through uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's just beautiful
 	
 	
 		really i'm excited about going because i haven't been in so long and i really don't remember and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of ours just moved up to um to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so we'll probably go see them too and i am really excited
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah how much time are you going to get to spend there
 	
 	
 		um really about a little less than a week
 	
 	
 		well but that's not bad is it a business trip or fun
 	
 	
 		uh it's for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> break i'm in college
 	
 	
 		oh good oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		oh well that is going to be neat
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh you're in college in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Tech</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> uh was in college in uh near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh he would go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego Palm Springs</ENAMEX> is another neat place
 	
 	
 		oh that's neat
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um there and uh
 		uh oh you get you i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX> is there you up up and on the you know between the two there's just an awful lot there
 	
 	
 		yeah see i know
 		yeah did he like going to school there
 	
 	
 		he liked it uh yeah he liked it a lot he happened to be there during earthquakes and uh
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		uh he loved it out there i mean he would say he loved it but he did get a little bit tired of the of the earthquakes they haven't had one in a while but they had them while he was there
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		so when he was in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> they had them and then he went to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and was there for the big earthquake there too on his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> break
 	
 	
 		gosh that would be scary
 		that would be really scary
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah but uh
 		anyways it's you know it's it it's it's just part of it it comes with that that and smog but then again it's got weather that's neat all the time and and uh just a lot of of other things that are great so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		see i'm so excited i think that'll be fun
 	
 	
 		yeah i think you'll enjoy that
 	
 	
 		so that's my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation of the year</TIMEX> pretty much
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah what about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">east coast</ENAMEX> have you ever been to the east coast
 	
 	
 		um no not really
 	
 	
 		no does anything interest you there
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		see i haven't
 		i have really never been there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um we've never gone there
 	
 	
 		you've never gone there
 	
 	
 		hum-um usually if we go on vacation we really pretty much go
 	
 	
 		it
 	
 	
 		God to like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint</ENAMEX> like you said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saint Thomas</ENAMEX> we've been there and like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mazatlan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Acapulco</ENAMEX> and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> do you scuba dive
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		or snorkel or any of that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that that and and do you sail
 	
 	
 		yep
 		
 		
 	