
 
     		
 	
 		i'm i'm ready
 	
 	
 		
 
 		why don't you go ahead and start off
 	
 	
 		okay well i don't have an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that i could send to a a nursing home or anything my both of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are dead
 		but i did have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that was in a convalescent home uh like a nursing home
 		and i had went there very often to visit her and uh
 		made me feel really sad if i did have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> living i don't think i could do that
 		i think they would be better off being at home with their family
 		you know
 	
 	
 		i agree although we're in that situation right now we have a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an eighty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> living with me right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and because of her circumstances she can no longer live independently
 		and even moving from her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> has been tremendously unsettling for her and we have several young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they about drive her crazy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i can believe that yes because most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> can't take having a lot of noise and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> running around and things like that in a situation like that maybe it would be better
 	
 	
 		well we've you know we've struggled a lot with it because again uh most of the nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> i've been in are very depressing to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she's still alert enough that i think she would really know that we were putting her there and i think she'd really resent it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think that would make it very hard but on the other hand i see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> with i guess our youngest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> now is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and her trying to struggle because her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> really cannot take care of herself she needs to be bathed and dressed and a lot of those kinds of things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh see now that's that's that's really a sad situation
 	
 	
 		and so the drain on the family
 	
 	
 		yeah really you know i just
 	
 	
 		and when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> come over you know she's always saying well why do they have to be here why can't they send them home it's too noisy and she'll say that to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah right right
 	
 	
 		so it's a hard situation either way i think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah in a case like that you know you more or less think it it would be better if she were in a nursing home because you have your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> growing up where
 	
 	
 		and i think that's one of the things we're really wrestling with when does it become detrimental to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to the point that you have to consider that as opposed to considering her current circumstances and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh but the cost of these nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> are so
 	
 	
 		oh prohibitive
 	
 	
 		you know a lot of people can't afford that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know so you really have no choice that way if you you know if you're not rich or something you know um
 		i know this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> that you know that was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine now her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was still alive at the time when she was in there you know and it was costing him a small fortune to keep her in there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i think we need to develop some alternatives like adult day care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's more readily available you know i think if we could send her someplace for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah then bring her back home at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she could be around some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> and have some activities would be of more interest to her and then in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> have her return and be with the family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah you know just come home for dinner and then usually they want to go to bed pretty early anyhow you know so that would probably be nice if we could ever get something like that but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but there's not many of those available <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and they're very hard to get them into and
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we tried sending her to a senior citizen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> but they're really not prepared to cope with her because she's somewhat senile and so a lot of the activities that they're engaged in she can't participate in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but i think it's an issue that you know with the graying of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> we're really going to have to as a as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> figure out how we're going to deal with this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because it is a difficult situation and you know you hate seeing them just sort of send off and not well cared for
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and yet
 	
 	
 		if if they don't know anybody and they don't know what's going on around them and everything like that well i can see maybe a nursing home would be better you know
 		but if they they have their wits about them and everything why
 		it's kind of hard
 	
 	
 		and then i think it depends on their physical ability too you know if they could be up and doing some things it might be better than when they're just sort of needing almost constant supervision and care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> always said she hopes she never had to be like that and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> luckily i mean she lived by herself and then you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> she had a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX> and she was gone so she never did have to go into a nursing home or anything like that but there's
 		so many of us <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> there was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of us that my we wouldn't have probably allowed that to happen anyhow
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know she could've taken turns living with each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of us you know for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a short a short a period of time</TIMEX> because we all don't live in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> anyhow or nor the same state
 	
 	
 		do you live at all close to each other
 	
 	
 		so
 		uh uh a couple i have a couple more that live out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> but then i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	