



In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1940s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond Stores</ENAMEX>, the largest men‚Äôs clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> at the time, created a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sensation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> by offering a wide selection of suits with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pairs of pants instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, reintroducing a level of product choice not seen since before the war.1 When the line of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful buyers</ENAMEX> at its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> stretched around the block, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bond</ENAMEX> had to impose a limit of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> suits per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>. During <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, the apparel and textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> had been converted to supply field jackets, overcoats, and uniforms to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied Forces</ENAMEX>. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years immediately</TIMEX> following the war, returning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, the end of rationing, and pent-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> demand meant apparel was in short supply.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fifty years later</TIMEX>, it is hard to imagine a retailer‚Äîbe it a high-end department store, mass merchandiser, or catalog <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service‚</ENAMEX>Äîlimiting an individual customer‚Äôs clothing purchase. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Retailers</ENAMEX> collect detailed point-of-sales information that reflects the real-time demand for goods by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. Through new computer systems, they share this information with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> who, in turn, can ship orders within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> to automated distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>. The contemporary equivalent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond Stores</ENAMEX> now has a much better chance of avoiding stock-outs of popular items and the inventory gluts that lead to costly markdowns. By the same token, the overall risk associated with fickle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, numerous selling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX>, and segmented markets‚Äîalong with fierce overseas competition‚Äîhas currently made this a tough arena for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>.
The most surprising aspect of this story is that today‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel and textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries‚</ENAMEX>Äîleft for dead by business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> and economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s‚Äîhave</TIMEX> begun to transform themselves, reaping new competitive advantages. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond Stores‚</ENAMEX>Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> were thrilled by a suit with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pairs of pants, contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> want and expect a huge range of choices, and the consumer desire for limitless variety has kept the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> apparel industry alive. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> purchased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28.7</NUMEX> outerwear garments (all coats, jackets, shirts, dresses, blouses, sweaters, trousers, slacks, and shorts) per capita; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> the estimated number of such garments was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only 2</NUMEX> per capita<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX>
The transformation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> clothing and textile manufacturing is very much still in progress and has by no means been successful for every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>; but these industries have entered a renaissance of sorts, one that reflects new information technologies and management practices as well as the new economics of international trade. This book describes what has happened since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the postwar era</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> related industries‚Äîretail, apparel, and textiles‚Äîand what such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> must do to improve performance. We cover the histories of these industries, including the information technologies that have transformed these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>, manufacturing processes, inventory management, the new role of logistics, and global trade implications and policies.
The story is a complex one, involving many individual cases and specifics. This study began with a focus on apparel manufacturing, but we soon concluded that apparel production must be viewed as an integral part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> is the set of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and relationships that get a product to market, including the original acquisition of raw materials; production of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> at a manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>; distribution to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>; sale of the finished item to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>; and any <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">installation</ENAMEX>, repair, or service activities that follow the sale.
A retail-apparel-textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> typically includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that manufacture synthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX>; produce, gather, and refine natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX>; spin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX> into yarn; weave or knit yarn into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX>; manufacture buttons, zippers, and other garment components; and cut and sew fabric into garments. It also includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> who sell garments to end <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. The retail link often involves services or instructions to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> about fabric and garment design, packaging, distribution, order fulfillment, and transportation. And it is in some of these areas, particularly distribution and order fulfillment, that channel dynamics have undergone substantial change during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX>.
Supply channels are not new, of course; for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> have sold their wares to those who cut and sew garments. But, until recently, most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> in the textile and apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> have been characterized by arm‚Äôs-length relationships among relatively autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. It is only since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX> that a number of market and technological changes have encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to enhance the links among different stages of production and distribution. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart Stores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kmart Corporation</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dillard‚Äôs Inc.</ENAMEX> have been the driving forces behind changes in manufacturing and logistics systems in a way that was unheard of in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond Stores‚</ENAMEX>Äô time. For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Walton</ENAMEX> built a retail juggernaut that began with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX> and grew to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost three thousand</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. He did so by insisting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> implement information technologies for exchanging sales data, adopt standards for product labeling, and use modern methods of material handling that assured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> a variety of products at low prices.
We contend that this revolution in retailing practices will determine future competitive outcomes in retail-apparel-textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>. These new practices‚Äîwhich we call lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">retailing‚</ENAMEX>Äîhave compelled apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> to reorganize the manner in which they relate to retail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, undertake distribution, forecast and plan production, and manage their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> relations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lean</ENAMEX> retailing has also changed the way the textile industry relates to both apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. Most important, because the apparel industry has been one of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to face the full brunt of the retail revolution, its story illuminates pervasive changes under way in the entire economy.
In many respects, our findings defy the conventional wisdom. When we began our research, we were advised by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> to establish better performance measures‚Äîfor example, how many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> does it take to make a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX>? The traditional view holds that because manufacturing performance is determined by the labor time required to produce an item, then what applies to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, for example, can also apply to clothing; therefore, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> might be able to save themselves by improving assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>.3 Yet after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of studying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, we have found that direct labor content is not the primary issue. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that have adopted new information systems and management practices, participating in a well-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, are the ones with the strongest performance today‚Äînot those that have simply improved assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>.
The changes we examine in retailing are not only profound but rippling through a growing segment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy. They have already transformed channel relations in such industries as food and grocery, home-building products, personal computers, and office products. The retail revolution is affecting the automobile, health care, and pharmaceutical industries as well. Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> of power tools and ball bearings talk about their products as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúfashion‚Äù items</ENAMEX>, the apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industry‚</ENAMEX>Äîalways subject to the whims of fashion‚Äîhas much to say to any industry that involves retailing. Every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> has its particular history, elements, and dynamics, and retail-apparel-textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> are no exception. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stitch</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> uses the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel story to highlight the transformation of retailing and manufacturing across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five Decades</TIMEX> of Change
When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond Stores</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> lining up around the block to buy suits, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúcasual</ENAMEX> wear,‚Äù as we know it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, did not exist. Even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> wore suits, ties, and hats to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballpark</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were clothed in dresses and millinery. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">As recently as 1969</TIMEX>, the dress code at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> required undergraduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to wear a collar, necktie, and jacket in the dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> had to wear a dress or a skirt and blouse. It wasn‚Äôt until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> that these vestiges of formality gave way to blue jeans and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>shirts‚Äîthe casual wear uniform. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX> ushered in yuppie brands, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> history repeated itself as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers‚</ENAMEX>Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> adopted the bedraggled grunge look. Many business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> have ‚Äúcasual days‚Äù for office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attire</ENAMEX>. Now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> now have casual days in their workplaces, all but a few establishing this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About seven</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> with dress-down days permit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to wear polo shirts, jeans, and sneakers<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel and textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX>, like the clothing and other products they produce, have undergone tremendous changes over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past half century</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1950 to 1995</TIMEX>, domestic production of apparel doubled, while textile production, less vulnerable to imports, increased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost three</NUMEX> times<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX> Yet since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, shifting tastes in clothes, rising real incomes, and domestic and foreign competition within the textile and apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> have markedly reduced the proportion of consumer budgets expended on apparel and its upkeep (laundry and dry cleaning). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1963</TIMEX>, apparel‚Äôs share of the Consumer Price Index was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10.63 percent</NUMEX>;6 by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1995</TIMEX>, that percentage had fallen to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.52 percent</NUMEX> of average household expenditures<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX>
Meanwhile, structural changes in the retail industry have influenced how and where clothing is sold. The growth of the highway system around central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and the rapid expansion of suburbs created new opportunities for shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>, and other outlets closer to a growing number of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> wage-earner <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. The metropolitan suburbs increased housing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s through the 1980s</TIMEX> far faster than the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> or the rural suburbs<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX> Because inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> retained a high proportion of lower income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, increased purchasing power for shelter, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, and clothing shifted to the suburbs. That means the large department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> traditionally based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macy‚</ENAMEX>Äôs or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marshall Field</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Company‚</ENAMEX>Äîserved by mass transportation and marketed through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> advertisements‚Äîsuffered from the competition of mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> and specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> in new locations.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> that compose the apparel and textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> manufacture a wide variety of products, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mix</ENAMEX> has also changed since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the postwar era</TIMEX>. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past thirty-five years</TIMEX> in the textile industry, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> employed for carpet and rug production has doubled and is projected to expand further over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decade</TIMEX>. In the apparel industry, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a quarter</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> now produce nonclothing items like curtains, draperies, house furnishings, and automotive trimmings; once again, employment since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> in these areas has doubled, while it has dropped off dramatically for actual garment-making.
These changes are related to new technology and foreign competition. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exhortations</ENAMEX> to buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúunion label‚Äù</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúMade in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.A.</ENAMEX>‚Äù have done relatively little to stem the tide of clothing assembled overseas. For example, the per capita number of outerwear garments purchased in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> increased from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14.3 to 28.7</NUMEX> in the period from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1995.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imports</ENAMEX>, however, provided half the total in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, leaving domestic production with only about the same per capita number of outerwear garments as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades earlier10‚</TIMEX>Äîall this, even though apparel and textiles in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> have long been characterized by special import regulation. Tariffs on their imports have remained higher than many other manufactured goods. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, national policymakers have sought to moderate the growth of imports, primarily through agreements with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Multi-Fiber Arrangement</ENAMEX> (MFA), a network of bilateral agreements negotiated with participating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> which became effective in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, established quotas for imports largely related to estimates of the growth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> domestic market. The stated purpose of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFA</ENAMEX> was to provide for the ‚Äúorderly‚Äù growth of trade in these products among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> on a negotiated basis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocates</ENAMEX> emphasized that ‚Äútextiles and apparel offer proportionately more jobs, including entry-level positions, to less well educated, more disadvantaged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> than most other sectors of the economy.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù11</ENAMEX>
Yet with the signing of the agreements that grew out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uruguay Round</ENAMEX> of international trade negotiations that concluded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFA</ENAMEX> has now been replaced; textiles and apparel trade are to be integrated into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATT</ENAMEX>) over a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten-year period</TIMEX> that ends <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 2005</TIMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policymakers</ENAMEX> believe these changes could deal a fatal blow to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel industry, which will become even more exposed to global competition. The impact of these trade changes remains uncertain, and national policies that take them into account are still evolving. But if one did not consider the shift in retailing practices that is also recasting the apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industry‚</ENAMEX>Äîand turned some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> into unexpected leaders‚Äîit might indeed look like ‚ÄúMade in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.A.‚Äù</ENAMEX> was a lost cause.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dying Industry‚Äîor</ENAMEX> Not?
For many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX>, a book about the future of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel and textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> is still an oxymoron. The conventional wisdom paints a grim picture of where these industries are headed. Low-cost labor overseas and the increasing penetration of imports have certainly undercut <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>; apparel imports grew rapidly in most categories starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1970s</TIMEX>. If we measure import penetration in physical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> (rather than dollar value)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,12</NUMEX> import penetration for men‚Äôs and boys‚Äô suits, for example, went from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 10 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. A similar expansion in imports occurred for men‚Äôs and boys‚Äô trousers, women‚Äôs and girls‚Äô dresses, and women‚Äôs slacks and shorts<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13</NUMEX>
As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> consequence, the number of business failures among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> climbed from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">227</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> to a high of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">567</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1993.14</NUMEX> Not surprisingly, employment in the apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> during this period declined appreciably. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics</ENAMEX> projects a further reduction in the domestic apparel industry during the period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996 to 2006</TIMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">864,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just 714,00015‚Äîthis</NUMEX> from an industry that employed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1.2 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> and reached a peak of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1973.16</NUMEX>
The conventional wisdom explains the industry‚Äôs decline in this way: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apparel</ENAMEX>, particularly women‚Äôs apparel, is driven by price-based competition among generally small manufacturing and contracting establishments<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> costs represent a significant portion of cost for many garment categories<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,18</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> wage levels far exceed those of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">People‚Äôs Republic of China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mexico</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.19</NUMEX> Although the magnitude of these differences varies as exchange rates fluctuate, under any realistic exchange-rate scenario, the labor cost differential is sufficiently high to put <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> at a very significant competitive disadvantage.
The manufacture of men‚Äôs shirts provides another illustration. Throughout much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-World War II</ENAMEX> era, the majority of men‚Äôs shirts sold in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> were white dress shirts, primarily through department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. Shirts with stripes, patterns, and uncommon colors constituted <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 30 percent</NUMEX> of all dress shirts sold through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1960s.20</ENAMEX> In this environment, low fashion content and limited product variety made demand for individual shirts relatively predictable. Store <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> succeeded by striking deals with apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> for large shipments of white shirts at the lowest possible price and with long delivery lead times. Unlike the women‚Äôs industry, where style has always mattered more, relatively large men‚Äôs apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haggar; Hart, Schaffner</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fruit of the Loom; Arrow Shirt Company</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hathaway Shirt</ENAMEX> emerged, seeking to capture economies of scale<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.21</NUMEX>
But <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> compensation levels have increasingly hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX>, if performance is principally determined on a price/cost basis. For example, because of wage differentials between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX> would need to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> times more productive than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> to be ‚Äúcompetitive.‚Äù As a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt manufacturers</ENAMEX> lost enormous market share to offshore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>. And employment in men‚Äôs and boys‚Äô shirts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1972 and 1996</TIMEX> declined an average of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.22
There is just one problem with these accounts. Although the production of basic white dress shirts may lend itself to a price/cost analysis, this ‚Äústaple‚Äù good, like many staple goods, now constitutes only a small proportion of all shirt production: by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, little more than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of men‚Äôs dress shirts were white<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.23</NUMEX> This one-time staple has been replaced by shirts of dizzying diversity in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX>, design, and style, providing the final consumer with a huge assortment of shirts while exposing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to increased risk of holding large volumes of unsold goods. Classical economic assumptions about market <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competition</ENAMEX> are not directly applicable in this situation, even in a ‚Äúmature‚Äù industry like apparel.
As shown in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> chapters, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> that invest in advanced information technologies and use them to change their methods of planning and production can significantly reduce the amount of inventory they hold, thereby reducing the need to mark down or write off unsold products at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of a season</TIMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> also earn twice as much in profits than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> that continue to operate along traditional lines. Yet the distinguishing feature of such high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> is not their success in shaving off labor costs in the assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>; it is their effort in changing basic aspects of the way they manage their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>.
Although it is true that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> apparel industry could have given up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>, with only distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> remaining in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, it did not. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> have developed, or have been compelled to develop, a competitive service for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>; best practice <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> can now deliver orders with just a few days‚Äô notice, something overseas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> have difficulty achieving. These <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> do so through electronic data interchange (EDI), automated distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, and sophisticated inventory management‚Äîa triumph of information technology, speed, and flexibility over low labor rates.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel Perspective</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Five Propositions</ENAMEX>
So what has changed the prognosis for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> apparel and textiles and provided new opportunities for these industries? The answer is not to be found simply in the clout of a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> or the use of bar codes or EDI. To understand why the apparel industry is a prototype for others, we need to look at the underlying dynamics of demand and its impact on manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>. Consider once again the contemporary customer‚Äôs appetite for variety. Increased rates of product introduction, product proliferation, and shortened product cycles mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have to respond much faster to rapidly changing markets.
For our purposes, we can represent growing product diversity in the form of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúfashion triangle‚Äù</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1</NUMEX>). Apparel items at the very top of this triangle include dresses from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">runways</ENAMEX>, which represent a very small share of apparel sold. The majority of fashion products also have a short selling life‚Äîusually <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> season‚Äîbut are produced for a broader market. At the triangle‚Äôs bottom are basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> that remain in a retailer‚Äôs or manufacturer‚Äôs collection for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>, such as men‚Äôs white dress shirts or underwear. Basics -historically constituted the majority of apparel products sold. In the middle of the triangle are fashion-basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX>, typically variants on a basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> but containing some fashion element (such as stonewashed jeans or khaki pants with pleats or trim). This expanding center of the fashion triangle indicates where the industry is headed. Because a growing percentage of basic apparel items have some fashion content, fashion-basic products are driving product proliferation.
Product proliferation and shorter product cycles, reflected in ever-changing styles and product differentiation, contribute to general demand uncertainty for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, thereby making demand forecasting and production planning harder <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. In a world where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> must supply an increasing number of products with fashion elements, speed and flexibility are crucial capabilities for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> wrestling with product proliferation, whether they are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> trying to offer a wide range of choices to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> responding to retail demands for shipments.
To be sure, technological advances in communication and transportation have helped supply <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> operate more effectively and efficiently in providing diverse goods. Although these changes have provided strong motivation for increased channel coordination, the development and implementation of key facilitating technologies‚Äîlike bar codes, the later spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX>, and automated distribution centers‚Äîhave been the real movers here. New channel relationships, in turn, have led to better performance, based on a variety of standards, and enhanced the competitiveness of many sectors of these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX>.
Note that these significant technological, market, and environmental changes largely originated outside the apparel industry itself. As we will make clear, changes that emerge in a market economy in one sphere often have unforeseen consequences in others. Bar codes, for instance, began with the food and grocery industry in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> to lower the labor costs of cashier work and avoid delays to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>.24 With the commercialization of the laser, automated checkout became more than an industry vision. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> from grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain stores</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> met in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> to develop a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äúuniversal</ENAMEX> product code‚Äù for scanning purposes: the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> digits stand for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> and the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> identify the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> at the stockkeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> (SKU) level<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.25</NUMEX> All the digits are represented in the now-familiar sequence of light and dark bars of differing widths. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, bar codes had begun to spread throughout food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain stores</ENAMEX> and grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost another decade</TIMEX> passed before the practice was adopted by apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> chapters about the retail revolution, inventory management, and apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, we provide an in-depth look at how such new technologies have affected the related industries. For now, we present <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> propositions that arise from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> perspective of this book. The conventional wisdom can no longer predict future industry dynamics or offer guideposts for private and public policies. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> perspective, however, indicates why the demand uncertainty and risk associated with today‚Äôs apparel industry offer new opportunities for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Proposition 1:‚ÄÇ‚ÄÇThe</ENAMEX> retail, apparel, and textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> are increasingly linked as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> through information and distribution relationships.
In conventional terms, these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> are considered distinct industries, separated by traditional market relationships. For example, arm‚Äôs-length transactions between retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> and apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> determine prices and quantities of goods to be delivered. Apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> periodically made deliveries based on these contracts and the transaction was then completed. In such a world, coordination problems between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> were of little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>.
But, as we have already emphasized, this is not the real world of apparel <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. At its most fundamental level, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> perspective reflects a revolution in retail practices. These practices have resulted in the integration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> at all stages of the distribution and production <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>, because of the infusion of real-time information on consumer sales. Instead of gearing planning and production decisions to forecasts and guesses made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> in advance of a selling season, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> now receive periodic ongoing orders based on actual consumer expenditures. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in transformed retail-apparel-textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> have established a complex web of computer hardware and software, other technologies, and managerial practices that have blurred the traditional boundaries between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Proposition 2:‚ÄÇ‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇFor apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, the key to success is no longer solely price competition but the ability to introduce sophisticated information links, forecasting capabilities, and management systems.
The conventional wisdom holds that the basis of competitive performance for apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> is lowest price‚Äîperiod. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Feldstein</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of Economic Advisers</ENAMEX>,
The labor intensive [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>] apparel market cannot and should not compete with much lower cost labor elsewhere. The stuff depends on somebody sitting at a sewing machine and stitching sleeves on; it is crazy to hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> by forcing them to buy that at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> an hour of labor. We ought to be out of that business.26
Fortunately, clothing production <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is more than a simple price/cost game. Successful apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> must now focus on their capability to respond accurately and efficiently to the stringent demands placed on them by new retailing practices. This requires establishing systems to handle electronic, real-time orders, as well as creating management and information systems capable of using incoming information to forecast, plan, track production, and manufacture (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>) products in a flexible and efficient manner. Needless to say, these new skills were not part of the management arsenal of traditional apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>.
Yet our research indicates that apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are building these new skills. Analysis of detailed industry data demonstrates that there have been substantial increases in apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers‚</ENAMEX>Äô investments in information technologies, distribution systems, and other associated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> during the same period that new types of retailing practices emerged. In addition, we have found that those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> under greatest pressure by innovative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> have been the most likely to make such investments, as well as to invest in innovations in other stages of manufacturing. Most important, apparel<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX> that have invested in major innovations to collect and use information perform much better than those that have done little to innovate production beyond providing basic information links to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Proposition 3:‚ÄÇ‚ÄÇThe</ENAMEX> assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room‚</ENAMEX>Äîthe traditional focus of attention for industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">competitiveness‚</ENAMEX>Äîcan provide competitive benefits only if other more fundamental changes in manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> have been introduced.
The inputs to garment production are relatively straightforward: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX>, thread, accessories like buttons and zippers, labor, and a modest level of capital investment. The majority of input costs are composed of materials and labor. For example, close to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of the value of shipments for men‚Äôs shirts comes from the cost of materials, while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> arises from compensation costs<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.27</NUMEX> Reducing textile costs is a viable option for larger apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>; they can exert some pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> because of the size of their orders. Small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, however, have few such options. As a result, the conventional method of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost reduction revolves, once again, around reducing labor costs. Because the largest labor cost is concentrated in assembly phases, the focus of most productivity efforts has been in the sewing room<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.28</NUMEX>
Garment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> is typically done by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúbundle‚Äù</ENAMEX> production, which entails breaking garment-making into a series of worksteps or operations. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> is assigned to a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>, who receives a bundle of unfinished garment parts and undertakes her single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> on each item in the bundle. Completed bundles are then moved forward to the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> in the production process. To foster productivity (physical output per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>) and constrain supervisory costs, wages are paid on a piece-rate basis, providing incentives for rapid completion of the operation.
Many industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> have sought to improve assembly productivity, the holy grail for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. This generally involves modifications to improve the efficiency of the bundle system, using a variety of methods: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äúengineering‚</ENAMEX>Äù the assembly process to reduce direct labor requirements for each step, changing the incentive rate to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to increase their pace, or adopting new technologies to substitute for labor-intensive assembly steps. It is true that through ongoing refinement of apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> processes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> have been able to achieve some continuous improvements in labor productivity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Trade Administration of the U.S. Department of Commerce</ENAMEX> expressed this view in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> that
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> who hesitates to employ new strategies will not likely survive, as expected innovations in technology dramatically alter the nature of clothing manufacture. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garment</ENAMEX>-making in its current labor-intensive form will eventually be phased out in favor of automated, robotized manufacturing, geared for almost instantaneous transition from one style to another. The difficulty of handling cut fabrics by machines may be resolved in the near future, and the quest for higher operating speeds will then receive more attention, taking production levels to new heights<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.29</NUMEX>
Yet here the conventional wisdom misses other significant measures of performance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managers</ENAMEX> in well-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> pay attention to inventory costs, inventory replenishment practices, information reliability, and time to market rather than the traditional direct costs of labor and materials alone. In fact, competitive performance is already being driven less by how a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> manages its assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> and more by how it manages the logistics of its operations as a whole. Our study shows that an apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> can still be successful with a traditionally organized sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>; a firm with innovative and productive assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, may not be competitively viable if it has not invested in information links with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and other changes in management practices.
Apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> are not the only ones learning this lesson the hard way. The emphasis on labor productivity that has preoccupied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> in many industries‚Äîsuch as the total <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">labor minutes</TIMEX> required to assemble a car‚Äîno longer makes as much sense now that information technology has revolutionized retailing in many product segments. For instance, the current labor costs associated with assembly constitute <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of the final cost of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. In contrast, distribution-related costs‚Äîthose associated with the traditional structure of automobile <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">retailing‚</ENAMEX>Äîconstitute anywhere between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34 percent</NUMEX> of final cost<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.30</NUMEX> It is little wonder that car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are currently in the throes of radically restructuring their method of automobile distribution.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Proposition 4:‚ÄÇ‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇInstead of fashion as the saving grace of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, basic and fashion-basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> will prove critical to its long-term survival.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel industry, they often think of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New York City‚Äôs Seventh Avenue</ENAMEX>, which is driven by new design, constantly changing seasonal offerings, and a willingness by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> to pay a premium for the cutting edge of fashion. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> continue to have a competitive advantage in this area because a large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> are located in these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and can respond quickly to changing demands, as well as shape them. This infrastructure allows for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúquick response‚Äù</ENAMEX> on the fashion end of the women‚Äôs and, to a more limited extent, men‚Äôs markets. Once established, a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> believe, the experience at the fashion end can be diffused downward to less fashion-oriented products. As a result, some of the fashion-oriented products that had been sourced offshore can then return to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
Those with a pessimistic view of domestic apparel manufacturing often assume that the high fashion end of the industry (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äútop‚Äù</ENAMEX> of the fashion triangle in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1</NUMEX>, page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>) may be its best hope because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> can capitalize on their proximity to market. The highly acclaimed report by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT Commission on Industrial Productivity</ENAMEX>, Made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, concludes:
Apparel, textile, and fiber <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> have recently joined to launch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quick Response Program</ENAMEX>, designed to improve information flow, standardize recording systems, and improve turnaround time throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>.... The program could be an important boon to productivity and competitiveness.... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Quick Response</ENAMEX> succeed? According to industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, that depends on whether it diffuses down to the high-fashion, quick turnaround segments of the industry or, like much new technology in this industry, is adapted to suit the needs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> still committed to mass production<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.31</NUMEX>
Regardless of where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quick Response</ENAMEX> has succeeded, however, our research indicates that very different time-based competitive demands have emerged in the industry, driven not by voluntary acceptance of policies but by the changing nature of market competition among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. Rather than arising in the fashion, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúSeventh Avenue‚</ENAMEX>Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> of the industry, the new form of retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competition</ENAMEX> involves basic and fashion-basic products like jeans, intimate apparel, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>shirts‚Äîthe bottom of the fashion triangle.
Basic and fashion-basic apparel categories now constitute the lion‚Äôs share of industry sales, accounting for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 72 percent</NUMEX> of all shipments<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.32</NUMEX> This implies that a far larger portion of the industry may be viable in the long run than the part that could be saved by ‚Äúquick response‚Äù at the fashion end<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.33</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX> in mind, however, that this viability depends on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> using information to plan and execute production in a more sophisticated manner than usual for this and other industries.
Similar dynamics are cropping up in nonclothing areas as well. Grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> now stock a profusion of toothbrushes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Depot</ENAMEX> has shelves and shelves of different light bulbs, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX> offers custom-configured personal computers. The growing presence of fashion-basic elements in myriad consumer products means that all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> may find new competitive opportunities using replenishment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Proposition 5:‚ÄÇ‚</ENAMEX>ÄÇEven with full implementation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATT</ENAMEX>, a viable apparel industry can remain in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>, drawing on a range of production processes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>.
When it comes to international trade agreements, the conventional wisdom sounds most bleak. It leads to stark conclusions about the long-term viability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel industry, even with steps taken to improve assembly-room productivity and fashion-oriented quick response. The following comment is typical:
Among the factors that are expected to have a substantial impact on employment in the textiles and apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX>, perhaps the most influential will be the trade policy agreed to in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">GATT</ENAMEX>.... The apparel industry, which is far more labor intensive and less competitive internationally than the textile industry, will probably sustain most of the losses from the new trade environment<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.34</NUMEX>
Even here, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> perspective tells a somewhat different story. When domestic channels reduce lead times to market, particularly with basic and fashion-basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX>, the comparative advantage of imports declines‚Äîdespite the lower wage costs of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, elimination of quotas on imports, and tariff reductions. This means that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel industry is not necessarily doomed by high direct labor costs, at least for certain products. In fact, we expect a resurgence in certain sectors because of the innovative practices being pursued by some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>.
To be sure, the international sourcing arrangements that have been created by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> over the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> reflect a quest for minimizing unit labor costs. But the long lead times they require will increasingly challenge such arrangements. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Manufacturers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> that rely on international sourcing will therefore have to reassess the total costs associated with offshore production and revise existing arrangements.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade</ENAMEX> data already suggest a major restructuring in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel imports. The surge in apparel imports in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> came from low-wage <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, primarily the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúBig Four‚Äù‚Äîthe People‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic of China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> provided <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39 percent</NUMEX> of all apparel imports in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51 percent</NUMEX> of all apparel imports by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> (measured in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">square-meter</NUMEX> equivalents, a measure of quantity). But by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Four‚</ENAMEX>Äôs share of imports had fallen to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26 percent</NUMEX>. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> share has been increasingly displaced by those of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>.35 Although these shifts in part reflect changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> trade policy, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North American Free Trade Agreement</ENAMEX> (NAFTA), they fundamentally arise from new sourcing patterns attributable to channel integration and the consequent need for apparel items that can be delivered in a shorter time to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> market.
The implications of these changes from a private and public policy perspective are enormous. Competing in the transformed retail-apparel-textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> now requires a set of management practices for both domestic and international sourcing. A successful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apparel-maker</ENAMEX>, for instance, may assemble basic men‚Äôs khaki pants in average sizes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, taking advantage of low labor costs as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mexico‚</ENAMEX>Äôs proximity to the maker‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>; at the same time, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can choose to manufacture products with more variable demand, like khaki pants with narrow waists and long inseams, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, providing fast turnaround for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and lower exposure to inventory risk.
Going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> for low prices alone is no longer the smartest course of action for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. Increasingly, they will factor in demand uncertainty and product proliferation when making such sourcing decisions. As we will discuss throughout, many of the capabilities required for this model of competition are new to the apparel industry. The post-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATT</ENAMEX> competitive arena will be extremely demanding, but, based on the innovations many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> are making, we believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> apparel industry has a future.
How <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Book Is Organized</ENAMEX>
Because of our separate academic perspectives and disciplines, the research underlying <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Stitch in Time</ENAMEX> comes from a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. Much of our analysis is based on detailed survey data we collected from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">118</NUMEX> business units‚Äîa sample representing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one-third</NUMEX> of the shipments‚Äîin the apparel industry. We supplemented the original survey with microdata collected from a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. Our work also draws on numerous case studies of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> and data gathered at site visits. We have modeled specific channel dynamics in order to understand what optimal practices might look like as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> develops over time. Finally, we have worked closely with business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, and our academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> to exchange views, test ideas, and refine our results on a continuing basis. The appendices present a list of acronyms, a description of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCTAR</ENAMEX> survey and other data sources, and a list of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that we visited or at which we conducted interviews with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stitch</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> is organized into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> sections, roughly corresponding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel components</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> provide an overview and historical context. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chapters 3</ENAMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> analyze developments in the retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chapters 6</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> establish a bridge between retailing and apparel/textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> through an exploration of the problems of inventory management‚Äîa central aspect of emerging channel dynamics. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chapters 8</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> focus on the apparel industry; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chapters 11</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> look at textiles. Chapters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 through 15</TIMEX> examine the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> as a whole, from global, private-performance, and public-policy perspectives.
After this introduction, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 2</ENAMEX> (‚ÄúThe Past as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prologue‚Äù</ENAMEX>) offers a brief history of recent technological and human resource developments in retailing, apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">production‚</ENAMEX>Äîincluding the role of jobbers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX>, and manufacturers‚Äîand textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>. Here we make clear that the changes wrought by lean retailing echo the last industrial transformation, which occurred in the late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteenth century</TIMEX> with the advent of the railroad and telegraph.
In the retailing section of the book, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 3</ENAMEX> (‚ÄúThe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retail Revolution‚Äù</ENAMEX>) contrasts traditional practices with the emerging method of lean retailing, starting with a comparison of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanamaker‚Äôs</ENAMEX>, the grandest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> of its time, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> leading the current wave of retail restructuring. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 4</ENAMEX> (‚ÄúThe <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Building Blocks of Lean Retailing‚Äù</ENAMEX>) describes how the essential elements of lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">retailing‚</ENAMEX>Äîbar codes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX>, the modern distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, and standards across firms‚Äîfit together. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chapter 5 (‚ÄúThe Impact of Lean Retailing‚Äù</ENAMEX>) presents some of the key results of our survey, indicating how lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> have performed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX> and their effects on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>.
Next, we move to the inventory ‚Äúbridge‚Äù between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>. Product proliferation has raised the uncertainty of overall demand faced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 6</ENAMEX> (‚ÄúInventory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Management</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retailer‚Äù</ENAMEX>) looks at formal models of retail inventory management and discusses how they have been modified by lean retailing practices. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 7</ENAMEX> (‚ÄúInventory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Management</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manufacturer‚Äù</ENAMEX>) switches to the supplier‚Äôs point of view. Because dynamics are shifting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> are confronting new inventory challenges in their efforts to replenish items rapidly for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. We present <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cases that emphasize the importance of using <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand variation for different items to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> set optimal inventory policies. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> also describes a new approach to production and sourcing strategies, one that balances traditional and short-cycle production lines.
The next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> are devoted to apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> and related human resource practices. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 8</ENAMEX> (‚<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ÄúGetting Ready to Sew‚Äù</ENAMEX>) describes the preassembly steps of apparel design, marker-making, and cutting and how they are adapted to new areas like mass customization. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 9</ENAMEX> (‚ÄúAssembly and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sewing Room‚Äù</ENAMEX>) examines the technical aspects of sewing‚Äîfrom different kinds of sewing machines to what sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> do‚Äîand alternative ways of arranging the flow of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly operations</ENAMEX> through an apparel workplace. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 10</ENAMEX> (‚ÄúHuman <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resources</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Apparel‚Äù</ENAMEX>) considers the impact of alternative methods of assembly‚Äîespecially modular, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>-based, production‚Äîon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> performance. We also discuss why human resource policies cannot be treated separately from other business decisions regarding rapid replenishment.
In the textile <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section, Chapter 11 (‚ÄúTextile Operations‚Äù</ENAMEX>) describes the technological processes involved in converting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> to a vast range of woven and knit products. The textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> has changed remarkably since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, in part because of the capital intensity and technological sophistication of textile equipment, much of which is automated. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 12</ENAMEX> (‚ÄúThe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Viability of Textiles‚Äù</ENAMEX>) places <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> textiles in an international context, detailing the ways in which the domestic industry has adjusted over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several decades</TIMEX> through dramatic productivity enhancement. Because textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are increasingly supplying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">users</ENAMEX> directly, as well as producing fabric for apparel<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX>, we also address the multiple channels evolving in this sector.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stitch</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> concludes with a look at the many factors shaping today‚Äôs retail-apparel-textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel‚</ENAMEX>Äîfrom the complex management challenges facing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> to labor standards and macroeconomic policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 13</ENAMEX> (‚ÄúThe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Marketplace‚Äù</ENAMEX>) reviews trends in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> imports and exports of apparel and textiles, including information on trade by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and specific products. It then connects these trends to changing trade policies, emphasizing the growing regionalization of trade flows in different parts of the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 14</ENAMEX> (‚ÄúSuppliers in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lean World‚Äù</ENAMEX>) examines our survey results from another angle, evaluating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> performance in an integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. Here we highlight the importance of combining information technologies, manufacturing innovations, and new methods of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to respond to lean retailing demands.
Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 15</ENAMEX> (‚ÄúInformation-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integrated Channels‚Äù</ENAMEX>) touches on a number of public policy issues raised by our findings. These include what can be done about the continuing problem of sweatshops, the new international economics of trade, and the effect of information integration on the business cycle and consumer prices at the macroeconomic level. Last but not least, we take a realistic look at the competitive future of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> retail, apparel, and textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX>.
The information-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, with its emphasis on time and product perishability, is the basis for our cautiously optimistic‚Äîand unconventional‚Äîoutlook. Even more important, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> examined in this book provide a glimpse into processes reshaping a considerable portion of the economy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consumers</ENAMEX> no longer line up for a special suit at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond Stores</ENAMEX>; they also expect an ever more ‚Äúfashionable‚Äù array of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cereal products</ENAMEX>, computers, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX>. As the next chapter shows, the changes now under way have their roots in new technologies, just as technical advances in transportation and communication shifted the industrial landscape at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the last century</TIMEX>.



