



The beauty of automatic replenishment is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> is really the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>. She is telling us what she wants and needs in the future. Quite frankly, of all the buying we do, letting our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> make the choice seems to make the most sense.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄîTom Cole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federated Logistics and Operations</ENAMEX>
Our goal is to replace the product on the retail shelf as quickly as possible, because that‚Äôs where the consumer buys it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄîJeff Kernodle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Replenishment</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF Corp</ENAMEX>
Many of the popular accounts of quick response, rapid replenishment, and supply-chain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> assume that all parties‚Äîconsumers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, and suppliers‚Äîwin as a result of these policies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consumers</ENAMEX> have definitely benefited because these practices afford them a greater choice of products at lower average prices.1 It is safe to say that lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> have also come out ahead, given their rapid growth in relation to, and at the expense of, traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> in many different retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>. But have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> benefited from entering into relations with lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>? Have such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> improved their competitive position along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> they supply?
The short answer to these questions is ‚ÄúIt depends.‚Äù Although it is certainly true that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> gains from successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, the degree to which such a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> actually benefits has much to do with its internal manufacturing choices. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> that has done little to change its internal practices may end up simply ‚Äúholding the bag‚Äù of a retailer‚Äôs inventory. Alternatively, an adept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> who uses information for planning, production, and distribution may well share in the competitive advantages derived from better information on the true state of final customer demand.
This chapter examines the reasons that different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> win and lose, reviewing many of the innovations we have discussed throughout<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX> Drawing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCTAR</ENAMEX> survey, we first look at the way apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> adopt combinations of information and manufacturing practices in response to lean retailing<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> We then show how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">supplier</ENAMEX> performance, ranging from the degree of inventory risk to profitability, is changed by their information technology investments and the sequence in which they are adopted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> concludes with a more general discussion of what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> in information-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> must do to succeed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clusters of Supplier Practices: One Innovation Is Not Enough</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lean</ENAMEX> retailing allows department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, mass merchandisers, and other retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> to capitalize on information, allowing them to minimize their exposure to demand uncertainty. Retail adoption of these strategies, in turn, means <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> must invest in a basic set of technologies to provide the information links necessary for rapid replenishment. These investments consist of the capacity to receive and transmit information electronically‚Äîthe minimum set of practices required for working with lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>.
In addition, apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> must invest in technology and capital improvements to package, label, route, and move products rapidly from their production <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>. Once again, these capital expenditures represent a basic cost of doing business in a lean world. As detailed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 5</ENAMEX>, our research indicates that the prevalence of information technologies, advanced distribution and logistics operations, along with the other related services apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> provide to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> have grown dramatically since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, particularly among business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> that supply a large percentage of lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>.
Last but not least, responding to lean retailing requirements ultimately necessitates much more sophisticated demand forecasting, production planning, and manufacturing strategies than the practices employed by traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> extreme, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> can simply hold inventory for lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and make few changes in its internal practices. At the other end of the spectrum, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> can alter its internal design, planning, procurement, and manufacturing operations and respond rapidly to demand changes through the use of flexible manufacturing or sourcing practices.
Determining the degree to which a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> benefits from its technological investments is the real issue. Although there are no easy formulas, it does appear that the specific combinations of information technology and assembly methods drawn on by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> make a difference in responding to lean retail requirements. In order to study performance we must first examine how different manufacturing practices fit together for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>. In this section, we will discuss the interaction of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> information and manufacturing practices related to apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers‚</ENAMEX>Äô ability to provide products in a lean retailing world. These key practices affect how apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> acquire and use information concerning demand at the SKU level.
Note that the information and manufacturing practices examined here are not specific to the apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industry‚</ENAMEX>Äîin fact, most were originally introduced in other sectors‚Äîbut are applicable to a wide variety of consumer product industries. We focus on the retail-apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCTAR‚</ENAMEX>Äôs surveys provide extensive evidence for the ways in which apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> are changing. Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> will not make the specific operational changes of an apparel-maker, an increasing number are establishing information links with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel players</ENAMEX> and combining information use with technologies and work practices to speed up order processing. For example, textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that supply <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> directly with their own products may have to combine equivalent information technologies with manufacturing innovations in finishing lines that shorten production cycles in order to gain competitive advantage. Much of what we have learned about the determinants of success for apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> can be applied to comparable situations faced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> in other retail-driven industries.
Key Practice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bar Codes</ENAMEX>
The adoption of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Uniform Product Code</ENAMEX> (UPC) provides unique, optically scannable bar codes for identifying products at the SKU level. The availability of a standardized system of classification gives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> the means to input, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, transmit, and access information concerning demand inexpensively. Use of the UPC bar code system has the potential for significantly decreasing transaction costs with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. Adopting bar codes, of course, requires a variety of technological investments by business units‚Äîin bar code <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, hand scanners, computer hardware and software‚Äîand conventions, such as those promulgated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uniform Product Council</ENAMEX>. Even so, use of bar codes has become the norm for apparel<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>; to date, few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel partners</ENAMEX> have failed to make this change.
Key Practice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electronic Data</ENAMEX> Interchange
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> basic practice involves the use of electronic data interchange (EDI) as a means for transmitting data on orders between apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. Like bar codes, the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX> requires a set of investments by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> in computer technologies capable of sending and receiving data rapidly. It also depends on conventions that standardize the system of data interchange, including payment mechanisms. While many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel players</ENAMEX> have adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX>, it also represents an area of evolving practice; the amount of information that can be transmitted between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> has grown at the same time that the costs of transmission have fallen.
Key Practice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Labeling of Shipping Containers</ENAMEX>
Marking cartons and containers for shipment according to channel-wide standards can speed up distribution. Modern distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> are capable of rapidly identifying and sorting incoming shipments from all suppliers‚Äîwhether apparel<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX>, textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, or grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers‚</ENAMEX>Äîthrough the use of scanning systems, automated sorting and conveyer systems, and computer controls. At the same time, these systems use the information on container labels to process and reconcile invoice information on incoming and outgoing shipments. This means incoming shipments must adhere to a set of technological and process standards regarding the use of bar codes for labeling cartons in addition to other standards for packing, labeling, placement, shipping, and display of products.
Key Practice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modular Assembly</ENAMEX>
Finally, apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> can make innovations in the assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> through modular, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>-based, production. Instead of breaking up sewing into a long series of small steps, modular production entails grouping tasks and assigning them to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to reduce the elapsed throughput time required for assembling a given product. Adoption of this assembly technique involves altering the physical layout of sewing machines as well as human resource changes in training requirements, compensation systems, and methods of supervision. As <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 7</ENAMEX> stressed, modular production need not be adopted for all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>; it makes most sense for products that require rapid replenishment, where the capacity to engage in short-cycle production matters. In particular, retaining some short-cycle capacity may be advantageous for production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> with higher levels of demand variation, whether because of fashion content or uncommon size‚Äîthat is, for garments that have unique design elements or are in a size few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> wear<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Combining Key Practices</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Firms</ENAMEX> responding to frequent purchase-order requests from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> benefit from combining these practices<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX> At the simplest level, the benefits of adopting a uniform system of production identification are reinforced by the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX> transmission of information, which lowers the cost of moving data between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel partners</ENAMEX>. Business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> adopting both bar codes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX> are therefore able to reduce the transaction costs for processing information about sales and orders.
When bar codes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX> are combined with advanced shipping practices, the benefit of each practice is enhanced; order processing occurs more rapidly, accurately, and with less paper. The standardized shipping container <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">marker‚</ENAMEX>Äîwhich is possible only because of the existence of bar codes in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place‚Äîprovides a scannable description of a carton that can be electronically associated with data files containing specific information on the individual products shipped to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>. This information, sent via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX>, can then be used to check incoming orders against purchase orders and authorize payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>. It can also rapidly identify discrepancies between invoices and actual shipments, once again lowering the cost of the transaction for both parties.
Meanwhile, modular production allows apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> to reduce the time required for a given product to move through the assembly process. For instance, by substantially reducing work-in-process buffers in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>, throughput time on the modular lines of business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in the HCTAR sample dropped to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two days</TIMEX>, compared with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine days</TIMEX> for standard assembly methods. But the benefits of throughput-time reduction cannot be fully realized unless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are rewarded for their ability to replenish rapidly. Rapid replenishment, in turn, requires the availability of detailed demand data and its frequent and accurate transmission. Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> must be capable of using this data to allocate production capacity between short-cycle (modular) and standard (progressive bundle system) production lines. In this way, modular assembly systems only yield real advantages in the presence of the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> practices.
In particular, advanced practices in distribution and modular production interact with each other because they both reduce throughput time. The time saved in production can be lost if the distribution method is slow, or if there are other impediments to the movement of products from the apparel-maker to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>. Alternatively, distri-bution operations that efficiently process finished products reinforce the benefits of a team-based assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX>. One extreme case illustrates the importance of fit between these performance elements. A men‚Äôs trousers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX> invested in modular production in some of its lines to reduce throughput times. Yet it left its distribution practices unchanged. The plant required that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> be filled before making deliveries, which often meant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> of production would build up. In other words, the savings created in throughput reduction in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> were lost on the shipping dock.
What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clustering Looks Like in the Real World</ENAMEX>
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCTAR</ENAMEX> survey, apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> do seem to invest in clusters of practices arising from the joint benefits of adoption. Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14.1</NUMEX> shows that combinations of practices increased quite dramatically <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1988 and 1992</TIMEX>.
For example, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, joint adoption of bar codes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX> systems was uncommon: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 25.2 percent</NUMEX> of business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> had adopted both, while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46.8 percent</NUMEX> had adopted neither. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> of the business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> had implemented both bar codes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX> technologies, while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 8.0 percent</NUMEX> had neither in place. Similar patterns of increased adoption can be seen among other combinations of these practices in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 14.1</ENAMEX>.
The mere fact that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> practices have been adopted, however, does not tell the whole story. The changing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of the retail and apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> also suggests that there is a particular sequence for adopting the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> key practices. To begin with, the adoption of bar codes came before rapid replenishment arrangements because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> required a low-cost means of collecting information at the detailed product level for their own use‚Äîthat is, they first developed an efficient method for scanning prices at the check-out register and tracking products for internal inventory purposes. Only after a common convention for bar codes had been established and in use for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> turn to such systems to transmit and receive data from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>.
Indeed, the use of bar codes, followed by implementation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX> systems, provides the basic foundation for subsequent investments in efficient logistics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> in retail distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Retailers</ENAMEX> do not get much out of investing in advanced distribution technologies, such as shipping container <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">markers</ENAMEX>, if they lack a means for electronically identifying and using information concerning the contents of incoming shipments or of connecting that information back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> for invoicing purposes. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> get little return out of providing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> with standardized shipping container <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">markers</ENAMEX> if neither of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel players</ENAMEX> has made previous investments in bar codes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX>.
As we detailed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 10</ENAMEX>, changing the method of production to reduce manufacturing throughput times also makes little sense if a business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> has not first invested in the necessary information links for carrying on rapid replenishment relationships. From an apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier‚</ENAMEX>Äôs perspective, the benefits of adopting shipping container <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">markers</ENAMEX> and modular production are much higher once bar codes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX> are in place.
In fact, our analysis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCTAR</ENAMEX> data shows that the probability of adopting shipping container <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">markers</ENAMEX> and modular production significantly increases if both bar codes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX> have already been implemented<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX> The probability of adopting shipping container <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">markers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, given that bar codes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX> had been adopted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77 percent</NUMEX> compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 47 percent</NUMEX> if bar codes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX> were not both present. Similarly, the probability of adopting modular systems in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">54 percent</NUMEX> compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> if bar codes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX> were not both present<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX>
From <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Supplier Practice to Performance Results</ENAMEX>
Once these manufacturing and information practices have been adopted, it should come as no surprise that they affect the performance of business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. Based on our survey research, we found that implementing a combination of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> key practices‚Äîbar codes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX>, advanced shipping systems, and modular assembly‚Äîincreases business-unit performance because these practices interact with and reinforce one another. This is sometimes described as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúcomplementarities‚Äù</ENAMEX> between practices. The specific sequence of adoption should also affect performance outcomes.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> types of performance measures are of interest in this regard. The first pertains to operational performance, or the ability of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> to respond to lean retailing replenishment requirements. Successful performance includes providing high levels of order completeness, short lead times for new products, and rapid response to requests for replenishment. However, operational performance measures do not necessarily provide a direct financial return to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> beyond allowing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> to continue supplying a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> with these service requirements. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> set of outcomes relates to the financial performance of the business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> itself. These include impacts on its revenues (prices and sales), cost structures, and profitability. Financial performance encompasses the impact of the supplier‚Äôs manufacturing investments on its inventory levels, which directly affects the business unit‚Äôs costs and the degree of risk it bears from holding high finished goods or work-in-process inventories.
From the perspective of operational performance, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> with different degrees of investment in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> practices may do equally well in the short run. But their financial performance, as measured by inventory levels or profitability, may differ substantially. As we have emphasized in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> chapters, an apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> that meets a lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">retailer‚Äôs</ENAMEX> replenishment requirements while optimizing the level of inventories it holds per <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> will be exposed to less risk than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that meets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> requirements by simply holding larger stocks of inventories.
Retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Replenishment Performance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> now have much higher standards than they did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier years</TIMEX> for the accuracy and timeliness of order fulfillment. Our studies of business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> with differing levels of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> practices indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> with the complete set of practices achieve similar or slightly better performance in regard to the percentage of goods delivered complete and on time, although these differences between business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> are not very dramatic<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX> This is to be expected, given the high penalties faced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> for violation of these standards<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,9</NUMEX> and the fact that retail standards may be met without extensive changes to internal apparel production practices.
In contrast, more innovative business units‚Äîthose that have adopted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> of the key practices‚Äîare able to replenish products more rapidly than less innovative ones. We have observed this in a number of different ways. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, the mean response time for replenishing products that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> had agreed to provide on this basis was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2.9 weeks</TIMEX> among those business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> that had adopted none of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> practices. But the average replenishment interval was only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1.3 weeks</TIMEX> for those that had adopted all the key practices. These performance differences persist even after controlling for other characteristics of business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, such as size and product mix, which might also be associated with replenishment speed and technology adoption<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.10</NUMEX> The results are particularly striking, given that only the most demanding lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> required replenishment within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> of order placement.
Lead times provide another measure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> responsiveness. Lead time is calculated as the number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> required for an apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> to procure textiles, manufacture, and deliver a typical product in its collection. The total time includes the number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> it takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> to order and receive fabric, make the marker, cut the fabric, sew the pieces, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> and package the product, ship it to a distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, and, finally, process it at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. The shorter the lead time, the more quickly a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> is able to deliver products to retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. Based on our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> survey, we estimated lead times for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different scenarios: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äústandard‚</ENAMEX>Äù lead times that represent performance for a typical product in the supplier‚Äôs selection and ‚Äúshortest‚Äù lead times that indicate a supplier‚Äôs best practice. Both measures were for products manufactured domestically.
As shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14.1</NUMEX>, those business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> that invested in a more complete set of innovative practices had significantly shorter lead times for standard products. The total elapsed standard lead time for business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> with little innovation in practice averaged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">172</NUMEX> calendar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> compared with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 117 days</TIMEX> for those that had invested in bar codes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX>. Even more striking, lead time dropped to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just 66 days</TIMEX> among those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> that had adopted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> practices.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14.1</NUMEX> suggests that the most innovative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are able to produce and deliver their products in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than half</NUMEX> the time of the least innovative apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>. Of course, other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> characteristics, such as business-unit size or product type, might also be correlated with adoption of innovative practices and performance outcomes. Even after we control for these factors using multiple regression techniques, the number of innovative practices adopted by business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> have a statistically significant positive effect on lead time<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inventory Performance</ENAMEX>
Throughout, we have argued that reducing the substantial risk presented by inventory, particularly in the presence of ever-increasing product proliferation, is essential for improving a manufacturer‚Äôs performance in integrated retail-apparel-textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>. That means inventory performance measures are crucial to determining the impact of information technology and flexible manufacturing. In this case, we draw on a unique, matched data set that combines the HCTAR sample results with detailed microdata collected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Commerce</ENAMEX>.12
Specifically, we matched data from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCTAR</ENAMEX> survey to corresponding establishment-level data from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Commerce‚Äôs Longitudinal Research Database</ENAMEX> (LRD). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRD</ENAMEX> provides longitudinal data for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX> included in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of the Census Annual Survey of Manufacturing</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13</NUMEX> To understand the relationship between technology adoption and inventory levels, we matched survey data on adoption decisions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> with inventory observations for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1988‚Äì91</NUMEX> period and adoption decisions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> with inventory observations for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1992‚Äì94</NUMEX> period.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> common way of measuring inventory is to calculate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I/S</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ratio‚</ENAMEX>Äîthat is, the ratio of total finished good inventories to total sales. This measure allows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to compare inventories in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> with different sales volumes. We calculated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I/S</ENAMEX> ratio for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> in our matched sample and then compared those with the ratios of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> that used different combinations of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> manufacturing practices. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14.2</NUMEX> illustrates the impact of manufacturing practices on average inventory levels.
The average I/S ratio fell considerably as business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> adopted more of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> key technologies during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">both time</TIMEX> periods under study. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1988‚Äì91</TIMEX> period, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that adopted none of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> technologies had an average I/S ratio of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.9</NUMEX>, while those that implemented bar codes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX>, and either advanced shipping container <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">markers</ENAMEX> or modular assembly‚Äîor both‚Äîhad an average I/S ratio of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 1.1.14</NUMEX> What is more, these differences between low- and high-level adopters grew dramatically by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1992‚Äì94</NUMEX> period, in which the low-technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> had more than twice the inventory/sales ratio‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äî2.46</NUMEX> compared with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just 1.22</NUMEX> for the high-level adopters<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.15</NUMEX>
A reduction in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I/S</ENAMEX> ratio means that changes in sales will be matched by smaller changes in inventories. Therefore, a lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I/S</ENAMEX> ratio implies lower inventory volatility or variation<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.16</NUMEX> This, in turn, suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> with more of the key technologies in place will have total inventories that are less volatile. One method of capturing volatility is to look at the standard deviation of each establishment‚Äôs inventory level and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I/S</ENAMEX> ratio for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> time periods<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.17</NUMEX> Based on this measure, inventory volatility did not decrease with more technology adoption <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1988 and 1991</TIMEX>. However, by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1992‚Äì94</NUMEX> period, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> technologies had lower standard deviations in total inventories compared with less technically innovative ones.This impact on volatility is even more striking when examining variation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I/S</ENAMEX> ratios for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1992‚Äì1994</NUMEX> period (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14.3</NUMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> deviations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I/S</ENAMEX> ratio of business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> with low levels of adoption were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.22</NUMEX> compared with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only .50</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> that had implemented all the manufacturing practices by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. Note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I/S</ENAMEX> standard deviations control for differences in firm size. And these results remain even after controlling for other factors, such as product diversity, that may be related to both inventories and the adoption of modern manufacturing practices by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>.18
Adopting more of these practices also decreases the growth of inventory levels. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14.4</NUMEX> shows the comparative growth rates in inventories from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992 to 1994</TIMEX> for business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> with low, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>, and high technology levels. Adjusting for inflation and other factors that affect inventory growth, we found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX> with low levels of technology adoption in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> experienced far higher annual growth rates in total inventories and I/S ratios than those with a more complete set of innovative practices. This confirms the fact that apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> investing in both information technology and short-cycle production capacity can move to lower inventory levels more quickly.19
The implications of these findings are significant. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> attempting to meet the rigorous standards of a lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">retailer‚</ENAMEX>Äîwhether a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt manufacturer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pasta-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph‚Äôs Food</ENAMEX>, or an electronic drill <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Depot‚</ENAMEX>Äîmust hold a far larger amount of inventory if it has not invested in a comprehensive set of information technology and short-cycle production capacity. As the next section demonstrates, holding larger inventories to service lean retailing demand translates into diminished profitability.
Impact on Profitability
Imagine <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> men‚Äôs dress<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-shirt suppliers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> still operates traditionally, except for the implementation of basic information links to receive orders from lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. The other maintains extensive information systems, which allow it to send, receive, and process information on retail demand, orders, and shipments; advanced information technology also helps it plan manufacturing capacity so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> can engage in short-cycle production. Although the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt supplier</ENAMEX> can respond to retailers‚Äô <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> orders in a timely manner, its costs for doing so are high, both in terms of the internal expense of transacting frequent orders and its increased exposure to the risk posed by holding inventory. It costs the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> less, however, to transact <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> because of the electronic systems it has in place. In addition, its capacity to use information on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of demand allows it to set inventory levels on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> basis that balances the benefits of having a product available against the costs of holding work-in-process and finished goods inventories.
As a result of these differences, we expect that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> dress-shirt supplier‚Äôs financial performance will be decidedly better than that of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> over the long run. Our survey evidence confirms this expectation. Consider the frequency with which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> reduce the price of their product for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> during the selling season. Apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> in our survey that had adopted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> of the key information and manufacturing practices reported fewer price markdowns by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> than those with few or none of the practices<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Therefore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> that work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> employing a more complete set of information, distribution, and manufacturing innovations need not eliminate as many of their unsold products at the end of season via price reductions.
Manufacturing markdowns to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> provide more direct evidence of the benefits of these innovative practices. Those business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> that had adopted all the practices reported an average discount provided to retail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 4.3 percent</NUMEX>, compared with an average discount of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22.2 percent</NUMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> that had implemented none of them. Although these differences cannot all be directly attributed to the adoption of the practices per se, they do suggest‚Äîespecially when combined with the significant inventory performance results reported previously‚Äîhow important it is for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to be adept at using incoming information from lean retailing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>.21
The real question, then, is how do these factors together affect the bottom line? And do business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> with the more complete set of innovative technologies have higher profitability? Here the answer is a definite yes. Profitability is measured as operating profit margin‚Äîrevenue minus costs of goods sold divided by revenue. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14.5</NUMEX> shows our basic results in regard to average profit margin for different levels of technology adoption. Business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> that did not adopt any of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> key practices earned the lowest profit margins, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 3 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. The most innovative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately four</NUMEX> times as profitable, achieving average profit margins of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11.7 percent</NUMEX>.
Even after controlling for the independent effects of firm size, product mix, and distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> on performance, we found that the most innovative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> were significantly more profitable than those that had adopted fewer of the key practices. In our sample, adding shipping-container <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">markers</ENAMEX> to established bar code and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDI</ENAMEX> practices increased operating profits by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2</NUMEX> percent‚Äîthat is, from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 6.2 percent</NUMEX> in average profit margins to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.4 percent</NUMEX>; adding some modular assembly capacity to these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> practices increased operating profits by about the same amount<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.22</NUMEX>
Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCTAR‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> survey, informal case evidence suggests that these disparities in operating and financial performance have only grown larger, as lean retailing continues to sweep across distribution channels. The least innovative apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> are seeing their chances for survival dwindle <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>. In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> that have continued to innovate and expand their use of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> practices, as well as other activities described in previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>, keep outperforming the industry as a whole.
Management <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Practice: The Final Ingredient in Enhanced Performance</ENAMEX>
The upshot of all this is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> need not hold the bag for lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> if they adopt a set of technologies and practices that allow them to collect and process demand information, incorporate it into planning, and use traditional and short-cycle production strategically. Simply doing business with lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> in no way confers competitive success. In fact, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> that attempts to provide rapid replenishment without any other innovations may end up performing poorly from the perspective of its retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. More important, it will sustain higher costs in inventories, face a greater need to mark down the prices of its products, and therefore earn a lower profit margin than those establishments that have invested in comprehensive changes.
Of course, becoming an advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> is not just a matter of buying more information technologies or setting up a short-cycle assembly line. The essential force behind the performance impact of these practices is their effective integration with one another. Integration does not arise from hardware or software purchases. It comes from successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>.
We have already described some specific ways that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> can think about integration of new information technologies and manufacturing practices. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 7</ENAMEX> presented <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> production planning cases. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> indicated how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> must assess a product line according to the variance in demand for particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> in setting inventory policies. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> case developed how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> must use this new perspective on demand to plan production or sourcing strategies. Both cases illustrate the necessity of creating managerial practices that explicitly link the data arising from information technology with changes in manufacturing practices to take full advantage of these innovations.
A contemporary apparel-maker, handling on average <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> in its collection, faces the challenge of replenishing weekly numerous retail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> at high satisfaction levels with a constantly shifting subset of its goods. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managers</ENAMEX> of such a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> must do so by drawing on information from the past weeks‚Äô sales as well as explicitly factoring in the impact of uncertainty. They need real-time information regarding what goods their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> have in finished, work-in-process, and material inventories. They must know the lead-time requirements for procuring textile products and establish relationships with at least some textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> that allow the apparel-maker to procure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX> in smaller quantities and with shorter lead times. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> must draw on production lines and sourcing arrangements that provide it with a range of response times, from short-cycle production capacity for products with high demand variability to lines or sourcing arrangements that create larger production runs at lower costs for items with low demand variability. But most important, it must have a managerial system capable of coordinating these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> on an ongoing basis.
Based on our observations of apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>, coming up with the money for new technologies and practices seems to be less of an impediment than altering basic management conceptions about using these technologies for planning and production. Many of the business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in our sample have adopted specific practices without changing their approach to using them together to compete in an integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. They continue to draw on traditional conceptions of planning, production, and sourcing‚Äîin other words, they still think in terms of large orders of their products, placed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> before delivery is expected. Needless to say, these business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> have not fully benefited from the investments they have made.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Suppliers</ENAMEX> in most consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> now face lean retailing pressures or its equivalent. Many are taking steps to adapt to the changed requirements placed on them. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> example is the restructuring beginning to appear in automobile distribution. Traditional auto retailing focuses on selling product lines in production quantities that were largely determined in advance of distribution. The system therefore placed tremendous pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">auto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> to sell the enormous finished goods inventory found in a car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX>. In contrast to this traditional retailing model, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> announced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> an effort to restructure its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> by allowing consumer customization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> purchases through the use of multimedia computer systems. By allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to design their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> hope to reduce their finished goods inventories<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.23</NUMEX>
Note that this system poses production questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> similar to those faced by apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will need to decide which auto <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> (or subassemblies) to produce using traditional assembly techniques and which to produce with short-cycle production methods. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> will also need to combine information technologies, planning and forecasting methods, and production techniques to implement such strategies<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.24</NUMEX> Similar pressure to innovate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobile distri-bution</ENAMEX> and production is also increasing because of the emergence of new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Car Max Auto Superstores</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Auto Group</ENAMEX>, which operate under principles more akin to lean retailing<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.25</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> examples from the computer industry further illustrate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> approaches that integrate information technology and manufacturing decisions. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>, facing product proliferation and replenishment requirements for its laser<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-jet</ENAMEX> printing products, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett Packard</ENAMEX> redesigned its manufacturing process for printers. It did so by separating those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subassembly</ENAMEX> processes that were standard across products from those that were distinctive to specific laser<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-jet</ENAMEX> products. By using incoming demand information in concert with this subassembly and assembly redesign, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett Packard</ENAMEX> can now assemble different products with shorter lead times in response to actual information concerning demand; at the same time it continues to take advantage of scale efficiencies in production. The resulting inventory and production policies allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett Packard</ENAMEX> to balance the costs of stock-outs with those of unsold inventories<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.26</NUMEX>
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq Computer</ENAMEX>, the world‚Äôs largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of personal computers, announced a plan to change relations with its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX>. Compaq‚Äôs main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell Computer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gateway 2000</ENAMEX>, sell directly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> through mail-order and Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> sells its products through computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>. Technological advances and rapid diffusion of older technologies make personal computers extremely perishable‚Äîmuch like apparel with a fashion content‚Äîand subject to almost constant price markdown pressure. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX>, like other personal computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, provides its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX> price guarantees on purchased inventories (i.e., it reimburses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributor</ENAMEX> if it must mark down prices in response to falling memory or other costs), its inventory carrying costs are significant.
Rather than continuing to increase inventory, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> announced that it would only assemble its new line of personal computers as its retail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> ordered them. And, instead of providing an open-ended guarantee on prices to its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would guarantee the price for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two weeks</TIMEX> after purchase by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributor</ENAMEX>, refusing to take back computers unless they malfunctioned. By changing its method of distributing products, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> hopes to reduce the level of dealer inventory across product lines to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">weeks‚Äô</ENAMEX> worth and in the process save <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> or more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. These cost savings will be used to reduce prices and compete more aggressively with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gateway 2000</ENAMEX> that do not work through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.27</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Therefore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq‚</ENAMEX>Äôs competitive strategy arises from its efforts to advance information-integration forward in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> in which it operates<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.28</NUMEX> Note also that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> seeks to take full advantage of these changes in distribution, it must also adjust its production strategies to account for differences in demand variability across the computer maker‚Äôs product lines.
In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in myriad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> are grappling with the same managerial challenges and opportunities of those in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> apparel and textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX>. Rethinking how to service stringent retail replenishment requirements for ever broadening product lines in more selling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX> has become a central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> challenge.
The implications of these changes do not end here. An economy consisting of lean retailing and corresponding ‚Äúlean‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> operates in a fundamentally different manner from one based on traditional retailing and supply practices. The industrial transformation currently in progress encompasses international trade issues, competitiveness, labor regulation, and macroeconomic policies. Accordingly, the last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> of this book is devoted to our reflections on the impact of channel integration on certain public policy issues.



