



More than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century ago</TIMEX> a major wave of innovations in distribution and production led to the modern department store, the mail-order <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain store</ENAMEX>, and reshaped their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>. The present transformation of retail and manufacturing engendered by new information technologies, production methods, and management practices also fundamentally alters the manner in which industries and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> take raw materials, turn them into a profusion of products, and deliver them to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. Although these developments are very much a work in progress, information-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> of production and distribution are emerging.
Such channels are not unique to retail-apparel-textile relations but have arisen in a wide variety of consumer product industries in which retailing practices are undergoing similar changes. The developments reported here offer a prototype of the new links among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>.
In fact, the transformation has been gradual and is still under way. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only as recently as the mid-1990s</TIMEX> has integration risen to critical levels, providing a clear picture of what channel relations will look like in the future. Information integration has reshaped much of the retail-apparel-textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, yet further transformation is likely in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade ahead</TIMEX>, not only for these linked industries, but for consumer product sectors in general.
In this final chapter, we step back to survey the ways in which information-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> will affect the public and private sectors. The pervasive changes arising from lean retailing challenge the conventional wisdom about the future of international trade, labor standards, employment, and even macroeconomic fluctuations. At the same time, these changes alter the nature of competitive strategy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that supply lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> in apparel, textile, and other industries.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade</ENAMEX> Issues: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New International Economics</ENAMEX>
[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>]e estimate that national income would improve if quotas and tariffs were eliminated because the cost to the economy of protecting each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> with import restraints exceeds the wage the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> is paid ... [F]or textiles the cost per job protected is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,200</NUMEX> while wages are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX>; for apparel the cost per job is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37,500</NUMEX> while wages are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14,000.1</NUMEX>
We want the world to know how strongly we oppose NAFTA expansion and fast track<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄîJohn J. Sweeney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>
These quotations aptly reflect the continuing controversy over international trade policies. The apparel and textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> have played a central role in trade discussions since the inception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, just as they have in other developing and developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> throughout the world. These industries have often been chosen as the means for building manufacturing capacity in the developing world; at the same time they have been the recipient of trade protection in developed economies. More to our point, information integration has added a new dimension to these long-standing controversies.
The textile and apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> have often been intertwined in public policy discussions about international trade, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uruguay</ENAMEX> round of trade negotiations, the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> and its labor side-accords, the renewal of fast-track negotiating authority, imports from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and human rights standards, and so on. This stream of general debate, however, is seldom related to a detailed study or analysis of the impact of such developments on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> textile or apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX>.
From the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ricardo</ENAMEX> down through the writings of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hechscher-Ohlin</ENAMEX>, economic analysis has been devoted to the consequences of trade restraints in the form of quotas, tariffs, and nontariff barriers on output, employment, and prices. Traditional international economics attributes trade to comparative advantage, relative labor costs, and the relative costs of logistics and transportation. A ‚Äúnew international economics‚Äù in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX> has stressed that much global trade actually reflects, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> puts it, ‚ÄúNational advantages that are created by historical circumstance‚Äù rather than natural resources. ‚ÄúBecause comparative advantage is often created, not given, a temporary subsidy can lead to a permanent industry.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù3</ENAMEX> Note that these economic analyses and policy prescriptions have been applied generally and are not focused on particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> like textiles or apparel.
In any case, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, such debates about the impact of international trade policy have been placed in a new economic context. Increasingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> and public policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> discuss trade issue in terms of the emergence of a significant and growing inequality in compensation between production and nonsupervisory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, on the one hand, and managerial, supervisory, or exempt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> on the other. These differences include a larger disparity in compensation between those highly educated and those who are not, particularly high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dropouts</ENAMEX>. In addition, there has been an appreciable growth in relatively unskilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">localities</ENAMEX> such as major metropolitan areas around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.4 The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Report</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, reporting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colloquium</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Bank of New York</ENAMEX>, attributes the growth of inequality to the following: technological change (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent</NUMEX>), international trade (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX>), a decline in the real minimum wage (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>), rising immigration (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX>), and other factors (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX>
Although such analysis and policy discussions have not singled out specific industries, the nature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">occupational structure</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> in textiles and apparel‚Äîparticularly the latter sector‚Äîmakes the general discussion relevant to these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> industries. It would appear that neither the market imports of textiles nor the immigration of low-skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> has had an appreciable negative impact on the wages of the textile industry or its major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX>. The average <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> earnings of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> products (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">SIC 22</NUMEX>) went from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.66</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10.02</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1997‚</NUMEX>Äîan increase of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">115 percent</NUMEX> and more than the increase in all manufacturing or nondurable manufacturing. This relative wage increase in textiles took place despite its concentration in a low-wage region‚Äîthe southeastern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> states‚Äîthe low level of collective bargaining, and the higher-than-average percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women workers</ENAMEX>.
But the experience in apparel is less categorical, especially because of the differential impact on various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> of apparel and other textile products (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">SIC 23</NUMEX>). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, the average <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> earnings of apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.25</NUMEX>. On the high end, automotive and apparel trimmings (SIC <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2396</TIMEX>) averaged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.36</NUMEX>; on the low end, women‚Äôs and misses‚Äô blouses and skirts (SIC <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2331</TIMEX>) averaged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.01</NUMEX>. Correspondingly, employment in automotive and apparel trimmings increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71.4 percent</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979 to 1997</TIMEX> while in women‚Äôs and misses blouses and skirts it declined by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60.6 percent</NUMEX> in the same period. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX> in mind, however, that blast furnaces and steel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX> (SIC <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3312</TIMEX>) declined in employment from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">478,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">163,300</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. This <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65.9 percent</NUMEX> decline from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979 to 1997</TIMEX> compares with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31.3 percent</NUMEX> drop for textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> products and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37.6 percent</NUMEX> for all apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.
Still, there can be little doubt that in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">women‚Äôs</ENAMEX> and misses blouses and skirts, in which employment is concentrated in small contract <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, import competition from low-wage developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and unskilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> have contributed to its deterioration. Moreover, the failure to comply with federal and state employment statutes relating to minimum wages, overtime rates, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> labor, uncovered in periodic enforcement forays, have contributed to the decline of this sector.
The general analysis of the consequences of trade and immigration in the textile and apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> clearly requires a much more focused application to detailed sectors to provide reliable conclusions. Moreover, and as this volume indicates, the offsetting influences of lean retailing and short-cycle production in comparison with low foreign labor rates must be evaluated by product demand variability, rather than simply making generalizations about aggregate trade and immigration. For instance, the information-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> in retail-apparel-textile are having some of their most significant impact on sourcing among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>, domestic and foreign. The low labor costs for sewing and short time to market from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, and the provisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Harmonized Tariff Schedule</ENAMEX> (formerly Section 807 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">807a</ENAMEX>, or currently <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9802.00.80</NUMEX>) that establish duties only on the value added to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-produced materials sent out for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>, all favor sourcing of apparel from south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> border rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. International Trade Commission</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚ÄúU</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.</ENAMEX> imports of textiles and apparel from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the traditional Big Three <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> suppliers‚<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ÄîHong Kong</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Korea‚</ENAMEX>Äîcontinued to decline in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, when these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> together with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23.4 percent</NUMEX> of total sector trade, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38.5 percent</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1991.‚</NUMEX>Äù6
The information-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> developed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, which are now influencing sourcing patterns from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean Basin</ENAMEX>, have begun to affect the textile and apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> worldwide. For many fashion apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">products‚</ENAMEX>Äîdefined as those planned to last <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only one season‚Äîthe</NUMEX> practice of sourcing on the basis of lowest labor costs may be expected to continue. Indeed, much of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> sourcing has been devoted to such items, with production shifting within <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">regions</ENAMEX> where wage levels have risen. But for basic and fashion basic apparel products, for which frequent replenishment orders are becoming the norm, the practice of sourcing some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> and sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> from nearby lower wage regions and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> is emerging. At the same time, design, distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, marketing‚Äîeven cutting‚Äîas well as some short-cycle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> remain in the market region.
As we pointed out in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 13</ENAMEX>, regionalization of apparel production in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> main areas has started to occur. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> market, most sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> take place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean Basin</ENAMEX>; in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, sewing operations go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Africa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX>; and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, sewing operations go to various <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX>. The formal analysis in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 7</ENAMEX> specified the factors that determine whether production of items under rapid replenishment policies should be done domestically or outsourced to low wage <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
For textiles, with their high capital costs, lower labor content, and emphasis on high quality and finishing operations, the concentration in the southeastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, and industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> may be expected largely to continue. But the longer term viability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> will depend on the development of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">infrastructures</ENAMEX> capable of supporting advanced textile production in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> market, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and elsewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Macroeconomic Implications: Inventories, Business Cycles</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Price Levels</ENAMEX>
In an information-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, the historic market relationships between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> change significantly. It is true that textiles <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> still sell to apparel<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX>, which in turn sell to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, which ultimately sell to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. Markets certainly have not disappeared, but these relationships have been transformed. Different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel players</ENAMEX> now share detailed information on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> sales; investments in technologies mutually benefit both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>; and because of the effective use of information and manufacturing technologies, risk has been reduced across the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. The adoption of standards in the supply <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, such as those that specify packaging, labeling, and marking of products, have reduced further time to market and enhanced efficiencies; this expedites transit and ensures floor-ready merchandise for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> at the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>. As a result, the traditional boundary lines between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are blurring as the cost of transacting business within and across industries falls dramatically<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX> Note that the technologies and standards that made these information-integrated channels possible were a product of private-sector <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">activities‚</ENAMEX>Äîindividual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>, trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>, and consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. The fundamental standards of product identification through bar codes and related technologies have become compatible worldwide without the prescription or regulation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Standards</ENAMEX> or government regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
Falling transaction costs between sectors allow an economy to increase the total output of goods and services it can produce for a given set of resource inputs<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX> The dramatic decrease in transaction costs across many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> parallels the wide-scale changes at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the last century</TIMEX>, which, in the words of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Chandler</ENAMEX>, reduced ‚Äúthe number of transactions involved in the flow of goods, increased the speed and regularity of the flow, and so lowered costs and improved the productivity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> distribution system.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù9 Yet it often takes time for an economy to reflect the impact of such fundamental shifts. In fact, the current combination of changes in information technology, management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>, and manufacturing strategy may be one of the places where the impact of computers on the economy has been hidden until recently<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.10</NUMEX>
The falling costs of conducting business between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> may also explain why there has been relatively little vertical concentration across industries in the channel‚Äîno textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> have gone into the manufacture of apparel or retail and few apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> have set up their own retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>.11 Indeed, an effective information-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> probably works against vertical integration. Sharing information and current knowledge of the market across <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel players</ENAMEX> achieves some of the same objectives‚Äîat lower cost‚Äîof formally reaching forward or backward into markets. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprises</ENAMEX> in different parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> can therefore concentrate on their business strengths.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lean</ENAMEX> retailing and the restructuring of manufacturing supply have also affected the economy as a whole in the area of inventories. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lean</ENAMEX> retailing itself implies a dramatic reduction in the amount of inventory held by retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 14</ENAMEX> documents the large inventory reductions of apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> that draw fully on information technology in concert with new managerial and manufacturing practices; in some cases they have decreased inventory levels by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>.
The impact of these new policies on retailing and manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> may have begun to show up in economy-wide measures of inventory. The overall ratio of inventories to final sales of domestic business fell considerably in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>, from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.78</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.34</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1997.12</NUMEX> It has long been known that inventories at the macroeconomic level affect the depth and length of business cycles<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13</NUMEX> The connection between recent changes in inventory policy and the business cycle have only begun to be studied in a systematic fashion<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.14</NUMEX> As noted in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Report</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>,
Adoption of just-in-time inventory management by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> also represents a significant development, since changes in inventories have often been an important source of business-cycle fluctuations. Whether just-in-time inventories will be able to dampen future business cycles, however, remains to be seen<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.15</NUMEX>
Our work on apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> adjustments to lean retailing suggests that an economy characterized by an increasing level of modern manufacturing and retailing practices should experience lower levels of inventories relative to sales. Because a reduction in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I/S</ENAMEX> ratio means that changes in sales will be matched by a smaller change in inventories, a lower ratio also implies lower inventory volatility. This is important because aggregate inventory volatility has historically made up a significant portion of the volatility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gross Domestic Product</ENAMEX> (GDP). If the effects documented for retail-apparel-textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> are more pervasive across other sectors similarly affected by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> integration, these changes could imply lower GDP volatility. This macroeconomic link may prove to be the most profound implication of the adoption of firm-level information technology and manufacturing practices.
Fundamental changes in inventory policies in retail and manufacturing may significantly affect price levels as well. The increased volatility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> and consumer prices in a number of sectors since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> has been attributed in part to the adoption of new inventory polices related to lean retailing<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.16</NUMEX> Some have suggested a connection between these policies and price fluctuations<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.17</NUMEX> According to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> view, an information-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> may lead to increased volatility in aggregate prices because the impact of shifts in supply and demand is more rapidly reflected in consumer prices without the buffering impact of inventory. Competitive information-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> may also reduce aggregate price levels, as expressed by price markup policies that in the past have reflected the incomplete information of channel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>.18 Whatever the effect, the more widespread adoption of information-integrated channels documented in this book raise a central question for future models of industry- and macroeconomic-price movements<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.19</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Standards</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Problem</ENAMEX> of Sweatshops
The most effective weapon used by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> in weakening the power of organized labor has been to hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant workers</ENAMEX>....[I]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mmigrants</ENAMEX> are cheap and controllable. The conditions they toil under make a mockery of the already low <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> labor standards‚Äîthe most regressive among the advanced industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>.20
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a century</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> federal and state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> have investigated sweatshops in the garment industry, including the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, and have adopted legislation to ameliorate their impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the last century</TIMEX>, unsanitary conditions, in addition to low wages, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long hours</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> labor, were the biggest concerns. State <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> were authorized to attach a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚Äútenement-made‚</NUMEX>Äù tag to garments produced by violators. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumers‚Äô League</ENAMEX>, organized in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1899</TIMEX>, adopted a voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">label</ENAMEX> to be attached to garments made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> that abided by labor standards‚Äîthat is, they obeyed state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> laws, manufactured on their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX>, employed no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 16</TIMEX>, and used no <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overtime work.21</TIMEX>
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fair Labor Standards Act</ENAMEX> (FLSA) for industry generally specified minimum wage rates, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overtime</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">forty hours</TIMEX> of work per week, and a prohibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> labor. The so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúhot cargo‚Äù</ENAMEX> provisions of the statute, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 15</ENAMEX>, made it illegal to transport or sell goods in commerce produced in violation of the provisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>.22 Despite these strict legislated standards‚Äîwith wage levels updated from time to time‚Äîwidespread violations in apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">workplaces</ENAMEX> have become commonplace in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>. Labor conditions have deteriorated for a number of reasons: the decline in the coverage of collective bargaining agreements with their provisions for regulation of contract <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>; the difficulty of policing contributions for health and pension funds from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> in this sector; the increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, legal and illegal, concentrated in certain areas; the intense competition from imports; and the sharp drop in employment in apparel in some markets<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">.23 Sweatshops</ENAMEX>, it seems, have always been with us.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Monte</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> working behind barbed wire, caught the nation‚Äôs attention in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> reported in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> City‚Äôs garment industry violated overtime or minimum wage laws.24 The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Labor Department</ENAMEX> reports that independent surveys, as well as federal and state compliance data, show minimum wage and overtime violations of the FLSA occurring in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of investigated establishments. The policy question is what, if anything, can be done to control or eliminate sweatshops and noncompliance with statutory standards in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>? And what can be done to ameliorate sweatshop conditions in developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that produce and export <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the apparel purchased in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>?
Historically, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> have employed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> general approaches to the problem of sweatshops. First, the federal and state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> used powers of enforcement to seek compliance with labor standards. For the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fair Labor Standards Act</ENAMEX> and its regulations specify the standards and enforcement procedures.25 But sole reliance on traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> enforcement activities has serious limitations<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.26</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Department of Labor</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 800</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> to enforce employment statutes for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800,000</NUMEX> apparel industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 24,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX>, not to mention the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">122 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.5 million</NUMEX> workplaces around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Monitoring compliance with wage and hour provisions and pursuing violations is an extremely complicated and time-consuming process.
A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> method has involved mobilizing public pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to raise the incentives for voluntary compliance with labor standards. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> has used his or her <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">‚Äúbully pulpit‚Äù</ENAMEX> to call attention to the problem, urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to avoid purchasing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> made in workplaces that do not meet the standards<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.27</NUMEX> Various reports have also publicized government enforcement actions to deter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX>, jobbers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> from violating the standards, such as the release of a series of government reports on the extent of violations and the penalties assessed against violators<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.28</NUMEX> In yet another example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke University‚</ENAMEX>Äôs adoption of a code of conduct to ensure that apparel items bearing the university‚Äôs name are not made in sweatshops has received public support<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.29</NUMEX>
Indeed, efforts to use public concern, and at times outrage, to tackle the sweatshop problem go back to the early part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>. The most famous case involves public reaction to the fire at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triangle Shirtwaist Company</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 25, 1911</TIMEX>, in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">146</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> died. The fire started in a loft of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> during the workday. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> working in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> could not escape because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> had locked the doors to the stairs from the outside, ostensibly to prevent theft by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. The lack of fire extinguishers within the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> and the inability of fire ladders to reach the windows made escape impossible. In this case, public outrage led to early workers‚Äô compensation and factory inspection legislation.
But, in general, the effectiveness of focusing public attention on sweatshops and poor labor conditions has been limited by the difficulty of keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, or other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> working on this issue for sustained periods of time. Such <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX> are at best a means for focusing the attention of key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in order to build longer term mechanisms that remain even after public attention wanes.
Finally, voluntary agreements among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel participants</ENAMEX> to ensure compliance‚Äîwhich sometimes have arisen from efforts to increase public pressure‚Äîhave been employed at various times. For instance, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX> sponsored the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apparel Industry Partnership</ENAMEX>, in which a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">UNITE</ENAMEX>!, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Consumers League</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Interfaith Center</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporate Responsibility</ENAMEX> and others agreed to monitor compliance with labor standards of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX>.30 Yet these initiatives also have limitations. It is difficult to select an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to do the monitoring, establish the procedures to be followed, and determine who should serve as outside or independent monitors<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.31</NUMEX> Voluntary compliance measures and agreements in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, outside of collective bargaining, have thus far had a history of short-term viability and limited effectiveness.
Policies to reduce repugnant workplace conditions‚Äîby U.S. standards‚Äîin developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> that export apparel to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> involve an even more complex range of issues. What are the appropriate labor standards? Is one only to apply the standards and regulations of the exporting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or are some higher international standards to be used? How are such standards to be established, recognized, and enforced?<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32 One</NUMEX> approach would be to extend the conventions and standards established by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Labour Office</ENAMEX> (ILO) and to enhance the effectiveness of its enforcement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILO</ENAMEX> held a convention on child labor in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1998</TIMEX> and is considering a proposal for an annual ‚Äúglobal report‚Äù on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that have not ratified certain core workers‚Äô rights, such as freedom of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>, abolition of forced labor, nondiscrimination and equal remuneration, and minimum age<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.33</NUMEX> Even with such international standards adopted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILO</ENAMEX>, the task of enforcement remains daunting.
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> a number of programs have been adopted that seek to change labor practices in workplaces overseas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Labor</ENAMEX> provided <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Program</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elimination of Child Labor</ENAMEX> in a joint effort with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILO</ENAMEX> to end the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the manufacture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> balls in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. (In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 million</NUMEX> soccer balls were produced there, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-quarter</NUMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee Gifford</ENAMEX> exemplify <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, brand names, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> who have adopted programs for overseas inspections to mitigate criticism of their possible sweatshop imports. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council on Economic Priorities</ENAMEX> has established a global, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">variable ‚Äúsocial accountability standard‚Äù</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can follow to prove they adhere to an array of labor standards and pay their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> a sufficient income<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.35</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commissioner for Employment and Social Affairs</ENAMEX>, have sought to develop among labor and management an acceptance of international standards to assure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> that the products they buy are not made in sweatshops<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.36</NUMEX>
In a significant sense, such efforts to deal with labor standards in apparel production simply illustrate the larger issues of trade, labor, and environmental standards that are likely to be a focus of international economic discourse over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade ahead</TIMEX>. In fact, it is doubtful that these issues can be separated to the extent they have been over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>. There are sharp differences in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> between organized labor and business and in the political arena as well. Persistent efforts in the labor standards field indicate that separating trade, labor, and other social issues will no longer be as acceptable in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> ahead. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> took up the issue of global sweatshops is a striking example of this reality<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.37</NUMEX>
The complexity of sweatshop problems makes any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúsilver bullet‚Äù solution</ENAMEX> as unlikely now as it has been throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>. Nonetheless, our analysis suggests a number of steps that might be taken to improve compliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> labor standards in the presence of information-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>. Given the inherent resource limitations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> enforcement, inspections must be carefully targeted to yield maximum impact. One method for improving targeting would be to require each garment to include a bar code <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">label</ENAMEX> that shows the place and time of fabrication. This would take advantage of the same technology that has been so fundamental to the changes examined in this book. Information from the bar code could more directly be used by the Wage and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hour</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> to sample compliance and more rapidly isolate violations. Such requirements could arise either as a result of voluntary agreements among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> or be mandated through regulation<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.38</NUMEX> Past experience suggests, however, that in this field voluntary measures need to be reinforced by regulatory authority.
The viability of collective bargaining as a means, once again, to regulate sweatshop conditions largely depends on the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">UNITE</ENAMEX>! to rebuild its collective bargaining and membership base in a smaller and more efficient industry responsive to lean retailing<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.39</NUMEX> Efforts by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> and apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to link compliance with wage and working condition standards to efforts to improve the competitive viability of the industry offer promise such as through sponsoring training of apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> or by helping to build more responsive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> of apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> to deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. But these initiatives are still at an early stage of development<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.40</NUMEX>
Finally, the central role played by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> in development and operation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> points to the fact that any measure‚Äîwhether taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, through voluntary compliance programs or via collective bargaining‚Äîmust include their participation and support. The reliance of lean retailing on the promulgation of standards of performance has been well documented in this book. A logical extension of those practices might be the adoption of procedures or systems related to labor standards in domestic or offshore sourcing operations.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coming Competitive Landscape</ENAMEX>
Since the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, textile-mill products and apparel have both been characterized by substantial reductions in employment; at the same time these sectors show substantial increases in output, including shifts to higher-value products and higher productivity. Total employment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> textiles is projected to continue its decline, reaching <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">588,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX>, with apparel down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">714,000</NUMEX> at the same date. Meanwhile, outputs are projected to increase <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 and 4 percent</NUMEX>, respectively, in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1996‚Äì2006</NUMEX> period<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.41</NUMEX>
These are scarcely moribund industries, with inflexible product and labor markets. The textile industry, in particular, has been characterized by rapid technological changes and automation; shifts to large-scale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX>; restructuring and consolidation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> in spinning, weaving, and knitting; substantial capital investments in these activities and finishing operations; and a shift to products with expanding markets. Wages have risen relative to the average of all manufacturing or nondurable manufacturing. Exports have been within <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few billion dollars</NUMEX> of imports in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>.
The economics of these channels depend on the costs of the separate steps and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">transactions‚Äîfrom</ENAMEX> manufacture, including inventory costs, through distribution costs, retail, and sales, including markdown and stock-out costs. The costs of time to market also matters. This view of costs examined throughout this book yields quite different estimates from the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> to comparative direct labor costs of manufacture as a sole basis for supply-choice decisions. Previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> have demonstrated that the lowest purchase price from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> does not necessarily yield the lowest costs at the point and time of sale or the largest profit. An established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> in which the various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> focus on time to market results in markedly different supply decisions and dynamics than those dictated by conventional direct labor costs of supplies. Given these crucial changes, the following sections review the competitive ‚Äúhorizon‚Äù for each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> that make up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retail Horizon</ENAMEX>
Information-integration is one of the major factors contributing to increasing concentration in the retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX>. Previously, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> to a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> were often in a better position, compared with any one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>, to report on shifting styles and tastes and estimate market direction. In many situations, they chose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> and set volumes for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. Now point-of-sales information provides <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> with reliable information on market developments and hence gives them more leverage in dealing with direct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> and others further from ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. In other words, direct measurable information of consumer behavior translates into market power. The lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> can also transfer to its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> the functions (and costs) of creating floor-ready merchandise, activities that traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> handled in the past. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX> in mind, however, that the information-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> requires substantial investment in technologies by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. Although small-scale retailing continues, it is clear that an increasing proportion of retailing will be concentrated among a decreasing number of larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>.42
The Internet has been often cited as an alternative to retailing and, presumably, a potential challenge to the dominant role played by lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. In this regard, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Mullin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Retail Federation</ENAMEX> (NRF) notes:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRF</ENAMEX> fields a deluge of calls <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internet‚</ENAMEX>Äôs impact on retailing. The most common question we get from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúHow long will it take for the Internet to completely replace physical retailing?‚Äù We have observed that traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> are taking a cautious approach to the Internet. Yet most understand its great potential, even if they openly admit they don‚Äôt have all the answers<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.43</NUMEX>
A limited number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> are currently experimenting with the Internet, although <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 9 percent</NUMEX> of those surveyed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> indicated that they currently sell products this way<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.44</NUMEX> Retailers are currently reluctant to go on-line both because they believe that their products are ‚Äúill-suited for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> sales‚Äù and are concerned about specific technical limitations, such as the security of electronic financial transactions<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.45</NUMEX>
A number of developments, many linked to issues we have discussed, indicate both the potential and limitations of electronic retailing. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense, the Internet offers opportunities akin to mail-order retailing for playing a very lean game. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lands‚</ENAMEX>Äô Ends became an early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in adopting certain lean retailing elements into its catalog <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> and has aggressively entered Internet retailing. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> launched its Web site in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, the first major apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> to do so. Its site incorporates an encryption system to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> against credit-card thefts<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.46</NUMEX>
The Internet provides some of the advantages of mail-order sales with even lower transaction costs. However, the obstacles to virtual retailing remain formidable. Product offerings are limited in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sites‚</ENAMEX>Äîthe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lands‚Äô End</ENAMEX> site, for example, offered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 500</NUMEX> products in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. In addition, just as in other areas of modern retailing, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> must have a distribution system capable of getting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> out efficiently on an order-by-order basis, either through internal resources or use of third-party consolidators. The economics of distribution for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> retailing, like catalog retailing, are therefore quite different from those developed even by advanced in-store lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>.
Finally, measurement, fit, color, and texture remain central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> of apparel sales. In apparel‚Äîunlike the sale of goods via the Internet such as computers, software, or tools‚Äîpeople want to see, feel, and try on the products. These aspects of selling apparel items do not fit well with ‚Äúvirtual retailing.‚Äù The mail-order <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> already contends with this problem, and these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> cope with returns that sometimes go over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-quarter</NUMEX> the value of sales in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given year</TIMEX>. Consider <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lands‚Äô End</ENAMEX> once more. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> (well before its entrance to the Internet), it was forced to cope with returns of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">132,000</NUMEX> shirts. Each return was associated with a processing cost roughly equivalent to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of its value<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.47</NUMEX> Thus, although Internet retailing will certainly grow as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> of distribution, the most essential longer term developments will involve the expansion of lean retailing principles to a wider and wider variety of goods sold by a decreasing number of major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apparel Industry Horizon</ENAMEX>
A central feature of information-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels‚</ENAMEX>Äîindeed, the basis for our term ‚Äúlean retailing‚Äù‚Äîis the effective management of inventories at the SKU level. Throughout the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, lean inventory management reduces the risk of selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúperishable‚Äù products</ENAMEX>, thus enhancing profits. The capability to compete increasingly depends on an enterprise‚Äôs ability to manage operations according to the logistics of time and flow of product, reducing time to market and the costs of holding inventory.
We have made clear that holding inventory can be expensive to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX>, whether it manufactures or sources its products, in several ways. These include capital tied up in work-in-process or finished goods; the costs of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> used; the risks of failure to sell; and price markdowns to dispose of products. At the same time, the inability to supply product to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> is another costly risk.
These risks and costs may be minimized and profits enhanced by using a combination of short-cycle and longer-cycle production lines. The short-cycle line turns out products faster but usually at a higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost. The long-cycle line takes longer to produce items, but at lower costs. Balancing these lines by establishing for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> the precise pattern of expected variability in demand and point-of-sale information provides the means for maximizing profits. Our research suggests that the cycle time of a fast production line should be no more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to be an effective alternative for the lower costs of a long-cycle line or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>.
The balancing of short-cycle and long-cycle production alternatives has direct application to the choices <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> face between domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> with potential short cycles and foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> with longer ones. The future of the domestic apparel industry rests on those items made using short-cycle production, which are often those with high <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> variations in sales. Such short-cycle production necessarily requires methods like modular or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> rather than the lengthy progressive bundle system. At the same time, it requires an ability to use incoming information on sales in a sophisticated manner to allocate production in this way.
In a related vein, the future of domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> also relies on their development of capabilities for supplying fashion products on a replenishment basis. Once again, this requires a combination of practices; by using advanced forecasting methods and innovative production techniques, apparel<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX> may be able to respond in very short periods of time to point-of-sale information regarding sale of products with higher fashion content. In addition, as we discussed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 8</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> attempting mass customization of apparel products such as jeans will need similar capabilities.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Textile Industry Horizon</ENAMEX>
Textile markets in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> no longer depend primarily on apparel as they did in the past. Currently, no more than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 35 percent</NUMEX> of textile shipments are for apparel items. Textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> now furnish a range of household products (such as sheets, bedding, towels, and rugs) and some knit products (T-shirts) directly to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. Such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> have adopted the information-integration described <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> as textile products have been upgraded from greige goods in a brokers‚Äô market to those that involve complex finishing operations and extensive product proliferation. A number of integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> have therefore been developed among textiles, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>.
Significant markets have also grown for industrial textiles in a wide range of industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>, such as automobile interiors and tire cord. The range of industrial products is expanding, including knapsacks, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> bags, tents, fishing nets, hammocks, air bags, and parachutes. Even if textile products flowing to apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sewn</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> (or in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean Basin</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> assemble garments using <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> textiles) decline, it is realistic to assume that some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> textile exports will increase in the near term and that there will be substantial increases in domestic industrial markets.
Still, at least one feature of textile markets warrants attention in their relations to apparel. The size of many orders preferred by the apparel industry is considerably smaller than that preferred by textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. Apparel-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> confront frequent changes in styles and new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX>, while textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> seek long runs to keep capacity operating round-the-clock. In the retail-apparel-textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>, there is a need for an information-sharing integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system‚</ENAMEX>Äîsome form of packager‚Äîto assist in ameliorating these differences. Once again, the development of Web sites to undertake some of these connections represents an important <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step in this direction.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Future of Information</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integrated Channels</ENAMEX>
As we have stated throughout, textiles and apparel remain significant sectors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, together they provided <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1.4 million</NUMEX> jobs, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX> they are projected to have combined employment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over 1.3 million‚</NUMEX>Äînearly <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> of all projected jobs in manufacturing. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> are far too vital to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and have proven sufficiently vibrant, to be dismissed by the conventional doctrine of comparative labor costs.
Indeed, rather than turning the future more bleak, the introduction and the widespread adoption of lean retailing by all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in the retail-apparel-textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> provides new opportunities for the textile and apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX>, at least in some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX>. We see a viable future for these industries‚Äîwith a few caveats. These revived opportunities do not apply with equal effect to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> of apparel or all parts of the fashion triangle. Garments amenable to rapid replenishment principles have the most potential for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> production.
Our less pessimistic view of the future of these industries should not be misinterpreted. The textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> appears more promising because it has become more directly connected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>. Yet survival in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> belongs only to the fittest adopters of the new order of retailing and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. Employment levels are not projected to turn around. Instead, employment will gradually decline in both industries, while output and productivity increase‚Äîthe best that any industrial sector can expect over time in the modern economy. The new order in apparel places more of a premium on scale and size, along with investments in the requisite technologies. The traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor shop</ENAMEX> and small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> will have a smaller and even less secure role unless linked to sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intermediary agents</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>.
In short, the paths these industries follow will be determined by their interconnection with one another. Providing a stitch‚Äîor a package of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pasta</ENAMEX>, a home computer, an automobile‚Äîin time requires a growing degree of integration among business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> within and across industries. Whether it is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federated Department Stores‚</ENAMEX>Äô or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Depot‚</ENAMEX>Äôs use of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">point</NUMEX>-of-sales information for inventory control; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi Strauss‚</ENAMEX>Äôs or Black and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Decker‚Äôs</ENAMEX> efforts at customizing products to suit very specific consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>; or VF‚Äôs or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell Computer‚</ENAMEX>Äôs innovations to provide product diversity more efficiently, channel integration is driving the current industrial transformation‚Äîand will continue to do so in the period ahead.



