



The emergence of textile, apparel, and retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is full of fascinating twists. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1790</TIMEX>, for instance, an act of industrial espionage is said to have launched the domestic textile industry, if not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> manufacturing in general. At that time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Slater</ENAMEX>, a skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanic</ENAMEX>, built the first successful water-powered yarn spinning <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pawtucket</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yarn</ENAMEX> was in short supply in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and much in demand in households that did hand weaving as well as in workplaces with looms that produced sheeting, shirting, and stockings for commerce. Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and improvement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX> had even offered generous rewards for the establishment of water-powered combing and spinning, especially those based on state-of-the-art <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> Arkwright <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> law strictly prohibited the export of drawings, plans, or models of these new technologies. It took somebody like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slater‚</ENAMEX>Äîan indentured apprentice for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over six years</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Arkwright and Strut‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England‚</ENAMEX>Äîto ferry the plans to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.1
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slater</ENAMEX> was interested in the financial rewards to be had in the new world while still in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. Mindful of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> prohibitions, he committed to memory the design and construction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">spinning mill</ENAMEX> where he worked. Arriving in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1789</TIMEX>, he was referred to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses Brown</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX>, a prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX> who had established a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Almy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, to develop ‚Äúframe or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> spinning.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Brown</ENAMEX> responded on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 10, 1789</TIMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slater‚</ENAMEX>Äôs initial inquiry, saying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Almy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> certainly wanted the assistance of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slater‚</ENAMEX>Äôs skills because an experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> had failed, ‚Äúno <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> being acquainted with the business, and the frames imperfect.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù2</ENAMEX>
Once in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Almy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brown‚Äôs Pawtucket</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slater</ENAMEX> found the existing machinery totally unsatisfactory. He entered into a partnership with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Almy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> to erect ‚Äúperpetual card and spinning‚Äù machines, otherwise known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arkwright</ENAMEX> patents. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1793</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Almy, Brown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slater</ENAMEX> was operating a seventy-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-spindle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX>, producing high-quality yarn. From the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pawtucket</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton</ENAMEX>-spinning industry was launched.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slater</ENAMEX> mill not only copied <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> technology but recreated that country‚Äôs arrangement of family labor, which included young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-day weeks</TIMEX>, the minimum twelve<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-hour day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sabbath</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and payment of wages partly in goods and partly in cash. The form of ownership and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> also followed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> lines‚Äîone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> financed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX>, while the other furnished the technical know-how. For these accomplishments, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Slater</ENAMEX> has been called ‚Äúthe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> manufactures.‚Äù His story underscores the international role of textiles and apparel, their impetus in national economic development, and their place in conflicts over domestic production and imports‚Äîa theme that recurs throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> history. For example, from the outset of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Washington</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Hamilton</ENAMEX> wanted to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-based industry. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> wore a dark brown suit, entirely made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, for his first inaugural on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 30</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1789.3</NUMEX>
In this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, we will concentrate on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past hundred years</TIMEX>, outlining major changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> retail, apparel, and textiles that occurred before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. The industrial transformation of this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> period, which affected far more than these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> industries, echoes today‚Äôs enormous shifts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">supplier</ENAMEX> relations, manufacturing operations, and human resource practices. The changes now going on have their analog in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last century</TIMEX>, when technological innovations of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroads</ENAMEX>, telegraph, and steam power‚Äîdeveloped for purposes far afield of retail, apparel, or textiles‚Äîhelped transform the mass distri-bution of goods and information.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Chandler</ENAMEX> described the last industrial transformation in his well-known book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Visible Hand</ENAMEX>. The use of everything from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroads</ENAMEX> to an improved postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>, created <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> with internal administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> that coordinated the flow of goods from many individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> to many more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. This administrative coordination reduced ‚Äúthe number of transactions involved in the flow of goods, increased the speed and regularity of that flow, and so lowered costs and improved the productivity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> distribution system.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù4</ENAMEX>
The parallels with the information integration now occurring in retail-apparel-textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels‚</ENAMEX>Äîthis time driven by advances in computer and related technologies‚Äîare striking. In fact, another industrial transformation is under way, one that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> the earlier revolution in organizational structure and management. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> sections of this chapter summarize the emergence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> retail, apparel, and textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past century</TIMEX>, including a number of human resource issues. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> section looks at their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> relations prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>, before some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> started interacting with each other in new ways. This brief historical survey highlights not only the crucial developments that still undergird these industries but also the systems and work practices from an earlier <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> that no longer match today‚Äôs competitive requirements.
Retail: From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Stores</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX> Retailers
In urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, there have always been small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> with goods for sale. Often the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> produced the goods themselves, such as the cobblers and silversmiths of old. At farmers‚Äô markets, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> would display the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> they grew or sell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>. At most, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> might have a general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> with a motley array of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dry goods</ENAMEX>, based on a limited distribution system‚Äîone that relied on local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> and faraway supply <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> with extremely long lead times and spotty delivery. The old system didn‚Äôt begin to shift until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-nineteenth century</TIMEX>, with the advent of a new kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">middleman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Chandler</ENAMEX> writes,
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1850s and the 1860s</TIMEX> the modern commodity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>, who purchased directly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> and sold directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">processor</ENAMEX>, took over the distribution of agricultural products. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same years</TIMEX> the full-line, full-service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wholesaler</ENAMEX> began to market consumer goods. Then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1870s and 1880s</TIMEX> the modern mass retailer‚Äîthe department store, the mail order <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> store‚Äîstarted to make inroads on the wholesaler‚Äôs markets.5
Until the emergence of mass retail, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wholesaler-jobber</ENAMEX> dominated the distribution of consumer dry goods to general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>: clothing, upholstered furnishings, hardware, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, tobacco, furniture, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">china</ENAMEX>, and glassware. Unlike traveling peddlers of the past, who carried everything with them, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesmen</ENAMEX> could ride the rails into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> with no more than a trunk of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> and catalogs. The new infrastructure created by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroads</ENAMEX> and telegraph contributed to the growth of wholesale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Retailers</ENAMEX> no longer needed to carry such large inventories, the risk of losing shipments was reduced, and delivery was more certain on a specified schedule. Increased volume cut unit costs and enhanced cash flow, reducing credit needs. Moreover, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesmen</ENAMEX> provided a flow of information to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> on changing demand in -various localities as well as the credit ratings of local storekeepers and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wholesaler</ENAMEX>-jobber <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> of the time, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leiter and Company</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> (which later became <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marshall Field</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Company</ENAMEX>), required both a purchasing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and an extensive traveling sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> to sell to the scattered general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country towns</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> each handled a major product line like hardware or dry goods. They typically determined the specifications of the goods purchased, the volume purchased, and the price to be charged to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> at retail. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> became the most important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wholesaler</ENAMEX>-jobber <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, foreshadowing the key status of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wholesaler</ENAMEX>-jobber distribution system peaked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1880s</TIMEX>. It was subsequently supplanted by mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> in the form of department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in large urban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and by mail-order <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> focused on smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> and rural markets. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> recounts,
Mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> displaced wholesale-jobbers as soon as they were able to exploit a market as large as that covered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wholesalers</ENAMEX>. By building comparable purchasing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> they could buy directly from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> and develop a higher stock-turn than the jobbers. Their administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> were more effective because they were in direct contact with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> and because they eliminated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> major set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">middlemen</ENAMEX>.6
Other factors drove the development of mass retail as well. The rapid growth of urban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and access to their downtown areas, initially with horse-drawn streetcars, encouraged mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. Department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, with a wide range of goods arranged in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äúdepartments</ENAMEX>,‚Äù provided one-stop shopping, both novel and appealing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> of the period. The increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> seeking ready-made clothing and home furnishings also contributed to the rise of the department store as did newspaper advertising. Although small specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> were limited to a few items, such as those found in a traditional dressmaker or milliner‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> offered fixed prices and the convenience of returning purchases for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> or cash. They sold goods at a lower markup than specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and, above all, concentrated on achieving a high level of stock-turn (or the number of times products turn over in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given year</TIMEX>).
Many of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> have names that are still familiar: Macy‚Äôs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Field‚</ENAMEX>Äôs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wanamaker</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> points out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1860s and 1870s</TIMEX> accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX> of the leading department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century later</TIMEX>. In addition, he writes, ‚ÄúBecause sales were made on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">store‚Äôs premises</ENAMEX> rather than through traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesmen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> had an even larger role than they did in the wholesale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>.... They had direct charge of the sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> who marketed their lines over the counter.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù7</ENAMEX>
Then there was the parallel growth of mail-order sales. With the help of new transportation and communications systems, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to market a wide variety of consumer goods exclusively by mail and parcel post was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montgomery Ward</ENAMEX>, formed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1872</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Grange</ENAMEX>, the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>, supported the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1887</TIMEX>, its catalog of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">540</NUMEX> pages listed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24,000</NUMEX> items. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears Roebuck and Co.</ENAMEX> outstripped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomery Ward</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1890s</TIMEX>. As with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wholesaler</ENAMEX>-jobber and the emerging department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> had full autonomy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> notes, ‚ÄúEach merchandise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> was a separate dynasty, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> was in complete charge.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù8</ENAMEX>
Department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and mail-order <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> (and later chain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> distribution) dominated mass retailing after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1880</TIMEX> through large volume, high inventory turnover, lower prices, payments in cash that reduced the need for credit and debt, and the crucial role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wholesaler-jobbers</ENAMEX> had faded from the scene, the policies, practices, and administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mass distributors</ENAMEX> were derived from them. Other buying practices came from small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>. Each retail merchandise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, particularly in multi-store <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, became a separate fiefdom, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> in charge of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> selection, scale, timing of orders, and pricing. Up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>, the buyers‚Äô personal network of contacts and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúfeel‚Äù</ENAMEX> for what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> wanted determined marketing policy. And although the wages of nonsupervisory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in retail have been and still are quite low<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,9</NUMEX> the compensation system for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> provided substantial rewards for favorable results.
Consequently, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> the decisions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> in retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> directly affected apparel and textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>. The distribution system that emerged after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1870</TIMEX> would not be challenged until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a century later</TIMEX>. Only in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, with the development of another system of mass distribution that includes new technology, new management methods, and new links to manufacturing‚Äîlean retailing‚Äîdid the role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> significantly diminish.
Apparel: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Home Work to Modern Manufacture</ENAMEX>
In colonial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewives</ENAMEX> typically did spinning, weaving, and tailoring for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">well-to-do</ENAMEX> purchased imported cloth and had apparel made by itinerant tailors or those in small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>. The ready-made garment industry grew out of altered rejects and secondhand clothing that were then sold to the poorer classes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1832</TIMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> import duty curtailed clothing primarily from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and increased the demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> home industry<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">.10</TIMEX> By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1850</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Census</ENAMEX> reports that there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,278</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97,000</NUMEX> workers‚<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Äî63 percent</NUMEX> of them women‚Äîin the ready-made clothing industry<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cloth</ENAMEX> was cut and assembled into bundles in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX>, given out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to take home to sew, and returned for finishing operations<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.12</NUMEX>
With the invention of the sewing machine by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howe</ENAMEX>, and its perfection by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1851</TIMEX>, a new era began in the manufacture of clothing, when more work became concentrated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> and the consequent need for uniforms stimulated the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory system</ENAMEX>, and the introduction of standard body-size measurements facilitated ready-to-wear clothing. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Schaffner</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>, for instance, opened its doors in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1879</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 40 percent</NUMEX> of men‚Äôs suits were ready-made. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1920</TIMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> wore suits that came from a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>. In this period, a number of key technological changes appeared: sewing machines that made many more stitches a minute, long knives instead of shears for cutting, and pressing machines.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From the nineteenth century</TIMEX> on, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> in the apparel industry have taken one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> general forms: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> with an inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>; the jobber; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> with an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, which can supply either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> or jobbers. The jobber, a form characteristic of women‚Äôs apparel, does not produce in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> that it owns. Jobbers may purchase cloth and materials; design or purchase design of garments; and cut or contract out cutting of fabrics. They turn over sewing and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX>, and their main role is to merchandise finished product.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jobber-contractor</ENAMEX> system developed to address many of the issues that still concern apparel<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX>. It provided great flexibility in coping with fluctuations in style, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, and economic conditions; at the same time, jobbers did not take on the substantial costs of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, equipment, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> that ‚Äúinside shop‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> did. This system also separated and specialized the functions of production from the purchase of materials and the selling of finished products‚Äîdevelopments that greatly influence women‚Äôs and children‚Äôs apparel <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, including the complexity of the regulation of labor conditions.
Regardless, apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> in both the men‚Äôs and women‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX> have always been labor intensive; even with continual technological innovation, the work still comes down to cutting cloth and sewing pieces together into a garment. Although union <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> has not been so extensive in retail or textiles, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> have been important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in apparel manufacturing. At the same time, apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> have pressed for ever greater productivity on the shop floor, hoping to cut labor costs in a variety of ways. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> related historical issues‚Äîthe ascendancy of a particular system of clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> and the role of unions‚Äîhave a direct bearing on what is now happening in retail-apparel-textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>.
Development of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive Bundle System</ENAMEX>
For the most part, in-plant production methods for apparel have been organized around the way in which cut parts of garments are distributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> for sewing and then assembled into the completed garment. From the outset of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory system</ENAMEX> in woven apparel, after cloth has been laid out and cut in the configurations of patterns for various sizes, the cut parts have been grouped by parts of the garment‚Äîfronts, backs, sleeves, patches for pockets, collars‚Äîand tied together into bundles for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>, who sew together individual parts‚Äîhence the term ‚Äúbundle system.‚Äù Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> specializes in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, or at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">most a few</TIMEX>, sewing operations.
By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1930s</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> systems of sewing and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> emerged in the men‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> of the apparel industry: the progressive bundle system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>) and the straight-line system (SLS)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13</NUMEX> The ascendancy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> in the men‚Äôs industry, where it remains by far the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, illustrates how product market competition‚Äîspecifically intense price-based competition‚Äîgave rise to distinctive human resource practices<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.14</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> refined the traditional bundle system by organizing individual sewing tasks in a systematic fashion. It entails better engineering of specific sewing tasks, including some specialized sewing machines, to reduce the amount of time required for each task. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> receives a bundle of unfinished garments. She performs a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> on each garment in the bundle. The completed bundle is then placed in a buffer with other bundles that have been completed to that point. Machines are laid out in a manner that speeds up shuttling a bin of garment bundles from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX>. With its roots in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taylorism</ENAMEX>, each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> task is given a target time or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúSAM‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Standard Allocated Minutes</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>-study <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> calculate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SAM</ENAMEX> for an entire garment for an experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> as the sum of the number of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> required for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> in the production process, including allowances for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> fatigue, rest periods, personal time, and so on<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.15</NUMEX>
The straight-line system (SLS) also attempted to apply <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tayloristic</ENAMEX> notions to apparel but in a way that had more in common with scientific management techniques used in other manufacturing industries. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLS</ENAMEX> breaks down tasks into simple sewing operations, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> does. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLS</ENAMEX> uses the single garment rather than the bundle as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of production. As a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLS</ENAMEX> operates essentially without bundles or extensive buffers; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> pass garments directly to the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>, thus allowing for single or a few apparel items to move through the assembly process rapidly.
In its limited adoptions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, the SLS sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> was organized in short rows of sewing machines based on the sequence of operations for the garment. Even more than under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, sewing tasks were broken down in minute detail, both as a means of increasing speed and decreasing skill requirements. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Engineers</ENAMEX> designed operations to take similar lengths of time to achieve line balancing. When a specific task took longer than the surrounding operations, multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> were employed on the slower task to achieve balance. Each operator‚Äôs workstation was connected by a bar or chute that fed the garment directly to the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>.
Yet line-balancing problems bedeviled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. Laying out a production line required exact calculation of the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> required for a given step to keep single garments moving through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> continuously‚Äîmuch as a car moves down an assembly line. The lack of buffers for bundles made the system vulnerable to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> fluctuations in the performance of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>, whether because of fatigue, health, mood, absenteeism, substitutions, or intentional slowdowns. In a competitive market that placed a premium on price/cost competition and little value on time to market, the small reduction in direct labor cost did not justify the high potential costs and risks that arose from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLS</ENAMEX> downtime. In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> provided apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> with a means for improving labor productivity along with adaptability to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> variations in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>-floor conditions.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>, virtually all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> in the men‚Äôs shirt industry, for example, was done on the basis of bundle systems of production. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41 percent</NUMEX> of production <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> were classified as operating under the traditional bundle system; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55 percent</NUMEX> assembled shirts through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 4 percent</NUMEX> used the line system. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>, the percentage using traditional bundles had fallen to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26 percent</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> had risen to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69 percent</NUMEX> of all production <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and line systems remained uncommon at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> had become virtually the only assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX> used in men‚Äôs and boys‚Äô shirt production, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 4 percent</NUMEX> of production accounted for by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLS</ENAMEX> and others systems<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.16</NUMEX>
The dominance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> affects current developments in apparel manufacturing and employee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons. First, the system depends on buffers between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly operations</ENAMEX> to minimize downtime. Standard practice is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> buffer between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>.17 With a pair of pants assembled through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly forty</NUMEX> operations, a large amount of in-process inventory is created. More important, a given pair of pants takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about forty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> to move from cut pieces to final product. Now that apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> face more stringent order-fulfillment requirements and are expected to provide a much wider range of products to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, the costs of large amounts of in-process inventory have grown tremendously.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> is not set up for large-scale modifications of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>. Although this system has never had as many problems with line balancing as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLS</ENAMEX>, creating sufficient buffers between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> steps to keep everyone in the sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> occupied remains a challenge. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, a balanced line is a function of the workers‚Äô rate of speed at each of the steps; the total volume moving through the system; the current incentive rates; and such daily uncertainties as turnover and absenteeism. Because introducing changes at any step may unbalance the system as a whole, technological innovations have not easily found their way into the sewing room‚Äîwhich may be out of sync with what an integrated retail-apparel-textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> requires.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Role of Labor Organizations</ENAMEX>
Apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">workplaces</ENAMEX> have historically been located in major metropolitan <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">areas‚ÄîNew York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis‚</ENAMEX>Äîand drawn on successive waves of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>. In the production of both men‚Äôs and women‚Äôs clothing, immigrant labor provided a continuing secure labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> that often already had the requisite skills. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> were foreign born, and a large percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native</ENAMEX>-born were of foreign parentage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> in the men‚Äôs clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> at the time issued official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> different languages. Practically all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-generation <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>.18 More recently, apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, seeking lower labor costs, have moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">American South</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. But a disproportionate number of domestic apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>.
Given access to a large pool of immigrant labor in urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jobber-contractor system</ENAMEX> in women‚Äôs apparel led to the wide-scale presence and abuses of sweatshops. Sweatshops at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX> encompassed a range of workplaces in which, as one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> noted, ‚ÄúCongestion, unsanitary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX>, lack of restriction on child labor, absolutely unregulated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, and miserable pay combine to create a condition which endangers the lives not only of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, but of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purchasers</ENAMEX> of their products.‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äù19</NUMEX> A study in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1893</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúsweating system‚Äù</ENAMEX> estimated that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-half</NUMEX> of the clothing manufactured at that time came from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>, while the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> originated in home work or was subcontracted in small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> often adjoining homes<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.20</NUMEX>
Organizing a relatively low-skill immigrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> presented great challenges to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> in the garment industry. Employer resistance to unionization, arising from the highly competitive conditions in apparel markets and the significant percentage of total costs arising from labor, further compounded the problem. This difficult environment shaped the organizing and representation strategies of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major unions‚Äîthe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Ladies‚Äô Garment Workers Union</ENAMEX> (ILGWU)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21‚</NUMEX>Äîas well as their relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> through collective bargaining arrangements<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.22</NUMEX> Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> established a foothold in the industry because they represented strategic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in the apparel production process: the skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cutter</ENAMEX> working inside manufacturers‚Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. Cutters required substantial training, and the withdrawal of their labor could quickly shut down all sewing and pressing operations. Because cutters worked on multiple layers of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time, their errors were likely to be costly. Not surprisingly, cutters were the highest paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> receiving day rates.23
By organizing cutters <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unions</ENAMEX> gained the leverage with which they could then organize and represent the much larger, but less skilled, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sewers</ENAMEX> who worked in factory settings, particularly in the men‚Äôs industry, or in the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> that characterized the women‚Äôs industry. The principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> of this approach, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Hillman</ENAMEX>, founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amalgamated</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Dubinsky</ENAMEX>, long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILGWU</ENAMEX>, were cutters and came out of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>-group<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.24</NUMEX>
Given this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> foothold, collective bargaining in apparel focused on the standardization of labor in a market area and a product line. This was done because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of work in clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>; the low capital costs and high proportion of labor costs, especially in women‚Äôs wear for contract <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>; the intense product competition among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> within and among geographic markets; and the diversity of products and changing styles. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> drew on several different methods to standardize wages and conditions within the markets. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILGWU</ENAMEX>, standardizing wages required regulation through collective bargaining of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> and ‚Äúsubmanufacturers‚Äù working for jobbers and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. Emphasizing the potential role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> in this regard, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILGWU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dubinsky</ENAMEX> commented on the difficult conditions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> in the stable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> whom they were anxious to keep suffered as much as we did because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> was weak. They had to pay decent wages and maintain decent conditions, but they also had to compete with the fly-by<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-nights</TIMEX> and chiselers. They began to recognize that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> was a necessary stabilizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. They could not meet conditions if their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> were free to ignore them<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.25</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Employers</ENAMEX> who signed the major collective bargaining agreements with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILGWU</ENAMEX> in the women‚Äôs industry (primarily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>) not only agreed to abide by wage and working conditions for their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, they also pledged to use only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> ‚Äúdesignated or registered‚Äù with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer association</ENAMEX>.26 These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX>, in turn, agreed to abide by the terms laid out by the collective agreement. The collective bargaining process aimed to control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> by making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> responsible in the area-product agreement for its suppliers‚Äô behavior and payment of wages and benefits<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.27</NUMEX>
Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> also sought to standardize wages by setting piece rates for assembly work. At the shop level, this was expressed in union involvement in piece-rate setting through union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>.28 At the manufacturer‚Äôs level, collective bargaining sought to standardize direct wage and benefit costs for product lines (such as women‚Äôs coats, suits, dresses, and intimate apparel) through various joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>. To support these activities, the apparel labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> created in their national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> industrial engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> to seek improvement in work practices and experiences<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.29</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> also became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX> in establishing neutral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">umpires</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arbitrators</ENAMEX> in the handling of labor-management disputes<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.30</NUMEX>
Over time, major growth in imports and traditional price/cost competition have reduced the strategic leverage of the apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> and their chosen methods of wage stabilization. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amalgamated</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILGWU</ENAMEX> merged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> to form the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union of Needletrades</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial and Textile Employees‚Äîor UNITE</ENAMEX>!). On a labor-cost basis alone, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> cannot compete with foreign apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly operations</ENAMEX> in developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. At the same time, the problem of sweatshops persists, despite government regulation of minimum wages, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overtime</TIMEX>, child labor, and safety issues. In fact, regulation has increased significantly since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secretaries of Labor</ENAMEX> continue to be concerned about sweatshops and violations of labor standards in apparel.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Textiles: From Fiber to Cloth to Finished Product</ENAMEX>
The basic processes of the textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industry‚</ENAMEX>Äîthe spinning of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> and the weaving of cloth‚Äîgo back to ancient times. The early phases of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Industrial Revolution</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> were closely linked to the mechanization of the textile industry and its transfer from the home to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>. Textiles have also led the industrialization process in many recently developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
For the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> this brings us back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Slater</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúfather of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> manufactures.‚Äù By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1810</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pawtucket</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>, enterprise begun with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slater‚</ENAMEX>Äôs cunning had spawned a vibrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton</ENAMEX>-spinning industry throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>. The next step in developing a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-based industry was to bring the machine that took yarn and transformed it into finished cloth‚Äîthe power loom‚Äîacross the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>. This feat was accomplished in much the same way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slater</ENAMEX> brought cotton spinning to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> of a crafty <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> merchant, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Cabot Lowell</ENAMEX>. As business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Dalzell</ENAMEX> notes,
[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he crowning glory of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britain‚Äôs</ENAMEX> textile technology ... remained beyond the reach of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. Until, that is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowell</ENAMEX> scored his triumph. Leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who twice searched his luggage none the wiser, he managed by meticulous observation to memorize the principal features of the power loom well enough to produce his own version of it on his return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>.31
A full-blown textile industry therefore blossomed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>, fostered by the region‚Äôs access to abundant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> power, capital, mechanical skills, and a hardworking labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. But the adoption of steam power in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> was delayed until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1850s and 1860s</TIMEX>, at which time most of the significant water-power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> were already in use. The efficiency of steam engines had by then been greatly improved through the use of better materials, and their operating costs reduced by cheaper transportation of coal<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.32</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> had already adopted steam engines for textile production, along with newer and more productive technology. As a result, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1880</TIMEX> the industry began to expand south, particularly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North and South Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1920</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half</NUMEX> of the spinning and weaving capacity was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, leading industrialization there. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, little of this basic part of the textile industry remained in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> textile industry has taken advantage of economies of scale in production to serve large, expanding, and, for much of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, protected markets for textile products. It has become an industry adept at producing high-quality products in large runs competitively and its strengths and limitations must be understood in this context.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Intensity</ENAMEX> and Economies of Scale
Primary textile manufacturing includes both the spinning of raw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> into yarn and the weaving of yarn into ‚Äúgreige goods,‚Äù or unfinished cloth. Although there have been specialized spinning and weaving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX>, the great majority of output is produced in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> that engage in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lowell</ENAMEX> and his associates established the first incorporated manufacturing operation when they set up an integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mill</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX> to finished fabric<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.33</NUMEX> The cloth produced in weaving mills requires further finishing‚Äîsuch as bleaching, shrinking, dyeing, and printing‚Äîbefore it is ready for sale to the apparel industry, to retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX>, or to industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. To undertake such a comprehensive set of activities, of course, requires significant capital investment. From the outset of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Industrial Revolution</ENAMEX>, spinning, weaving, and finishing have called for substantial investments in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, power, and equipment<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.34</NUMEX>
Because of this capital intensity, the textile industry has been driven by economies of scale. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> have largely succeeded through making huge runs of a limited range of products and, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, technological changes on the floor‚Äîmuch quieter machinery, for example, or removal of the ubiquitous cotton dust (now required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Occupational Safety and Health Administration</ENAMEX>) that used to affect both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> performance and the quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cloth‚Äîhave</ENAMEX> dramatically improved industry performance. Further, the knitting machine has been a key development in manufacturing technology. Knitted goods are an essential and growing segment of the textile industry, a trend that reflects the increasing demand for casual wear. The knitting machine produces cloth as the loom does but uses a different method. The warp knitting machine produces a flat fabric much like woven cloth, while the circular knitting machine creates a tubular fabric. The most important knit goods products are hosiery, knit underwear, and knit outerwear‚Äîpopular casual wear items like T-shirts, polo shirts, and sweatpants. Knitting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX> now account for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 30 percent</NUMEX> of production <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> engaged in textile manufacturing<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.35</NUMEX>
Continuing integration of the industry also contributed to the rise in productivity. Although small, family-owned and operated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were the norm in traditional textiles, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1950s</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burlington Industries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milliken</ENAMEX> undertook vertical integration to handle textile products from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX> to finishing<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.36</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Historically</ENAMEX>, finishing operations were often undertaken by separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> known as converters, which played a large role in the design of finished goods. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burlington</ENAMEX> integrated forward by bringing converting operations in-house, while a number of converters extended their operations backward into primary textiles.
Beyond restructuring for materials flow, the industry has experienced substantial horizontal integration. As a consequence, some segments of textiles, such as spinning, weaving, and knitting, became more concentrated by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX>. The industry underwent another substantial restructuring in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, and product lines became even more concentrated<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.37</NUMEX> Much of this happened because less efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, using older technologies, went under or were absorbed by larger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1977 and 1987</TIMEX>, the number of textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX> declined by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX>, from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,202 to 6,412</NUMEX>, and industry employment fell by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 25 percent</NUMEX>. At present, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> control <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 40 percent</NUMEX> of weaving and yarn mills output, although many finishing and dyeing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and knitting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> remain small.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Resources</ENAMEX> and Productivity Growth
The drive to gain advantage from economies of scale and the role of manufacturing technology in textiles have also affected the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who work in the industry. Ever since garment-making entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory system</ENAMEX>, the textile industry has been much more capital intensive than apparel. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> we estimate capital per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> in apparel at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX>, while the figure for basic textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX>. As a result, human resource practices in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> industries differ considerably.
For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, the textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industry‚</ENAMEX>Äôs machine operations involve a large number of distinct job classifications defined by the technology and production process; they fall within a narrow range of compensation, with the classifications of loom fixers, weavers, maintenance electricians, and machinists above that range. Because the textile industry has become so capital intensive, there are fewer jobs than in the past‚Äîbut the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who remain are, on average, paid more than apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>; some lower-skill jobs, such as the picker tender opening <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bales</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX>, have now been automated out of existence. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>, average <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> earnings in textiles were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.23</NUMEX> an hour compared with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.24</NUMEX> in apparel. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, textile <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> earnings had risen to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.07</NUMEX> compared with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.56</NUMEX> in apparel; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, textile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> earned an average of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10.02</NUMEX> an hour, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21.5 percent</NUMEX> more than the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.25</NUMEX> an hour of those in apparel<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.38</NUMEX> Currently <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 48 percent</NUMEX> of textile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> constitute <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77 percent</NUMEX> of apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.
Labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> have historically had a small proportion of the textile industry under collective agreements. As the textile industry moved south to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, it drew on a rural and small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community workforce</ENAMEX>, largely made up of native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>.39 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Textile</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX> at their outset often provided the principal employment in the locality. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> were formed among some of the skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craftspeople</ENAMEX>, such as loom fixers, weavers, spinners, and slasher tenders, particularly in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>. With the advent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIO</ENAMEX>, industrial unionism sought to organize more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in the industry, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Textile Workers Union of America</ENAMEX> merged with the established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amalgamated Clothing Workers Union</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> met fierce opposition from southern textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>.40 Currently, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 15 percent</NUMEX> of the textile production and nonsupervisory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> is organized compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> in the apparel industry.41
The combined impact of these factors is captured by the following trends. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1950 to 1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> production of textiles increased almost threefold. Over the same time period, the number of production <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> decreased by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX>. And the rate of textile productivity over this period far outpaced that for the manufacturing sector as a whole. (We discuss the performance of the textile industry extensively in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 13</ENAMEX>.) Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> struggled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, competing with foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> on labor costs, the domestic textile industry fared much better. Successful exploitation of economies of scale, favorable international trade agreements such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFA</ENAMEX>, and special arrangements for apparel imports made of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">textiles‚</ENAMEX>Äîeven the clout of certain southern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, looking after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in their states‚Äîmean the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> has not been determined by import penetration.
Even so, lean retailing practices pose both new opportunities and challenges for the textile industry. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Supplier</ENAMEX> relations in retail-apparel-textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> are shifting. Textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> no longer simply supply apparel<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX> with cloth; they may also sell a variety of household goods, such as sheets and towels, directly to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> or serve industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> with a wide range of products. Because product proliferation is the order of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> in all these markets, textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are being asked by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to provide many more products in smaller lot sizes and with shorter lead times. In the new competitive arena‚Äîwhere demand uncertainty and time to market have become important factors along with price‚Äîtextile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are being forced to adapt to information-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>, rather than just drawing on the economies of scale that led to their success in the past.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historical Relations Among Retail, Apparel</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Textile Firms</ENAMEX>
For most of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in one of these industries related to those in another through markets as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>. The business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> that emerged in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> retail, apparel, and textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> were, for the most part, separated. They weathered diverse competitive conditions; they differed markedly in their capital structures, costs of entry and exit, size and scale of operations, the proportion of direct labor costs, unionization, geographic locations, and so on. There was almost no vertical integration across retail, apparel, and textiles. For example, only a few major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> in men‚Äôs apparel have also entered into the retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business‚</ENAMEX>ÄîBond <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stores</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> era, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Schaffner</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> more recently‚Äîalthough <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi Strauss</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> of jeans, has opened some retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. As for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mass distributors</ENAMEX> have focused on buying and selling rather than manufacturing products.
No textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of woven goods has been a significant apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burlington Industries</ENAMEX>, sells directly to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that purchase uniforms for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, and fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>. It specifies in the sale that, regardless of the apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> used to fabricate uniforms, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burlington‚</ENAMEX>Äôs cloth must be used<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.42</NUMEX> Another major textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milliken</ENAMEX>, has a degree of common ownership with a retail business, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercantile</ENAMEX>, although these arrangements remain unusual.
Textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, however, have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in multiple supply <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major categories of sales <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> for these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) woven goods and some knit goods destined for clothing, in which materials are sold to apparel<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX> for fabrication and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) home furnishings‚Äîsuch as sheets, bedspreads, towels, and some knit goods‚Äîin which the textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> sells directly to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>; (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3)¬†industrial</ENAMEX> products, from automobile seat covers and rugs to commercial fishing nets, in which a textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> sells <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> to a car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nonapparel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>. Thus, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> kinds of relations among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX>, and multiple textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> are on the rise. Although apparel uses dominated textile consumption in the past, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX> apparel‚Äôs share of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX> consumption was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 37 percent</NUMEX>; home furnishings was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 38 percent</NUMEX>; and industrial textile products consumed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 20 percent</NUMEX>.
Textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springs</ENAMEX> have taken advantage of these new outlets‚Äîfor example, producing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>-character sheets for retail‚Äîbut a new dynamic is also developing with apparel<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX>, who want shorter runs of materials much more quickly from their textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>. Historically, the textile-apparel relationship involved long lead times or advance commitments to secure the necessary cloth in the right style, texture, and patterns. This occurred not only because of the greater concentration of businesses in the textile industry, but because textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> generally plan to run their expensive capital equipment at full capacity around the clock. Our research indicates that the relationships between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in the textile and apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> remain underdeveloped, with new competitive forces driving both sides to change.
Even if integration efforts in the past have been uncommon, information flows, transport, and inventory have always been decisive factors in shaping the relations among retail, apparel, and textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Chandler</ENAMEX> and other business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> have made clear, successive changes in information <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> and transport over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last century</TIMEX> have reshaped relations among industries, as well as the internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> notes,
Significantly, it was in several of these [labor-intensive] more fragmented industries‚Äîtextiles, apparel, furniture, and some food processing‚Äîthat the mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> (the department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, mail-order <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain stores</ENAMEX>) began to coordinate the flow of goods from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>. In those industries where substantial economies of scale and scope did not exist in production, high-volume flows through the processes of production and distribution came to be guided‚Äîand the resulting cost reductions achieved‚Äîby the buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> of mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> who handled a variety of related products through their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>.43
And so we arrive at the new information technologies of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. These have begun to create integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> industries, facilitating even more product proliferation and stimulating changes in merchandising, inventory management, internal production practices, and methods of using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human resources</ENAMEX>. When it comes to the driving force behind the late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twentieth-century</TIMEX> industrial transformation, lean retailing is at the forefront of that revolution.



