



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Dillard‚</ENAMEX>Äôs simple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">maxim1</ENAMEX> succinctly captures the central‚Äîand perennial‚Äîinventory challenge facing retail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. To make a sale, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> must have ‚Äúon its wagon‚Äù the product the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> wants. Absence of an item often translates into a lost sale and reduced revenues and profits. The magnitude of such lost sales for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> can be significant. For example, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">roughly 25 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> who entered a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macy‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> left without making a purchase because the product they were seeking was not available<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX> On the other hand, the retail ‚Äúwagon‚Äù should not be too full, since stocking retail shelves with unpopular items also results in excess <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">costs‚</ENAMEX>Äîthe cost of capital tied up in unwanted goods, the opportunity cost of the space that could be used for products that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> would buy if present, and, ultimately, lost margin when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> must resort to price markdowns or product disposal to clear languishing items from their shelves.
The main goal of retail inventory strategy is to maximize profitability by managing the inherent tension between stocking too much and stocking too little. Retail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> of old grappled with this problem as they do today. But as product variety has increased and product life cycles have shortened, this tension has become increasingly acute, prompting inventory management practices to evolve in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> to meet rapidly changing market demands. Although a seemingly mundane, tactical aspect of business, a firm‚Äôs inventory strategy reflects its approach to managing risk. Indeed, the inventory strategies chosen by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in a supply channel‚Äîand the congruence of those policies across channel partners‚Äîhave enormous implications for the channel‚Äôs speed, flexibility, and profitability.
Conceptually, retail inventory management is straightforward enough: Forecast demand for a product; order the product in the appropriate quantity; stock it in the right retail locations; keep track of its sales and the resulting inventory levels; and replenish its store inventories if possible (either from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> if it offers replenishment services for that product or from the retailer‚Äôs central <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> had purchased a large quantity of the product in advance of the selling season). In practice, however, retail inventory management is fraught with challenges, such as long and uncertain order-fulfillment lead times, and errors in product identification and record keeping. Consider, for instance, how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">store clerks</ENAMEX> still scan items incorrectly at the register. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> may purchase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> similar polo shirts in different colors or sizes, but because the price is the same for all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> may simply scan one of them <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three times‚</NUMEX>Äî-losing important information about consumer color and/or size preferences. Even without such obvious errors, forecasting demand at the SKU level has become difficult, as an ever wider array of products cycle through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. Many lean retailing practices are rooted in retailers‚Äô attempts to deal with growing demand uncertainty. In this environment, ordering large quantities of products far in advance of the selling season is simply too costly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Retailers</ENAMEX> now prefer to place relatively small orders before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> and then observe consumer response to the product offering before ordering more. As we described in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 4</ENAMEX>, many have transformed their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouses</ENAMEX> into modern distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> to facilitate the receipt and distribution of these smaller orders.
The forecasting and inventory models presented in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> are not new; they have been recommended for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statisticians</ENAMEX> and operations <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>.3 However, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> had neither the data collection and computing capabilities required to execute these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> effectively nor the tremendous impetus to implement them that lean retailing has precipitated. Because the effects of lean retailing are sweeping across many industries, it is imperative that everyone involved understand how inventory policies have been affected. This chapter covers the key steps in retail inventory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>: forecasting demand, choosing appropriate stocking strategies, and determining order quantities and frequencies. Although few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> have embraced the complete set of forecasting and inventory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> described in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> are moving in that direction.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retail Forecasting Challenge</ENAMEX>
We first turn to the problem of forecasting sales in retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. Imagine trying to predict how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> will walk into a particular downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> store <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> prepared to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$48</NUMEX> (full price) for a size-8 pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi</ENAMEX> blue jeans, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúlong‚Äù</ENAMEX> pant length, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúloose‚Äù</ENAMEX> fit, stonewashed finish, and a pleated waist‚Äîin other words, one particular SKU out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>. How will that compare to the number who would buy the same product but with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúshort‚Äù</ENAMEX> pant length? How does a retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> even begin to approach the problem of making forecasts at such a minute level of detail?
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> might start by trying to get historical data on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> sales of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi</ENAMEX> jeans in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. But wait‚Äîshould that be on the sales of those jeans throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greater Boston</ENAMEX> area? Should the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> base her prediction on sales of only this particular size and style or would it be more accurate to look at the sales of all jeans in this style and then multiply by the percent of all jean styles sold that were size-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> long? Maybe she should restrict herself to this year‚Äôs data to ensure that it is as current as possible. On the other hand, one would hate to lose the information that might be contained in past years‚Äô selling patterns.
The complexity of the problem, even for basic blue jeans, is staggering. Now consider the same exercise for a new dress style not previously available at retail‚Äîperhaps a style that gained attention when worn by a controversial film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> at the most recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy Awards</ENAMEX> ceremony. How many of these dresses will sell <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX>? Specifically, how many will sell in a dark-peach tone in size <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>?
If the challenge of making such predictions for this season‚Äôs sales is not sufficiently daunting, try predicting how many of each item will sell during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given period next year</TIMEX>.The impossibility of making -accurate predictions of demand long in advance of the selling season‚Äîespecially at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> level‚Äîis clear. But because products are manufactured and ordered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX>, some attempt must be made to forecast demand at that level. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> have to make demand forecasts for products in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different categories: existing products for which historical sales data are available and new products with no selling history. The following section discusses the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> category and provides general background on the elements of a demand forecast. It is followed by a short discussion of new product forecasting.
Forecasting Demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Products</ENAMEX> with a Selling History
Creating a forecast for a product that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> has sold in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> starts with collecting and analyzing historical selling data. Those data provide insight into historical trends and suggest how the product‚Äôs sales are related to other factors like weather, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX>, special advertising campaigns, general economic indicators, or simply the passage of time. Air conditioners sell in greater quantities during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer months</TIMEX>, for example, neckties just before <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Father‚Äôs Day</ENAMEX>, and consumer electronics when the economy is booming. Once these relationships are understood, predictions of future sales can be made, although a high level of uncertainty is always involved. Before discussing how one might analyze the trends in historical data, it is important to recognize <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> often overlooked aspects of demand forecasting.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Caveats About Forecasting</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> of all, a product‚Äôs selling history is only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of future sales if the product is sold in a stable environment. For the blue jeans discussed above, the selling environment will remain stable as long as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> do not introduce competing products that draw from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Levi‚Äôs</ENAMEX> demand; fashion preferences do not change; a new, more desirable type of denim is not introduced that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> prefer; and the economy does not dip into a recession. However, even for a basic product like blue jeans, it is unlikely that all these assumptions will hold. Given the volatile nature of demand in many industries, an assumption of stability is suspect, meaning that forecasts based on historical sales data may be less accurate than the historical data suggest. Consequently, lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> prefer to forecast demand, set target inventory levels, and place orders on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> basis, because the selling environment is much more likely to be stable into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next week</TIMEX> than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> into the future.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> gather sales data, not demand data. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Customers</ENAMEX> rarely inform the sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> in a typical retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> if a desired product is out of stock; they either buy a different product or leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> without making a purchase. Direct-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, such as catalog <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and those that sell via television or the Internet, are important exceptions. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> must write, call, or e-mail these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> with a specific purchase request, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are able to capture actual consumer demand rather than sales numbers alone. Such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> can also gather data about customer demographics, past purchases, and responses to potential substitute <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">items</ENAMEX>, all of which add up to a gold mine of information about consumer preferences<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>
In fact, the value of such data may induce traditional store <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> to offer incentives for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to share their demand preferences, even when the product is not available in stock. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1990s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nordstrom</ENAMEX> ran newspaper ads promising, for certain products, that if the size or color of an item the customer wished to purchase was not in stock at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nordstrom</ENAMEX> would locate the desired item and mail it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> at no additional cost‚Äîboth the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> and its delivery were free. (Not surprisingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nordstrom</ENAMEX> limited this offer to a small number of basic styles and sizes and to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> item per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>.) The only thing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> had to do was tell a sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> what he or she wanted.
This approach has benefits on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> fronts: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> avoids a lost sale and its associated margin; a potentially dissatisfied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> is delighted by the store‚Äôs additional service and free product; and last, but certainly not least, for a very small fee‚Äîthe wholesale cost of the product and shipping fees‚ÄîNordstrom gains critical information about consumer demand. Without such programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> may find it difficult to judge how demand is faring after a product stocks out at the retail <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> and therefore may have trouble making sensible reordering decisions.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> caveat to bear in mind is that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúpoint forecast‚Äù</ENAMEX> (a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX>) alone has relatively low value. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> forecasts that customer demand for size-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi</ENAMEX> jeans <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> in one of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> pairs, what does that mean? Will exactly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> pairs sell? Is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> the most likely number to sell‚Äîor will at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> pairs sell? A forecast consisting only of a single number provides no indication of the degree of uncertainty.
Indeed, the purpose of the forecasting process is to provide a basis for deciding how many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> of a given product should be shipped to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> to minimize the costs‚Äîthat is, risks‚Äîof over- and undersupply. But risk exists precisely because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> are uncertain about what demand will be for their products. Therefore, to provide a useful basis for making decisions that minimize risk, a forecast should include an explicit assessment of the relative likelihood of different demand levels occurring. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> might capture this information by saying that there is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> probability that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand for size-8 jeans in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> will fall <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between two</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seventeen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúexpected value‚Äù</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> units. She might add that there is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> probability that demand will fall <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between six</NUMEX> and thirteen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.1</NUMEX> shows a demand distribution having these properties. (Note that there is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> chance that demand will be less than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seventeen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> next week‚Äîthus, if our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> decides to stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">seventeen units</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the beginning of the week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> should be able to offer a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> order fulfillment rate on this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX>.) It is only with such probabilistic forecasts, which explicitly characterize uncertainty, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> can make inventory stocking decisions that minimize risk.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Components of Historical Demand Data</ENAMEX>
With these caveats in mind, let‚Äôs assume our store <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> has representative historical demand data for blue jeans for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>. She will first analyze the historical data by separating the causes of past changes in demand into the following categories: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) trend, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) seasonality, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) cyclicality, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) random fluctuation<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX>
The trend in demand data describes a medium- to long-term growth or decline. Such trends occur in all industries and can be steadily increasing, steadily decreasing, or varying over time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seasonality</ENAMEX> describes within<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-year</TIMEX> trends that are associated with the season of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> and that occur <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year after year</TIMEX>. For example, Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.2</NUMEX> shows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand for men‚Äôs dress shirts at a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>: There are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> peaks in demand at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Father‚Äôs Day</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, when many shirts are bought as gifts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyclicality</ENAMEX> in demand describes longer-term, gradual rises and declines that are typically associated with aggregate business activity. For example, demand for new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> tends to increase during times of economic prosperity and decrease during recessionary periods.
The final component of a demand distribution, random fluctuation, is perhaps the most critical; it is also the most difficult to assess and incorporate into inventory planning. Essentially, random fluctuation in demand cannot be explained by trends, seasonality, cyclicality, or other factors like advertising and new product introduction. Examine Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.2</NUMEX>. In addition to the seasonal trend associated with major holidays, random fluctuation in shirt sales occurred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from week to week</TIMEX>. For our purposes, note that high demand fluctuation decreases one‚Äôs ability to forecast demand accurately.
Building a Demand Forecast
After completing an analysis of how different factors relate to past demand fluctuations, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> can draw inferences about what future demand for women‚Äôs blue jeans might be in her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.6 In this case we assume a stable environment: specifically, that past relationships among variables are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of future relationships among those variables. Although this may not be a realistic assumption for many situations, it makes it easier to understand the fundamentals of demand forecasting here.
Let‚Äôs assume that the store‚Äôs demand for the size-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi‚</ENAMEX>Äôs jeans <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> can be described by the distribution in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Let‚Äôs</ENAMEX> also assume that the average demand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX> has been growing at a rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 1 percent</NUMEX>, so that the average demand for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next week</TIMEX> should be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10*</TIMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.01</NUMEX>) = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following week</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 10*</TIMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.01</NUMEX>)<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, and so on. Then the expected (average) demand is the solid black trend line shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.3</NUMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> could incorporate demand uncertainty into the forecast by indicating different possible values of demand, and the likelihood of that actual demand will fall within those values. For example, in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.3</NUMEX>, the lines directly above and below the solid trend line indicate a range of demand for which the likelihood of demand falling within that range is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>. The lines further from the trend line indicate the range with a likelihood of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX>. Thus, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 1</TIMEX>, there is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> probability that demand will be between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> and -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seventeen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, exactly as depicted in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.1</NUMEX>. Predicting what -<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> will do when they walk into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> will always be challenging, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> can be confident that if she stocks seventeen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the next week</TIMEX>, she has a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> probability of meeting all consumer demand on this product.
Forecasting Demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Products</ENAMEX>
Of course, when a product has just been launched and no historical data exist on which to base a forecast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> confront additional challenges. In this case, most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies resort</ENAMEX> to informal forecasting methods. A common approach is to forecast ‚Äúby analogy,<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äùusing</ENAMEX> data for similar products that have been on the market previously. One might assume, for example, that sales for this year‚Äôs new fashion will be similar to those for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last year‚</TIMEX>Äôs new fashion. This is clearly a subjective call; but once made, it gives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> a basis for predicting demand patterns for a new product.
Obviously, forecasting demand for new products accurately requires a broad understanding of consumer preferences and market trends. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Obermeyer</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raman</ENAMEX> have introduced a method that proved successful in predicting demand for new fashion skiwear as part of an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúAccurate Response‚</ENAMEX>Äù forecasting and planning approach<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX> This approach combined individual forecasts by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the company‚Äôs Buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>, creating a probabilistic forecast whose uncertainty was determined by the level of agreement among forecasts made by individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. Statistical analysis showed that those garments for which the Buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> had the greatest disagreement were indeed those with the greatest demand uncertainty. The skiwear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> has credited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accurate Response</ENAMEX> approach with increasing its profits by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly two-thirds.8</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Impact of Product Variety</ENAMEX> on Forecast Uncertainty
The forecasting challenges <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> confront have been amplified in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> by product proliferation in almost every category. As a result, demand forecast uncertainty has grown substantially, thereby increasing the level of inventory that must be held to meet customer service requirements. High demand uncertainty, previously associated only with fashion products, is now pervasive, characterizing even those items once regarded as basics‚Äîsuch as power tools, industrial seals, men‚Äôs dress shirts, and blue jeans.
A good rule of thumb for understanding how product proliferation affects demand uncertainty is that the demand uncertainty for a product category increases as the square root of the number of products in the category (assuming that the total demand for the product category remains unchanged and that the individual items in the category have demand distributions that are statistically independent and identically distributed). A common standardized measure of demand uncertainty, the coefficient of variation (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cv</ENAMEX>)‚Äîdefined as the standard deviation of the demand distribution divided by the mean of the demand distribution‚Äîfor a specific product is proportional to the square root of the number of products offered<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.9</NUMEX> For example, increasing the number of products offered in a category by a factor of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> (say from fifty items to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>) without increasing total demand in the category would increase the coefficient of variation for each individual product by a factor of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. And, as we‚Äôll see in the next section, doubling the demand uncertainty roughly doubles the amount of finished goods required to provide the same level of product availability in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.
Therefore, product variety is costly due to the increased demand uncertainty associated with each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Retailers</ENAMEX> thus must either limit product variety or change their way of doing business so as to minimize the impact of high variety. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lean</ENAMEX> retailing is the major such change that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> are adopting to reduce significantly the costs associated with product variety.
Setting Inventory Levels in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Store</ENAMEX>
After completing the process of developing a demand forecast for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> must determine how much of each item to stock on the shelves of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Retailers</ENAMEX> have an incentive to stock high levels of inventory: They want both to provide sufficient display stock to attract customers‚Äîempty shelves are not inviting‚Äîand to have products available for those who wish to purchase them. Yet carrying inventory is expensive: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Retailers</ENAMEX> pay capital costs for having their money tied up in inventory, for the physical floor space necessary to store goods, and for handling, managing, and monitoring the inventory<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.10</NUMEX> Most important, they pay a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúrisk premium‚Äù</ENAMEX> for carrying products that might become obsolete, either because they are damaged or fall out of fashion.
A retailer‚Äôs decision about what to stock will depend on a variety of considerations, including the demand forecast for the product, the level of product availability it wishes to provide to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, the frequency with which it will place replenishment orders, and the lead time to acquire replenishment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. We‚Äôll describe later in this chapter how these factors affect retail inventory policy. A number of other straightforward costs are associated with any inventory stocking policy, such as the cost of ordering and transporting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX>; the cost of determining inventory levels; and the impact on purchase price of any quantity price discounts.
In order to evaluate the performance of different inventory options, it is important to emphasize the less straightforward costs involved. Take the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> primary types of inventory ‚Äúerrors‚Äù a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> can make: stocking too much of an item the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> does not want and stocking too little of something the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> does want. Although the categories for the costs of mismatched supply and demand are simple in concept, in reality they are difficult to measure accurately. Evaluating forced markdown costs is hard, for example, because one must separate markdowns made for promotional reasons from those made to liquidate stock that cannot be sold at full price. The difficulty of measuring these costs is further exacerbated by the fact that a given product may be attractive to different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> at different prices, so determining the appropriate ‚Äúfull price‚Äù for a product is not an easy task.
Stock-out costs are also complex. To determine the magnitude of a stock-out cost for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, one must understand consumer behavior. Will the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> buy a substitute <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> if a particular item is out of stock or return to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later date</TIMEX> to purchase the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> when it is again in stock? In these cases, stock-out costs are minimal. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> may leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> because a desired item was not in stock, thereby not purchasing anything else; that means the stock-out cost would equal the margin on all the products the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> would have otherwise purchased. In the most extreme case, a stock-out might cause a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> to switch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, costing the lifetime value of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> and others who might defect due to negative word-of-mouth.
In addition, it is useful to divide the items <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> order into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>: those for which additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> can be obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> during the selling season for that product and those that cannot‚Äîthat is, replenishable products versus nonreplenishables. This distinction matters, because inventory management differs for products in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> categories. All else being equal, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> would prefer to have replenishment opportunities for every product. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lean</ENAMEX> retailers‚Äô rapid replenishment arrangements radically reduce the risk of undersupply‚Äîthe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> can essentially ‚Äúcorrect‚Äù for those items that it ordered too little of prior to the start of the season‚Äîand of oversupply, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> orders smaller initial quantities. In contrast, orders for nonreplenishable products must be placed in full prior to observing consumer demand for the product. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> ‚Äúrolls the dice‚Äù and makes its entire order commitment based on preliminary demand forecasts, considerably increasing the risk of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>- or undersupply.
Inventory Models for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonreplenishable Products</ENAMEX>
When a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> has no ability to replenish a product, the inventory decision is reduced to a single question: How many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> of the item should a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> order to maximize that product‚Äôs profitability? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Retailer managers</ENAMEX> are relying less and less on their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúgut‚Äù</ENAMEX> and past experience; lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> are increasingly using more sophisticated statistical models, even in the risky realm of nonreplenishables, to help guide stocking decisions. In this section we review briefly the well-known ‚Äúnews-vendor‚Äù problem to illustrate the basic trade-offs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> must make when determining inventory stocking levels<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX>
To determine the optimal quantity for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> finds the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> to order so that the expected marginal cost of stocking an additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> and not being able to sell it equals the expected marginal cost of not stocking that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> when it would have sold if available. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathematically</ENAMEX>, this relationship translates as follows.
Find the optimal inventory stocking quantity, Q*, that satisfies the relationship:
[Probability the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cannot be sold)](<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX>) =
[Probability the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> could have been sold](<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cu</ENAMEX>),
that is [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prob</ENAMEX>(D<Q*)](Co) =[Prob(D‚â•Q*)](Cu).
where Q* = the optimal order quantity
D = demand for the product
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX> = cost of oversupply
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cu</ENAMEX> = cost of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">under</NUMEX>-supply
At the simplest level, the optimal stocking policy for nonreplenishable goods is to stock the quantity (Q*) that satisfies [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prob</ENAMEX>(D<Q*)] =(Cu)/(Cu+Co). For=example, suppose=a retailer=can purchase=a dress=for $200=that it=sells for=$440. Suppose=also that=if the=retailer stocks=too many=of these=dresses, it=can only=sell the=leftovers for=$120 each.=In this=case, the=cost of=oversupply comes=to $80=$200 ‚Äì=$120 because=the retailer=loses that=much on=every leftover=dress. Conversely,=the retailer=loses $240=$440 ‚Äì=$200 whenever=it stocks=out of=a dress=that a=customer would=have purchased=at full=price. According=to the=model, the=retailer should=purchase the=quantity Q*=that will=yield [Prob(D<Q*)]=240/(240+80) =240/320 =.75‚Äîthat is,=a 75=percent probability=that demand=for the=dress will=be less=than the=quantity purchased.</txt>=<txt>With this analysis completed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> must next forecast demand for the dress at the SKU level. A sample demand forecast for the dress appears in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.4</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> should order <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, since there is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> probability that demand will be less than this. Note that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> would be ordering more than she expects to sell (the mean value of the distribution, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX>). This makes sense, because the margins on these dresses are high relative to the cost of buying additional dresses and having to dispose of them below cost.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Inventory Model</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Replenishable Products</ENAMEX>
Although determining an inventory policy for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nonreplenishable products</ENAMEX> continues to be an issue for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, inventory decisions that involve replenishables have undergone the most change with the advent of lean retailing. Indeed, many products sold in retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>, particularly basic and fashion-basic items, can now be replenished after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the start of the selling season</TIMEX>. The jagged heavy line in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.5</NUMEX> (page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>) depicts a typical inventory pattern for a replenishable product like our blue jeans in size <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Note that the inventory level drops gradually as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> purchase the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX>. Once a week, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> places a replenishment order with its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> and receives a shipment. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 17 and 24</TIMEX>, the replenishment order arrives in time to restock the inventory before selling out; however, during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week of July 24</TIMEX>, high demand led to rapid depletion of stock, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> stocks out of the product prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the week</TIMEX>.
To understand this product‚Äôs inventory requirements, it helps to divide the inventory into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX>: cycle stock, which is held to cover expected demand for the product; and safety stock, which is held to cover higher than expected demand. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.5</NUMEX> breaks out these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> components of stock. The straight dashed lines show the inventory pattern that would result if there were no variation in demand‚Äîthat is, if exactly the same number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> were bought <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>. Specifically, the dashed lines indicate the inventory pattern that would result if demand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX> were equal to the average, or expected, demand. In the figure, cycle stock is the amount of stock necessary to meet average demand. Below the cycle stock sits the safety stock, a buffer that is held for those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> (such as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 24</TIMEX>) in which demand exceeds the average. If there were no uncertainty in demand, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> would need no safety stock. But the higher the demand uncertainty, the more safety stock is required to ensure a low probability of stocking out.
As Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.6</NUMEX> shows, the safety stock needed to achieve a given customer service level is proportional to the standard deviation of the demand forecast<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.12</NUMEX> Simply put, the less certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> are of the demand for their product, the more safety stock they must hold to meet consumer needs. In the figure, we assume that the order-fulfillment rate equals <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">97 percent</NUMEX> and the order-fulfillment lead time is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX>. The parameter choices for the figures, although based on data from actual apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, are for illustrative purposes only. By reducing order-fulfillment lead times, lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> are able to reduce the level of safety stock required to deal effectively with a given level of demand variation.
Because safety stock is directly dependent on demand uncertainty, increasing product variety increases retail safety-stock requirements. For example, when the coefficient of variation increases from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.5 to 1.0‚Äîwhich</NUMEX> would happen if the number of products offered increased by a factor of four‚Äîthe amount of finished goods required to provide the desired service level doubles. Formally, one determines safety-stock levels by weighing the costs of having too much inventory (overstocking) with the costs of having too little (understocking), in much the same way as we did for nonreplenishables.
From the retailer‚Äôs point of view, the only way to mitigate the effects of increased demand uncertainty is to have frequent replenishment opportunities, in which replenishment orders can be filled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> with very short lead times. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 7</ENAMEX> examines what this entails from the manufacturer‚Äôs perspective. At this point, however, we will introduce the standard inventory model that many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> use for rapid replenishment items, considering the implications of demand uncertainty raised above.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">s</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>) Models: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traditional Inventory Policy</ENAMEX> for Replenishables
A standard inventory policy for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> proceeds as follows: At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of every week</TIMEX>, check the inventory of your product. If the inventory has fallen below a stated amount, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">s</ENAMEX>, termed the reorder point, place an order for more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. The amount ordered should be sufficient so that the number of units on hand plus those that are on order equal some ‚Äúmaximum‚Äù stocking quantity, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> For a particular item, our store <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> may reorder when the inventory level falls below s equals <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, in a quantity that brings the current inventory up to S equals <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. With this policy in place, if at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of a day</TIMEX> she notes that inventory has dropped to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, she would order <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> more, as shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.7</NUMEX>. The parameter <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> in this model refers to the length of the time period between inventory status checks; in this case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> checks inventory <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>, so <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 days</TIMEX>.
Note that there is a short delivery lead time from the time the order is placed: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> during the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cycles shown in the figure, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> cycle. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> typically are sold during the delivery lead time, the actual inventory in stock rarely reaches <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. Instead, at the time of ordering, inventory in stock plus that on order equals <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. But if order lead times are long, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> must order up to a larger number S to meet demand during the replenishment lead time. Once again, if lead times are uncertain, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> must hold additional safety stock to meet demand in the event of an unusually long lead time. It can be shown that high variability in lead time means higher costs for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> than somewhat longer, but more reliable lead times; that is, it may be better to have a longer reliable lead time than an unpredictable one with a shorter average duration<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.14</NUMEX> The lean retailing policies described previously attempt to reduce both average lead times and lead-time variability through the imposition, for example, of penalties for late deliveries.
We noted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> that a retailer‚Äôs decision about how much to stock depends on the demand forecast for the product, the level of product availability it wishes to provide to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, the frequency with which it will place replenishment orders, and the lead time to acquire replenishment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. Let‚Äôs see how these factors would combine to create a stocking policy for our size-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> blue jeans. We continue to assume that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> has the weekly demand distribution shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.1</NUMEX> (page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX>). Assume that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> wishes to provide a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> order-fulfillment rate for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX>, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> checks inventory once per week, and that the manufacturer‚Äôs lead time to deliver replenishment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>. (This last assumption is unrealistic in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many situations15</TIMEX>; we choose it only to simplify the exposition. It is not difficult to extend this analysis to the case in which the replenishment lead time is longer.) Finally, we assume that like most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> replenishes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX> exactly the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> that sold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous week</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Formally</ENAMEX>, this translates into an (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">s</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>) policy with s = <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S¬†‚Äì¬†1</ENAMEX>: that is, if the current stock is S ‚<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Äì 1</NUMEX> or less, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> orders S <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äì s.</ENAMEX>)
Given the desired <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> service level, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> should set a target stock level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seventeen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. Thus, the retail replenishment system would check the stock of these jeans every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>; if the current stock is thirteen pairs of size-8 jeans (meaning that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> sold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous week</TIMEX>), then it would automatically order <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> more pairs, bringing the amount of this SKU up to its target level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seventeen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. This order would be combined with other replenishment orders for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi</ENAMEX> jeans destined for the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, thereby reducing shipping costs<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.16</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Periodic Versus Continuous Review</ENAMEX>
The policy described above involves what is known as periodic review. After a fixed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">period of time</TIMEX> (e.g., <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> checks the inventory level. If the level of inventory is less than the specified reorder point s, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> ‚Äúorders up to‚Äù the specified level S. This is still the most common practice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
An alternative approach offers continuous review‚Äîor an (s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>) model‚Äîin which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> continuously checks the inventory level. The moment the level hits s, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> orders up to a specified quantity S. Unlike a periodic-review policy, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> may order when the inventory level is less than s, with a continuous-review policy, they always order when the inventory equals <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">s. Thus</ENAMEX>, under a continuous-review policy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> always order the same quantity (Q = S ‚Äì s) but after a variable amount of time since the last order was placed. Conversely, under periodic review, they order after a fixed length of time, but the quantity differs because it depends on the amount that is in stock when inventory was checked each period. Use of continuous review allows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> to achieve a higher service level with a lower amount of inventory. By monitoring the inventory continuously, they ensure that it never falls below s before placing an order.
The choice of which <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> to use depends on a number of factors. Prior to the use of bar codes, implementation of a continuous-review policy at retail was nearly impossible because it was extraordinarily difficult to keep track of actual inventory levels on a continuous basis<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.17</NUMEX> Today bar codes and retail information systems allow access to stocking levels on a continuous basis, but most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> choose to use periodic review systems to restrict ordering activities to set times of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>; that way, they can save on transportation and other costs by ordering multiple products from the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX> at the same time.
Finally, a complete economic analysis of the appropriate parameters for an (s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>) or (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">s</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>) policy must include consideration of some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúsofter‚Äù</ENAMEX> costs and benefits of inventory. A retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> may choose to stock more of a product than indicated by an economic analysis because she believes that more stock is necessary to attract the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> and sustain the desired level of sales. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> have been hampered in their efforts to reduce in-store stocking levels by the size and shape of the fixtures in which their products are displayed. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fixture</ENAMEX> was designed to hold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> shirts of a particular color and size, for instance, it is both wasteful of space and visually unappealing to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> shirts out‚Äîeven if an economic analysis recommends the lower quantity. In fact, many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> have introduced new fixtures with smaller slots for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> (or flexible slot sizes) that can hold a more economically desirable quantity of stock without sacrificing pleasing appearance.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Vendor-Managed Inventory</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most significant changes in retail inventory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> has been the introduction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX>-managed inventory¬†(VMI) programs, also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continuous Replenishment Programs</ENAMEX> (CRP) or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Continuous Product Replenishment</ENAMEX> (CPR). These programs involve having either the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> together determine desired inventory stocking levels for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">manufacturer‚Äôs product</ENAMEX> in the retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. After these ‚Äúmodel stock‚Äù levels are set, data about product sales and current retail inventory levels are transmitted electronically to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> then decides how much to ship‚Äîand, in many cases, when to ship‚Äîto the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> in such a way that its own costs of manufacturing and shipping are minimized while still meeting retail inventory policy requirements. Typically, these programs result in the frequent delivery of small quantities of items to the retailer‚Äîit would not be uncommon for a blue jeans <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> to ship a carton of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one dozen</NUMEX> blue jeans of mixed styles and sizes to a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.
The benefits of such policies are significant. In the grocery industry, the implementation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VMI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> has been shown to increase retail inventory turns from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent to 100 percent</NUMEX> over those achieved prior to implementation, even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> had previously used electronic data interchange for communication of retail orders.18 The advantage of using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VMI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> stems from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> working together to determine a flow of shipments that optimizes the economics of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> as a system. Otherwise, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> make independent decisions that myopically optimize their own profits, without complete consideration of the impact these decisions may have on other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>.19
A few caveats are in order, however. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCTAR‚Äôs</ENAMEX> survey, the incidence of retail model stock programs increased significantly over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1988‚Äì1992</TIMEX> period, from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent to 16 percent</NUMEX> of total volume shipped by the business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in our sample (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.1</NUMEX>, page¬<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">†73</NUMEX>). But there was a much smaller increase in the prevalence of model stock programs governed by apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>, reflecting the dominance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> in instigating new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> relationships as well as the reluctance of most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> to control merchandise on the shelf. As in all cases where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> might benefit the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> involved, real-world considerations‚Äîwho has the most power, who is responsible for instigating change, who will make the initial investments‚Äîoften slow integration.
Managing Inventory in a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lean Retailing Environment</ENAMEX>
The new world of rapid replenishment implies additional capabilities for both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> must be able to gather and synthesize point-of-sales data quickly to determine what has sold and then update its demand forecast for the product accordingly. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> must deliver the ordered product quickly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>. As we describe in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 7</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> have essentially two choices in supplying replenishables. They can hold finished products in inventory, thereby reducing their processing requirements during the replenishment lead time to picking, packing, and shipping the order. However, this approach increases the risk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>: It has to commit to holding finished goods of a product for which it has little or no consumer demand information<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.20</NUMEX>
The alternative is to adopt quick-response manufacturing strategies that allow items to be produced to order. But given the increasingly short lead times dictated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> (often just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX>), most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> cannot produce in this way<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">.21 Therefore</ENAMEX>, it is not surprising that most replenishment products are basics or fashion-basics with relatively stable demand: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manufacturers</ENAMEX> are unwilling to hold speculative stock to meet replenishment requests from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> for fashion products because the risk of holding those fashion goods in finished goods inventory is too high.
Ironically, replenishment capabilities would be of most value to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> for fashion products, but because of their short product lives and the unpredictability of demand, fashion products are typically not offered on a replenishment basis. From the apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier‚</ENAMEX>Äôs perspective, that‚Äôs a good thing‚Äîat least for the time being. As the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> will make clear, the demands of lean retailing have already created plenty of inventory challenges for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>.



