



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Retailers‚Äô</ENAMEX> calls to apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late</TIMEX> delivery are the basis for many a tall tale at retail conventions. In the past, the standard reply to a query about what had happened to an order was ‚ÄúIt‚Äôs on the loading dock.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù Information</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> at apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> were primitive. If all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> for an order were not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX>, substitutions of the same style in a different size would be offered to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>. Or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> might not even notice if an unplanned substitution had been made because their information systems were equally as primitive. If there were insufficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> of the requested style, the order would be shorted or a phone call made to the retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> to negotiate a solution to the problem. If no SKUs of the order were in the finished goods <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX>, then the search of the factory floor‚Äîwhere there might be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of partially completed items to look through‚Äîwould begin.
Then along came lean retailing and the need for rapid replenishment‚Äîmanufacturers are now expected to replenish products in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than a week</TIMEX>. At first, only a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> required this, and apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> tried to meet these needs with minimal changes in their internal practices. Often, this was done at the expense of a manufacturer‚Äôs non-lean retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of a men‚Äôs dress<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-shirt supplier</ENAMEX> reported to us in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> that its finished goods warehouse was divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> areas. A locked section contained finished goods reserved for orders from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dillard‚Äôs, Inc.</ENAMEX>, this manufacturer‚Äôs biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> and its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> with stringent rapid-replenishment requirements. The rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> held inventory for all other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. If the locked section had insufficient inventory for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dillard‚</ENAMEX>Äôs order, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> from the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> could be picked and sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dillard‚Äôs</ENAMEX>, but no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> could receive products from the locked section reserved for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dillard‚Äôs</ENAMEX>, no matter how severe their needs. This arrangement worked well from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dillard‚</ENAMEX>Äôs perspective; it found this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> to be one of its best rapid-replenishment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>, with high order-fulfillment rates and on-time deliveries‚Äîthe main criteria for success. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>, it meant a larger finished goods inventory and worse service for its other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>.
As long as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one or two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> required rapid replenishment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> could get away with this type of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX>. But it didn‚Äôt take long before most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> wanted orders for basic apparel items replenished this way and they became very demanding. As an increasing number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> are dancing to the demands of rapid replenishment, they are finding it a complex tune. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Manufacturers</ENAMEX> suddenly have much more to do than just make clothing‚Äîthey are being asked to do work previously done by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>, such as picking and packing the order for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">retailer‚Äôs warehouse</ENAMEX>. Each store‚Äôs order has to be put in a separate carton, labeled with its own bar code, and accompanied by an advance shipping notice. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> want an order to arrive at their distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> at an exact time. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> is late, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> often has to wait until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX> to unload, if allowed to do so at all. Deliveries made a day late are sometimes refused and sent back.
Such retail requirements have certainly put substantial pressure on apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to change their own practices. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 5</ENAMEX> described some of the basic changes many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> are making to stay in the game with lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. But even if lean retailing has led to suppliers‚Äô wide-scale adoption of bar codes and EDI-related capabilities, divergent production strategies among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> have emerged. Conceivably, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> could each meet the same lean retailing requirements yet have very different internal practices and performance. One could raise finished goods inventories substantially (like the dress<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-shirt manufacturer</ENAMEX> described above); the other could make crucial operational changes to reduce manufacturing lead times. However, in light of the growth of rapid replenishment, our research predicts that the performance of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> units will vary over time, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> that has implemented flexible planning and short-cycle production processes coming out ahead. By investing in these practices, apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> have the potential to satisfy lean retailing performance standards without bearing the costs of greatly expanded inventory in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. From our standpoint, holding high inventories to meet rapid replenishment demands is strictly a short-term strategy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>.
The increasing emphasis on rapid replenishment raises a related question: can offshore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> meet retailers‚Äô requirements for such short delivery lead times and so many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX>? More specifically, what are the characteristics of products for which inexpensive, long lead-time production is preferable to more costly production with extremely short lead times? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> and analyses presented in this chapter help shed light on this critical question.
We begin this chapter with an overview of the impact of demand variability on a manufacturer‚Äôs own inventory and production planning processes. Next, we describe how apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> can use statistical analysis and simulation to gain insight into inventory planning and production scheduling for products they offer in their rapid replenishment collections. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> case studies illustrates how demand uncertainty affects a firm‚Äôs target inventory levels. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> case study demonstrates how short-cycle production translates into inventory reduction for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>, thereby radically reducing the increased exposure to inventory risk a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> would otherwise face to meet lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">retailers‚</ENAMEX>Äô demands. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> concludes by emphasizing the relationships among demand volatility, manufacturing lead times, and inventory levels, addressing a critical decision apparel manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> face <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: Given <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, with different variable production costs and lead times, how does a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> decide which products to make in each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>?
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Key Role</ENAMEX> of Demand Variability
The most important thing we are doing is ‚Äúconsumerization,‚Äù to be the best in the business in delivering products customized for what the consumer wants. All of our initiatives are to drive consumer value. And as we reduce costs, we reinvest those savings in improving our consumer responsiveness<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄîMackey McDonald</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF Corporation</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
Because being responsive to consumer tastes is central to lean retailing, dealing with variability in demand has become crucial to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> competing in a lean retailing world. Even for basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX>, demand varies from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day and week to week</TIMEX>. Thus, if a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> follows the simplest strategy of ordering at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of each week</TIMEX> exactly those items that sold during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> must be prepared to ship an unknown number of items <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX>. Very few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> can produce items in production quantities in the limited lead time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> allow for replenishment and consequently they must fill such orders from finished goods inventory. And, as one would expect, the higher the variation in week-to-week demand, the more inventory a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> must hold to meet a retailer‚Äôs high service expectations.
Because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand variability is a key determinant of the finished inventory a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> must hold, each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> should conduct an assessment of the demand variability of each item in the product line<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Retailers</ENAMEX> require orders to be filled at the SKU level, so such demand variability analyses should be conducted at the SKU level as well.
We conducted such an analysis of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> of men‚Äôs coats, suits, and blazers. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.1</NUMEX> depicts the weekly demand for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU‚</ENAMEX>Äîa single-breasted coat in one of the firm‚Äôs most popular sizes (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">regular</NUMEX>)‚Äîduring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first twenty-four weeks of the year</TIMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">week‚Äôs</ENAMEX> demand has been divided by the average demand over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty-four weeks</TIMEX>; therefore, the average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand is simply equal to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> on this normalized scale. (The important features of demand for scheduling coat production are contained in demand data presented in this normalized fashion. Normalizing the data also allows us to keep this manufacturer‚Äôs actual demand volume confidential without obscuring the central information contained in the data.)
Plotting the data in this way allows us to focus on the deviation of the weekly demand from the average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.2</NUMEX> depicts the weekly demand for a different SKU‚Äîthe same single-breasted coat‚Äîbut this time in a less popular size (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">regular</NUMEX>). Again, the normalized data highlights the weekly deviation from the average demand. In this case, there is greater week-to-week variation than for the more popular size.
The amount of variation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand exhibited in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.2</NUMEX> is quite remarkable, especially if we consider that the manufacturer‚Äôs demand is based on the total sales of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a thousand</NUMEX> retail <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX>. It is important to note also that this product was not promoted at retail with discounted prices at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">any time</TIMEX> during this period, so the variation is not due to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> preferring to purchase a product when it was ‚Äúon sale.‚Äù In addition, the demand peak for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>-regular occurs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 10</TIMEX>, which was only an average demand week for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">regular</NUMEX>.
It is useful to outline the ordering and manufacturing processes on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> basis to see how this manufacturer‚Äôs inventory policies might differ for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different sizes. Suppose that, as described in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 6</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> consolidates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POS</ENAMEX> data for the previous week‚Äôs sales <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and places a replenishment order with our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) processes the order; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) picks and packs the desired items from finished goods inventory and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) places a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> order to manufacture those items that it shipped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>. Assume that the manufacturing lead time‚Äîthe amount of time required to go from a production order to a product ready for shipping to retail‚Äîis <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than one week</TIMEX>. Then, by the following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the items ordered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous week</TIMEX> would be completed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> and available in the manufacturer‚Äôs finished goods inventory. At this point, the manufacturer‚Äôs inventory is restored to the ‚Äútarget‚Äù level it had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous week</TIMEX> and is ready to fill the next week‚Äôs retail <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">replenishment</ENAMEX> order.
For the popular <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>-regular coat, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand never exceeds twice the coat‚Äôs average demand. Thus, as long as the lead time for producing more coats in size <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>-regular is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than a week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> could hold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">weeks‚Äô</ENAMEX> worth of inventory and be able to fill‚Äîimmediately‚Äîretail orders that replenish the previous week‚Äôs demand. That is, it could set a target stock level of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> of finished goods inventory and be able to provide a very high customer service level (defined here as order-fulfillment rate) to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>.
However, for the low volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>-regular, the maximum <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> times the average. To provide the same service level to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> for both sizes, our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> must hold twice as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many weeks</TIMEX> of demand of finished goods for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>-regular than for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">regular</NUMEX>. Note that we are comparing the inventory levels in terms of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of average demand, which measures the ratio of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> of finished goods to average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> sales. In fact, the actual number of units of finished goods inventory would be higher for the popular <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>-regular than for the low volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">regular</NUMEX>. The point to keep in mind here is that, compared to a product‚Äôs average demand, more popular products required relatively less finished goods inventory than less popular ones. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX> in mind that the actual sales of our manufacturer‚Äôs coats showed no seasonal variation. If a product has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> sales trends, then the manufacturer‚Äôs inventory must rise to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> demand during peak seasonal demand. Furthermore, if the manufacturing lead time exceeds <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> faces more demand risk and therefore must hold even more inventory.
As explained in previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>, variation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand can be characterized by a standardized measure, the coefficient of variation, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cv</ENAMEX>. Formally defined as the standard deviation of demand divided by average demand, the coefficient of variation can be considered a measure of variation that is normalized; it allows us to compare the variation of demand for different products, even if the average demand of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> products is quite different. The value of the coefficient can vary from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> (if demand is exactly the same <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>) to numbers much greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> for wildly fluctuating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand. In our analyses of demand patterns for different apparel products, we have found that the most predictable items have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cvs</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.6</NUMEX> range. But in most situations in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> provides a wide range of goods to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, some of its products will have low or moderate demand variation, while others‚Äô demand will vary a great deal. As illustrated in the previous examples, high volume products often have lower coefficients of variation than low volume products. (In Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.1</NUMEX>, the high volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>-regular has a low <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cv</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.55</NUMEX>. In Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.2</NUMEX>, the lower volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>-regular has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cv</ENAMEX> equal to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX>, which means the weekly demand departs much more from the average.) This is a result of the familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äúdemand pooling‚</ENAMEX>Äù argument, which shows that the total variation for the sum of many customers‚Äô demand is less than the sum of the variation in individual customers‚Äô demand.3
The same argument can be used to explain why growing product variety has increased demand variation at the SKU level: As variety grows, demand is distributed among an increasing number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX>, thereby reducing the pooling effects of demand aggregation. Take the single-breasted coat of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>, which is sold through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a thousand</NUMEX> retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>. The total <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> sales of all SKUs of this kind of coat are in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX>. Yet sales of some of the less popular sizes, such as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>-regular, are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only a few hundred</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. When considered on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> basis, this translates into average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand across all retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than ten</NUMEX> units. Therefore, even a small swing in demand from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week to week</TIMEX> translates into high relative variation‚Äîthat is, into a high coefficient of variation.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.3</NUMEX> (page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">114</NUMEX>) plots the coefficient of variation for men‚Äôs single-breasted coats. The graph shows that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> with the lowest total <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> sales have the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cv</ENAMEX> values (the largest variation in week-to-week demand). The coat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> will have to hold relatively more finished goods inventory of the low volume SKUs than of the high volume SKUs.
Taking demand variability into account becomes even more important given recent trends toward product proliferation. Over time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> must manufacturer more and more goods that have the joint characteristics of low volume and high variability. As a result, product proliferation represents a shift in the curve relating sales volume and variability (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>).
High demand variation similarly occurs during the beginning and end of a product life cycle. This variation is due in part to the lower demand volumes during those periods relative to the middle of a product‚Äôs life, but such fluctuations also occur because of the inherent uncertainty during the ramp up or ramp down of a product‚Äôs life.
Demand variation plays a central role in determining a manufacturer‚Äôs finished goods inventory levels. In the following case studies, we describe how demand variation can be used to determine a firm‚Äôs production and inventory planning processes. These cases offer a rational approach to inventory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, one that is premised on receiving accurate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POS</ENAMEX> information from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and maintaining good working relationships with all channel players‚Äîfor example, retail orders are not placed at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX> and textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> come through when they say they will. Reality is messier of course: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> often ‚Äúsurprise‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POS</ENAMEX> data are rarely perfect or may not even be available. Yet these nagging problems do not negate the need for a new approach to inventory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>; they merely indicate how complicated supplier relationships have become.
Case <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inventory Control</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Men‚Äôs Coat Manufacturer</ENAMEX>
Our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> case study examines the inventory management practices at the men‚Äôs coat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> previously described. This manufacturer‚Äôs standard approach to rapid replenishment requests was simply to carry large inventories. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> treated all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> alike; it held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same number of weeks</TIMEX> of demand for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX>. Specifically, our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> checked inventory of every item <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX>. If the inventory of any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten weeks</TIMEX> of demand or less, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> would place a production order for that item so that the current inventory plus the planned production was equal to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen weeks</TIMEX> of demand. (This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> essentially followed an (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">s</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>) policy as described in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 6</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> = time period between orders= <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX>, S = target inventory level = <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen weeks</TIMEX>, and s = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reorder</ENAMEX> point = <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten weeks</TIMEX>.)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
Note that this response is not unusual. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> do not explicitly track and use information like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand variation for different SKUs. Currently, no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> we know of has implemented all the changes described here and in the following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>. In that respect, this men‚Äôs clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of the industry.
In our initial assessment, we found that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> was in stock for most SKUs most of the time‚Äîa pretty good result. However, we also noticed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> was out of stock for some items, especially those with the most variable demand. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managers</ENAMEX> first thought that was true just for its largest sizes, but further analysis revealed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> had the same problem with some small sizes as well as with some less popular styles. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> was stocking out of the low demand items, which, as described above, suffered from relatively high demand variation. This is illustrated in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 7.1</ENAMEX>, which shows the average order-fulfillment rate for products with different levels of demand variability, assuming the same level of average demand is held for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX>.
The data suggest that when a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> chooses the same inventory policy for all products, its order-fulfillment rate for highly variable products is usually worse than for low variation products. Such a policy rarely maximizes profits; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> stocks out, thereby losing the margin on the sale, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>, which typically desires a consistent (or at least predictable) order-fill rate across items in a product group, is unhappy. Simply increasing inventory for all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> would be a poor allocation of investment, further increasing the order-fill rate for those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> for which service levels are already high. Thus, for most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, tracking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> variation for different SKUs is essential and will help to guide a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in setting appropriate inventory targets for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX>. To do this, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> need a planning tool that translates demand variation into inventory targets by weighing, for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX>, the opportunity for more sales against higher inventory carrying costs.
Once demand variation for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> was determined for our men‚Äôs coat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> faced the question of how to manage the inventory of the items in its rapid replenishment collection while maintaining a smooth flow of products through the sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. Using traditional sewing operations, it typically takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight weeks</TIMEX> to produce a coat, from the time an order is issued for cutting to the moment the finished goods are hanging in a manufacturer‚Äôs distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks</TIMEX> are spent in the cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, where the cloth is spread, cut, inspected, and has backing material fused to appropriate parts of the outer <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">(‚Äúshell‚Äù</ENAMEX>) fabric. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four weeks</TIMEX> are spent in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> processes. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two weeks</TIMEX> involve final inspection, repairs if necessary, shipping to the distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, and hanging the finished coats so they can be picked to fill individual orders for a given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.
A men‚Äôs suit coat or a blazer requires <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a hundred</NUMEX> assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> (compare this with only forty operations for a men‚Äôs shirt); it is one of the most complicated and expensive apparel items to make. Although the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> partly determines how long it takes to get a garment through production, other factors come into play, including the firm‚Äôs policy about how many finished coats should be allowed to build up in work-in-process and finished goods inventory. Given this manufacturer‚Äôs policy of ordering production only when inventory levels dropped below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten weeks</TIMEX>, with the production quantity set to restore the inventory to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen weeks</TIMEX>, the minimum production quantity for each item was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks</TIMEX> of demand. Thus, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least four weeks</TIMEX> of demand‚Äîa large quantity for most products‚Äîof the same style and size could move through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sewing plant</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time, minimizing setup costs for thread changes and the like.
The diagram in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX> depicts the production process, including all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> and information flows relevant to the inventory decision. In general, to maximize operating profit, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> must know the factory‚Äôs overall cycle time, work-in-process carrying costs, finished or hanging goods carrying costs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> production costs, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> selling price, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cv</ENAMEX> for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> of a given style. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> in this example effectively had limitless capacity to produce the single-breasted coat, since <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only approximately 30 percent</NUMEX> of the plant‚Äôs total capacity was devoted to producing a variety of rapid replenishment items. This capacity could be invoked when necessary by putting aside the lower priority products made in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>.
Our approach to the problem was to use operations research techniques and computer simulations of demand to explore the appropriate inventory levels, taking into account the statistical nature of the weekly demand for each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> for a style. In our approach, we assumed that an unfilled order was a lost sale with a lost profit. Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.2</NUMEX> reports the recommendations derived from the method<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX> Setting a target inventory level for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> that maximizes profit is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step; we did this using a computer simulation. As expected, the target inventory levels depend on a product‚Äôs demand variation. The larger the variation is, the higher the inventory level should be for an item to satisfy demand, as shown in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> columns of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 7.2</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> columns of the table indicate our manufacturer‚Äôs standard approach to inventory and are included to allow comparison with the optimal policy.
The optimal policy is one for which marginal increases or decreases in chosen inventory levels will not confer additional profits. For example, when demand for an item was quite variable, with the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cv</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.90</NUMEX>, the optimal policy called for placing a production orders when inventory dropped to twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of demand, rather than the lower standard level of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>. Put in a different way, increasing the amount of inventory from the company‚Äôs uniform level to the optimal level raised the manufacturer‚Äôs order-fulfillment rate to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 97 percent</NUMEX> for all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX>, which raised profits more than it cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> in terms of added inventory carrying cost. As a result, overall profits increased because of the change in inventory policy.
Following this strategy, it is true that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> will carry more inventory for certain items. Yet the percentage of time (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97.6</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99.5 percent</NUMEX> in our simulation) that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> is in stock for these SKUs translates into more sales and fewer stock-outs, which increases gross margin and, ultimately, operating profit. Because margin is primarily determined by the difference between the selling price and manufacturing and materials costs, if the margin for a unit is high, it pays to be almost always in stock. The resulting profit accrues, even after the higher finished goods carrying cost associated with larger inventory has been considered.
This view of production and inventory planning also provides a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> with a more sophisticated tool for balancing alternative plant operating choices to maximize profits. For example, consider whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> should cut fabric and assemble garments in smaller lots. In order to make this decision for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> with a given level of demand variation, this firm‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> should weigh the increased unit costs arising from manufacturing smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX> against the benefits this might create in shortening production lead times, which would reduce the amount of inventory the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> must hold for that product. Similarly, the impact of alternative methods for reducing plant cycle time depends not only on the direct costs of changes, but also on the reductions in inventory levels allowed by shorter lead times.
Fundamental to any resulting scenario is the idea of coupling inventory carrying costs to other manufacturing costs in order to make optimal production planning decisions. This allows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to balance the potentially higher operating costs associated with decreasing lot sizes (the minimum number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in a production run) with the opportunities to reduce inventory carrying costs and increasing sales. The failure of most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> in the apparel industry to make inventory carrying costs an explicit part of their decision-making process remains a significant impediment to enhanced profitability. On the flip side, the performance results presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 14</ENAMEX> indicate that moving toward this more sophisticated method of handling production decisions can yield significant competitive advantages.
Case <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Multiple Plants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Production Planning</ENAMEX>
Of course, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that relies on multiple production <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> has a more complex problem than the example just presented. Not only must it set inventory levels and schedule production for each product, but it must choose which products to assemble in each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>. In many cases, the choice is between a more expensive plant‚Äîprobably located close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">market‚Äîthat</ENAMEX> provides shorter lead times and a more distant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> that takes longer to make items but does so at a lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost. Under the traditional retailing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> filled an order by carrying out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> in the least costly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, as long as its quality was adequate for the market for which the product was destined. In a lean retailing world, however, factors other than the direct costs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> and transportation need to be considered.
Caught between lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">retailers‚</ENAMEX>Äô need for immediate replenishment and the high risk of carrying inventory for products with uncertain demand, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> must go beyond traditional direct costs and also include manufacturing lead times and inventory carrying costs in its sourcing equation. Most production <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> instinctively believe that having at least some manufacturing capability close to the market adds value to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, but expressing that value in dollars and cents, and making specific allocations of products to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, are difficult.
Manufacturers‚Äîwhether of suits, CDs, office products, or pasta‚Äîgenerally classify products in terms of product lines. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning</ENAMEX>, therefore, is done for fall fashion lines, jazz ensemble CDs, yellow legal pads, or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fettuccine pasta products</ENAMEX>. Even if this method of categorization is important from a marketing perspective, it often glosses over what is, in fact, common to many products that seem different and different about products that seem the same. Once again, demand variability is key. For our men‚Äôs suit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>, the men‚Äôs size <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>-regular coat may have less in common with the size <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>-regular coat in the same size and color than with a fashionable <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">boy‚Äôs blazer</ENAMEX>.
To set an optimal policy for a multi-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> or multi-source setting, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step is to determine the coefficient of variation for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> and then to arrange the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that have similar variations in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand (i.e., the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cv</ENAMEX>). Figuring out how to assign products to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> rests on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> findings explored in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>. First, the previous case study suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> with large demand variance (high <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cvs</ENAMEX>) will require larger amounts of inventory than low variance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> to provide a high order-fulfillment rate to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, we argued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> that reducing manufacturing lead times can lower the amount of inventory needed. The combination of these factors suggests that high variance SKUs are the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> with short lead times‚Äîthe higher direct costs of production are balanced by the reduction in inventory carrying costs resulting from the shorter <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">manu-facturing</TIMEX> lead times.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plant Model</ENAMEX>
Our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> case study is based on a prominent apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> that acted as one of our research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>. Here we will show how a decision tool can be used to make the transition from general intuition to specific decisions about (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) which products to make in each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) how to schedule the time and quantity of production for each product.6 This analysis can help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> allocate production among existing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. It also illustrates what <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> characteristics a close-to-market production <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> must have to be competitive with low-cost, offshore <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>. For this analysis, we assume that that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> already exist‚Äîthat is, we do not evaluate the option of building a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> or modifying an existing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> (i.e., we are seeking a solution to a short-run optimization problem.)
A simple depiction of the production situation is presented in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX> diagrams represent this manufacturer‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> as well as the retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> involved. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> production lines or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>; in the ‚Äúquick-line‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, it costs more to produce an item of apparel but it does so more quickly than in the ‚Äúregular-line‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>. The flow of goods is shown in solid lines, and information flows are represented by broken lines. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> are capable of making the same set of products. We assume that once a week, orders from all retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> selling the product are received, picked, packed, and shipped to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> from the manufacturer‚Äôs distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. On receipt of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> orders, production <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> total the quantity of each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> ordered and determine production needs to restore each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU‚</ENAMEX>Äôs distribution-center inventory to its target level. The total production quantity for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> is allocated between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. The cost to produce a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> and deliver it to the distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> is known for each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, as well as the time it takes<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX>
For confidentiality reasons, the actual costs and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> sales volumes for our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> are disguised; however, the cost numbers and sales volumes that appear in this case are reasonable numbers for, say, an upscale dress<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-shirt manufacturer</ENAMEX>. Let‚Äôs assume that we have a single style of dress shirt and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX> can be made in one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúregular‚Äù</ENAMEX> production line, the average direct cost of producing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> shirt is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13.15</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.15</NUMEX> in materials costs (including all buttons, thread, and lining material) plus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.00</NUMEX> in labor and transportation costs (including direct labor at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> level; transportation costs for fabric and other supplies shipped to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sewing plant</ENAMEX>; the cost of transporting finished goods to the manufacturer‚Äôs distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, any customs fees or insurance associated with transportation, and any other costs associated with producing an acceptable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of finished goods). The other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> (the ‚Äúquick-line‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>) has production costs that are <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> higher than for the regular line, but the manufacturing lead time from the time a production order is placed until a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX> is available in finished goods inventory is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúregular</ENAMEX> line.‚Äù
The question a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> faces in this situation can be stated as follows: For which dress shirts is it more profitable to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13.75</NUMEX> per shirt (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.15</NUMEX> materials plus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.60</NUMEX> production costs) but have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-week</TIMEX> production lead time, rather than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13.15</NUMEX> with an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-week</TIMEX> lead time?
If this case involved traditional production strategies in the apparel industry, there would be no problem to study. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managers</ENAMEX> would just decide to make all these dress shirts in the regular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> because its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> production cost is lower. But in the world of lean retailing, the decision becomes more complicated. Now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> wholesale selling price, assumed to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22.00</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX>, is relevant to the decision because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> must weigh the cost of carrying shirts in inventory with the foregone revenue if they stock out of shirts in the distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>.
In addition, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> need to know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand variation as well as average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX>. In this case, we assume that total <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand for all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> averages <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10,000 shirts</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>. We classify the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> categories: those with high demand (averaging <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,700</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>) and low demand variation (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cv</ENAMEX>=<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.6</NUMEX>), those with medium demand (averaging <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>) and medium demand variation (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cv</ENAMEX>=<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.7</NUMEX>), and those with low demand (averaging <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>) and high demand variation (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cv</ENAMEX>= <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.3</NUMEX>). These particular volumes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cvs</ENAMEX> were chosen based on the values shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.3</NUMEX> (page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">114</NUMEX>). 
Finally, to allocate production appropriately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> need to know the inventory carrying cost for carrying work-in-process and finished goods inventory. The inventory carrying cost should reflect not only the cost of capital tied up in inventory, but also the risk of holding that inventory. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> indicator of risk is the cost of markdowns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> must make to clear inventory that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> are not willing to purchase at full wholesale price‚Äîif at all<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX> For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCTAR</ENAMEX> survey found that an average apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> unit discounted its products to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.
Determining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Optimal Allocations</ENAMEX>
Next, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> must determine what percentage of its total capacity should be allocated to the quick line (we call this percentage the quick-line capacity ratio), with the remainder allocated to the regular line. Once this decision is made, specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> must be allocated between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> basis. As in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> case study, we assume that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> places an order every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and that the order must be filled during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that week</TIMEX>.
We have developed a software package that solves this problem by using computer simulations of the weekly demand and production that determine the consequences of different quick-line capacity ratios and production scheduling policies for the manufacturer‚Äôs inventory and service levels (order-fulfillment rate) to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>. For a given quick-line capacity ratio, the computer program searches for a target inventory level for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> and finds the values of the target inventory for each group of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKUs</ENAMEX> that maximizes profit. The number of computer searches necessary is very large, but with a fast desktop computer and by using special search reduction techniques<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,9</NUMEX> the computations can be carried out in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just hours</TIMEX>.
The results of a search for the maximum profit in this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-plant case appear in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.7</NUMEX> (page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">124</NUMEX>), which shows how the quick-line ratio increases as the inventory carrying costs increase<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.10</NUMEX> As we would expect, if the cost of carrying inventory is very low, the quick line is not used; that is, the quick-line capacity ratio equals <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>. As inventory costs rise, the percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">units</ENAMEX> allocated to the quick line increases; eventually, when the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> inventory carrying cost approaches <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX>, the ratio equals <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one‚</NUMEX>Äîthat is, all the production is allocated to the short-cycle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>. With higher values of inventory carrying costs, it is more profitable to shift more production to the quick-line <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> to allow reduction in work-in-process and finished goods inventory<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX>
The major point here is that inventory carrying cost is a critical variable in making such plant capacity decisions. A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-percent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> inventory carrying cost amounts to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 2 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>. For the long-cycle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, work-in-process and finished goods inventory will cover about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen weeks</TIMEX> on average before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> is sold. At <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>, this results in an inventory carrying charge of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 8 percent</NUMEX> of the cost to assemble (plus <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX>). This <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> charge against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> and production should be compared with the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24 percent</NUMEX> of wholesale selling cost our survey reported as the average markdown needed to clear inventories<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.12</NUMEX>
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.8</NUMEX> shows the full relationship between inventory carrying costs, lead times, and the quick-line production ratio. Again, our earlier intuition is confirmed. The decreasing lead time of the quick-line <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> makes it competitive at a lower inventory carrying cost. The short-cycle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> becomes more competitive for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) there is less work-in-process; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the finished goods inventory level necessary to satisfy retail demand for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKU</ENAMEX> is less because the short-cycle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> can respond to actual demand more quickly.
In this figure, the cycle time of the slower <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> has been set at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>; the short-cycle line can make our products with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different times‚Äînamely, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks</TIMEX>. In this case, the cycle time for the long-cycle plant represents the number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> typical for offshore production. Note that some outsourcing of production for fashion items is done in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Rim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and flown directly to distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Limited</ENAMEX> have often claimed that its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> can produce an item offshore in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a thousand hours‚Äîor just six weeks‚</NUMEX>Äîusing air-freight delivery to its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>. But most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that use foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> take longer, which is why we have chosen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> as the cycle time of the slower production line. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.8</NUMEX> shows the curves for the various lead times listed in the legend on the right-hand side.
Both components of total inventory (work-in-process and finished goods) decrease as the most profitable production shifts to the short-cycle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>. Less finished goods inventory is required because finished goods can be rapidly replenished after a peak <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">selling week</TIMEX>.
Therefore, the amount of finished goods in the manufacturer‚Äôs distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> needed to satisfy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> demand for all SKUs depends on the cycle times of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> supplying finished product, and what fraction of production is made in each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>. In the single-breasted coat example of the previous section, there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> involved, which made the most profitable target inventory level a single number for each <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">SKU.13</NUMEX> Increased profit came from missing fewer sales by being in stock a higher percentage of the time. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> case, the finished goods in the distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> are generally a blend of the output of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and the target inventory level varies with the quick-line capacity ratio. Most important, when a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> considers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sourcing options, the one that offers the lowest direct cost is not always the most profitable.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Manufacturer‚Äôs Dilemma in a Lean World</ENAMEX>
This chapter shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> must take additional dimensions into consideration when they make decisions about sourcing. To maximize profits, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> must consider the complete set of benefits and costs of production decisions. The disadvantage of lower cost, slow production <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is that it is necessary to risk large inventories to provide reasonable levels of service to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. The omission of such costs from sourcing decisions‚Äîas well as the failure to consider the benefits a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> gains by being in stock on certain items‚Äîwill reduce a manufacturer‚Äôs profitability as well as its ultimate ability to compete.
This dilemma in a lean retailing world is summarized in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.9</NUMEX>. Exactly how a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> divides production between <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> with different production costs and cycle times depends on the details of the situation, such as those presented in the cases above. However, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> general rule emerges from the cases we have studied: The cycle time of a fast production <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> can be no more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or two</TIMEX>. Needless to say, a local, more expensive production line with long cycle times cannot compete with slower, low-cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, even when allowances are made for late deliveries, markdowns, and the like<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.14</NUMEX> But as Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.9</NUMEX> suggests, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> can pay somewhat more to make certain units‚Äîthose with high <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> variation in sales‚Äîin quick production lines and still reap a better return than it would by making all of the product in a less expensive, slower <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>.
Balancing these production alternatives clearly has implications for foreign competition and the current transformation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel industry. It also requires changes in internal processes, including manufacturing innovations and the sophisticated computer tools necessary to do this kind of production planning. Although many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> apparel<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX> are only beginning to incorporate these changes into their operations, lean retailing practices will continue to push <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> in this direction.
The next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> chapters examine apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, starting with a look at the use of information technologies and automation equipment in the preassembly stages of garment-making (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 8</ENAMEX>) and then the sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 9</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 10</ENAMEX> considers how new human resource practices that allow for short-cycle production, in concert with the use of information technology, can positively affect the performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>.



