



The late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Gerber</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerber Garment Technology Company</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tolland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, invented automated fabric cutting and introduced it to the market in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>. This innovative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> went on to create a new industry in automatic-cutting equipment. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerber Garment Technology</ENAMEX> was supplying the automotive and apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> with its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GERBERcutter</ENAMEX>, allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to cut cloth and nonwoven material more effectively. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerber</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> first made it possible for a computer to guide the cutting knife anywhere on the cutting table. Gerber‚Äôs automatic-cutting equipment, as well as that of several other international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, has continued to improve; cloth from a single ply to layers up to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six inches</NUMEX> thick can now be cut quickly and accurately.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerber</ENAMEX> is also a major worldwide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> of information systems for the sewing products industries. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Product Data Management</ENAMEX> software provides <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> with all the information about an apparel product, including design, patterns, markers, sewing instructions, and assembly costs. This single software package can be made available through an in-house local area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web</ENAMEX>. Computer data systems like this have enormous potential for the apparel industry. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private-label</ENAMEX> apparel for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, for instance, is generally designed in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and produced by domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> or overseas. Regardless of geographic location, it is always difficult for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> to know if it has the latest information on sewing patterns and other construction details. But via a network that allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> access, manufacturers‚Äô <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> can make sure that the information available is the most recent and complete. In addition, video instructions, which do not rely on spoken language, can demonstrate to foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> what is acceptable and what is not.
In previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>, we have described the impact of crucial information technologies, such as the use of bar code scanning and electronic data interchange, on the retail-apparel-textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. The ability to transmit order information in unambiguous electronic forms between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> and apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, along with the possibility of sharing point-of-sales information, allow these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to understand in real time what is happening in the marketplace. It is then up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> to use this information in product design and production planning. Indeed, for many apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, speed in the market now means using modern computer tools that make the process of creating a piece of clothing‚Äîfrom conceptual design to fabric cutting to sewing‚Äîsmooth and efficient. From the first use of computer-assisted pattern layout in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, computers and specialized information technologies have spread widely in the industry. Such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> have the potential to develop patterns and color fabrics; adapt apparel patterns for custom-made suits, shirts, pants, and other garments; and evaluate production sourcing alternatives to maximize profit while allowing for demand uncertainty.
Yet not every aspect of apparel production depends on new technologies; in fact, automated sewing processes and the use of robots on the apparel shop floor have not turned out to be profitable or effective<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> do a better job than computers of adjusting fabric alignment through sewing machines and compensating for prior sewing and cutting errors. As a result, the marginal costs for human sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> are lower than those of the complex robotic systems needed to guide sewing of limp fabric in most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>.
In discussing apparel manufacturing, it is important to make a distinction between preassembly of garments‚Äîdesign, marker-making, spreading, cutting, and bundling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> that are the focus of this chapter‚Äîand garment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>, the subject of the next chapter. Most of the innovations in production and information technology are taking place in preassembly processes, which can be more readily automated. Although changes in how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> orchestrate production flow through the sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> are starting to make a difference, shifts in the practices of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>-floor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> have more to do with new human resource policies than equipment.
As most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> of the apparel industry know, contracting out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> of garments has become common for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, although the use of contracting differs between the men‚Äôs and women‚Äôs industry. Men‚Äôs clothing has generally been made in long production runs with only small variations among styles in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given year</TIMEX> and relatively little change from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year to year</TIMEX>. This has allowed men‚Äôs clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to capture the benefits of their own highly efficient sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> through long production runs. Women‚Äôs clothing is characterized by great diversity in styles and short production runs. Small contractors‚Äô sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> are the norm for most women‚Äôs apparel. The use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> has grown at the international level in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s and 1980s</TIMEX>.
We will examine some of the complex issues related to international sourcing in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 13</ENAMEX>. But we want to stress here that today‚Äôs apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> usually does not produce all of its own garments, from start to finish. Apparel manufacturing can involve many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcontractors</ENAMEX>, creating a complex web of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> relationships. Jobbers‚Äîsuppliers that may contract out every aspect of clothing production except for design‚Äîrepresent one extreme. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liz Claiborne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAST Industries</ENAMEX> are essentially current versions, although their operations are much larger than those of jobbers in the past.
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-based apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, not to mention the apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>, have long recognized that producing higher quality garments may be the best means for competing against low-cost foreign labor. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way to increase quality is to control fabric purchasing, marker-making, spreading, cutting, and parts preparation in a central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> can then transport the cut parts for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> to sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, which may be either local or out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCTAR‚Äôs</ENAMEX> survey indicates that the average cutting room services 4.5 sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>. Quality <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> of garments from pieces of material cut according to a particular pattern involves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> that can be carried out almost anywhere in the world. Whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of apparel is assembled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, the overall process is quite similar. The differences from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> remain in the details‚Äîprincipally in the layout of the pattern on the cloth and in cutting the patterns.
For instance the high-end design of a women‚Äôs jacket, made from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300-</NUMEX>a<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-yard</NUMEX> cashmere plaid fabric, can still be of very poor quality if the plaids do not match on the lapels, the inseams of the sleeves, or along the seam joining the back panels. Pattern layout may not seem important at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, until one sees a plaid mismatch when this jacket is buttoned. A very small amount of plaid mismatch in cutting can be overcome by a skilled sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX>, but the essential step in achieving a quality product is to make the pattern parts correctly. This <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter</ENAMEX> describes the various steps involved before a garment is sewn, focusing on the technical innovations that are having the greatest impact<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX> Before looking at preassembly operations in apparel-making, however, we will examine the very beginning of the process‚Äîgarment design and the creation of a pattern.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Step: Apparel Design and Patterns</ENAMEX>
When most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think of apparel design, they see fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">runways</ENAMEX>. Yet the vast majority of design in the apparel industry has little to do with the way clothing is created in the high-fashion world. Often apparel design and pattern-making are done by department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, private-label <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, and small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> in addition to major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. The name <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> generally create fashion directions and the next tier of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> fill out the new directions into many levels and for many items of apparel<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> also have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> who prepare designs and patterns for their private-label collection.
Although many apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> do have in-house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>, most of the work of garment design comes in adjusting previous -patterns or small elements of existing garments‚Äîsay, the trim or the fabric‚Äîand is more a matter of technical creation than a flight of fancy. Consider the expansion of basic and fashion-basic garments in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> market. For T-shirts, sweatpants, and different types of jeans, the design elements that change <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> may only amount to a change of color, fit of the jeans, or the addition of a pocket to sweatpants.
Traditionally, a new apparel design was created by asking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> to make a watercolor sketch. If the fabric was to have a pattern, there might also be a close-up colored sketch of it. Many designs would be grouped together into a storyboard, which was then presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> for final decisions. Next the designs that passed this stage went through a technical design step in which details were added and patterns made. After this step, fabric might be cut and a sample made to see how it would look on a mannequin. If the new garment was a blouse, for example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> might wish to see how it looked with skirts planned for the collection. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> was not satisfied with the drape of the garment, the fit, or the pattern, he or she might go back to square <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Several iterations of these initial design steps could add <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> to the process before production began.
Although some haute couture or high-end apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> may still work in this manner, each year more garments are designed using computer technology. In our survey, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of the business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> reported using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer-Aided-Design</ENAMEX> (CAD) systems to prepare new products in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employing CAD</ENAMEX> was particularly common among the largest business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in our sample. The use of modern design tools and information technology can collapse the design time so that managerial decision-making becomes the longest step in the process‚Äîand even the time for that step can be shortened with information technology. The new way allows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> to work creatively with a computer pen or brush to outline the sketch, which appears on a computer screen. The computer can ‚Äúwatercolor‚Äù the sketch and produce the storyboard for presentation. Once past the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> steps, these systems let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> drape fabric patterns on sketches or photographs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the computer screen. For example, sketches or photos can be draped with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> of different colors and patterns. The size of the pattern can be changed and the visual images compared to get a sense of their appeal. And a colored ink-jet printing of the pattern can be made on basic plain fabric to help identify and demonstrate the desired colors in future discussions with textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mills</ENAMEX>.
Design changes can be implemented in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>. For example, if the apparel item is a skirt, the proposed material on the computer image can be changed with a few key <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>. Prints can be scanned into the computer and used as the pattern for the visual image. Entire collections can be created in a day with the selected materials draped on a sketched figure or actual photograph of a model. The colors of the blouse can be changed with a few computer steps. The color and texture of the rest of the garments in the photograph can be changed with equal ease. Computerized design systems collapse <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the time</TIMEX> needed to explore new design ideas into <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of work, rather than the traditional work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">time of days</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. The resulting visual images can be shared with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">decision-makers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> wherever they might be, without the need to wait until everyone is in town for a meeting. Computer images can be viewed on the local area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> or even put on the Internet in a secure form.
Other development applications allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> to begin with an actual garment and make appropriate changes to achieve the desired design or construction modifications. In this case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> pin the garment to a special design table. A computer pen is used to outline a panel of the garment with a sequence of contact points. The computer, on command, then connects the image of the points on its screen with a series of line segments that form the silhouette of the pattern piece. Another computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX> adds the seam allowance and, after the desired modifications have been made, a piece of the new design is created. When all the individual pieces of the garment have been modified and entered into the computer system, the final garment pattern is ready to be cut and sewn into a sample garment. Numerically controlled fabric cutters are now available that can rapidly and accurately cut patterns from a single ply of cloth, removing the usual obstacle to sample garment-making. The cutting equipment is driven by the output of a pattern-grading and marker-making program.
Note that this entire design sequence can take as little as part of a day, yielding a sample garment hung on a mannequin. Again, the time it takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to reach a decision is what determines the length of this process. However, it may take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> to produce a sample garment in a desired fabric simply because that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX> takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> to make.
Design information systems, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerber Garment</ENAMEX> Technology software discussed above, can also greatly affect how and when design changes are made. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerber‚Äôs Web</ENAMEX> version of such a system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WebPDM</ENAMEX>) allows worldwide access to designated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> with information stored on a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> server about relevant apparel products. Naturally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> for sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> will not be allowed access to estimates of production costs and information about other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>; however, once a change is made in a garment‚Äôs design, then everyone involved will have access to and can work from the identical information <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>. The system can store design, costing, measurements, and detailed construction information, all in multiple languages.
Preassembly: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marker</ENAMEX>-Making
An order to an apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factory‚</ENAMEX>Äîwhether from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>, jobber, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> contracting out different stages of the work‚Äîspecifies the total number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> to be made of a particular design, with a given fabric, and with a certain number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in each size. Because a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> normally will have already seen a sample garment before placing an order, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> therefore will have the pattern pieces for all sizes in-house, with coordinate outlines of the pieces on its computers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> might also have the patterns cut out from stiff fiberboard so that the individual pieces can be traced by hand onto a large sheet of paper. But several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">preassembly</ENAMEX> processes have to be performed before the cloth can be cut. The order must be broken down into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> to be worked on together. Then all the pieces of the patterns must be laid out for the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> so that they can be cut at the same time. The silhouette for each individual pattern piece is generally traced or imprinted on a sheet of paper, which is called a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúmarker</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Finally</ENAMEX>, the cloth must be spread in as many layers of thickness as necessary to achieve the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> requested or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as</NUMEX> can be properly cut at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time.
Each piece of the pattern in a marker has a seam allowance added to the basic outline. This allowance serves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> purposes: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, the sewn seam must be made far enough in from the edge of the cloth so that it will not pull free of the cloth; <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, the seam allowance provides a region into which small alignment notches can be cut. The notches are the basic instruction to sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> regarding where the fabric pieces to be joined should match up or be aligned. In a sense, these notches visually encode the basic sewing instructions into each pattern piece of the garment. This means that skilled sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> do not need to be able to read a language to follow instructions. They can -follow the general outline of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> from supervisors‚Äô or video demonstrations.
Before the pattern layout is made, there is the assortment problem of determining which apparel sizes should be included in a given marker. Because each roll of cloth has a particular width, grouping different sizes together will result in varying percentages of cloth utilization for each width. For example, if one is laying out a marker of men‚Äôs pants, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> large panels for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX>, along with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> other small pieces like waistbands and trim<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX> Yet the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX> of a pair of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">forty-inch</NUMEX> waist pants will not fit in the typical <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">sixty-inch</NUMEX>-wide bolt of cloth. To achieve the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> cloth utilization typical of this kind of production, one needs to combine <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> pairs of pants into one marker. An efficient marker will have larger sizes of pants balanced with smaller sizes.
A typical marker for men‚Äôs pants is shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.1</NUMEX> (page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">137</NUMEX>). At <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance, it might appear that almost all of the cloth is used in the marker; in fact, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 90 percent</NUMEX> has been covered in the layout of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">108</NUMEX> individual pieces. Given the basic shapes of the pants pieces, it is unlikely that a substantial increase in marker efficiency can be achieved. At best, experience with different combinations of waist sizes and leg lengths for a given design allows a scheduler to aggregate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> to be made into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of large and small sizes, which means marker-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> can achieve efficiencies near <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> for casual pants. Higher cloth utilization is possible with jeans, but lower levels are normal for blouses, jackets, and intimate apparel (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.2</NUMEX>).
Making a marker is a complicated task, even with modern computer assistance. Because fabric is generally the most expensive part of finished garments, the skill of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">marker-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> is critical for achieving high cloth utilization and lower fabric costs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marker</ENAMEX>-making is easier with fewer pieces, but with fewer pieces, overall cloth utilization is generally lower. A typical production pants marker is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 265 inches</NUMEX> long and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">59.75 inches</NUMEX> wide. This marker, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 22 feet</NUMEX> long, contains all of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">108</NUMEX> individual pieces of the shell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX> that make up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> different pairs of pants. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> or more of experience with pants markers can take up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> to achieve an efficiency of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">89 to 90 percent</NUMEX>. Manipulation of the arrangement of these pieces, whether on a computer screen or not, is a time-consuming task. It resembles putting a jigsaw puzzle together, except that the cloth pieces do not fit together exactly. The separate pieces can be moved around on a computer screen by the normal drag and drop procedure, but even this involves a complex mixture of trial and error and relies heavily on a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">marker-maker‚Äôs</NUMEX> experience. A trial marker might leave the right-hand end very uneven, for example, resulting in low utilization when the cloth is cut straight across the bolt in the standard ‚Äúguillotine‚Äù cut. Such a marker would not be acceptable for production. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">marker-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> would have to reconstruct the layout to give it the appearance of those in Figures <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.1</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.2</NUMEX>.
Computer layout systems also improve the quality of the finished apparel by preventing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">marker-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> from tilting the pieces by more than a predetermined amount, typically <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">degrees</NUMEX>. These restrictions ensure that the weave of the cloth is aligned along the length of the garment. After all, stripes should be vertical‚Äîa quality feature of the final product determined when the marker is made, not later in the process. Such quality is difficult to achieve with hand layout and manual tracing of the silhouette onto the marker cloth. When the layout is done by hand through tracing on a sheet of paper, there is always a temptation for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> to tilt a particular piece a bit more, squeezing it into the marker or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúshrinking‚Äù the silhouette of some of the pieces to get them all on the marker. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Subcontractors</ENAMEX> who might do cutting as well as sewing are provided with enough fabric to make the order. Any fabric left after the order is completed is kept by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcontractor</ENAMEX>, providing an incentive to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúsqueeze‚Äù the pattern pieces more than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> might want.
When the computer screen layout is finished, it is automatically printed full-size on paper by large computer-driven printers. The paper marker identifies each piece in the layout so that the cloth pieces for individual apparel items can be put together after the fabric is cut. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Computer-assisted marker</ENAMEX>-making can offer large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings</ENAMEX> with basic garments, like men‚Äôs pants or women‚Äôs intimate apparel, which may be manufactured repeatedly over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>. The same assortment of sizes might be needed many times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>, and the finished layout can be called up from computer memory and used over and over again, provided the width of the fabric remains the same. There are, however, small variations of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric width</ENAMEX> from bolt to bolt, and from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> to another. If the cloth runs wide or narrow, an efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> would remake the marker to take advantage of the full width. Variation of just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a quarter inch</NUMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">sixty-inch</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">width</ENAMEX> can yield <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a 0.42 percent</NUMEX> change in cloth utilization.
Part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCTAR‚</ENAMEX>Äôs research effort has resulted in new automatic marker-making software based on computational geometry techniques. The software allows a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> to take existing production markers and automatically ‚Äúcompact‚Äù the arrangement of pieces by translation or a combination of translation and allowable amounts of rotation<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX> It automatically adjusts for changes in fabric width by moving the pieces to the left and up or down to fill the available width most efficiently. The more pieces in a marker, the more effort required to make an efficient marker of a given width. Therefore, if the cloth of a given bolt of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">half an inch</NUMEX> wider than the marker, there is a tendency to cut the marker as is. Yet some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of this software have been able to decrease the amount of cloth lost in this way by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much as 2 percent</NUMEX>.
The pants marker shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.1</NUMEX> was produced by this automatic layout software and yielded cloth utilization of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">89.66 percent</NUMEX>. The equivalent production marker made by the manufacturer‚Äôs highly skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator</ENAMEX>, using a computer but without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCTAR‚</ENAMEX>Äôs software, achieved a utilization of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">89.54 percent</NUMEX>, or just a little less than the fully automatic software system. Sometimes a human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> can beat the automatic system by a small amount, but the following example is typical. The production marker for the intimate apparel item in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.2</NUMEX> was initially laid out by a trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">79.96 percent</NUMEX> utilization; the HCTAR software compacted the marker and achieved cloth utilization of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81.54 percent</NUMEX>, an improvement of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.47 percent</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One-third</NUMEX> of the wholesale price of apparel is typically fabric cost. A <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> savings in fabric over the entire production goes directly to the bottom line. Such savings can add up to many <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> for large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>.
Based on our survey results, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two-thirds</NUMEX> of the business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> generated markers by trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> with computer assistance; when the survey response is weighted by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> sales, however, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99.5 percent</NUMEX> of the business units‚Äô production came from computer-generated markers. In contrast, apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> in developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> generally do not use computerized layout systems. Markers are made by hand, tracing pattern pieces onto sheets of paper from thick, pre-cut cardboard pattern elements. The primary alignment tool is the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX> stick for measuring distances from the edge. It is not hard to imagine a tendency to allow a slight twist in individual pieces to achieve a closer fit between neighboring pieces.
There are also stories of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcontractors</ENAMEX>, in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as well as overseas, crumpling a marker up so that when it is laid out again it will be just a little smaller in width and length‚Äîa trick to save <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a fraction of a percent</NUMEX> from each piece. The savings can add up for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>, since the apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> that supplied the cloth might not notice. As far as final quality is concerned, however, such arrangements create the wrong incentive‚Äîanother reason why it may make more sense for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to control all aspects of preassembly, including marker-making and cutting.
Preassembly: Spreading
Every <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX> of fabric destined for apparel production is normally inspected by the textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>. As a part of this inspection and repair, a detailed map is made that locates any remaining defects; the minimum width of the bolt is measured along with the overall length of the unstretched material. After final inspection, the cloth is wound ‚Äúwithout tension‚Äù on a roll for shipment. But it is actually impossible to wind the fabric onto a roll without leaving some stresses in the cloth. Variations in storage temperature and humidity also cause changes. Indeed, all the residual stresses in the cloth cause problems when it is spread on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">manufacturer‚Äôs ‚Äúlay‚Äù</ENAMEX> table prior to cutting.
Spreading cloth out on a table in a way that leaves it flat but unstretched, without tension in the cloth, is more difficult than one would think. To get the cloth flat, without mechanical help, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> could hold the cloth by both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ends</ENAMEX> and stretch it out flat, then release <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just one end</TIMEX>. But the friction between the table and the cloth will leave this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">layer (‚Äúply‚Äù</ENAMEX>) of cloth stretched; just how much will depend on the amount of friction between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. Putting another ply on top the same way creates an additional problem. The friction between the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> ply and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> can create a wrinkle in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ply. When plies of cloth are piled high‚Äîa foot or more is not unusual‚Äîthere are often wrinkles in the plies after they are cut. This is especially true for knit goods, which are easily stretched and adhere well to neighboring plies in a stack of cloth.
The number of plies of cloth spread at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time depends on the fabric, which, in turn, determines how many are cut at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time. Thirty plies of denim might be cut together, whereas <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> plies of men‚Äôs dress-shirt fabric might be cut at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time. In contrast, a men‚Äôs dress suit might be cut from a single ply, or from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six</NUMEX> plies of the same or different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>.
Spreading the cloth many plies thick without stressing the cloth is, again, one of the quality steps of getting ready to sew. If the cloth has tension before it is cut, then it will contract after it is cut into separate pattern pieces. Because it is easy to stretch many fabrics by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up to an inch</NUMEX> in a yard, one can imagine the amount of distortion possible in the final garment. But technical innovations have aided the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>. Stresses in the cloth on the lay table can be minimized with the help of mechanical spreading machines, and such devices come in all sizes and costs. The most elaborate allow an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> to ride the machine, which holds the rolls of cloth, so that it can feed the cloth onto the table at a speed that just matches the speed of the machine as it moves along rails fixed to the table. On-board computers compare the location of cloth defects with pattern pieces in the marker. If the type of defect and its location are deemed unacceptable, then the bolt of cloth is cut and a new ply started with enough overlap to ensure that all pattern pieces are whole and without defects. In our sample, business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> used some type of automatic spreading for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 39 percent</NUMEX> of the volume of goods they shipped.
Simpler spreading machines have no on-board computer, but they do unroll the bolt of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cloth ‚Äúunstressed‚Äù</ENAMEX> and properly aligned with the edge of the ply below. However spreading is done, it is important for the plies to lie directly on top of each other. Misalignment of the edges can ruin many pattern pieces and the final garments for which they were intended. Once a ply is laid down, it is almost impossible to shift it because of the friction between the plies. With simple spreading machines, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> must look for fabric defect indicators placed in the selvage by the textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>.
After the cloth is spread, it is ready for the appropriate marker to be fit on top and fixed to the lay of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX>. Sometimes staples are driven through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> into the underlying cloth. If the lay is made by hand, then the cloth is generally cut directly by hand-guided electric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">knives</ENAMEX> that slice through the cloth on the table. If computer-controlled cutting is used, the lay of cloth is pulled onto the cutting table by an underlying paper sheet. In either case, the pattern pieces can now be cut.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Preassembly: The Cutting Room</ENAMEX>
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early twentieth century</TIMEX>, the cost to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> of a cutter‚Äôs mistake has been much greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> committed by a sewing machine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX>. Wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">stitching</ENAMEX> can be pulled out and a seam redone in the sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, but a big mistake by a cutter can involve the loss of many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yards</ENAMEX> of cloth‚Äîand cloth costs range from one or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two dollars</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> for inexpensive fabrics to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three hundred dollars</NUMEX> for some cashmeres. Even relatively small errors in cutting can degrade the final quality of garments. If the fabric is defect free, the marker efficient, the lay flat and unstressed, then everything else is up to the cutter<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX>
Some magazine advertisements for upscale men‚Äôs dress suits tout hand-cutting by experienced tailors. Occasionally the ads include a drawing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a large pair of scissors. But cloth is rarely cut this way, even when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> ply is cut at a time. An <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>- or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twelve-inch</NUMEX> pair of scissors is an unwieldy instrument, difficult to guide within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1/32th</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an inch</NUMEX> of the pattern outline. It is even harder to accurately cut the notches used by sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> to align cut parts.
Most often, an electrically driven vertical reciprocating <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX> is used to cut the fabric. The vertical knife oscillates less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an inch</NUMEX> but can cut cloth plies a foot or more in thickness. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX> and motor are supported above the base plate by a frame. The frame also gives the cutter a place to grip the machine for hand-guided cutting. The base plate is a smooth cap with a slit to contain the moving end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX>. The knives have built-in sharpeners that run a stone up and down the blade every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">few minutes</TIMEX>. In such a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚Äúhand-cutting‚</NUMEX>Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> guides the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX> along the outlines on the paper marker fixed to the fabric lay. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> hand holds the marker on the lay, the other guides the electric <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX>. When a pattern piece is cut from the lay, the cutter then makes the notch cuts indicated on the marker. These slits should be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about one-eighth of an inch</NUMEX> cut into the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighth</NUMEX><NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-inch</NUMEX> sewing margin around the pattern. The chances are high of making the slit too deep or forgetting it entirely. Computer-controlled cutting machines, on the other hand, do not forget.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Gerber</ENAMEX> solved the major problem in cutting‚Äîhow to hold the cloth while the knife cuts through the material‚Äîby putting the entire lay on a vacuum table. The fabric lay with the marker on top is covered with a thin sheet of clear plastic. When the vacuum pump comes on, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five pounds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> per square foot push down on the fabric. The thin plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sheet</ENAMEX> effectively cuts off the flow of room air through the fabric. The vacuum holds the cloth firmly and compresses the thickness of the lay, typically by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>.
Gerber‚Äôs automatic-cutting equipment holds the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX> on a frame that spans the cutting table and moves back and forth along the table. The location of the knife anywhere on the table can be precisely controlled by a computer, allowing it to cut its way along the silhouette of the patterns. Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerber‚</ENAMEX>Äôs equipment enabled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX> to slice through all the cloth without hitting the top of the vacuum table, supporting the lay of cloth on a brush between the fabric and the inlets to the vacuum table. The stiff bristles of the brush were made of plastic with flat tops, similar in appearance to a flat-headed nail. The flat tops supported the fabric. The plastic bristles were stiff enough to support the fabric layer under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of vacuum while remaining sufficiently flexible to deflect out of the path of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX>.
The most up-to-date versions of automatic-cutting equipment, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GERBERcutter</ENAMEX>, are even more effective. Cloth is cut by having the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX> oscillate up and down while it moves along the silhouette of the apparel pieces in the marker. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX> support tilts to keep the blade erect when going along curves. Software can prevent lines from being cut <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice</NUMEX>; it can control the touchy job of cutting the apex of wedge-shaped pieces by approaching the point from both sides of the wedge rather than attempting to cut around the tip. The vacuum tables have also become ‚Äúsmart.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù One</ENAMEX> level of vacuum is maintained over the general lay area; a higher level is arranged under the region being cut to keep the cloth fixed.
Yet despite the obvious advantages of computer-controlled cutting, only a minority of the business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in our survey (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX>) were using this kind of equipment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. Most continued to use manually guided electric knives to do their cutting, including some of the largest business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in the sample. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Manufacturers</ENAMEX> have told us that hand-cutting with skilled cutters is as accurate as computer-cutting. Small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">factory</ENAMEX> operations, without sufficient volume to support <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> shifts of cutting, claim that they cannot justify the capital cost of computer systems<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX>
Those that do have computer equipment say that the consistency of cutting was their primary reason for purchasing computer-driven cutting systems. The computer cutter does not tire during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> nor forget to cut the notches, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> of computer-cutting equipment does not need the skills of a manual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX>. As with many new technologies that have developed since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, adoption of innovative equipment is still occurring in fits and starts and depends on a given firm‚Äôs size and mix of products. In the case of computer--controlled cutting, however, there appear to be long-term advantages for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, especially those that produce large runs of basic or fashion-basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX>. Apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> providing garments with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple dimensions‚</ENAMEX>Äîfor example, men‚Äôs shirts that are sized according to collar, sleeve length, and often torso length‚Äîrequire much more consistent cutting than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> whose apparel is sold only in small, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>, and large sizes.
Knit material, which is easily stretched, poses other challenges for cutting. Tubular knits are often cut in a die-cutting press. With most tube T-shirts, for instance, the die-cutter serves the twin functions of pulling the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">knit material</ENAMEX> into the machine and centering it under the die before cutting. The machine then presses the die down on the fabric, cuts through the fabric, and unloads the machine. The centering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> is important because the diameter of a knit tube varies slightly along its length, and it is necessary to reference cutting from the midline of the tube. Some die-cutting operations allow for a number of knit tubes to be centered, placed on one another, and then cut.
Like computer-controlled cutting equipment, large-capacity knit die-cutting presses are expensive machines; they can cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $400,000</NUMEX> and are generally found only in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> of the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>. The die is a razor-sharp steel outline of the desired item to be cut. Like a cookie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cutter</ENAMEX>, it is pressed down on the fabric and, if all is aligned, a replica of the die is cut from the tube. To change the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> to be cut, the die must be removed and a new one installed. The machines are massive in size because they must be rigid to achieve cutting along the entire silhouette. Die-cutters are much safer when fully automated, but building computerized loading and unloading features into the machine adds cost. Therefore, such machines are used only where long production runs of a given size of T-shirt or sweatpants will allow a payback of their capital costs through round-the-clock or multi-shift operations.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> other technical innovation deserves mention here, partly because it illustrates why the most sophisticated equipment is not always appropriate for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">factory</ENAMEX> operations. Laser-cutting of fabric remains a little used technique in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and abroad. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCTAR</ENAMEX> survey indicated <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.6 percent</NUMEX> usage among responding business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and, if the survey results are weighted by the dollar value of production, then the use drops to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 0.0002 percent</NUMEX>. We have seen such equipment working in a production setting in a knit goods manufacturer‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>; however, we believe that its immediate potential use is limited for several reasons. Laser-cutting equipment must be totally enclosed to be safe for human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>. A high-energy light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam vaporizes</ENAMEX> a very narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">path</ENAMEX> around the silhouette of the patterns to be cut. The enclosure contains the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vapors</ENAMEX> and conducts them to an exhaust outlet as well as prevents human access to the cutting region. A laser <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam</ENAMEX> can seriously harm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may not notice the small-diameter beams of light in an industrial environment.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty or more years ago</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">lasers</ENAMEX> were first used to cut cloth, a mixture of polyester and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> as well as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-percent polyester cloth was common. Attempts were then made to cut several plies of cloth at the same time. The light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam</ENAMEX> did cut through the plies, but it melted the polyester <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of the burn and fused the edges of the cloth together. No matter what is done, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam</ENAMEX> affects the edge of the cut. With the lower-intensity laser beams of the past, the bead of fused material at the edge of the cut formed a rough edge and was unpleasant to touch. Some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-edge sewing operations common with knit goods actually trim the edges of cloth just in front of the needle; in these cases any fused material from the laser cutting could be trimmed away. But, if nothing else, the temperature effects on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX>, combined with the cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">installation</ENAMEX>, appear to limit the use of this technology to those applications in which the connection between plies before sewing could be an advantage.
The great advantage of laser-cutting is speed. Modern laser-cutters, developed both in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, leave the laser fixed in position and move the light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam</ENAMEX> around simply by computer-controlled tilting of the mirrors that guide the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam</ENAMEX> along the desired path. With high-powered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">lasers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam</ENAMEX> can be moved quickly and still cut through the cloth. There may come a day when the demand for single-ply cutting and the economics of continuous laser-cutting will allow this technology to be more cost effective. Until then, it will not be widely used in the garment trade.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bundling the Parts</ENAMEX>
When cutting is completed, the pieces are removed in stacks and arranged in bundles for sewing. For many, if not most, applications, each ply in a bundle is marked with a sticker to indicate the actual garment to which the piece belongs. This can be an important step in men‚Äôs dress-suit assembly. Each suit is ideally made from pattern pieces cut from the same ply of cloth and the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>. This is done to avoid cloth matching problems, especially if the shade of the cloth varies along the roll. The point is to make sure that even very slight shade variations will not be apparent in the final assembly. It is also necessary to identify the individual pieces in order to assemble the correct pieces for a garment of a given size. As we have already noted, garments of various sizes are often grouped together on each ply of cloth<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX>
Some stacks of parts are further broken down into smaller bundles of parts so that sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> can use the same thread for everything in a bundle. Suits and pants require thread colors that match or blend with the shell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX>, and it is important to reduce the number of thread changes the sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> has to make. A work ticket is attached to each bundle of cloth, indicating the garment style, size, and all other necessary parameters. The main tag generally has subtags or tickets that the sewing machine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> collects to indicate that a sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> has been completed<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9</NUMEX>
This final preassembly step and those that precede it affect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly operations</ENAMEX> that follow. As we will see in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 9</ENAMEX>, work processes in the sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> have been designed to minimize the direct labor content in a garment. To ensure that sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> remain busy and operate at high productivity, apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> traditionally carry large ready-to-sew cut goods in front of their sewing lines. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> carried a median of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty-four hours</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> worth) of such goods. However, our sample also reveals that some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> began to adjust to the new demands of lean retailing: By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, the median dropped to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten hours</TIMEX>, reflecting their desire to reduce the amount of work-in-process at this beginning stage of apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX> Customization
The percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> wearing factory-made apparel has grown steadily since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the nineteenth century</TIMEX>. Some still rely on custom-made clothing, especially those who have to go this route because of their size and shape or those with the money to afford custom tailoring. Although many might like to have customized clothing, few consider it a realistic option. It is only recently that ‚Äúmass customization‚Äù may make sense for both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and apparel<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX>.10
Mass customization involves a number of preassembly innovations. When somebody orders custom-made clothing, his or her measurements are taken by a fitter in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three to six weeks later</TIMEX>, the garment appears. In this case, how was the suit, shirt, pants, or pair of jeans made? Were all the preassembly steps followed or did an individual tailor cut the cloth and make the entire garment? The answers depend on the garment as well as on just how ‚Äúcustom-made‚Äù it really was. Regardless of how customization was done in the past, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> paid more for the end product. Mass customization, however, has the potential to make ‚Äútailor fit‚Äù at least somewhat less expensive, as new systems combine features of the efficient factory system with attention to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least</NUMEX> a few critical customer measurements.
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different approaches under way. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> modifies an existing apparel design in a few dimensions to improve its fit for an individual customer. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi Strauss</ENAMEX>, which is currently offering custom-fit jeans for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, provides the best example of this kind of mass customization. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have a difficult time finding a pair of jeans that fits to their satisfaction. Buying jeans is based on both style and fit; for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> this means trying on several different brands and finally making compromises. Jeans-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> have tried to satisfy the majority by making many different styles and sizes, but for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> there still are not enough choices<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX> Fit for a given style involves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least four</NUMEX> different measurements. Obviously, waist and hip measurements are important, but where the waist should be also matters and, once that is determined, there is inseam length<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.12</NUMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi‚</ENAMEX>Äôs custom jeans is asked to try on the style that comes closest to the fit she wants. The store sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> then takes the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> key measurements: waist, hips, where the waist should be, and inseam. These measurements, along with the style of jeans and the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX>, are sent to a sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> where they are cut, sewn, and then mailed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi‚Äôs</ENAMEX> uses proprietary software to make these modifications, but other software systems are commercially available for modifying standard patterns and producing a marker to guide fabric cutting<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13</NUMEX>
The actual making of custom jeans or any other item of custom apparel is slightly more complicated than making an equivalent item under standard production conditions. The pattern pieces for each individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> of jeans must first be modified. Then a unique marker must be created that combines different orders using the same fabric. Under these conditions, a marker will not be as efficient as the standard production markers shown in Figures <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.1</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8.2</NUMEX> (page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">137</NUMEX>) because the amount of cloth that can be saved for a single ply does not justify the time required to reach high levels of cloth utilization. Indeed, fabric-cutting costs are higher for custom clothing than for mass-produced items simply because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> item of apparel is cut at a time.
Mass customization of this sort also means that a single garment must pass through the sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> at a time. Apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> is described in the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, but for now it is enough to say that all the pieces for a custom garment must be kept together during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>. If the sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> is making garments <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at a time, it is probably not using the progressive bundle system. Instead, items will be assembled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, who will do all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly operations</ENAMEX>. Such a short-cycle production system adds to the cost of customized apparel.
You cannot make a completely customized item of apparel with just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> measurements. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi‚</ENAMEX>Äôs process merely adjusts the pattern pieces of a basic style of jeans with these measurements. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> wants more areas or features customized, many more measurements are necessary. Achieving consistent measurements presents a major problem because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> trained <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fitters</ENAMEX> will generally come up with important differences in the body measurements of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. No matter how the measurements are taken, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being measured in this way have a difficult time standing up straight and holding in their stomachs.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> approach to mass customization attempts to overcome some of these problems by optically scanning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> with light beams in a private area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. In this case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> needs to be dressed in appropriately tight (form fitting, but not form modifying) athletic shorts and a top. The computer-processed results of such a scan are shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.3</NUMEX> (page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">148</NUMEX>), with a sample of the extracted body dimensions in inches printed on the right side of the figure. For reference, some of the measurements are highlighted and presented as darkened lines on the processed image.
The optical system that produced this image was developed by [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX>]<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and is now ready for commercial demonstration<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.14</NUMEX> This system will probably cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>, and a demonstration in a shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> is currently under way. When in place, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> will be scanned at a central location in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>. They would then take their body measurements to any of several participating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>, who pass the information on to their apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> and have the clothing custom-made.
Computer-generated body measurements are just the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, if most important, step in achieving success in fit for customized apparel. The measurements must still be transmitted to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAD</ENAMEX> system that will automatically alter the pattern to conform to specific body measurements. From that point, the pattern must be laid out, cut, and sewn by a group of sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>.
The technology now exists to do mass customization, whether that involves a pair of jeans based on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> measurements or a garment custom-made from a whole body scan. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, including [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX>]<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, offer 3-D scanners, and there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> with systems that can adjust basic patterns to conform to individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> measurements. Custom clothing may therefore be financially available to a wider <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> in the future, opening a new market in which domestic apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> can compete. The general public interest in the possibilities of mass customization is evidenced by a recent article in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The¬†New York Times</ENAMEX> describing the techniques and reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of several apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> expressed interest in exploring the public willingness to pay for better fitting clothing<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.15</NUMEX>
From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preassembly</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assembly</ENAMEX>
Mass customization represents an innovative combination of new technologies in information, design, marker-making, and cutting. For the short term, its impact will be on a relatively small niche market. However, lean retailing and product proliferation place much more general pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> to decrease time and cost per SKU associated with the design and preassembly steps we have described.
In many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, central spreading and cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> abut the area of fabric inventory. Finished goods distribution is often a part of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. Centralization of this kind makes financial sense because <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> that take out cut parts to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">firm‚Äôs sewing rooms</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> can return with finished goods for inventory. Having spreading, computer-cutting, fusing, and inspection in the same areas also allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of cross-trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to prepare the order for sewing, finishing, final inspection, and packaging. This is one place in apparel manufacturing where teamwork has been quite successful. In many cases, it has shortened the cycle time from order to ready for sewing by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. In addition, computer-cutting or die-cutting makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> less dependent on the skill of a manual cutter and allows all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to operate automated-cutting equipment.
These centralized spreading and cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">facilities</ENAMEX> generally operate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> shifts per day and, in some large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, around the clock. The equipment is capital intensive, especially if computerized or die-cutting machinery is used; therefore, plant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> try to keep these lines producing as much as possible. We have visited a large knit goods <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> that combined final fabric finishing operations in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> with cutting and initial automated sewing, all of which operated around the clock. Although automation of sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> is generally not cost effective, these innovations have made some inroads in particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T-shirts</ENAMEX>, which are consumed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX>, are a good example. A commercially available machine can automatically make the sleeves of T-shirts. This machine picks up cut material from a carousel at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one end</TIMEX> and delivers finished sleeves at the other. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> can tend to the needs of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> such machines. Yet because the investment per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX>, it only makes sense if the equipment is used nearly continuously.
Sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>, in contrast, are not capital intensive and are rarely operated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> shift. Because of this, most expensive automation equipment is concentrated in preassembly, drawing on multi-shift operations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marker</ENAMEX>-making, fusing processes, sleeve-making for T-shirts, die-cutting, and computer-driven knife-cutting fall into this automated <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚</ENAMEX>Äúgetting ready to sew‚Äù category. As always in a world of lean retailing and rapid replenishment, the need for faster production is what drives these capital-intensive technical innovations. Because some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> have found that centralizing preassembly operations also improves the quality of products, this may provide another edge for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> apparel<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX> in the future.
Our survey indicates that the average length of time it takes to get a garment ready for sewing, from issuing the order for a given marker to having the pieces cut and otherwise prepared, is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4.9 working days</TIMEX>. The cut parts are then sent to sewing areas or other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>. If the sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> is in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> as the cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, then cut goods are sent over many times a day. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sewing factory</ENAMEX> is far away, then a shipment once a week is typical. Reducing the time from placement of the order to cut goods in the sewing room requires decreasing both the time it takes to complete preassembly and the wait for delivery to the sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. Indeed, logistical considerations enter assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> before garments are finally sewn together. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> really is money in today‚Äôs apparel industry, a theme we will expand on in the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>.



