
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh well how is it appropriate to be talking about exercise attitudes
 	
 	
 		what um well um my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is right now teaching an aerobics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> he's an aerobics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um is going to be uh entering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Texas</ENAMEX> for uh a kinesiology program there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um  the the how i met him was through uh the aerobics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> that he used to teach
 	
 	
 		um-hum you're a student
 	
 	
 		yeah so i'm i'm an avid aerobics  uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and just very very athletic enjoying a you know uh anything dealing with sports
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so and how do you feel about it
 	
 	
 		um i'm i am a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who wishes i had more time to exercise i
 		i don't feel like i
 		i don't very often do things for the sake of exercise i don't feel well unless i am exercising and i try to do things that involve exercise but i very rarely do things
 		like um i've never done aerobics or any sort of structured this is my exercise time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i do lots of outdoor sports and things bicycling uh
 		you know
 		mountaineering a little mountaineering this and that and i spend a lot of time and i probably get more exercise than your average person
 		but it's not a a structured sort of thing and i have to admit i have a certain resistance to the idea of exercising for exercising's sake and perhaps it's because somehow that implies to me it's not fun or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well i i've my that's the way my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> stands on it she feels like if it's something that you have to do you know if you look at it as if you have to do it then it becomes it becomes a chore and and she doesn't enjoy it when it's a chore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		so um and i feel that way too as far as
 		you you know just sitting and doing you know to the idea of doing fifty sit-ups or something you know to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know a a calculated you know calculated down and do your calisthenics you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> or but but i do try and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i do try and regulate how much exercise i get a week
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah is that why you like aerobics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> because you're not sort of someone else is doing the counting for you so it makes it less of a chore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and it's got and i've always enjoyed dance
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it involves you know i i can't get out to dance all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah would that we could
 	
 	
 		and yeah  and it's and it's more regulated i mean you're you're using different parts of the body so it it is like dance and and it's structured like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that but you have the music and someone like you said someone else is counting so it makes it easier for me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and someone else is telling me okay you know let's let's move this way let's move that way instead of me having to think about it so much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right you can just trust someone else to give you full exercise and all you do is follow along and enjoy yourself
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah but i'm like you i also um
 		like to participate in uh things like well we just went to the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myerson Symphony Run</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> and and that was a lot of fun and you get to meet different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just get out you know out and about and it's it it's something you can all like our we did it as a family so it was it was quite a lot of fun and biking and i i i love to swim so i love it when you know it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		swimming weather and uh
 	
 	
 		hm well you're talking to someone from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> where it's often swimming weather
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't realize that i'm sorry well i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i i just assumed that i had this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> call i've done and i didn't realize that they had were gonna
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		reach out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from all over the country
 	
 	
 		so it's the it's it's the the active well it's actually it's interesting because there are real real regional differences um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> there's uh almost an assumption
 	
 	
 		you wouldn't know that  oh i
 	
 	
 		um
 		unless you're sort of clearly of an
 		older generation or something you know in your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> or something like that i'm i'm i'm
 		uh there's an assumption that you do something for your physical fitness and and at least in urban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and maybe not i don't know about rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> too well but in urban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> it's just
 		you know for all i know aerobics started out here i don't know where they actually started but they you know the craze really picked up big here
 		and before that there was the running craze and they <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> gets you know tends to be a bit faddish but the remarkable thing is how well the fads catch on elsewhere so there must be something to some of them and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are are more encouraged
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> seem to be more health motivated all around i mean as far as the diet and everything uh the diet and uh just
 		your your your health consciousness and i mean it just seems like uh a lot of those ideas generate out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> not just exercise but health health related
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		ideas and i it's curious i don't know why don't know if it's
 		do you does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> have a
 	
 	
 		well there's a sense of it being a package i think there there is a sense of you know whole there's a lot of you know you'll get
 		which is uh turned into a fairly well subscribed to uh newsletter
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> or biweekly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsletter</ENAMEX> or something like that and
 		and it doesn't deal with just exercise or just stress <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> or just diet or anything it it's
 		on fairly solid solid scientific ground uh it's just dispensed with these distinctions it says every all sorts of factors go into health and there's no reason to talk about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> rather than another so that they they combined them all together
 		and uh so it's had that orientation for quite sometime um there's been some progressive medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> out here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that have taken that approach and um
 	
 	
 		now do you think that's because they've realized that
 		for whole health that the you know you have to have that combination or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are motivated that way so that they've incorporated that into their program
 		do you think the program came <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> or the
 	
 	
 		boy yeah that there's a i i can say there's a correlation but i couldn't say which which caused the other they sort of developed you know each developed a little bit and then would feed off one another and develop a little bit more and a little bit more
 	
 	
 		yeah the more money they put into it i can see that because i knowing from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutes</ENAMEX> of learning like that i know that they've got to get their money somewhere and somebody's got to be willing to pay for it and believe in it so
 	
 	
 		yeah and some
 		yeah yeah exactly
 		and part of it is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> you know in back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> had a lot of alternative movements and some of them fizzled out and some of them were disastrous and others of them um had an impact on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> around here and one of the ones that had an impact was
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um people</ENAMEX> becoming interested in alternate
 		practices i don't know if it was a meditation practice or sure it was you know
 		which is similar to a stress management practice or alternates to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> approved <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine um</ENAMEX> you have you know major um acupuncture <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and things out here and
 		and you could have them around long enough and more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> start believing them or wondering how to combine them with other things and before long
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you you get this this whole kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gestalt</ENAMEX> this whole package of of health of health care and options
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh and exercise is is strongly considered one of them
 		the irony is is it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in my experience that are most oriented
 		towards
 		doing the exercises and i guess because they spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> in back of their desks the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> out on the farm at least traditionally now they drive fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractors</ENAMEX> as much as anything but at least traditionally the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX> last thing pardon me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		or they're older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> don't you think they tend to be older in the rural area i i i sometimes think that it's almost frantic effort on the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> i live in a rural area so you know i see the
 	
 	
 		oh like everything else yeah yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> race to exercise
 	
 	
 		it's it's yeah it's it's like it's frantic to you know to uh achieve something that that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">area um</ENAMEX>  almost doesn't worry about it to such a degree but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		stays you know more healthier you know as a fit person
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i think so i mean you you've if you look at certain if you look at other cultures like i know a little bit about
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were considered very healthy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and they don't do very much vigorous exercise at all but they do a lot of low keyed low impact low stress exercise and they combine it with a you know meditation or whatever some sort of relaxation and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they seem pretty you know they don't have the hard body they don't have that perfect look and an awful lot of exercises is sort of image conscious but they you know they live to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and ten</NUMEX> some day you know and that that's
 	
 	
 		yeah well don't you think a lot of that is diet too yeah
 	
 	
 		and a lot of that is diet that's true yeah i mean they eat they eat a lot of carbohydrates and not much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fat um</ENAMEX> for economical reasons not for preference um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and as we can see well i'm a i'm a practicing vegetarian so uh i've read a lot of information knowing that to be true what's that
 	
 	
 		yes as am i actually i as am i
 	
 	
 		oh are you also  well that's that's good as far as the calisthenics is that is that um pretty predominant as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> do do
 	
 	
 		yes
 		it is in the urban areas yes most for example most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> in an urban area will have a little vegetarian section now
 	
 	
 		in the urban areas
 		um-hum oh that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		well most most modern sort of modern looking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> will
 	
 	
 		yeah that's great i mean we uh it's such a trouble it's such a trouble here i mean you just have to eat at home basically
 	
 	
 		you can
 		i was wondering that because i was actually applying for a job in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and and and uh it occurred to me
 	
 	
 		well of course in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> yeah well in the cities we live close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> so um which
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you you know you get uh an influx of a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're gonna have a lot of  more choices but in urban areas it's you know steak places an and it's not a you know it's uh it's definitely it it's it's changing to a degree but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		um  it's very frustrating and even even with health food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> where you can buy natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> or uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		organic you know materials and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> and things you don't really have that i mean you would think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	