
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		have you done a lot of camping recently
 	
 	
 		no i haven't been camping since i was about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		but uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> used to have a pop-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> and we'd go camping to a lot of different places we spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bastrop Texas</ENAMEX> once
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		uh where's that
 	
 	
 		it's near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay i'm not that much familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we've been my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> has been everywhere
 		but mostly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> on the way to someplace else we've had oh gosh we've
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've camped in a in a in a back of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van van</ENAMEX> then we got then we got a pop-up camper and then we got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> now they've got now they've got a big motor home so they they still do a whole lot of camping
 	
 	
 		have you ever been camping in any of the big national parks
 	
 	
 		oh gosh yes uh  oh Yellowstone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years ago four or five years ago</TIMEX> and um
 		oh we did my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> when i was younger we went that was just you know what we did in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> was go to the from you know national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> to national park
 		we had a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		when i go camping i don't i don't like to rough it i like to have some a little bit of electricity electricity and a little bit of running water
 	
 	
 		yes
 		me too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm not really into this going and sitting in a tent for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> with nothing
 	
 	
 		oh no no  i've done it but it's not fun  you don't want to do it for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> at a time that's for sure
 	
 	
 		God
 		i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that go camping for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks every summer</TIMEX> they're both geologists and they load up their truck with their tent and they go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX>
 		and they just find places to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and go looking for rocks and
 	
 	
 		ooh no  no
 	
 	
 		doesn't sound like a lot of fun to me uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> said that the last time they went uh she just got tired of the tent and it was cold at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and she got tired of eating out of cans and so they stayed in a hotel <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		just for fun
 	
 	
 		shaking the scorpions out of their shoes
 	
 	
 		no kidding no kidding gosh that's what the the the bugs i don't like the bugs
 	
 	
 		oh me neither me neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">the mosquitoes</ENAMEX> just keep you up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> good nice thing i remember about camping with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> is they had a big hammock and they would always find a couple of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campsite</ENAMEX> with a couple of good <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> to hang it in between and i could just lay in that hammock for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that that's nice
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> when my family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> we're the the only time you're at the camper is when you want to sleep  otherwise you're just going constantly you know in all the in all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Parks</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		oh
 		hum
 	
 	
 		we camped at the let's see we camped down at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">at Galveston</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years ago</TIMEX> and that that was that was fun except that they uh were having a lot of problems with dead <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> on the shore and they were
 		and the and the smell of that was kind of gross but
 	
 	
 		we stayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Galveston Island State Park</ENAMEX> once but if a storm blew in and it was just horrible and the sand was blowing up our camp the little camping area was pretty near the shore
 	
 	
 		oh how awful
 		um-hum oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and there were some pretty big dunes before the the camping area and the sand was all blowing up and couldn't even go out of the camper the wind was blowing so hard because you'd get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX> in your eyes
 	
 	
 		oh that's miserable
 	
 	
 		yeah it was pretty bad
 	
 	
 		yeah i had
 	
 	
 		yeah pretty bad but we had a good time in our camper we usually we usually took box games and things to do in case it rained and they my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> always let us take a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> so we always had a good time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it's it's you it's you you always when you when there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you've always got to have other stuff to do because it's always gonna rain sometime  and then your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents parents</ENAMEX> they drive the parents nuts
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and
 		yeah well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> aren't easily entertained by just enjoying the nature
 	
 	
 		oh i know i wish i'd appreciated i wish i'd appreciated it more you uh when i was when we were camping so extensively you when we when we were younger
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now i wish i could go back to those places yeah the time and i've got got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the way so  i wish i had time my my our pop-up camper just sits in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> and collects dust unfortunately
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh gosh it makes it a little
 		my fiance and i <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> would like to own a big motor home
 		mainly because he's a football he's a college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> and we're gonna have to travel a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it'd be nice if we had a big ole motor home and that way i could load up the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> and go to wherever the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football game</ENAMEX> is and have someplace to sleep without spending big money for a hotel and and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> it outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> and have a good ole time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's true
 		plus it's nice to have your own stuff there yeah plus you get eating out is expensive is so expensive and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that is nice
 		no kidding it really is
 	
 	
 		so it it it it's a it can be really handy to have a camper just
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		because my our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> and uh when we take trips home we take our pop-up with us in good weather and stay overnight at a state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> or something so we don't have to rent a hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and that's
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		that's nice you know paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six dollars</NUMEX> instead of forty
 	
 	
 		yeah no kidding
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 		what else
 		
 
 		well
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think that's just pretty much it we've been on here awhile
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well it's been nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		nice talking to you too bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	