
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh how do you feel about gun control
 	
 	
 		uh on the scale they gave <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> i'd say i'm probably a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four</NUMEX>
 		i'm not totally i'm not
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that believes that we should not be able to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> but i don't think we should be carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uzis</ENAMEX> either  you know what i mean  yeah i know i mean i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine guns</ENAMEX> automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> i don't believe in things like that but i think
 	
 	
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do i know
 	
 	
 		that everyone should have the right to have a hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> if they so choose and but i think there should be some  restrictions when you buy one you know they should do more background search on you they should i think it should be harder to buy one
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah there's a lot of crazies out there that can just go in and buy a gun because they don't really ask a lot of questions when you walk into those stores
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no they don't they don't ask anything except how old you are i don't think that's kind of scary
 	
 	
 		i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> the last time i was like purchased a gun my  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> that he wanted like an antique <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>  and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they he had to fill out some forms but i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> might be tougher i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah they might be or you know how we are here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it's like everybody's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> so  i'm not much of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's
 	
 	
 		i've never even bought a gun myself my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s given it to me or someone's given me one so i'm probably real illegal you know carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> that aren't even mine
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it's a it's a hard decision to make
 	
 	
 		it really is uh the only problem i have with gun control is that they the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX> wanna ban all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and then the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are gonna be be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are gonna kill you anyway
 	
 	
 		like the bumper sticker  it's true yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly right it really is because they're gonna get them one way or another they will always have a way look at <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> they always have a way to get that so
 	
 	
 		right
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and they're illegal so i don't think it would do us any good to outlaw them all together
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i yeah i i i i i agree that it would be like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> are the ones that are gonna get them and then you have no defense against these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when they do  come into your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's true
 		i think they ought to teach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> how to shoot them too how to take care of one how to act around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> when they buy them
 	
 	
 		yeah i have have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun gun</ENAMEX> have have gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> 101
 	
 	
 		right yeah exactly you cannot take the gun <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> until you've taken this course sign up here  something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah or required required required for every college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>  oh
 	
 	
 		right exactly  before graduation
 	
 	
 		God gun control  it's it's such a heated topic in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">the</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get so emotional about it
 	
 	
 		yep
 		oh yeah they do they get real emotional about it all the i've worked with a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that hunt and they just they they don't see any sense in it at all
 		they think it's ridiculous to have any kind of gun control but then of course they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> they know what they're doing they don't realize there're a bunch of crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there that
 	
 	
 		some of them are crazy too  whew yeah yeah they go out there and get drunk and start shooting
 	
 	
 		don't use it for that  well yeah that's true  they shoot each other thinking they're a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer  yeah darn</ENAMEX> i thought you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> Bob sorry my mistake
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marge</ENAMEX> i don't know what happened to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> he just never came back
 	
 	
 		looked like antlers i don't know
 		
 
 		yep that happens a lot too
 	
 	
 		yeah  oh
 	
 	
 		but i guess that's it
 		that's my opinion on it  so what now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm not sure
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh i think we just hang up yeah okay  thanks bye
 	
 	
 		i let's see
 		yeah yeah we just say good-bye and hang up okay okay okay thanks bye-bye
 		
 		
 	