
 
     		
 	
 		this is Archie
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hi Archie i'm Sharon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have you seen Dancing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i've seen that that's uh that was a really good movie probably one of the best things about it was the scenery and uh
 		i thought the story was pretty good too i think i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> did a really good job with it
 	
 	
 		have you ever lived in that part of the country
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		have you ever visited it
 	
 	
 		um i've visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> area i'm not sure exactly where Dances with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Wolves</ENAMEX> was filmed
 	
 	
 		i think it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black Hills</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		could be i  i haven't been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>
 		have have you been up to that
 	
 	
 		well i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omaha</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five winters</TIMEX> and that rolling kind of uh
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		terrain
 	
 	
 		yeah is is fairly familiar the thing that i thought was interesting was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> apparently it's gonna win everything
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i had been told you know you wouldn't notice that it was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> long and all this kind of
 	
 	
 		that's true i agree with that um i i noticed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in the paper something said that it i think it's been nominated for twelve awards and and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> initially said that you know it wouldn't go anywhere that it was just gonna be a dud so it it has surprised everybody
 	
 	
 		well the interesting thing was is i had heard that and i i i tend to i think overreact occasionally when somebody tells me it's that great and and it was the thing is it was a it was a good story
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and and and i guess that's what i really like although i must admit i did look at my watch after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		did you
 		have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleeping with the Enemy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i've heard i've heard that's really great though
 	
 	
 		you you have to go see that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and how about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silence</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lambs</ENAMEX> go
 	
 	
 		no you must really keep up
 	
 	
 		i do i go <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekend</TIMEX> i i uh those are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> definite must see movies i think
 	
 	
 		well isn't isn't Sleeping with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enemy</ENAMEX> isn't that a is is it is it a terror movie or is it just suspenseful
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's suspenseful i don't think it's very terror i mean there's not really any uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and guts in it or anything like that it's it's more suspense
 		um  the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silence of the Lambs</ENAMEX> is kind of a a gory movie if if somebody's not into that kind of stuff it's it's pretty graphic at points but uh i think they're both excellent movies
 	
 	
 		do you do you listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Cohill Cohill</ENAMEX> is uh you know who he is
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh
 		yeah somebody in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> told me about him
 	
 	
 		he's a the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> um oh you've oh okay he's a movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> on channel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and he does uh he has a talk show on the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLIF</ENAMEX> anyway it's on from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> or something and and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> call in and it's if you keep up with movies it's kind of interesting there's a certain amount of drivel that they do they've got uh they've got a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> and they call in and they review movies but it's uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		he anyway he it's interesting you listen to him and then you you go watch the movie fact they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had just seen i was listening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> a little bit when i was going to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pick up my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> but anyway it was uh it the it it's interesting though the the the difficulty with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">with Dancing with Wolves</ENAMEX> is that when you make a movie like that and you produce it and then you star in it
 		uh the question is did he did he really know it was gonna be good or did he just do it
 	
 	
 		i think that i think he really his heart was in it but i don't i don't think he really knew it was gonna be as big as it was i think it was something that he really wanted to do
 		he wanted to direct it he wanted to act to star in it you know he he enjoyed the story line and i think he just really wanted he really wanted it whether it
 		whether it won all kinds of awards or whether it just was okay at the box office i think he would have been happy because
 		i think that i think he did a good job and and the self-satisfaction he got out of it is much greater than any awards that they can give him
 	
 	
 		do you know who the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was that was playing the uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		a little piece of trivia you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> when he <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> headed out from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">army</ENAMEX> post
 	
 	
 		yeah who no i don't know who that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		he he plays on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murphy Brown</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh he does
 	
 	
 		yes he's
 	
 	
 		as a recurring character every week
 	
 	
 		he's Eldon her housepainter
 	
 	
 		oh no now see i'd a i'd a never put those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> together
 	
 	
 		do you believe that
 		that's  that's one of those interesting pieces of trivia that somebody said did you notice that i thought no it's really funny but i thought it it turns you think back and yeah it was him but with a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know with the beard and all that stuff i mean it's uh
 	
 	
 		yeah real scruffy looking
 	
 	
 		yeah real scruffy looking and it was it was really funny it's uh that that he winds up playing in the movie but i thought it's good that you know it was a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know how long this conversation is supposed to go but we're at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about five minutes</TIMEX> i should think we've done enough
 	
 	
 		you think so i mean i haven't been watching my watch um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i don't know what how do we end this thing i think it just says hang up
 		why don't we do that good-bye <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	