
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i am new to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so i don't even know what the law is in the state do you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well yes of course we do have capital punishment and we've you know done away with our quote fair share number
 	
 	
 		oh that's right i think now that i recall reading about it in the paper
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		um you know different things is it restricted to certain crimes or just
 	
 	
 		yes it's certain crimes uh capital crimes murder of course uh rape this sort of thing
 	
 	
 		um-hum hum
 		well
 	
 	
 		and it seems to be a disproportionate number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> you know that get into the system
 	
 	
 		yes i know the one thing that i think is really sad about it as i recall from the articles that i've read is that if if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have been there
 		
 
 		are going to be killed  um there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> and
 		and they're very violent and they want i mean they're anxious for someone to be killed i just i can't see that
 	
 	
 		um-hum yes that
 		that happens on occasion it sure does maybe it just depends on you know how closely the crime you know has affected you personally you know i don't know or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> personally
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no
 	
 	
 		i think i would be  you know i guess really if i had to say yes or no i guess i would say you know that
 		i am in certain cases in favor of the death penalty i don't know that it's a big deterrent really i don't know that it is i don't know how we'd ever find out you know really whether it is or not
 	
 	
 		well there is so many chances for appeal that it keep
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh absolutely yeah it goes on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of thousands of dollars</NUMEX> taxpayer money
 	
 	
 		yeah it's really sad i don't know i just think um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		somehow i hoped that as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we could be better than than um expecting
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		the feeling that it right with someone is calling for someone else to be killed you know
 	
 	
 		yes um-hum
 	
 	
 		is really kind of bad and
 	
 	
 		yeah it is it's it's a tough tough question it really is
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		i suspect i would be uh you know a lot more favor of it if you know one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were you know brutally killed or something like that like i say i think it depends on how personally affected you know you might be by it
 	
 	
 		that's true and there really are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> that are hard-core and repeat and never never have any chance for
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely
 		that's
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know is it do you feel at all like it's a religious issue
 	
 	
 		not with me personally it is with a lot of other people
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's not not to me personally no
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		i don't know sometimes i feel i mean i do go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and things i don't know how i would feel about it but like you say if it hit you personally closer at home you would feel feel differently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 		that's a it's a tough tough question it really is
 	
 	
 		do you think most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have that or
 	
 	
 		yes i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> do have capital punishment yes
 	
 	
 		um-hum hum
 	
 	
 		but i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> is one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that still do
 	
 	
 		that still does it that's right
 	
 	
 		yes they're only i was reading something about it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> i think there was only like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six or eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the world that have capital punishment still
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a lot of them had to have elected elected not to do so now i don't know what they do in place of it you know maybe it's
 		life imprisonment or you know something i don't i don't know how they handle it but
 		i was surprised to learn that so few <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have capital punishment
 	
 	
 		have that well and it doesn't seem like very many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh are really i mean there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are on death row but there's not very many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that actually um do get killed
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yes a lot of them do get their sentences commuted to something else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so it seems like a of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live there and
 		through appeals because i know they do frequently i mean they cover cover it pretty heavily on television and the newspaper
 	
 	
 		yes
 		uh-huh yes
 	
 	
 		if it finally gets to that point
 	
 	
 		right the first appeal is automatic so
 		that delays it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> just right off the bat
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there's there's a lot of you know last minute uh
 		things that happen cause a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> not to have to go through the whole thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so is it uh  are we doing lethal injection now
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh that's that's fairly recent i don't know how recent but fairly recent in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> before that it was uh death by electrocution
 	
 	
 		um-hum which which seems so awful
 	
 	
 		yes it certainly does
 	
 	
 		so it's a little bit more humane i guess it is
 	
 	
 		yes it would almost have to be i suppose if you if you had to chose i guess i would i am sure i would take the lethal injection
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> just seems so terrible
 	
 	
 		yes absolutely
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		it's a it's a tough question it really is i guess if i had to say
 		you know yes or no i would say you know yes i i would have to lean toward capital punishment you know for certain crimes
 	
 	
 		well do you think that we do it because we want it to deter crime or it's not because we don't want to pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> to stay in prison
 	
 	
 		no i don't think it's a monetary thing i think we hope that it will be you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some sort of determent deterrent or you know an eye for an eye type thing or something like that
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		some of the crimes are just so brutal and so you know useless
 		this may seem to be the best way out i don't know
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		easiest way out maybe
 		no i don't think it's a monetary thing
 	
 	
 		hum
 		well um and i notice that the crime rate was up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area  it's
 	
 	
 		yes especially the murder rate its just gone crazy
 	
 	
 		and it's kind of been scary to think about it and
 	
 	
 		yes absolutely
 	
 	
 		and you're hoping there is something that will cut down on that
 	
 	
 		yes i wish i had the answer for that everybody does
 	
 	
 		you hate to have the dubious honor of being
 		you know so high in the
 	
 	
 		yes it's nothing to be proud of certainly not
 	
 	
 		in statistics
 		but i you know we have been really fortunate our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> hasn't had
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		any crime
 	
 	
 		so have we been very very fortunate
 	
 	
 		and so we don't
 		it's harder to think about the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have suffered that way
 	
 	
 		that's right absolutely
 	
 	
 		and how they would expect how they would
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hope i mean you you hear of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have um committed crimes and then they get out of jail and they go and they do the same thing again and you wonder why they can't just stop it
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's right
 	
 	
 		so maybe you would
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but still i would hate to be on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that sentenced someone
 	
 	
 		so would i i fortunately i have never been in that circumstance i hope i never am like like everybody else
 	
 	
 		no  i know when um we just we moved here um i from the
 		i got a summons jury summons just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like constantly it seemed like but fortunately i had small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i didn't have to go and it's not that i mean i think everyone should have to serve on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> it's just that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i didn't i hate having to be in charge of someone else's life
 	
 	
 		sure it's it's a big responsibility it really is
 	
 	
 		and i would hate to have to hear any kind of case involving a violent crime or anything
 	
 	
 		yes
 		so would i
 	
 	
 		that would be really awful
 	
 	
 		yes absolutely
 	
 	
 		well anyway i sure have enjoyed uh  talking to you about this although it has been difficult but uh
 	
 	
 		it is it's a tough subject it really is
 	
 	
 		i'd hate to decide it but i guess um
 		guess it's important that we decide as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> what what we're going to do
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		anyway well you have a good day
 	
 	
 		well thank you it's nice talking to you uh-huh bye bye
 	
 	
 		thank you bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	