
 
     		
 	
 		okay hi
 	
 	
 		hi um yeah i'd like to talk about how you dress for work and and um what do you normally what type of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> do you normally have to wear
 	
 	
 		well i work in uh corporate control so we have to dress kind of nice so i usually wear skirts and sweaters in the winter time slacks i guess  and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> just dresses
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we can't even well we're not even really supposed to wear jeans very often
 		so it really doesn't vary that much from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is kind of you know always the same temperature
 	
 	
 		and is
 		right right is there is there um any is there a like a code of dress where you work do they ask
 	
 	
 		so
 		not formally
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but it's kind of understood that we're supposed to dress a little bit nice a lot of times we have to go over to uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Junkins</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Ellsworth</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to deliver stuff
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and we prepare a lot of foils for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin</ENAMEX> and Bill so  we have to dress a little bit nice we're not
 	
 	
 		right right and does it does it change i guess um you can can you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> like  depending on what you think you'll be doing that day
 	
 	
 		yes now you know if if everybody like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> when everybody's on vacation or something we can dress a little more casual or
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		ice storms of course you know we all came in in our tennis shoes but  i guess that would have to do with the weather but um
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah yeah well it it that's right and it
 	
 	
 		unless it's an extremely you know an unusual day
 	
 	
 		yeah and it was usually uh also uh where i was it was um in in engineering and and it was it was a casual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> there was no formal dress code but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um uh usually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> are expected to to dress you know little more professionally it just in case things would come up during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> sometimes unexpected meetings or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> would come in and wanna see you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh other times it could be very casual if you knew you would be at a desk <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> and nobody would see you  um
 	
 	
 		yeah or um-hum what area do you work in
 	
 	
 		uh well i was i was in a uh private consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> so um and uh and uh anyway um right now i'm i'm not i'm not there but  but anyway
 	
 	
 		um
 		okay
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and season really same season to season um uh it changes with the weather you know uh wear light clothing i guess if it's hot out but um
 	
 	
 		it with the
 		yeah
 		but then usually in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> it's cold in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> because the air conditioner's doing its job so well
 	
 	
 		that's
 		that's true and and i think also that um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> actually have uh uh you have a little bit more variety maybe maybe lighter <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX> clothing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and woolens in the winter whereas the
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> often have to wear shirt and tie no matter right right right what time of what time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> that's right
 	
 	
 		it
 		uh-huh just suits and there's not a whole lot of fabric variance there and they can't have a rayon suit  so
 	
 	
 		that's that's true so um do they were were there um are you allowed to um be casual like if it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> were were you allowed to wear sandals and those that  not really
 	
 	
 		not really i think i mean it's kind of unwritten but i think we're supposed to wear hose and and shoes you know most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do anyway
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> wear uh most actually most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> wear suits more than anything else
 	
 	
 		oh i see uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but i'm not in that professional of a position  so i don't i'm not expected to do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and and
 		and also like the um also the the all the supporting kind of stuff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> and things are they also they have same similar similar yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes pretty much i'm a secretary  yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah ours were ours were different i guess it seemed like they they were much there was much more casual dress although i don't think everybody looked at that you know as a good thing
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah but there's really no written rule i guess they couldn't write that down that might be discrimination or something i don't know i mean i've never been told what to wear or what not to wear
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's that's right
 	
 	
 		it's just you know judging from what everyone else wears is how i determine
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and
 	
 	
 		you know what i feel a comfortable in you don't wanna stand out too much
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		yeah that's true and um hm  well that's it
 	
 	
 		well that pretty much covers the subject  well thanks for calling me
 	
 	
 		yeah  i don't know what else what more we can say about that that's
 		oh it's been nice talking to you and i guess we just hang up huh okay all right nice talking to you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		yep that's all good-bye okay bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	