
 
     		
 	
 		okay i'll let you start first okay
 	
 	
 		okay we um i'm presently living in a house uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time uh
 		we had the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> built and so this is our our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> year in it i guess and uh
 		um it was a really excitement to uh
 		
 
 		to go out and select a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and have one made and built and like you wanted it we were the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> to build out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred and forty</NUMEX> houses
 		and um as we did with probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety five</NUMEX> percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Fort Worth</ENAMEX> we bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacobs</ENAMEX> home
 		and they're good for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years or four years</TIMEX> and after that they start falling apart
 		so i would um
 		not recommend F and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> to live in uh because they're overpriced
 		um but they're a cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> if you can't afford something good you know they're good for that and um you can call it a home because it's a place to go home and keep the rain off your head but as far as the costs for what your getting
 		uh the longevity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is not uh is not worth it
 		how about in your case
 	
 	
 		well in my case my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is not a carpenter but in fact he's in electronics but he knew the only way we'd ever have a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is if he would build it
 		so it took him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two and a half years</TIMEX>
 		but uh he built us a house
 		it's uh we have <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thirty two hundred square feet</NUMEX>
 		and it's a brick house
 		and pricewise it wasn't great because he did it all hisself you know so that way he could we could kind of control in control it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um we live in kind of a small town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i mean it's nothing fancy you know it's it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> it's nice and it's real pretty and we're all comfortable in it
 	
 	
 		well that's great that's great that's uh i've heard i have another gentleman <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine who uh
 		who had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> built  matter of fact another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s building one now he's been doing it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s a little upset with him but i understand you save a lot of money off uh by doing that and uh
 	
 	
 		oh you can because that way your not having to pay the middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and everybody else
 	
 	
 		nothing wrong with that uh i'll vouch for that
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so but uh of course my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> did everything except my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s a trim carpenter and he came in you know and did the inside for us
 		and that helped and and uh yes and uh we had to hire course the plumbing and the brick and everything else nothing you know he did everything else
 	
 	
 		that was a big savings
 		well that's great well have you been in it long
 	
 	
 		we've been in it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really well have you do you have any plans to uh maybe um expand or move onward
 	
 	
 		no no well well uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are kind of still small now and we had thought before when they get a lot older we don't need such a large house
 		that we'll sell it but he will not build a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one himself  because he says agewise he'll never be able to handle that again yes yes
 	
 	
 		i see well
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one's always a bear
 		we're having a an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect friend</ENAMEX> of mine design a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for us and uh that can basically be be be put on any lot in any state any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you know so that's kind of the
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		we just got with him and told him what all we wanted and he's charging about a buck a square foot to design it and he's registered certified and registered so at least we know we're it's not gonna fall in or something if it's built but uh i have heard
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah oh
 	
 	
 		that your approach is is is right you can actually go out and sub it if even if you don't wanna get hands on you can even just sub it out the concrete and those kind of things and and that's kind of the plan i have so um uh everyone i talk to uh i've
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i file in my little book and do other things with it uh that's great that's great
 	
 	
 		but uh like i said otherwise you know a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the</TIMEX> the expense but you know we could not had one as large as we have if you know we hadn't did it ourself
 	
 	
 		sure i can imagine
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean it's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eldorado</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or anything like that but you know it's ours
 	
 	
 		if your happy with it that's all that counts
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		that's only only uh you only have to uh satisfy yourself and no one else
 	
 	
 		apparently apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appraisers</ENAMEX> likes it because our taxes sure is high  isn't it it really is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ooh</ENAMEX> and that's uh that's uh a a encouraging sign if you ever wanna resell it i guess
 	
 	
 		because i i'm always shocked at about you know what they've got have it appraised at i think oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		a lot of money i bet well that's great  well  yeah i guess that about does it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and it was nice talking to you okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		nice talking with you too bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	