
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 		um how's it been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> for you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weatherwise</ENAMEX> or otherwise weatherwise
 	
 	
 		weatherwise
 	
 	
 		damp
 		cold
 		warm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh no damp
 	
 	
 		we have we have gone through what might be called the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four seasons</TIMEX> uh in the last week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we have had highs of seventy two
 		lows in the twenties
 	
 	
 		my goodness well i don't even want to tell you what ours has been like then
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety six</NUMEX> yesterday
 	
 	
 		i heard about that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah we set a record <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and uh very very windy but then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the wind has dropped off and also the temperature so
 		very cool  uh i think right now it's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty nine</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and that's cool for
 		or if it it feels cool compared to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> but very pleasant no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last month</TIMEX> i don't think ground's very dry and
 		our yard work everything everything is in bloom so our yard work's pretty tough uh ground being dry but
 		i guess it also uh brings about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> we're having a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> down here right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		everything blooming and and the weather and uh think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have contracted uh spring fever
 		too so had a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out at work you know for fishing and and uh golf reasons and things like that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		the blue flu yeah
 		yeah the blue <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> or the white collar flu depending on where you work i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yes
 	
 	
 		oh we have had uh as i've said we've had variable weather uh
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		it has been
 		untypically wet for this time of year
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and also we have a lot of
 		green you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> has been growing and
 		if you look outside you
 		would like to go out and mow your lawn if you could go out and
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		buy a new spark plug or something along those lines but fortunately it <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rains</ENAMEX> and you uh
 		do not have to
 		go out and buy the spark plug no but we've had an unusually uh uh warm
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		spring and well i guess we're still in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we have had no snow
 		to speak of to speak of
 	
 	
 		no snow
 		hm
 	
 	
 		we usually average oh anywhere from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six to twelve inches</NUMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> and
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> as well as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> we have had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than four</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">inches</NUMEX> total accumulation
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so it's been inordinately warm uh here for uh for this time of year
 		so uh in that regard it's it's fine but uh
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i envy you you're at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety four</NUMEX> degrees i thought i heard <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> it was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nineties</ENAMEX> yesterday
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes yes it is down in uh more southern and and western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> and of course we're um <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about two hours</TIMEX> from the northern border straight south and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh very windy it's amazing to me because i've only lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> and i cannot believe that the wind blows all the time
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it does i i i very seldom if any i can't remember you know a day that i walked out and the wind wasn't blowing
 	
 	
 		um-hum well i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> at in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
 		in the flatlands and it was that way everyday
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		rarely a day went by when the wind was less than
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twenty miles an hour</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer and and winter</TIMEX> so
 		that uh we you you became accustomed to it i guess but uh otherwise
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we as i said we have had a uh relatively mild
 		winter for speaking for this area of the country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh really where did you go to school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Purdue i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> that lives in uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Southbend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		and i had to always well i've lived there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> myself i'd always said i was gonna go back to school and go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notre Dame</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i didn't uh
 	
 	
 		well you are not from that area originally i can tell
 	
 	
 		no originally i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> i was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> and we lived in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southbend</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighty eight years</TIMEX> and uh then moved to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee</ENAMEX> actually
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		well
 		um-hum well i thought i heard a little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> in  there
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		very much very much because i i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen years</TIMEX> there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh then moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years ago</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		gee you've moved almost moved around as much as i have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's uh uh uh uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh i see well i worked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> so i i moved uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		much more frequently than i had intended uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen years</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess the uh this this is my first conversation in this uh uh
 		series
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i had i received a call <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> because of the uh
 		i had not received my uh personal identification number
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i had to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Godfrey</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and ask him what it was because i i had to abort the call <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last evening</TIMEX> because i couldn't get on the line
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh is there any i'm not sure how long we're supposed to talk
 	
 	
 		it's um it's just as long as you want to i mean it's just a
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		as long as you want to and just you know a reasonable lengthy conversation now uh do you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		no i do not i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and i uh
 		of course was i was sent a uh
 		an application from uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> i've known <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> for sometime i'm in the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		speech processing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> and have been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> so i was very much interested
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in in being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> for this
 	
 	
 		oh actually i i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> and um
 		i'm in a i'm an environmental engineer
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		and uh  they just published this internally
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved so that that's really strange i i was wondering why we had somebody from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> though i was thinking God do we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		
 
 		i'm sure you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> somewhere in the area just nothing more than a business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> or government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> representative
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and um
 		but i have uh
 		i have been an a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> in other uh similar
 		type of activities uh and i know the reason why this is why the uh this is being
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		gathered and the program and so forth so i was interested in as i said i was interested in being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we haven't talked much about the weather i know that's what we're supposed to do
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh well
 		yeah yeah well really it uh
 		the the letter just says um
 		
 
 		let's see i can't i was looking at it i was trying to find out
 		speedy short cuts and all it says not necessary to measure your time just to go ahead and enjoy the conversation and and end it
 		when needed so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		in environmental engineering uh
 	
 	
 		okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that with regard to workplace engineering or just
 		you know environment the work place environment or
 	
 	
 		uh well it's actually um <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waste water</ENAMEX> taking taking care of uh i'm actually in the air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> and we monitor um
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		anything that comes out of a stack or out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> or
 		um
 		we do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> that um
 		their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> are in the work place and we take care of that but in within
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		our department we uh take care of everything <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waste water</ENAMEX> uh solid waste and recycling and and air
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i had my  the the call <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last evening</TIMEX> was supposed to be about uh concerning recycling in the community the call i received
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i had uh
 		i had thought a little bit about it um uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		beforehand
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so i
 		but that that's interesting i have a um uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who
 		is a planner
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		uh a city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planner</ENAMEX>
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his and he models uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city districts</ENAMEX> and so forth uh does computer modeling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the uh he has inputs or gets inputs from a an environmental engineer
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah we actually our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> is corporate wide and we take care of just the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area course we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> here but um we do air modeling also
 	
 	
 		to
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		and and yeah i take care of all the air modeling specifically for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area what we do we have a weather station
 		that we get all of this information you know temperature wind speed and wind direction and and uh we have a huge chemical data base
 	
 	
 		well that's interesting
 	
 	
 		and uh our our chemical data base  so that we know every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX> on site and and um it's concentration and and if if anything ever happened God forbid
 		you know a building explosion or something like we'd be able to track <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> from that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> with our weather station
 		
 		
 	