
 
     		
 	
 		all right
 		i play volleyball and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">softball</ENAMEX> and ceramics
 	
 	
 		ceramics sounds interesting uh i do computer programming kind of as a hobby on the side and i also like to uh do gardening and also like to workout
 	
 	
 		i didn't think of working out as a hobby
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		or playing with the computer i do both at home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well i i uh i work with computers at work and then i come home and do and i have uh a little lap top at home that i just like to play with
 	
 	
 		uh we've gotten a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atari</ENAMEX> computer uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> describes it as a a computer with training wheels
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well pottery sounds interesting have you made a lot of uh a lot of vases and things or
 	
 	
 		no i i do ceramics i i you know the pieces are made from a mold and i paint them
 	
 	
 		what kind of
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh you know you get them you clean them up you know get the uh mold line off
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know you scrape that off and uh make it as smooth as possible uh
 		then you uh put it in a kiln and fire it you know it's like a big ogen oven
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh when you pull it out it's called bisque uh it started it off with greenware
 		when you first start off and then it goes to bisque and that's when you can paint it
 	
 	
 		huh
 		do you have your own kiln or do you do you
 	
 	
 		no i've uh
 		you you can rent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s kiln they they uh you take your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or their ceramic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and uh pay them there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that charge <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> for fire all that i wanted
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh well that that doesn't sound like it's too expensive a hobby does uh does the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay</ENAMEX> and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">paints</ENAMEX> and things are they expensive
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">paints</ENAMEX> and stuff can get expensive the greenware it depends on what you buy
 		now i bought a a chess set for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and painted it for him and i'd say the greenware for you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty four</NUMEX> pieces i think is what they're no no
 		thirty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pieces is a was cost cost me <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about eight dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that doesn't sound very expensive to me
 	
 	
 		no i liked it i had fun with it but uh you know uh i'm a little shaky when it comes to detail work so i couldn't get the fine pieces so you know i had to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		get parts that had big spaces in them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> couldn't do the fine detailed fine detail on it
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		but uh you know i made my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> his uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Duck</ENAMEX> and you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> painted them for him in real bright colors
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh he enjoyed them till he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two</NUMEX> and then he uh had fun throwing them and broke them
 	
 	
 		hm
 		oh no
 		well
 	
 	
 		and that was during one of my softball games and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had him and he just kept giving them to him and letting him breaking them
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will tend to do that
 	
 	
 		yeah well i didn't get mad at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> i got mad at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> for giving them to him
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well i i i enjoy working out when i i get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from work just to just to have something to do that that i know isn't going to that's that's good for me something to do other than
 	
 	
 		i workout with that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		excuse me
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i workout with them or try to
 	
 	
 		occasionally i'll record <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the shows that's on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">in the morning</TIMEX> while i'm at work and i'll do them when i get home
 	
 	
 		yeah well i don't work
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah well i i really
 	
 	
 		so i do it in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i enjoy doing that
 	
 	
 		i haven't worked out in quite awhile i play volleyball i guess that's good enough workout
 	
 	
 		that is that can be a a workout uh big workout do you play volleyball a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah it's fun
 		at once a week uh sometimes sometimes we play <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two night</TIMEX> games a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> you know consist of uh fifteen point game and you play <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> games and you know the best uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that wins <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> games wins
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and uh few times we've had a tie breaker so i played <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> games
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then we'll get a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX> break or so and then i'll go and play another set with somebody else you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's fun
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah i i enjoy volleyball i'm just not very good at it and i end up just
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		killing my knees
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh i've torn mine up uh you know uh we play with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church team</ENAMEX> so we're not competitive we're just having fun
 	
 	
 		
 
 		huh
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh when i played softball it was with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church team</ENAMEX> it was just for fun although the church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> we made it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationals</ENAMEX> we were ranked fifteenth in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> so i you know i'm proud of that
 	
 	
 		wow
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but that was a for another you know i was in another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i'm not with the same softball team
 		but they're starting up soon so i'll be playing again
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i have several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that play softball they play softball in different church leagues
 	
 	
 		it's
 	
 	
 		around town
 	
 	
 		it's a good way to get out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and you don't have to uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh let's see what's the word
 		they have fun without doing
 		the drinking and all that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know you don't hear a lot of
 		angry words i'll you know be nice and uh you know it's going out to have fun
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because it you know it's a it's a hobby you do not want to be stressed out after playing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no kidding hobbies are supposed to be enjoyable they're not supposed to be difficult or or they're not supposed to make you less relaxed than when you began
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well uh get back to compooter computer programming of yours uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i've been uh trying to program some uh
 		disk or some uh what do you call them putting some programs into the on the disk
 		and uh i'll get to about fifteen sixteen lines and i'd mess up and it just says you have entered a error in line and i don't see how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do that that drives me batty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		well i i have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer Information Systems</ENAMEX> degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and i've been at it awhile so you know you just kind of learn the tricks of the trade and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and move on
 	
 	
 		the closest i come to uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		having a uh program work on me was the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atari</ENAMEX> toot toot
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and you know that was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just a couple</NUMEX> lines and you push a button and you hear a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> and then the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the the toot</TIMEX> toot
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like it though they think it's a hilarious
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well i need to run i enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		uh
 		all right thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		sure bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	