
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		so what do you think uh do you know any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yes i i used to work with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> when i worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett Packard</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and uh  he was a native and had gone to school there and got transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> where i was living
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and he had some interesting times getting used to it um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> the the language was a little bit different although he did speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah have you ever been there
 	
 	
 		it was just some of the  excuse me
 	
 	
 		have you ever been there
 	
 	
 		i've never been there my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> used to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DuPont</ENAMEX> and they built a chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> down there i almost moved there when i was in high school
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		no i've never been there either i've not known but just a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from there
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		one uh there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		in my flight in in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> basic training actually who was from there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> flew down there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX> he was down there about once a month <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> per month
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i wanted to move there it sounded like uh a neat place to live an island in the sun you know and uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it turned out my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that didn't want to go because she didn't play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> or tennis  and there wasn't really a job for her there
 	
 	
 		it always sounds more
 		oh its
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i think i think everything always sounds more glamorous than it really is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		every because i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and everybody goes oh you're so lucky and i'm like well yeah sort of you know it's but having lived there it's not it's not anything like you picture it
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		yeah
 		
  
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know it's not it's like i still have the fantasies about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> and all that stuff but
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> for a while and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kept saying the same thing to me oh it must have been great
 	
 	
 		
  
 		and your just like yeah well sort of right
 	
 	
 		i go oh it was just a place to live
 		yeah i was
 	
 	
 		but um  what do you think about about um their situation should they should they become a state
 	
 	
 		
  
 		i i think the status quo seems to be working i don't think um from talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that lived there that they don't seem um upset about it or anything and
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i think it would upset more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if they tried to change it
 	
 	
 		really i i think
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i'm not opposed to it but when its when the time is right it will probably just kind of happen you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't know fifty one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> on this flag wouldn't look too good
 	
 	
 		where are they going to put the other one
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah if they got another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> they could bring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in and fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> might be able to uh be arranged better i don't know
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
 
 		well where are we where are we going to get another state
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah i don't know cut <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		
  
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> no that's not a good idea
 	
 	
 		
  
 		but um i know a lot of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> kind of like it because they'll build <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> down there because they don't have to pay taxes on the stuff
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and they make i guess it's no income tax there or federal no federal income tax something like that
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
 
 		oh yeah because it's just a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> or is that what it's called a territory
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 		um yeah i think it's a territory
 	
 	
 		
  
 		okay
 	
 	
 		that makes sense
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i mean there's uh lots of tiny islands in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pacific</ENAMEX> that are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territories</ENAMEX> like that they could make <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> like Guam
 		
 
 		or uh
 	
 	
 		is that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U S</ENAMEX> territory though
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U S</ENAMEX> territory and it's just we own it or
 	
 	
 		
  
 		that would be kind of bizarre
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's kind of far
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> is pretty far too think about it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that's true but there is not a whole lot between here and there
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		where you you start dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guam</ENAMEX> it's like you know flying over all these other places to get there
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 		it's definitely a way out of the way where  where as
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
 
 		My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was stationed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guam</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> Two though
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		yeah where as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> is pretty close by
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		of course you could annex <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> but they wouldn't like that a bit
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		no i don't think they would
 	
 	
 		i don't think they'd go for that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		but actually i knew another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> that i went to school with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he was coming he came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to to go to school
 		and i think he was going to go back be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> out there
 	
 	
 		oh yeah do you think
 	
 	
 		he was really funny
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		both of the ones i met have been really funny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i don't know if that's uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
  
 	
 	
 		if that's true about all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Ricans</ENAMEX> or not
 		ones i met have been pretty pretty funny
 	
 	
 		no i have no idea but uh so you think that mostly they're they're pretty much satisfied with things the way they are
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't i didn't hear any major complaints about it um  i definitely think that we ought to let them decide and not say okay you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> now or you're your own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		but um let them decide
 	
 	
 		really that's why i said you know when it when when their time is right when they're ready for it you know that it will come about
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i think that makes the most sense
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick it</ENAMEX>'s been good talking to you
 	
 	
 		okay have we have we been on for a long enough time
 	
 	
 		
  
 		i think so i think its they want like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> or something don't they
 	
 	
 		
  
 		okay yeah this is this is actually the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i've i've had someone call me so
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		it went fine
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		all right well it was good talking to you Becky bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	