
 
     		
 	
 		okay um i don't know about you but where i am we have a like an extremely lax dress policy at work and it varies like everyday i mean from jeans <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> to business suits the next
 	
 	
 		were
 	
 	
 		it's pretty bad but it's true  you know they tend to try to be you know real lax and supposedly the policy is like you know
 		we you know we hire these wonderful creative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and we don't want to smush their creativity you know we want to go ahead and let them do what ever they want and you know you really will see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in in jeans <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and business suits the next
 	
 	
 		well i'm kind of that way too i work in the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and where we are now what we're doing is some very big lawsuits that happen to have a heck of a lot of boxes of documents
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i get to toting around boxes of documents several times a day it always seems like i'm doing that and i can't see getting dressed up and wearing heels and stuff when you have to carry
 		you know boxes of documents around so if i'm just gonna be there working in the litigation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and doing you know odds and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ends</ENAMEX> and stuff with the boxes of documents i dress down but if we're going to have a meeting
 		where we're having the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> come in or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from uh other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and stuff then i normally dress up yeah and i'll wear a dress and hose and stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you know we're kind of that way too i try to i'm the same way you are i kind of try to judge from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> to day i know you know where i am we work a lot with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> and we have a lot of government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> come in all the time and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know if i know that they're gonna be there you know you you i try to really watch it and like you say you know really dress up and if i know they're not
 		you know i i've been doing a lot of reorganization you know the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last couple of months</TIMEX> the same way you are you know and it's just so it's just impossible to crawl down on the floor and dig through boxes in a dress you know it is so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right that's right
 		a matter of fact i thought i had one funny story when um i was at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> or so we were sent out to our record retention <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> to look through
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX> boxes we had them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> and at that point it the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> was over across the road and it wasn't air conditioned
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and if we were there like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the summer</TIMEX> it's unair-conditioned it was dusty and dirty
 		um there was like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> at the very end of the row and that was it and so we didn't really know we weren't supposed to we thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> dress code was just dress appropriate to your job we wore shorts we didn't know that was a big no no
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> from another area came up to us and you know this area where record retention is there's only a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that work there and he should he knew who worked there he should have realized that we weren't regulars in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he came up to us and he just said who's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> well he called our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> and it went up all the way to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> complaining that we were wearing shorts
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		he didn't at least say to us did you know you're not supposed to do that that could have alleviated a big problem we ended up getting called out on it
 	
 	
 		oh how awful sounds like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mister Power Hungry</ENAMEX>  but you know just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> though i saw a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in the spin out here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewisville</ENAMEX> that had on a pair of shorts
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i don't care you can call them split skirts and you can call them culottes all you want
 		but these were shorts is all they were i mean i i don't care what else you call them you know if they're below the knee okay maybe you can call them split skirts if they're above the knee they turn into shorts you know and these weren't even really
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> ones i mean they had a problem out here with it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> wearing these shorts that were you know the real wide full ones you know and because these weren't even those these were like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pretty short black and they were very dressy they were black velvet shorts and she had on black hose and black heels and she looked very very nice
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		but you don't wear shorts to work you know i mean  as far as i'm concerned she was in violation and nobody says anything to them it's always been a big problem in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lewisville</ENAMEX> in the summertime you know if they just you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> doesn't ever seem to want to take an
 	
 	
 		um
 		hum
 	
 	
 		cut off you know that yeah no this is where we're going to draw the line this is shorts you know and and nobody will ever kind of take control and do that you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so it always gets annoying because the rest of us are going well God we have a pair of those at home too it sure would be cool and comfortable to wear you know but
 	
 	
 		well i've seen some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> try to just come in like over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> because they want to use the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TexTeller</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine</ENAMEX> and they have said no
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh yeah and then during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> you see these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the you know just because you put on a pair of hose with them doesn't make them not shorts anymore you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean i've never seen them do it without hose i mean they always have hose on but still it's they're shorts i don't care what you say they're shorts you know well i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s dress code is pretty lax considering everything anyway you know i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i know i didn't know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDS</ENAMEX> has a very strict dress code i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> oh
 	
 	
 		oh do they really
 	
 	
 		definitely i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who worked there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or so</TIMEX> and they spell it out
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> it's particular suits uh the pin stripe and the particular colors of shirts and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing wing</ENAMEX> tipped shoes oh it is definitely lined out
 	
 	
 		oh my God
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are not allowed to wear slacks she wears coordinated suits
 	
 	
 		i could i couldn't afford to work there
 	
 	
 		and a and a particular kind of shoe you know so high heel oh it is
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		spelled out when i was looking at her materials when she first started you know she had her benefits package and all that kind of stuff and it told about the dress code and it said
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		these are the color pastel shirts you may wear or white shirts with this kind of stripe in it for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and this kind of shoe and  hair just this way yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> says no shorts and no halters you know that's it
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDS</ENAMEX> is very particular about this hair cuts i mean it was like you can't have you know such and such facial hair no beards you know and just really detailed
 	
 	
 		wow
 		i don't know that that would be a good environment to work in i mean i
 		i see i i am more i don't know about anybody else and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> may say i'm nuts but i am more productive when i'm in pants
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i i am i work faster i get things done faster than when i'm in a dress and heels you know i it and it's weird but i it's i do i i can i can get so much more done if i'm dressed comfortable you know
 	
 	
 		well the uh the time we were there at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> we felt really bad because
 		we had uh another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> our outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> and she was told that we were gonna be in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> but she really didn't get the idea that we were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> part of the warehouse not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> but the warehouse
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and she came with skirts just like she'd be going into the office
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we'd try we'd try to say didn't you bring any pants or anything we're we're out here in the warehouse
 		you know you you got your skid of you know that wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pallet</ENAMEX> of boxes and you're gonna have to unload unload your skids look at the documents in the in the boxes and then repack your skid
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you can't do that in a skirt  poor thing
 	
 	
 		and she
 		and she was so she was so hot and miserable you know in the skirt she finally tried to go buy you know a pair of pants but you know i mean it was just completely miserable for her
 	
 	
 		oh yuck
 		yeah that's terrible that's terrible gosh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i don't know i just figure
 		you know yeah sometimes i worry about
 		you know if i go in in pants and i never i never ever ever go in in a pair of jeans you know but i'll go in in pants i mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i had on a pair of you know navy blue dress slacks and a and a like a peach colored top and you know not
 		cruddy but not a dress either and sometimes i wonder if stuff like that would will hold you back you know if you don't dress in you know your dress for success business suits everyday if
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know if upper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> doesn't notice that and remember that later on but you know i don't know if they do or not you know i see a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and they're in jeans so you know
 	
 	
 		some of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the legal department we have um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> to the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> and it's funny because there's one that always wears a suit a matter of fact he's never seen without his jacket to the suit on buttoned
 	
 	
 		really wow
 	
 	
 		and then there's another one who's who's a little younger and a little more yuppyish and he's always kind of like in the khaki pants and you know a shirt and sometimes he wears the jacket to it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and some of the patent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> have been real casual in their clothes and then other ones tend to always wear a suit with a very starched <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton</ENAMEX> shirt so that's just you
 	
 	
 		isn't that funny
 	
 	
 		you know with the you know the little suspenders or something on so we
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		we've kind of had a variety there but i think a lot of times it's it's mainly who they're going to meet with they're they're meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that they know is gonna be dressed that way then that's how they are if there just gonna be meeting with TIers
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like to talk about a patent kind of thing and the they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> that they're talking too they dress kind of like how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> are dressed and they're usually casual
 	
 	
 		that's the way to do it i mean that's the smart way to do it it really is because your making you know if when they're meeting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> who they know are going to be dressed down if they come in you know in a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six hundred dollar three</NUMEX> piece suit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's gonna make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they're meeting with feel very uncomfortable you know  or it would me you know
 	
 	
 		it's it's one of those slippery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> coming in here
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah look at this slick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i wonder what kind of money does he make uh-huh  i can see it now  well it was good to talk to you it was really enjoyable
 	
 	
 		yeah this is this is kind of a fun project i've done i've done some of the other speech programs but we've never got to talk to another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> it was always just talking to the computer so this is a little different
 	
 	
 		it really is
 		oh yuck yeah well it's kind of enjoyable i'm really looking forward to it  well thanks a lot bye-bye
 	
 	
 		yeah okay bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	