
 
     		
 	
 		all right do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 		no
 	
 	
 		i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and it is hard to find day care for them
 	
 	
 		what um what do you think needs to be the criteria set for those
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		what would you like to see in one
 	
 	
 		well i i've seen the bad side in most of them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i took my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to a day care <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time when he was just  you know just uh not even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months old</TIMEX> and uh you know it was a desperate thing
 		and uh when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> went to pick him up she he said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> had been crying the whole time he was asleep but you know how they cry in their sleep
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know this uh couldn't catch his breath even in his sleep and that turned me off of day cares
 	
 	
 		i bet
 	
 	
 		and then when i took uh
 		i've seen these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that uh
 		it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> volleyball they have a day care set up there for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> playing volleyball and uh one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> was real mean to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and that was you know he she'd just she had treated him like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> does you know and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it you know it uh i know most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> up there and the ones that keeps my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are real good uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> doesn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh when when we leave there he uh gives the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> a hug and tells her i'll miss you so you know
 	
 	
 		oh well that's good
 	
 	
 		so i know they treat him good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		is it
 		i don't know maybe would you think a
 		better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> ratio
 		do they have too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in most day cares for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they have
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah uh i don't know much about day cares itself you know uh you know this is more of just the nursery for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and under
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh there's only there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> taking care of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh where i'm where i'm taking my two
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and but uh in most places yeah they got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at best i guess
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		you know and maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and that's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah um we don't yeah we don't have any but we have you know plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> that that have them and
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure that there is a solution to that as far as uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> there you know everybody has in their mind the kind of day care that they want but
 		it seems you know that there's not really the perfect one out there
 	
 	
 		no there's not nobody can take care of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> better than you
 	
 	
 		right and that's not even possible anymore i don't think to be able to take care of your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> without you know with everybody working these days
 	
 	
 		well i had to quit my job because of uh my my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> you know uh day care wise or babysittingwise and stuff
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> was keeping them uh uh we just lucked out and she uh met a military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who lived down here and we came down here for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so i had her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> sitting but she was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> pregnant and it was getting too much for her so i just quit i'd rather quit and take care of my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> than let somebody else raise them
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah that seems probably the best way to do it
 	
 	
 		well you know they're getting raised right
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah um
 		i haven't really the only day cares that i have been familiar with are the ones that are local here with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> and they seem to
 		from my experience be the best at what they're doing just because of what they're based on
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah if um
 		i i know one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> that uh there was some problems with but that was just uh basically a personal problem between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that was taking in charge
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> uh day care that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh they don't go to a day care you know it's uh during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> and stuff uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there are really nice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah i think i think that's that's important
 	
 	
 		yeah well they
 		i think it's one of the important things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if uh because if they don't like it uh you can't get them that separation thing and i need that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i need to cut the strings on them they're not very old but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		how old are they
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four and two</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so you know they're they're good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know they do bad things but they're good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		but you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids kids</ENAMEX> do those
 	
 	
 		yeah uh but
 		i don't like the punishment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> care does you know i don't know exactly what they do but i don't want no one punishing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that's another problem with day care because you're not there so you don't what they're doing
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and if
 	
 	
 		yeah they're probably i would think needs to be i don't know if they have any type of uh formal or informal spontaneous or routine drop ins of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> checking up on like they do nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> you know they drop in to see if you're meeting all of the requirements by law and
 		and i think they need to do that with day cares and just see what's going on
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's that's something that should be brought up with these people
 	
 	
 		so but i'm not really sure
 	
 	
 		i don't know if they do it either to be truthful
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't either it's not until you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i guess you worry about those things
 	
 	
 		well uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		with me i just decided not to face it and you know in most in in so many words you know in one way or the other i just decided not to face that issue and i just keep them with me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well
 		i don't know what we've done to solve any of this  but i've enjoyed talking with you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah so have i oh
 	
 	
 		and welcome to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well thanks and i guess i we've we've been on long enough so you have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> all right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	