
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> hey how you doing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 		not bad not bad What's your name
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Fernando my name is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nick</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wait let me turn off my stereo here
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		because i've been like waiting like for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about ten minutes</TIMEX> to get connected to somebody yeah
 	
 	
 		really
 		man am i
 	
 	
 		right what time is it over there are you are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> or not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> i'm in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		are you
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 	
 	
 		because every time i got through i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well you're on the uh lets see
 	
 	
 		on the other coast
 	
 	
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty one</TIMEX>
 		yeah shoot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> it's what <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> almost
 	
 	
 		what yeah yeah it's uh i'm watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		yeah okay all right well i guess we're supposed to talk what about credit card
 	
 	
 		what wait what what did how how did you get to know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> thing
 	
 	
 		oh one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructors</ENAMEX> uh said that they were doing something like this and
 	
 	
 		what what are you working on
 	
 	
 		a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master's</ENAMEX> in uh information systems
 	
 	
 		really i'm doing my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master's</ENAMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer Science and Computer Engineering</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah where at
 	
 	
 		at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Carolina State University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hey how do you like it out there
 	
 	
 		uh i don't because uh
 		i come from a lot a bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> than this one and i i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh Durham</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that area and it's really small all all you have is like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> built around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel Hill</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah so it it's basically a bunch of small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> anyway kind of quaint little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> but they don't have a whole lot there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		where are you at
 	
 	
 		uh well i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monterey California</ENAMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		oh okay so so i mean it's like this this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> probably has like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred and fifty thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and that's about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two hundred</TIMEX> fifty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay it it's it's a lot bigger than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monterey</ENAMEX> is but we're just uh just south of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a couple of hours</TIMEX> away or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a hour</NUMEX> away to a you know to a large city
 	
 	
 		so so where do you go do you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no i go to the it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Postgraduate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> out here
 	
 	
 		oh okay because um i was looking at at the doctorate degree in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer Science center at Berkeley</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're asking like for a um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like three</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or something like that and like they're looking like for uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRE</ENAMEX> like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">percentile</ENAMEX> and this and that and it's like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well that's what they look for whether or not they get it it's hard to say
 	
 	
 		yeah i know that's why that's why i didn't apply i mean it was like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		for me it was like practically impossible to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between like ninety and ninety nine</NUMEX> percentile on the on the verbal part
 	
 	
 		yeah it's pretty tough it's pretty tough i mean uh let's face it you know and you know are you  did the you know as far as i found it a lot of times with regards to education you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> only takes you so far you know it's what you do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know so uh i don't lose any sleep sleep over stuff like that
 	
 	
 		so are are you going to go for your doctorate
 	
 	
 		probably not see i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> funds it i probably won't do it until i if i do do it it will be after i get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when do you get out
 	
 	
 		oh probably be another twelve years
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		oh you know i like what i'm doing right now
 	
 	
 		but uh but what if they pay for it
 		what if they pay for
 	
 	
 		excuse me
 		if they pay for a PhD
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		nah they won't pay for it they've i think they have maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> go get get their PhD
 	
 	
 		because i know i know a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here that work for um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah they <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> or uh military
 	
 	
 		i think i think they're military but i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is still in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um he uh he works over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so he's doing his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master's</ENAMEX> here they gave him like a scholarship like for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and he's doing it in like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and a summer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so he's getting that and uh they said like they got a lot of benefits and that that's why you want to join
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i mean you can earn a lot more money so you say i go why you still there if you can earn a lot more money once you've get your your you know Master's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they go well they got a lot of benefits that would go with it so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well a lot of times it's you know a lot of times it's not the money that keeps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that keeps people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they they like what they're doing they you know they feel good about what they're doing that type of thing it's more
 	
 	
 		but i mean i mean you the once you get your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s you can be earning between anywhere between like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven forty five thousand</NUMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		oh easily i'm sure
 	
 	
 		and that's not what they're paying
 	
 	
 		no well it depends on what rank you are of course
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i know
 	
 	
 		well i mean like i say if you're if you're you know if you're at an upper level in the rank category you know you're probably pulling down close to seventy grand a year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but that's uh
 	
 	
 		yeah those are few and far between though
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's like uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> you can get certain points
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh everyone's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> but nobody can get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more point to become you know like whatever you need to earn so much money
 	
 	
 		ye ah i imagine it's really competitive
 	
 	
 		you know it's like no i i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> is like there's a joke about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> which says you know it's like
 		uh all all the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> get into a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a boating</NUMEX> race right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> says well we have to we have to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> right
 		and then they come in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last</TIMEX> and they have this whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> you know analyze why they came in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last right</TIMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> asked for it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		saying he goes uh the problem was that there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saying row row row and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> rowing right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so he goes have you come up with a solution uh have you come up with a solution they go yeah change the rower  you know it's like everyone's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> but you know it's like only use like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> does the work so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> and not enough <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		yeah oh that can be that that can really slow you down
 	
 	
 		yeah that well that's the way it works i mean that's that's why they're having problems i mean everyone's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i didn't realize that
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean it's like it's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that actually do the work there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		are uh very few and then the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just plan it you know it's like it's like have you have have you ever seen the commercial like for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Express</ENAMEX> where the with uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tank</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah push paper around
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know like all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just standing sitting sitting sitting around just going you know like what shall we do has anybody thought of anything no And then this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Federal Express</ENAMEX> comes along they go what's that this track
 		which it's going around the world and they can tell you where your package is anywhere any time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so it's like the same thing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> you know so they have this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tank</ENAMEX> and they got to come up with ideas but see uh the the thing is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> is so stabilized that everybody will buy their stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah they've got a they've got basically a uh you know a lock on a lot of the market
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and a lot of times you figure you know with the support that they provide you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> generally go with that because they figure that the you you you probably won't get fired for getting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> material where's if you try something different
 	
 	
 		and it fails and you're dead
 	
 	
 		they'll they'll say yeah why didn't you buy why didn't you try something more mainline
 	
 	
 		yeah well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> doesn't fire anybody
 		because uh what they do is they they put you in a different job
 	
 	
 		no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which you you actually are like sitting around not doing anything so you quit
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i mean that's their policy they never fire anybody unless you're caught doing something illegally
 	
 	
 		illegal illegal or something like that yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah like if you're stealing something or doing anything like that
 		but they won't let you off what they'll do is like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		suppose you know like you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> so they'll put you into
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		keeping up the paper you know it's like how much paper is going in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then you say that's not my job so you quit
 	
 	
 		so in other words that's the way they force <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that's why they can say you know there's no layoff policy
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but it doesn't they don't really say that you know you're you're always going to have great career conditions
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah hey that's kind of sad
 	
 	
 		no but i mean it's like it's like
 		they they have like this different policy i don't know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> works for them but it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> like never in their commercials they never put down any other company you know it's like
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		they won't say
 	
 	
 		well they're the standard right now or as far as that goes you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think of computers they think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> a lot of times and the main
 	
 	
 		yeah because see what happens is they have a good backup policy and anybody can fix it
 		and so that's what you're gonna go for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well you know that's that's a that's a big thing
 	
 	
 		and and you know it's like for example like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leading Edge</ENAMEX> have you ever heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leading Edge</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah they are out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		leading edge don't they
 	
 	
 		they they made like uh small personal computers
 	
 	
 		yeah small PCs aren't they're out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		i don't know i i don't know but what they do is
 		what they did i don't know is buy all the parts that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> would throw away
 		and build an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> PC with all the parts that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> would throw away yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah because so is it like for example you test a chip
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it can't last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> but it can last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> says let's throw it away <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leading Edge</ENAMEX> will say we'll buy it from you
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and so that's i mean they're still around i think
 	
 	
 		yeah i've seen well i've seen them around anyway you know
 	
 	
 		so that's what that's what they do they buy all all the things that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> throws away and they  that's why they're so compatible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i mean and by the time you have computer for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> you're going to throw it away anyway
 	
 	
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do or they have to anyway
 	
 	
 		you know
 		well i mean there's like
 		when when you realize  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> got this computer and it was like voice synthesis and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he got that he said you know it's like um
 		i was testing it and it was wonderful and then when you tried to erase and correct you know all the errors in your voice it takes up all your memory
 		and i want more you know and it's like
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX> you know it's like why do you want more because it's like one second
 		of recording i mean you put into a Wave
 		and you want to correct the errors into Wave
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it takes so much i mean it's like of course it does i mean by the times it transforms into Wave by mark off model
 		and you put it in there and you want to correct those and then you know you're trying to make the the Wave smooth so you can approximately of course it's going to take a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		imagine imagine what it is for us to make mark off models you know it's like  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's amazing yeah
 		well when you get yeah when you get right down to it the uh the more they can do for you the more uh like i say the more the more memory they're gonna require
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah both both in terms in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">RAM</ENAMEX> as well as uh you know standard memory or disk memory disk base
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well like they say like nobody can get enough you know it's like
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		once you have something and it's like i was watching this program on TV <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in nineteen seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> came up with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> graphics right
 	
 	
 		well yeah you find out more
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they were showing this like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three</TIMEX> D graphics Three <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> graphics view of like
 	
 	
 		like those hologram deals
 	
 	
 		what no no no no this is like this is like video game stuff okay but the only thing was that it was just lines okay like if you
 	
 	
 		like a hologram with just graphics on a on a
 		okay
 		
 		
 	