
 
     		
 	
 		here goes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well  what do you think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan Ryan</ENAMEX> being the first <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> to earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX>
 		that's the only thing i found out tonight
 	
 	
 		oh you found that out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> i hadn't even heard that that's great i think he deserves every <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">penny</NUMEX> of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but there are some others out there that i don't believe deserve the money they're getting
 	
 	
 		well isn't it funny how <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s getting less than like <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> would
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		wonder because football
 	
 	
 		and they play a lot they play a lot longer season too
 	
 	
 		and a lot more games right
 	
 	
 		yep that's exactly right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i think let's see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that were there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> were
 		see somebody from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i don't even know who won the pennant last year
 	
 	
 		beats me i mean i know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> have won a lot of games through the years
 	
 	
 		yeah  not lately though
 	
 	
 		we have been talking about this i tried to call earlier
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we had made a list of all these uh baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> that they were from then i started cleaning and i don't know where i even put that paper i yeah i was just cleaning and throwing
 	
 	
 		threw it away  oh gosh let's see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that  i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX> were in it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oakland A's</ENAMEX> and i think it was
 		i don't think it was an all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> baseball
 	
 	
 		well have you ever played baseball
 	
 	
 		i play softball
 	
 	
 		well that's what i did when i was growing up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that was fun
 	
 	
 		yeah that's fun  that's a whole different sport
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		let's see but i think i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> need to go and i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pirates</ENAMEX> will go
 		and uh
 		let's see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> have got a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> i don't remember his name either
 	
 	
 		do you ever go see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		every once in a while i i like to go on the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> when there's not anybody out there not very many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there it's a lot more fun when you're not fighting a crowd
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it's fun i like just looking at the billboards
 	
 	
 		yeah but sometimes when i if you go out there during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> you just fry under the sun
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it's nice at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's when i've been
 	
 	
 		it is
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and and do you know anything about that new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> have you seen all those pictures that they're going to put out there
 	
 	
 		well
 		no
 	
 	
 		yeah that that huge it's suppose to be a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> and it's going to have little shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> in it and little like a lake or something running through it and uh they're going to try to make it a real <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community center</ENAMEX> out there
 	
 	
 		and you're going to be able to buy your what was no wait
 	
 	
 		of course
 	
 	
 		what was it about the liquor
 	
 	
 		that's that's in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> play
 	
 	
 		was that
 		
 
 		oh yeah see you just
 	
 	
 		and they're never going to let <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX> in there
 	
 	
 		well they're trying
 	
 	
 		i know but they try <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> they get thrown out
 		it's so stupid because they let you take it in there but they don't they don't allow you to sell it don't allow them to sell it there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh that new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX>'s going to be real nice and i heard that there's uh
 		that you can bid on that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> on the news i heard they said you could you could bid on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> to have it named after you
 	
 	
 		kind of right
 	
 	
 		it's going to it's going to go to the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well that's the way to do it
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah so that could be your you know fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> of fame
 	
 	
 		you hear that that's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> turning on their music let me see  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holly</ENAMEX> turn it down
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i think it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartman</ENAMEX> the Simpsons
 	
 	
 		oh God  i stay away from them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i wish i could
 	
 	
 		i bet you do
 	
 	
 		yeah well where are you
 	
 	
 		in Plano
 	
 	
 		okay i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you are
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> teaches in Plano
 	
 	
 		oh what's he teach
 	
 	
 		C V A E
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so what do you do
 	
 	
 		i teach but i teach for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you do
 	
 	
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> i'm trying to get out
 	
 	
 		is that a tough system to be in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		real hard
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i mean it's good because they they try new things you know but it's like
 	
 	
 		yeah i would think it
 	
 	
 		they'll try something and then they throw it out and get something else you know and you get tired of that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's typical bureaucracy though that's that's i think it's going to be any where you go it's just worse in the bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> than it is in the smaller ones i don't know sometimes the smaller ones are just as bad
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		well but they can't be though they don't have as much money
 	
 	
 		yeah but the politics the politics gets worse in the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> sometimes
 	
 	
 		most the time
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> you don't even know who's in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> there's so many of them
 	
 	
 		you don't even know who to payoff huh
 	
 	
 		i mean somebody walks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> and you don't know what they're there for you know when they're coming how long they're going to be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh how funny
 	
 	
 		you know it's just them there they are and they're writing the whole time
 	
 	
 		no communication whatsoever
 	
 	
 		no i had them walk out of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and not say their name anything and i finally got to where i go okay i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debbie Moore</ENAMEX> you know may i ask who you are and what you are in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> for
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know because you know you never know where they're going  what they'll report or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i know
 	
 	
 		and they'll tell you they've written something down and you
 	
 	
 		and you haven't you and you never see it
 	
 	
 		hope they're telling you
 		
 
 		no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		that's got to be frustrating
 	
 	
 		oh it is
 	
 	
 		how long have you taught taught <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> schools
 	
 	
 		uh this is my eleventh year
 	
 	
 		ooh that's about uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> too many
 	
 	
 		no actually it's now my job's
 		good much better than a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter</ENAMEX> One and all i do is teach reading <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it's just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at a time
 	
 	
 		well that's not bad
 	
 	
 		no it's good and you've got a lot of federal money too
 	
 	
 		but hasn't it changed a lot over the years
 	
 	
 		teaching  oh yes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		or working in the system
 	
 	
 		yes when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> started teaching i remember i went up to my job and i said okay i want to see a curriculum guide you know so i'll know what i'm suppose to teach and they go
 		we don't have one of we don't even know where one is
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh God
 	
 	
 		and  i go okay i mean you just you did what you  wanted to do
 	
 	
 		oh
 		how funny
 	
 	
 		and now they tell you what to teach and how long and
 		you know what day
 	
 	
 		yeah you don't know which is you don't know which is worse
 	
 	
 		what period
 		yeah no i know which is worse
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess so yeah being told what to do is worse
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so how long are we suppose to talk for
 	
 	
 		well you can talk for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> but you don't have to
 	
 	
 		oh you can
 	
 	
 		yeah and no if you talk to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> then they come over on and say oh you've extended your limit and please say good-bye within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next five seconds</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i haven't ever talked that long
 	
 	
 		well you know i hadn't either till last night i was talking to this retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland Ohio</ENAMEX> we started talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		oh how funny
 		he lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and everybody else that i've talked to has been right around here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but she was real interesting
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and then tonight this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> called have you taken any incoming calls
 	
 	
 		the yours is my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one
 	
 	
 		okay so hers was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one i got
 		gotten and uh
 		oh she was telling me all her problems
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and it went over <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		did she did she did you all not talk about the topic at all
 	
 	
 		well yeah we did but the topic was boring i thought what would you serve uh if you were having a dinner party
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh gosh
 		
 
 		what was i'm trying to remember oh the other the one i talked about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> was good it was
 		um about movies you know who what have you seen at the movies lately and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i could go on and on about that
 	
 	
 		me too because we go all the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i was talking to never goes he was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> it sounds like your really up on this and i said i see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>  so
 	
 	
 		ooh neat
 	
 	
 		that was real good to talk about that have you seen like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Silence Of The Lambs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		you've got to go see that
 	
 	
 		the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> i saw was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances Of The With The Wolves Of The Wolves</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah we talked about that one too and he he said he didn't think it should of gotten all those awards he thought it was too long but
 	
 	
 		oh i enjoyed it i mean it was just more for my money
 	
 	
 		i
 		i did too
 		yeah i didn't think it was too long at all
 		um he said after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about the first hour</TIMEX> he started looking at his watch
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		the other one you need to go see is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleeping With The Enemy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and how old are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		one is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and one is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		you probably don't want to take them to see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Silence Of The Lambs</ENAMEX>
 		it's it's not it's not too cool for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they usually pick their own
 	
 	
 		i bet they do
 	
 	
 		you know they've got it all figured out
 	
 	
 		yeah they want to see all the horror movies
 	
 	
 		well and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ninja Turtles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ninja Turtles</ENAMEX> got to have those
 	
 	
 		but most of the time really we watch them on the video
 		don't you just massive rental
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you bring that's well heck that's a lot cheaper then uh taking them out to the show
 	
 	
 		going to
 		i know
 	
 	
 		especially if you get them for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of nights</TIMEX> you don't have to watch them all at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night one time</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's what we do especially when it's bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weather man</ENAMEX> just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		plug it in
 	
 	
 		of course you have to get there early if you want to get anything
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		decent
 		well
 	
 	
 		it's good when you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Thumb</ENAMEX> though and they're cheap and nobody's got them yet unbelievable
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		that's true we saw um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Heroes Has Always</ENAMEX> Been <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> tonight
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was okay it was kind of slow and i felt like it kind of got chopped off at the end you know
 		it just it and i don't know it one of those movies it's not going to be around long it'll be a dollar movie in no time
 	
 	
 		do you read
 	
 	
 		not very much no
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		i don't have the patience to read
 	
 	
 		see i do that to make myself go to sleep at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah oh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> read all the time
 	
 	
 		you saw <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Field Of the Dreams</ENAMEX> right a long time ago
 	
 	
 		yeah sure did
 	
 	
 		so i was reading the book and it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shoeless Joe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		it was so wonderful and then i was um i decided well i like this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> so i got a uh book of his short stories and that's been real good
 	
 	
 		who's the who's the author
 	
 	
 		don't don't ask me  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ghost Of Shoeless Joe</ENAMEX> was the name of the book
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shoeless Joe</ENAMEX> was it like the movie
 	
 	
 		yes quite a quite a bit but you know in the movie the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was black
 	
 	
 		okay
 		right
 	
 	
 		he wasn't in the book
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> difference
 		there really wasn't a lot of difference
 	
 	
 		i didn't uh see i never even heard that there was a book tied in with that movie
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's interesting
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		that was a good movie too
 	
 	
 		well do you think we've covered baseball
 	
 	
 		i think so
 	
 	
 		okay well have a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 		
 		
 	