
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> did it click okay um well how do you feel about food and cooking
 	
 	
 		yes
 		oh i love food and i love to cook i really love to cook i'm not a really gourmet cook i'm just a normal everyday <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> what about you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well we're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vegetarians</ENAMEX> and we just became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vegetarians</ENAMEX> for i i just became a vegetarian over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past uh year</TIMEX> and a half
 		and it's a real challenge to find <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods proper foods</ENAMEX> to eat and
 		it's a real challenge not to become like what they call a junk food junkie where your menu is composed of
 		uh things that you want to eat that aren't vegetable you know that aren't don't contain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat products</ENAMEX> or don't contain animal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> but maybe aren't you know uh balanced meal so to speak
 		so but we we feel a lot better since we've become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vegetarians</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		don't you do you miss <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		i did at first but um not really no not i i can't imagine eating meat
 		um the reason i tranged uh changed to become a vegetarian was for ethical reasons so the idea of me eating meet would be like eating something you know i i think of it as something alive
 		you know so it i can't do it you know for for me it's it just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i do sometimes when i smell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> you know when i smell particularly uh say steak or something you know that i i do admit that i
 		you know still wish you know that i could have that flavor but but i know what it i know what it is so i you know i don't want it but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so when if you have if you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over would you fix all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> or you know when you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> do you fix just all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah you you'd be surprised the things i mean you could like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> we're having um nature <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">burgers</ENAMEX> which are like a grain burger
 		and you can it's really pretty good i i the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i serve it to like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> members
 		well my family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vegetarians</ENAMEX> now basically i mean they're not they're not when they go out to eat they sometimes eat other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meats</ENAMEX> and things but at home we eat vegetarian meals
 		and uh you can make you know make uh pasta <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> and
 		different things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are use to eating that wouldn't offend you know that they wouldn't be offended that there wasn't a meat there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know at the at the table or even pizzas you can make a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> that's not that doesn't have any animal product animal you know
 		you would have animal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> it would have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> but you know not meat
 	
 	
 		yes but that's
 		do you eat cheese do you eat like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> an
 	
 	
 		yeah we do eat i i had become for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three or four months</TIMEX> i was a vegan which is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that eats um no animal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheeses</ENAMEX> no eggs
 		and that's even more difficult it's really hard to find the products and it's hard that's even harder to keep yourself from eating
 		because it it adds so much to meals you know when you put <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> on something or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it really makes a difference
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs yeah eggs</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> just said <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> it's hard to find substitutes for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> when you're baking and cooking and things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so although you can i mean there's cookbooks and there's ways to do it it's a lot more expensive too i think you know the the the market is just not made for a vegan so but um
 	
 	
 		but it's becoming more that way i think it's probably easier now to find things
 	
 	
 		yeah it if well it really is because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> we were in the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and they had lentils and i
 		you know i wasn't really sure whether they would have lentils in the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> we've been living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> they had a um  a health food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> that really had a lot of good stuff
 		and where we're living now is a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that really doesn't you know just having that kind health food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> that caters to those kind of needs and you just have to hope that the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> will you know the bigger grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they actually had lentils which some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> don't have things like that you know which
 	
 	
 		i don't think i even know what a lentil is
 	
 	
 		yeah see that lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't and that's
 	
 	
 		i've heard i've heard of a lentil
 	
 	
 		yeah like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lentil soup</ENAMEX> or something <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't and that's such a good source of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> or like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soybeans</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think ugh they think it's something really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		horrible but there's a lot of things you can buy that have soybean <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> in them to begin with that you don't even know where in there so um
 		it's it's just a matter of learning you know
 	
 	
 		you had to learn i was going to say you have to learn a whole new way to cook
 	
 	
 		yeah so but it
 	
 	
 		oh no way
 		but i bet it's really i bet it is healthy because a couple of times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> i went without meat
 		um i had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pasta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> just because i just want you know oh no particular reason i just didn't feel like eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and uh i think even after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> i felt different
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well think of it as think of it like this takes a long time for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> to digest
 		and you know if you've got that sitting in your stomach i mean even when you sleep it's still sitting there digesting so you you kind of giving your stomach a chance to relax a bit and not have to work so hard to digest all that meat
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know because it takes longer than some products some other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> in your stomach to digest that meat
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		so when you prepare a meal like say on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> what do you
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you prepare a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> and there's lots of different casseroles and things so you just make you just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		everything but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no yeah you just you just well see at ours uh we're living with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> now so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know they they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX> you know they do they can't they you can't stop you know everyone's life but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think if in our own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> we didn't we would have things like a casserole things like that that centered more on
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> as far as
 		we might have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> special dish <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> special casserole that was our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> special thing like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX> you know with the main meal kind of thing
 		and and i suppose because it's for me ethical we'd just play up the fact that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thanksgiving</ENAMEX>'s you know is a time for everyone to give thanks even turkey you know yeah
 	
 	
 		even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey yeah</ENAMEX> that's true
 	
 	
 		so
 		um
 		but it it's interesting finding different recipes although my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is the one that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cooks</ENAMEX> um
 		which
 	
 	
 		well do they have special cookbooks out for for just vegetarian <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal meals</ENAMEX> you know special books that you
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah lots of them lots of them and uh i have this one in front of me right now as a matter of fact it's called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moosewood Restaurant</ENAMEX> and
 		uh it's out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> it's a pretty famous restaurant out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and almost every single recipe in there is um vegetarian there are some fish recipes i think in it but a few of those but not anything
 	
 	
 		but you don't eat fish either do you
 	
 	
 		no we don't eat fish either but it the majority of the book is um vegetarian with no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meats</ENAMEX> so or you know of any any kind of animal
 		so there's quite a few out there
 	
 	
 		i have a
 		i have a hard time with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> i don't i when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> i didn't like them very much and i never really learned how to cook them
 		right i guess i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i'll eat a little bit of broccoli and i'll steam it and i like carrots just certain things you know but uh i'm not really good with them and i'll go sometimes and not even fix them i mean i'll have everything else and no vegetable that's strange isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah it's strange because well it it's not strange because i use to be the same way and i'm even to this day  you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> really turn me off but when you read so much information that says
 		this is a healthier way to go you know and this is what your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> wants this is what your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> really needs and when you think about what is what's the real reason your eating i know i know it's for taste because i'm boy am i a taste <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but really the main reason is for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> you know and and when you read so much information that tells you that meats
 		and different animal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> you know are causing uh can cause uh different kinds of diseases
 		you know  like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart heart diseases</ENAMEX> and different <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> and things like that different kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> it's like uh is it really worth it
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i i really think in general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> just don't eat enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> you know because
 		you can talk grain all you want as far as you know cleaning your system out so to speak but you can't beat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> to give you all the nutrients and vitamins and and the the the kind that you can't get from a little pill
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> doesn't doesn't synthesis synthesis in the same way that it does when it gets it in raw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		but now if you cook them wrong you can loose the vitamins to
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true that's true so you it's it's all important you know it's an all important thing that you
 	
 	
 		and i'm terribly overweight i'm obese probably is the word i've never used that word on myself before but i am very large and probably if i could give up the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat products</ENAMEX> and just get on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> i would probably look a lot better
 	
 	
 		i think you'd feel probably a lot healthier um  my almost almost everyone in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is is obese
 		yeah i i would say you know the almost everyone and uh except except me except myself and you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> but um
 		and uh yeah i i
 		i don't know that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> have seen any improvements since we've been here as far as them switching to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>  but do you think you fill healthier mom
 		she my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> says she feels healthier
 		
 		
 	