
 
     		
 	
 		well i haven't uh i've been working in my own home for just um
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the last three years</TIMEX> but so i can just wear whatever i want around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> but before then i taught taught at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Houston</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		oh now that's nice yeah
 	
 	
 		so i tried to wear things that were
 		comfortable but still tried to look you know
 	
 	
 		somewhat business attire yeah
 	
 	
 		yes but it wasn't quite business but to give the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> um an made you feel like you were the authority i felt like if i came in just in jeans or tattered clothes that i didn't have as good control over the class
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		and if i tried to wear things that were a little bit more businesslike
 	
 	
 		exactly well i i work uh i'm a financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> and uh uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> uh nearly everyone wears a a sports coat and tie uh but that does change in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> uh they they get a little more lenient and we can wear like uh an open collar or uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a lot of times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> i'll try to uh like on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> i'll try to take off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> and maybe go play some golf
 	
 	
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		so uh i'll try to wear a short sleeve shirt and uh um and that that's okay that's appropriate
 	
 	
 		well do you um
 		meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and so you have to dress a certain way for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		not really it's uh it's just uh in our small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> we uh we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX> and uh we support a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> and uh the senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> is uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is big on business attire and so um um he sort of funnels that down to uh
 		to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that work in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> so um i i i enjoy it i think it uh it makes a nice environment and uh i don't know gives it a little more business type uh atmosphere
 	
 	
 		well i uh i have noticed with my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for example that they will depending on what they're wearing it it makes a big difference on how they act and so that could be the same can be said for the business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		right
 		see i think that's exactly right you know if if you're uh if you're dressed in a uh a suit and uh
 		to me it make it helps me feel uh sort of like you were saying a lot more confident in myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh if i do have to approach the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> i feel i just have that little little extra confidence in myself being dressed that way
 	
 	
 		well and i noticed in my uh teaching experience that since a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were my own <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age or older</TIMEX> even um
 		that because i taught <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as a second language so i didn't have your average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman student</ENAMEX> and um so i
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		i had to do something to just elevate myself a little bit off their level i mean you want to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> but you don't quite want to be their equal
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and so for me to dress in uh in businesslike um clothes my you know i i preferred slacks because we had to walk park pretty far away from
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> and down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> it'd be so hot yeah
 	
 	
 		yes and you wouldn't want to have to walk uh you know in high heels it's hard to walk a long way and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> is pretty large
 	
 	
 		right
 		i see
 	
 	
 		so i preferred slacks and um you know
 		kind of dressy shirts and things but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so that i would look a little bit different and i would come in and i would have just the appearance of a little bit more authority than they did and that helped with their discipline and
 	
 	
 		right
 		i see
 	
 	
 		didn't make me have um to much trouble and
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think clothing you know it it just uh
 		it it does like you were saying the the way you dress makes you feel different ways um if you like when you go out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> uh you may just want to have a casual <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> or something so you you sort of dress down but if you're going to a uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a social type <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> then you dress up and that i think it just has a a change on your attitude
 	
 	
 		well and i i noticed since we moved down here to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but uh i'm not and that you don't have to have uh such a wide variety of seasonal clothes that you do up north where you have to
 	
 	
 		i see
 		i'm i'm sure that's true yeah
 	
 	
 		totally different wardrobe with different fabrics you know heavier wools and
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah see the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter season</TIMEX>'s just not that long to to invest a whole lot of money in in uh
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		in the the heavier heavier materials
 	
 	
 		no and you don't um you know if you usually can wear pretty close to the same types of things just with a jacket or sweater
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		or something rather than having the whole entire different wardrobe with
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly
 	
 	
 		different shoes you know we always had like um
 		higher
 		higher shoes higher tops on them rather than just um the lower
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skimmers skimmers</ENAMEX> i think they call them that you would wear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		and see i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> clothing um uh is a lot more varied than than than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s clothing
 		because uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> or at least in my situation you can uh i can wear the same slacks and uh sports coats nearly <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">nearly</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> round
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh ladies you know uh uh i don't know if that's marketing or what but they they definitely have a uh i think a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a winter</TIMEX> type wardrobe and then a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> and then a summer
 	
 	
 		that's really true a lot of it is um
 		the color certain colors seem to be more acceptable
 	
 	
 		true
 	
 	
 		you know if you wear um pastels it's needs to be warm weather
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and otherwise you have to wear darker colors in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> for some reason and
 		i guess part of that is um
 		just the physics of it that in what isn't it dark colors attract the sun and light colors repel repel them so
 	
 	
 		right
 		exactly
 		plus the social attitude you know if if you walk into a place and and uh i know in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> gives everyone a hard all the ladies a hard time if they wear white shoes i think it's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is it after uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX> or something i don't know and and uh so you know the the social attitude has a little bit to do with uh i think the way we dress
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's true there's some rule that's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between Labor Day</TIMEX> uh no is it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Day</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not for sure it's that one in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> is when you need to quit
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right and the one that's like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> you can only wear and and supposedly we don't have an opportunity my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i we don't go to a lot of like where you have to wear
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		a white dinner jacket or something and so you can only wear a white dinner jacket between those two
 	
 	
 		i see right
 		exactly exactly
 	
 	
 		holidays too that's pretty funny it's funny that we have as a society
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		go to so much trouble when we have so many other things we could be spending our time thinking about
 	
 	
 		exactly a lot more uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th at</ENAMEX>'s right a lot more helpful ideas that we could be uh spending time and effort on rather than our appearance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 		i noticed uh when we moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> that um the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> here <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Collin Creek Mall</ENAMEX> i don't know where you are but um
 	
 	
 		right
 		i live here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		oh you do that there there is a pretty um
 		i wouldn't say snobbish  but it it's kind of borders on that that if i depending on what i'm wearing i get better service at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> i felt since
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really
 		huh
 	
 	
 		uh where you know from where i've lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> that you have to in order to get
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the attention you might need help
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you need to be you can't just come in off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> is what i'm trying to say
 	
 	
 		exactly and i think that's you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX> type attitude
 	
 	
 		oh is it
 	
 	
 		and uh because i noticed that uh like even going to church uh seems like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really dress up a lot more uh here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX> going to church
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i don't know that's that's uh because i i went to school with at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Tech</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> was a a lot more casual uh rather than uh you know here it's like going to a fashion show almost
 	
 	
 		yes i think i think your right i've noticed that too it's just it's very different but i've
 		i think um it's kind of sad when you have to
 		go in and make dress up to go somewhere i mean just to the shop
 	
 	
 		right to try to keep up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> almost yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah and you have to be sure that your everything coordinates and everything everything is um freshly pressed and everything
 	
 	
 		right
 		you can't just wear your sweats and an old T-shirt and
 	
 	
 		no
 		you can't just drop in well i appreciate um the conversation we've had about clothing i know i've it's interesting to hear a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s point of view it's usually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he's got a pretty good deal i go out and buy all his clothes  and they magically
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well now that is that is so uh well that is great i appreciate the call
 	
 	
 		well thank you and you have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		you too bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	