
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		wonderful touch tone telephone there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh what kind of books do you enjoy reading
 	
 	
 		uh having have uh i have a wide variety of of hobbies therefore my my reading pleasures are quite wide um
 		i get a charge out of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> highway uh which uh is very colorful and uh not being a native of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh but being here <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> have a tendency to uh find out the uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		about the different areas of of the kind of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> by reading it
 	
 	
 		right i've read that one too i  only had a subscription once but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> always gave me hers and i i really enjoyed you know all the little
 		things that you find out about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's it's uh absolutely it's great the way that it's broken out and you can uh set up little trips and day trips and things it's pretty pretty neat
 		um oh i like photography um  magazines i don't take a subscription or anything like that um
 		things oh
 		being an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> i do read a lot of a lot of uh building <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and and and plant engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and read up on different ways to do things and energy management type of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh kind of strange because i it's not unusual to uh see um an engineering manual or something laying around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and then i'll sit up and read just to refresh uh you know to keep active on it but uh  how about yourself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well um i have an interest in art so i frequently purchase and read um books mainly on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> color because that's my big interest at the moment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		and um
 		oh i guess i like a variety of things um lots of fiction uh type
 		books
 		um right now i'm occasionally reading  on a book about uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mardi Gras</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> and it's history that's fairly interesting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i bet that would be rather interesting uh
 		that's uh self-improvement that's that's always well that's that's kind of a hobby but it is self-improvement uh from the standpoint of probably relaxing um
 	
 	
 		yeah i i don't know that i read anything strictly labeled self-improvement how about you
 	
 	
 		um
 		well i hate to yes i do
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		we um we have these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> we attend uh management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> then and they give you books and and the last book uh matter of fact i read was
 		At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America's Service</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Albridge</ENAMEX> it talks about um who the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> is and being customer oriented uh which falls in line with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> culture here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um one of it's great slogans is if you're not serving the customer you better be serving someone who is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh so that's all in self improvement to stay focused on who the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> is and as you probably well know all of us are our own customer your my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> i'm your customer sort of thing um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now</TIMEX> and then i'm loaned the tape i can stick in the in the car cassette on the way home to make the drive more enjoyable talking about uh
 		better outlooks on things and the philosophy of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Haggerty</ENAMEX> and these kind of uh mind stimulating philosophy type
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		actually which all you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">betters</ENAMEX> yourself
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well i guess maybe i am into some things occasionally that i don't think of in terms of self-improvement
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean they are but i don't label it as such
 	
 	
 		like what for example
 	
 	
 		well i don't know um
 		i uh have attended some seminars that had some tapes that went with them but uh i guess not so much books although they sometimes have manuals and things but um they would
 		be things on like how to be successful and sort of talking to yourself you know getting getting your yourself in gear to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh sort of pull yourself up by your boot straps and do what you really wanna do  convincing you that you need to get on with it
 	
 	
 		sure
 		sure how about items like um The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">One Minute Manager</ENAMEX> which used to be a big okay so those are self improvements um
 	
 	
 		yes
 		sure
 	
 	
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> uh suddenly bought all of us a book called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Every Supervisor Should Know</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		by a main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Doctor Bittel B I T T E L</ENAMEX> and it's a very <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">layman</ENAMEX>'s uh uh approach towards managing different types of people
 		and the very last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> and i haven't figured out why that one was last is how to manage engineers
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so it's it's very it's interesting here again it's it's casual reading and it's not eaten up with a lot of uh technical stuff and it's really uh excellent fast reading and uh
 		but as you say it's it's sometimes it's difficult to to know if it's you know i think if somebody wants to say okay read these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> books because these are self-improvements i would probably be turned off to them
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		he casually just walked into it and uh put down a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> book and uh picked up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them it might be a little more interesting
 	
 	
 		i don't know i i'm not sure i could take too much of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> that's a little little little heavy for me
 	
 	
 		yeah they're uh quite uh they're hard to set down because it's so interesting and course they're always a little spookier than the movies but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's always they're always challenging to get through one of them i have a hard time finishing books
 	
 	
 		well i guess i also have been reading uh a lot of things on uh quality improvement and that type of thing because that's what i'm involved in a lot at work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		in quality especially nowadays uh that's almost everything that comes across the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the the the airways</TIMEX> of the
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you could almost label everything quality in some sense or other but i think sometimes the word is a little over used but
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly right
 		yeah we we have i think we we name drop it a little too much and and don't fully understand what what what it is we're saying i think it's it's focusing in on the issue and walking your talk and and all that kind of rolls in together there but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's kind of part of it
 	
 	
 		okay well any other comments
 	
 	
 		uh not that i can think of um i think i'm under my quota a little bit i need it if i if i make a phone call or two
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well we just started right
 	
 	
 		ah this is true i've enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		well you too and uh
 	
 	
 		have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">good-bye</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> bye-bye
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">good-bye</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	