
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay i guess we're on
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		Central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> have you ever lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i wasn't in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> but uh talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> i kind of i consider <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> to include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> and i did live in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sao Paulo Brazil</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you do you think that that we should have given up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Panama Canal</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh realistically realistically i
 		yes i don't see the the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Panama Canal</ENAMEX> that hasn't had a whole lot of usefulness to us recently since it's not not really big enough to uh accommodate the
 		the shipping that it once did and uh maybe it would be better that we let the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Panamanians</ENAMEX> run it however i think we're certainly justified in uh our actions dealing with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noriega</ENAMEX> in this
 	
 	
 		well there are those that that that think that that that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Panama Canal</ENAMEX> has some considerable strategic
 		importance particularly for the military interestingly enough my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was who was in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> Two
 		and as uh as a civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> they they they offered him a commission as a captain
 		if he would uh go in and and uh help with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">defenses</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Panama Canal</ENAMEX> he had worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Fruit Company</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there and they uh they in fact they had this was in uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late twenties</TIMEX> and they in fact used some of the equipment that had been left over
 		and uh he turned them down it it's interesting that that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't realize how small the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canal</ENAMEX> is have you ever been there
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		it's it's really i i haven't been there i've been to been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salvador</ENAMEX> and
 		and uh in fact we went back to visit some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> that we went in fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> i guess
 		and interestingly enough the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canal</ENAMEX> is quite small and and realistically could be sabotaged quite
 		quite easily the thing i find interesting though is that uh is the whole colonial approach and and and do we do we support the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sandinistas</ENAMEX> or
 		or do we support uh
 		you know when they thought uh they thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX> if you gave them a free election they would vote for the
 		will you uh did did you ever studied the the political makeup there in in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i have a a little bit i can't say that i'm i i would be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on the on the region but uh certainly uh i
 		it it gets it gets there you you've got this this toss up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between</NUMEX> or not not so much a toss up but a a dilemma when when you want a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to have it's it's um
 		own uh dominion or its free rein over its its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and then on the other hand uh the uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in power that under what seem what seems to be popular support uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sandinistas</ENAMEX> had to a given extent popular support um starts
 		making overtures to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and and into what we consider our sphere of influence and now we're we're in this dilemma over
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh United States</ENAMEX> is believes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democracy</ENAMEX> and and self-determination where and but that on the other hand we believe in self-preservation and
 		uh agree with the or not so much agree with but are terribly concerned about the influence <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> influence in in what's considered to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' fear of the world which is not only
 		you we used to see spheres but now we're in a situation where the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is looks like we're it now
 	
 	
 		well the interesting part about it is that if realistically it was economic i don't know if you read any of the history on where the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Panama Canal</ENAMEX> but there was an option to build it across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and there were uh there's a big there's a big lake
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um from a technical standpoint it wouldn't have been a lot more difficult to have built it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX> but the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the United States uh</ENAMEX> had some and i've forgotten what the political influence was
 		but there were economic ties then the issue of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> of if if it's in the economic interest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 		uh do we go in and and prevail and and uh in other words do we make the world a safer democracy but if there's no economic benefit
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i think particularly if you're if you're looking at the at the at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasant</ENAMEX> uh whether he's in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> regardless of where he is
 		is his life  is his life better off under Communism or or uh or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> government you look at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salvador</ENAMEX> where the
 	
 	
 		well he doesn't care as long as he's feeding his uh his family
 	
 	
 		yeah and and the question is is does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> make a difference if they'll mostly leave him alone
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i think that's the difficulty they that that we have that uh it it it reality doesn't make uh
 		doesn't make a difference if he has no income and apparently even some of our alleged uh
 		Central <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> that uh are are that are mostly democratic have done some pretty terrible things so it's uh
 	
 	
 		yeah oh you can look in
 		if you pretty if you look at the region and and on to their detriment they came from uh this
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> control in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spaniards</ENAMEX> have a horrible history of corrupt uh government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greedy uh rulers</ENAMEX> who
 		uh have been uh
 		i don't know manipulating manipulating their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> for their own their own good i mean if you go back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> and then the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the conquistadors</TIMEX> coming in and and the whole the incredibly horrible things they did to the
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> i mean they make uh they make the things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Custer</ENAMEX> did look like uh like trivial and uh you get
 	
 	
 		it it's it is interesting that that you know we we look at the exploitation and and and then we accuse some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of exploiting and and and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
 		have uh have a pretty good reputation of exploiting you know we basically the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Panama Canal</ENAMEX> we went in and and took it
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely and now we set up
 	
 	
 		and uh we stole it fair and square i think is uh
 	
 	
 		and i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX> didn't have the reputation speak softly and carry a big stick for uh for nothing and uh
 	
 	
 		well what's going to be interesting is to see what the economic impact of of uh of the the region uh you know at the moment it
 		the tremendous drug traffic through there but uh the idea of of uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		what's the what's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s role there and it it uh
 		with with other things going on it it it seems to have lessened but you've still got uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> that exception exerts some influence
 	
 	
 		i've the only the only thing i see about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> though is uh after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX> dies i don't think there'll be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> power anymore i i can't see Communism in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> carrying on past him
 	
 	
 		well when you take a a situation where i think in particular in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salvador</ENAMEX>
 		where there is a significant under under class
 		excuse me
 		and that uh having a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a lot of difficulty
 		uh surviving
 		uh the question is would they
 		you know would they be better off under communism
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i wouldn't don't know that i would advocate communism but uh the question is can a can you can a can a democracy uh afford the
 		it's like the street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are starting to show up all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> is that that's essentially an underclass and when you get enough of them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh you know Communism would feed them all
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i don't know if maybe Communism's the right the right word for it but what we would there'd have to be some kind of there there may be a point at which at at which you've uh
 		you might want to consider some kind of socialistic uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> or socialistic setup to to deal with the problem and then be able to gradually transform back to a Democracy
 	
 	
 		well that
 		yeah if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> got some incentive if he's got uh you know if if he if he can raise enough uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX>
 		to uh where he's got something to protect other you know whether he can export or at least uh set up trade and all then democracy of a considerable interest to him
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocoa</ENAMEX> leaves sell real low right now
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		it seems yeah
 	
 	
 		as as well as some other various things that are growing in tropical environments
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 		absolutely i don't it's gonna be hard to um we've that's you that's you that's that's where you're absolutely right as we've got to do something in that region to encourage
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or to make to make him growing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX> profitable again i mean
 	
 	
 		yes but the but the question is you know if somebod y offered you you know a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> a day to to grow something in your backyard would you do it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		well not that we could be bought but uh
 	
 	
 		i got to watch what i say here i never know when the DIA maybe uh listening on my phone  right
 	
 	
 		well of course all everything we're saying is being recorded and
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah uh it's tempting it's got to be it's got be horribly tempting for those for those
 	
 	
 		of course of course
 	
 	
 		because yeah yeah yeah you it's not just it's not just a matter of uh of having an
 	
 	
 		particularly if you're hungry
 	
 	
 		extra <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or having a better car this is a matter for them of
 		of feeding themselves their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and and you there's a certain degree of honor in being able to feed your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and there's dishonor in not being able to do it and
 	
 	
 		uh starve to death is not a not a whole lot of fun either and that uh and and and
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		you know when somebody comes in and offers i think that's one of the real problems particularly when
 		when the uh religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> has been accused of a lot of things in reality i think what they were doing is basically going in and trying to feed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and help them protect themselves not not that they
 		i'm i'm not sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> is is is particularly particularly political but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know if somebody's hungry
 		
 		
 	