
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		Arch how are you doing tonight
 	
 	
 		good and yourself
 	
 	
 		oh that yeah fine kind of tired
 	
 	
 		yeah me too
 	
 	
 		where am i calling
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 	
 	
 		where are you
 	
 	
 		i'm in Lewisville
 	
 	
 		Lewisville okay i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> um have you read anything about how they propose to uh come up with the taxes to increase the funding for schools
 	
 	
 		little bit
 	
 	
 		what do you think about it equalization of funding
 	
 	
 		that's a hard issue to decide uh on the one hand you don't want to have to take away but on the other hand you don't want uh the poorer school districts to go under either and uh here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lewisville</ENAMEX> they had a thing on the ballot that they wanted to
 		uh rollback the taxes on everybody's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and everybody would save
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or whatever but it would cut back <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">twenty million dollars</NUMEX> in to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and i happened to know a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> here in the school district and she was really against it because that would just take away all all their money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and as far as i'm concerned you know hey twenty bucks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> is not too much to me and they could raise a few more dollars and get better uh things for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that's what we need because we got
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is known for it's poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and that's too bad because we got little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and we're uh not too pleased about that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but we're not funding them like other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> either though you know it we're not funding our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> like other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> either
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		that's right but just because we've got a lot of money doesn't mean that's gonna solve the problem
 	
 	
 		yeah i know that's that's only part of the problem
 	
 	
 		i mean i think there's a lot of waste in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> i feel that yes i feel i definitely feel that way all this money that's being paid for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think we're gonna see
 		are you
 		okay
 		i think were gonna see a day come
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		hum-um i can
 	
 	
 		i think i think we're gonna see a day when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> uh grade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are gonna be charging tuition just like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> are uh and it'll only be to those who are having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> going to school that's probably the most fair way but
 		you know uh that way old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't have to have have money going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> because they don't have little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> going to schools
 		but uh i wouldn't be surprised if that happens within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX> uh that sort of thing happening and uh we'll see what happens
 	
 	
 		well they're already talking about freedom of choice you know for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that's an idea
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes
 		um
 		i don't know that i think has
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pluses</ENAMEX> and minuses because uh those that
 		are economically disadvantaged won't have the ability to make a choice the choice will be thrust upon them and so where's the freedom of choice no freedom of choice in that case and that's
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		but like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>  you can choose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that you're going to  can you tell this is past bedtime  um
 		like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> they get to choose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that they're gonna go to but they got to have the transportation to them if it's out of their district you know out of their area i mean
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so and i like that because you can find out the good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in your area
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i think the only way they're gonna really get to the problem and solve it is to have equal funding for every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in the state whether you it's in a poor tax district or a high tax district and uh
 		that's the only way that i can see it's gonna be resolved is there are gonna be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the rich district that are gonna fight that and and it's gonna be a real bad mess because there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on every side of the problem
 	
 	
 		so just distribute it equally and not raise taxes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and they should give every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent raise  that  that's the problem is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> don't get enough money and anybody who could be a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> doesn't want to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> usually because they don't pay enough
 		i mean when i was in college i did a lot of teaching uh for my degree and uh i got a lot of good out of that and i liked teaching but i really couldn't go into teaching because it was not economically feasible for me to do so
 	
 	
 		yeah what do you do
 	
 	
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematician</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh so you picked a good field then you picked a good field
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 		oh i don't know there are better fields to pick
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah but that's not a bad one
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		yeah where i you know kind of stuff i do i i use my education quite a bit but where i was before i wasn't using it hardly at all
 		so it all depends i mean it depends on where you wind up i guess but i really enjoyed teaching it you know i but wouldn't mind getting back into it someday but who knows what'll happen in the future
 		the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are being laid off right and left it's all a matter of uh what happens next
 		but uh back back to the taxes though i mean uh it's a difficult issue no one wants their taxes raised but on the other hand you got to do something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what do you think about a state income tax
 	
 	
 		i can see that there might be a reason for one but i would hate to do that because uh that would be very difficult for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> financially to to afford a state income tax
 		and
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have it i know and i've lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that have had it but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> uh way financing is now if we had a state income tax i'd uh have a very hard time financing my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> again you know paying off my mortgage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each month</TIMEX> that's so that's a problem
 		um
 		which just matter of we'll see what happens i'd rather have that i guess than have a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state state</ENAMEX> lottery because when you bring
 	
 	
 		but didn't they pass that thing that we were gonna have a lottery or not
 	
 	
 		no it didn't
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		which means there's a higher probability of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> having a state income tax even though good old tax and spend Annie my favorite
 		uh decided that uh during the campaign she said we weren't gonna have a state income tax and now she's gonna renege on that which i expected her to do anyway uh we'll see what happens i don't know
 		at any rate uh
 	
 	
 		so what about your income tax
 		think they're hitting you too hard
 	
 	
 		actually no um
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		i'm surprised that my uh my income taxes are as low as they are we just finished our income taxes and we're getting a nice little refund back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> which is which is nicer than having to pay out
 		uh which is a matter of uh
 		um i'm surprised it's
 		well considering the national budget i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> wanted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four trillion dollars</NUMEX>
 		for the national budget and for a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> like what i got that comes out to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over twenty two</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> that we it it's our share to pay in but i'm not paying that much income tax
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you're gonna think well wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">now</TIMEX>  where's the other eighteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> or whatever coming in where how how is that coming from me i guess it comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and whatnot but
 		it's interesting i don't know i can't imagine i guess that's why we're going in debt so deeply
 		they bring in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half a trillion dollars</NUMEX> and they spend <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and then the rest goes to to the national debt
 	
 	
 		which just keeps accumulating  i don't know  what else do you think about them let's see the state
 	
 	
 		that's about it i guess
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> tax the sale tax they used to you really didn't even think anything about it when you bought something but now you do  it figures in what is it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> oint
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> percent or something it depends on where you're at some places in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i guess it's like closer to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and places like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lewisville</ENAMEX> it's a lot closer to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't even know how they figure it really i'm glad i don't work in a store
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 		how's that
 	
 	
 		because i wouldn't want to have to figure this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> point something percent i guess they've got a little table though and it's all written out
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		so it wouldn't be so bad  all right so you think
 	
 	
 		that's the way to do it
 	
 	
 		federal tax is okay
 		state tax you can see the logic of it but
 		you don't think it would be economically feasible for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and ours see both of us are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and we got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we don't need anymore
 	
 	
 		and so when you start taking talking taking more out of your paycheck to go to the state income tax
 		uh
 	
 	
 		but we can do this tax sheltered annuity that's the only thing that's saving us
 	
 	
 		yeah i think what we need what uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> needs to do is get in there and cut spending
 		because when they got all this fraud and waste going on they need to just get in there and and get out the garbage that's in there right now i mean i once heard that uh
 		uh for the for the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> at least that if they uh
 		uh well for like on the welfare system if they gave all that money directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> every welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> would be making like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty five thousand dollars</NUMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and you know they're not making that much money they're making probably more like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six</NUMEX> on the welfare so where's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the other ninety</NUMEX> percent going well it's going to the some fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in the middle who's sitting there on his behind all day doing nothing but filling out papers
 	
 	
 		part
 		lots and lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> before they get it
 	
 	
 		lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but still i work in southeast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		and a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are from poor
 		you know socioeconomic areas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and it's just like they always have money they they always are dressed nice you know most of them are fairly nice not like you would think a a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i mean they've always got dessert money or they've always got you know dollars on them and everything and i'm thinking you know this isn't right because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> don't have that
 	
 	
 		yeah well i don't have that  a lot of times if i've got a dollar in my wallet it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> where do i go where did where'd i find that
 	
 	
 		yeah and you give them you know they get their free lunch and they throw most of it away but then they have their money to go buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX> and that they eat
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		you know it's just you see garbage pans i mean pails just filled and we pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to haul them off right
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		and the like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> does it and he has his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		quite a quite a world we live in
 	
 	
 		that he
 		yeah it is oh well is that you got anything else to say i don't think i do
 	
 	
 		oh well
 		yeah that's all i have to say thank you
 	
 	
 		okay well talk talk to you later then bye
 	
 	
 		um-hum bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	