
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay uh my favorite show is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Masterpiece Theater</ENAMEX> and it has been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> but
 		i feel almost ashamed to say that to anybody now because i've never met anybody who likes it  do you by any chance you do
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes very much
 	
 	
 		well wouldn't you know
 	
 	
 		as a matter of fact i prefer public television
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i have particularly enjoy the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">English</ENAMEX> comedies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the
 		English mysteries
 	
 	
 		yeah i watch Mystery too um is is that what you're referring to okay yeah that is good i like uh do you read
 	
 	
 		yes
 		vociferously
 	
 	
 		okay well that's the reason why i like both of those programs is because they're kind of based on books and the plots are more
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh challenging you know than the sitcoms
 		of regular TV
 	
 	
 		well unfortunately for us at least here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> we the only access we have to that of course is public television
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i i'm not a great television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watcher</ENAMEX> in in any respect uh but uh
 		the
 		watching what i do watch is uh
 		usually news and whatever is on public television uh any kind of i also uh
 		am very fond of great performances in in that regard
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah me too
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		did you stay up late and catch this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red Dwarf  oh</ENAMEX> that was a scream
 	
 	
 		no uh no uh no as a matter of fact
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Turner Broadcasting</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		has been uh broadcasting
 		all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX> movies
 	
 	
 		really uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> so i have concentrated on watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX> movies  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 		i used to like him too he was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> in fact i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX> to this day
 	
 	
 		well they're showing uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live and Let Die</ENAMEX> at this moment and it is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> appearance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Moore</ENAMEX> as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">007</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it it
 	
 	
 		oh he could never cut it
 	
 	
 		no no that's true i was just thinking that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> he well in some of the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">later</TIMEX> movies he looks very effeminate in the early movies whereas uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX> has maintained the
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah yeah he does
 	
 	
 		i how would you ruddy uh look uh but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		i liked his accent too
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes
 	
 	
 		and he can even be in movies that are not uh uh  sexually oriented and he still comes off great
 	
 	
 		well you know he was uh
 		when was it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year or year</TIMEX> before last
 		he was voted
 		the
 		sexiest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> in movies or something
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah he had my vote double
 	
 	
 		i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty two years old</TIMEX> if
 	
 	
 		i don't care
 	
 	
 		but uh otherwise you know we uh  with you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and so forth and i i particularly enjoy i don't know whether you've whether you had a chance to watch it on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the series uh Yes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minister</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh what's that about
 	
 	
 		that was about a the interior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> it was a comedy the interior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> of uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> with the permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> and bureaucracy and all that
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		i like i've seen it several times it's a scream but i had to go to bed i have to get up and and work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next morning</TIMEX> i wish they'd put those
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's why i say did you stay up late to watch this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red Dwarf</ENAMEX> it came on after Doctor Who on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> here at least
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's just of course i don't you know you really it was
 		i don't think they should show it on during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">prime time</TIMEX> but still
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it was funny
 	
 	
 		yeah i know well i i'd
 		i as i said i'm not much of a television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watcher</ENAMEX> i read as i said and uh quite a bit i i read about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> novels a week
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in addition to all the technical stuff what do what what do you do what kind of work do you do
 	
 	
 		i'm a payroll <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> just an accounting clerk
 	
 	
 		at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no uh i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who works for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and uh i work for a a tire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> here in i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		um-hum well the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have called both worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and i just wondered huh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it could be TIers uh i think probably are participating more than anybody else but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i needed the money  this is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> bucks here  yeah really do you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess yeah i i guess we all can
 		no no i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really how'd you hear oh we're not even supposed to be talking about this though are we
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> yes
 		well that i guess it it doesn't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how did i hear about it well i work you know they're gathering a database for voice processing and that's my field of of work also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> who are doing this and i heard about it so i called them and ask if i could could participate and uh
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know sent in the forms etcetera and uh so forth
 	
 	
 		huh
 		right
 	
 	
 		we could go back to television shows if you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you know speaking of public TV have you caught any of this series on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i have
 	
 	
 		i've heard that it's really against the well i mean that it's coming out with the idea that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>'s not true
 	
 	
 		well no that's it you could interpret it that way
 		uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think
 		what they're trying to say is that there is a great deal of
 		historical truth
 		but the interpretation that
 		actually got into the um
 		the writing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> itself is probably
 		uh after the what uh was it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Version</ENAMEX> when the committee
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		did it wrote wrote the uh the or translation that so much was lost in the translation uh particularly since most of the translations most of the translations were from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh well for example uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> different words for love
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		okay so you can have there's one word for love of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> one word for love of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> one ler word for you know love uh love of uh your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and that sort of thing
 		so in those translations those types of interpretations uh
 		really made a difference in how one might interpret the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> now and what it says so that you know it's it you know you can look at it as though they are saying it's not true but there's too much historical
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		fact involved just from the
 		uh the histories that are that were developed around that time that are available
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		to deny that at least you know the majority of it is true so you know you know it depends on how you look at it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you can look at it if you know if if you want to say that it's proving that
 		it isn't true then you can you very much look at it that way
 	
 	
 		i guess if you're looking for that you're
 	
 	
 		yeah hey you could well you can interpret that the what the TV show in the same way you can interpret the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> well uh so
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		really
 	
 	
 		but uh i as as far as that goes i at we at we at least agree on you know on what we enjoy in that regard but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		i don't know if there's a there is a time limit on this so uh
 	
 	
 		yeah surely we've made it  well it was nice talking to you okay you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		i think so too all right well it's been very pleasant talking to you
 		and have a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>
 		good night
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	