
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay i don't know which end do we  push but okay
 	
 	
 		okay well um let's see i i think uh there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that don't vote because they don't really think their their uh opinion is going to be heard and
 		you know there's such a
 		small voice and such a huge number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and
 		that you know their votes votes not going to make that much difference
 		and whether you vote for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> the issues is what you know what you believe in and that person
 		is going to have a lot of uh since there's so many issues this one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can believe a lot of different ways on all of them so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it'd be really difficult to have that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that believed exactly what you believed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's true you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh uh i think the that it ends up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that uh vote every time uh elections come around are more the the polly uh the party type  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that uh
 		you know follow the party lines you know and they you know just go in and if they're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> they vote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> vote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> you know and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are independent
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know are the ones that don't uh don't really
 		uh show up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> because they can't seem to
 		to decide which are the good aspects and which are the bad aspects of a candidate
 	
 	
 		right yeah that's good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i always thought it was back when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> was running i was hoping that things would change and he'd actually get elected and party politics would start going down the tubes but  that didn't work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah there's uh a lot of extremes on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> too with the you know the real uh far side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> they're real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> now to where probably fifty or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred years ago</TIMEX> um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> being liberal like they are now you know would never be thought of it would be the other way that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> minded
 		as far as like uh moral standings and those kinds of things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's uh
 		and and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> always get upset about it too because you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are the ones that are usually pushing for more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to vote they they each think that uh if more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> vote they'll get more votes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm always amazed at that that each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> thinks it's going to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that come out that will vote for him you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's that's true i think in uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> election i think more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> turned out to vote against somebody than for somebody this time
 	
 	
 		yeah well that uh that's something i i know that there's certain issues that can really motivate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because we live in a predominately predominately predominately <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> type area
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and when things start uh when when abortion comes on the issues then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just get all inspirational inspired you know and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		still on the other hand we're also uh this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> but uh uh down in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> where where things are a little bit different uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">and</ENAMEX> and that sort of movement and so it's uh quite the opposite so elections start getting very uh the elections where they have that topic seem to be a little bit better attended than some of the other ones
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true that the different places in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> that uh you know different issues would be a lot more important than say in another place
 	
 	
 		yeah i can understand why why some of the the rural areas the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> turnout isn't as much because it does seem sometimes like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> are like controlling things for the
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> and uh it doesn't matter who they put in office they're going to fall subject to uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the pressure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> can put
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah and it's uh
 	
 	
 		well
 		
 
 	
 	
 		real true that uh
 		you you know they'll say one thing
 		to get elected and then once they do get elected they don't have the power or the authority or the willingness to do those things that they promised you know beforehand
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know maybe it just wasn't possible at all in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place you know like the no new taxes thing you know that's uh
 		with the economy going the way it is and everything that was nearly ridiculous thing to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		even try to do
 	
 	
 		yeah well i don't think he's going to have to worry about that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> i think he can probably raise taxes and still get elected
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">right</TIMEX> after the war
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that really uh
 	
 	
 		unfortunately that'll probably even drop lower the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> turn down even more uh turnout even more because more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will think that they don't have a shot so they won't even bother turning out
 	
 	
 		uh that's true
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they'll just say oh well you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have this election we'll see you in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		uh but yeah i hope some of the local well that's what they they keep saying that it seems like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with it with
 		old-fashioned values are the ones that aren't turning out at the at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booths</ENAMEX> they they say that these older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that uh
 		you know they they feel like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are running the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> so they they don't come out turn out to vote and they're the ones that uh you know really know what's going on have the experience and have seen you know how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> can you know screw up or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> hasn't voted in years
 	
 	
 		right that's right you know neither has <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact and uh that's true they i think they look at it as well everybody the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think this way when that's not necessarily true
 		because you know that's what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> says well the majority believes this way so
 		uh they don't even bother turning out to vote to express their uh opinions
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's that's true
 	
 	
 		yeah wonder if they're going to take into account with this commutiv uh this computerized conversation that there's little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know bouncing in your knee the whole time your talking
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah do you hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> in the background here okay they're
 	
 	
 		no i can't hear them
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> next door just opened the fence and they went off yeah but anyway that's i guess we've uh talked long enough and that was sort of interesting what part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are you from
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Washington DC um</ENAMEX>-hum
 	
 	
 		are you really wow this is i'm in from this is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> where i'm at the outskirts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay well i figured with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> they'd probably have a few uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> on the line now and then
 	
 	
 		yeah do do you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in any way
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		wow how did you how did they get you or
 	
 	
 		uh basically they they went through engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and uh we're communications i work i work in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">com munications</ENAMEX> company
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh okay right i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> so
 		we saw it on the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TV News</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and i thought wow that might be interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah we sort of different
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they called me at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">uh ten o'clock one night</TIMEX> that was very strange
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess they were doing it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Standard Time</ENAMEX> i was like well i don't know how long it takes whether it takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> so i
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Standard Time</ENAMEX>'s what they're doing it by
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i still haven't figured out what the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days</TIMEX> which day is which yet but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i didn't study it that hard so maybe i'll figure it out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but anyway it was nice to talk to you and uh sort of meet you and that was an interesting topic
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah okay well if you're ever in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> can look up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Sherman</ENAMEX> you'll say oh yeah talked to that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay i'm i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle Hunt</ENAMEX> too if you ever come to to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area well we live right by the airport
 	
 	
 		oh
 		okay
 		yeah yeah yeah so do we
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah right next to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulles</ENAMEX> all right well i'll talk to you later bye-bye
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	