
 
     		
 	
 		all right um i think the topic was crime in the city
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i do not live in a city i live in a real small little place
 	
 	
 		where is that
 	
 	
 		uh it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about thirty miles</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">north</ENAMEX> south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> or west
 	
 	
 		it's north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well you live almost in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it not too far
 	
 	
 		yeah that's kind of ironic because i don't live too far from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> either
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		you know where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saint Joe</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		uh i've been through there
 	
 	
 		i'm <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about eight miles</NUMEX> south of it
 	
 	
 		okay oh yeah i had been through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saint Joe</ENAMEX> but um just as far as you know watching the news and reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> and all that it sounds like the crimes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> are really getting bad
 	
 	
 		well you know
 		i've i've seen those statistics and everything
 		and you know what frightens me
 		is that you put a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out in the middle of the desert
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with high tech weaponry
 		you know i mean
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> didn't have a lot of high-tech weaponry but they had mortars and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine guns tanks</ENAMEX> and all that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and they didn't kill as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">forty five days</TIMEX>
 		and they were intending to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean that was their job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as they killed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i know i know
 		i know um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think nowadays <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just really just murder is nothing to them you know
 	
 	
 		well
 		i formulated a pretty radical theory
 		over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last ten years</TIMEX> i guess
 		and
 		i've come to the conclusion
 		and this is
 		a pretty scary thought to me even
 		that if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is convicted or a gal is convicted of a crime
 		rather than put them in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>'s proven not to work
 		just let them go
 		say okay you're convicted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and just let them go
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and if they get convicted again
 		well just kill them
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah because uh most likely that will happen won't it that you know
 	
 	
 		well i think that
 		the best hope
 		to eliminate
 		crime
 		as we know it today
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is to eliminate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> from society
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if someone is known to have been in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> they can't get a job
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		you know they can't be accepted into society
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know if they're not going to be accepted into society then everybody's going to become sociopathic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know who's to put the limit on it
 		i mean i was watching a thing last night up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State</ENAMEX>
 		if you get convicted of uh
 		sexual offenses
 		on a regular basis i mean some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> and got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> convictions
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're still let out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one or two years</TIMEX>
 		well in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State</ENAMEX> if you're a habitual sexual offender
 		they just don't let you out
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		uh you serve your prison term
 		and then you go into the mental hospital and if you're pronounced cured they'll let you go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 		they may find a cure for it but there is no known cure now
 	
 	
 		hum so you're you're kind of thinking in other words if you get if you do something the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that's not real bad you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hey people</ENAMEX> make mistakes
 	
 	
 		yeah to go ahead and let them go but if they do it again and they really need to face the consequences then uh
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah use that or you know there's other consequences rather than killing them you know you could always make them the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they committed the crime against
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know
 		at least they might be some benefit in that and if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they committed a crime against
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		feel at some later date that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have learned their lesson are are okay you know well they can free them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh you know with the technology technology we have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you can put a collar on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> leg
 		that will knock him down if they leave the property
 		i mean it will just in incapacitate them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you can put a collar around a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> leg
 		that will
 		prohibit them
 		from committing any kind of
 		you know prohibitive act
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you know putting them in prison my God that doesn't work
 	
 	
 		no apparently not because look how many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> they've been doing that and look  i mean yeah
 	
 	
 		well you look at places like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> has death penalty for just about everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean if you get
 		convicted of uh you know drug trafficking they just kill you
 		you get convicted of uh
 		you know uh heinous crimes
 		they just kill you i mean there's no <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		you look at their society and the repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> are very few
 		you know and you look at our society
 		almost everyone out on the street
 		that has been in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> has been in prison <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times yeah
 	
 	
 		right i mean you know
 	
 	
 		that is true i know
 	
 	
 		you know the way to stop that kind of behavior
 		is this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fold
 		one
 		you need to make it illegal for
 		both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to work while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
 		i i think that's very important
 	
 	
 		oh i'm i agree very much so on that i yeah
 	
 	
 		and then
 		if a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> has proved to be unfit
 		for any reason
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		take t he <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> away from the parents
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because
 		you know we are what we teach
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because that's what our society becomes i mean we have a just a bunch of people
 	
 	
 		comes yeah
 	
 	
 		and i've and i've i've lived in that that environment for quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> when i was doing construction work
 		you know and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> they come to work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every morning</TIMEX> and they're stoned to the bone
 		i mean their so high they could fly up to the top of that building
 		and they work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> and they go home and they smoke their dope and drink their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX> and shoot their drugs
 		and when they run out of money they go down to the corner store and pop the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and take his money and then they go back to work on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> of these people
 	
 	
 		sure they just think that's the normal thing to do don't they
 	
 	
 		are phenomenally
 		they're sociopathic
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and i worked in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade uh classroom
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one full semester</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were more foul mouthed than i've ever been
 		i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> threaten my life first grader
 	
 	
 		in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade
 	
 	
 		threaten my life told me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>'s going to whoop me to death
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		you know and they flipping me the finger and all that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i just said to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> i said you got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> choices <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> you can step into mainstream society or you can die
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because you will eventually be killed
 		and  you know i just i'm just totally aghast aghast at a what's going on
 	
 	
 		oh i know i know um  i work in school
 		you know that's huh-uh something i do and i it really is i'm like you astonishing what the younger ages know and they react to what they see at home You know
 		if they see violence at home that's what you're going to get from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at school you know it really is
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and that's kind of sad
 	
 	
 		well you can see it in the work place
 		you know
 		used to be when you had a
 		personality conflict you just you worked with it and you got through it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get fired
 		or
 		what's even worse is they promote them into a position that they can't handle and let them get fired
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or one thing or the other you look at another kind of society like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
 		you put
 		that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on that small of a space they've learned to live together
 		okay it's in their culture
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things that's in their culture that i really think the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> should pay attention to is the fact that while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> was becoming a great power financially
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that worked for those companies
 		worked for the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> they worked for at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty five</TIMEX> as they did when they were eighteen
 	
 	
 		teen
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> took it upon itself to find a position for these people
 		if they weren't fit for the job they were hired for they didn't just can them
 		they made a position for them some where
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you look at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frito Lay</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> used to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frito Lay</ENAMEX>
 		as a typist
 		you know transcribing stuff into the computer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well she can type <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one hundred and five</NUMEX> words per minute
 		but she don't like it
 		she she just doesn't like to do that i mean she will
 	
 	
 		cause yeah
 	
 	
 		but you know her preference is to be in an office situation where her job is
 		
 		
 	