
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		we just bought our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> home after being in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and so we're just <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowners</ENAMEX> who've only been living here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		okay um well i've lived in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> area for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about uh twenty five</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half years twenty six years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		and we're in our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> now we've been in it for uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about thirteen</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen years</TIMEX> i think now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh so you're you're an old pro then
 	
 	
 		
 
 		we've lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> area for that you know for the full time uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well what do you find having to be like out there i've always heard that it was expensive
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it's it's not really all that bad uh i think you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> so uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Plano</ENAMEX> area and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> area probably are are about the same pricewise i would think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 		hm
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		well we uh when we graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> went went to school at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX> and got his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhD</ENAMEX> so that that's what brought us here and um we had um
 		heard a lot about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> being a good area and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> there being really nice and but we kind of just got the impression it was out of our price range
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well um
 		i know i i think that there's some areas in you know in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> that may be a little bit higher priced but uh of course it like i said i've it's been thirteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> since we've really priced a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i'm not sure what the prices are like now uh i know that our price that the the value of our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> went up you know considerably over over a you know uh oh an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight or ten year</TIMEX> period
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but then for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last several years</TIMEX> it's pretty well stabilized uh and perhaps even dropped back some from what it was so
 	
 	
 		really
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but uh we've done uh you know in order to maintain ours we've done some remodeling and stuff you know just to to kind of change do some some little changes occasionally so
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh but uh i guess i'm i'm a little encouraged with home prices i i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPA</ENAMEX> and i was just talking to one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> uh or you know over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of days</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that makes sense
 	
 	
 		and they have sold a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that was quite expensive and bought one you know that was was more reasonably priced it's uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> but it's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richardson School District</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> is very pleased you know she says it's got everything she want's you know thinks she'll ever want in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and it was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several thousand dollars</NUMEX> less than the one that they sold so
 	
 	
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		so i I suppose that the housing market is uh you know it is on the on the down side right now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well do you have a lot of homes out there that have um foundation problems that seems to be the pretty much the rule out here
 	
 	
 		well i'm not really aware of those i do know that that our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> uh we've had to have the shower pan in the master bedroom replaced twice
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		because uh apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> shifts a little bit under that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because uh apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> shifts a little bit under that but that was a design problem because we put uh and we designed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so it's our fault but we had them put the shower on a corner uh like our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is built in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> shape
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and in inside that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> but on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the corners uh is where that shower is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so any shifting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of course or or you know i guess i feel that way anyway that that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shifting</ENAMEX> would cause some problems in that in that area of the house
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and of course the shower pan is a pretty fragile piece of uh of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal</ENAMEX> or plastic whichever it is anyway so
 	
 	
 		so  did it look cracked to you i mean that's how you knew it was broken or
 	
 	
 		no it uh it started leaking through the you know out through the pan and out onto the floor and it's soaking up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sheetrock</ENAMEX> or in things right
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh so that's that's how you knew well since like i say we're <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowners</ENAMEX> i'm still scared about everything like that  going wrong and how do you know it's going to happen and all
 	
 	
 		yeah uh but uh
 		yeah but i think uh you know i think so far as uh as the location <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson Plano</ENAMEX> are probably comparable the the school districts are you know are about the same uh you know quality wise
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		we really like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our school</TIMEX> out here
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		but we um
 		we were scared to buy a an house
 		in our neighborhood because all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> did have these foundation problems and we didn't know um you know if we were afraid we'd be living there and all of a sudden the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> would crack in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> and split open or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah but uh well our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and i'm not sure how all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builders</ENAMEX> you know how most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builders</ENAMEX> do but ours is what they call uh post tensioned which means that there are iron <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bars</ENAMEX> you know that run through the foundation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and once they get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> poured then they they apply tension to that iron bar which compresses the concrete
 		and makes it more uh stable more stable and and puts more strength into it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh you know it it
 		
 
 		uh potentially that's supposed to just mean that the foundation kind of floats when the you know when the the earth itself shifts around so
 	
 	
 		well that's good well that's really good well our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is older it's like a nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty three</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> that we bought so i'm not doesn't seem like it um i mean i know so much has changed in their technology in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		right uh is yours a is it a a slab <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX> and beam
 	
 	
 		it's slab
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah so that's and that's what ours is our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> we had before was over we live on the east side of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> now and the other one was over on the west side and it was uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX> and beam house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i just drove by there this morning and it still looks just as good as it did when we moved out of it thirteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		yeah so you know i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> uh i think they hold up pretty well if you've got a if you have a good builder
 	
 	
 		yes my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builder</ENAMEX> and so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> always lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> that he built and then they knew they were getting a good deal so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i uh appreciate that information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> i know it was um it's got a really good reputation and
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 		yeah so well it uh you know i think it's a a good place to live uh or course if i didn't think that well we wouldn't still be living here so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that's pretty good well thank you and well um you good good luck with this program then bye-bye
 	
 	
 		right yeah that would
 		okay thank you uh
 		okay thank you you too um-hum
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	