
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh the topic is to discuss the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> where i receive news
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh for me that's uh mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and radio i almost never watch television
 		as a matter of course so i don't get news from television except during the war i watched a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> because it was so good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well why was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the only</TIMEX> of course i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> only allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> to broadcast it is that not true
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		it was unusual not to have the different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> you know of news coverage
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 		i don't know i guess uh i don't even know why i watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> i guess i just wanted more news it's one of the few times i wanted
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i know even if you watched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC NBC</ENAMEX> or or the other you i mean what's the other one  uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> they all were were tapped into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		more news than
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>
 		were they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's the only thing they broadcast and like you i listen to the radio on my job at work and all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> they've been having this uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a discussion about that is why uh why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> was
 		well i listen to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> radio station and they were saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> is definitely a world uh news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that  was you can't really be sure of the quality of what you got you know
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		uh we had some uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> uh just for a uh tour sort of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i was watching on TV they they broadcast this terrible riot supposedly that was going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> so we got all fearful
 		for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come to find out they came back and said they weren't even aware of it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so it really made me question as to what how do we know about you know uh if the news we're getting is any good
 		so
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess the news just focuses on major events that probably
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		don't affect ninety <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nine percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are right there when the news is being made
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but uh i can i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and i can remember being in
 		uh in these earthquakes and i mean they were they were very minor kinds of things from my point of view and it seemed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know from anyone else's point of view but they'd get all blown up in the news
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well i it i find it depressing to watch or especially TV you know it's  uh local news
 		concentrates on murders and things like that i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we have a lot of bad stuff it just really  gets me depressed even to watch it
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		so then you wake up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX> and you're in war with somebody you don't even  know about it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		oh what newspaper uh do you read in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Times Herald</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> but i don't
 		i don't read newspapers
 	
 	
 		don't you how come
 	
 	
 		huh-uh i have find it hard to uh follow from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> page to another it's just something i've never developed uh an interest in
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and i live in kind of a bad area where if i have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> delivered
 		it's stolen before i can get out and get it
 	
 	
 		God that's uh that sounds pretty bad to me i mean who would steal a newspaper
 	
 	
 		you'd be surprised
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		they just come by and pick them up even if it's just for the TV you know  uh
 		selections of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> i don't know it just wouldn't be there whenever i've tried it
 	
 	
 		i see
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so  you're right who would steal a newspaper
 		but they do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> are you from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
 		but i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh North Carolina</ENAMEX> right now that's where i'm speaking to you from
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		but i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX>
 		i work out here
 	
 	
 		huh you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i don't i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Carolina State University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but uh i know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and i have a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who have graduated and gone to work for them so i'm in the computer business
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i boy current events is not a good subject for me
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		i don't keep up with it that often
 	
 	
 		let's see i've i've i've never done this before i mean i've never
 	
 	
 		this is your first call
 	
 	
 		this is my first call because i just got my password
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so i don't know are we suppose to it seems to me it says you're supposed to talk for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three minutes</TIMEX> but i think we've been talking for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three minutes</TIMEX> and nobody has interrupted
 	
 	
 		yeah well i'd i got into a conversation last night with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> and they interrupt at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		so if we've done <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">our three minutes</TIMEX> let's just let the conversation end and say bye   nice talking to you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well all right nice talking to you
 		all right bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	