
 
     		
 	
 		okay the question was um what what is your opinion of youth uh spending  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two</TIMEX> in in public service
 	
 	
 		i think it would be a great idea i'm not sure about requiring it you know of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going you know feeling resentful i don't know but i think it would be a great idea
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		seems like there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that don't have any since of you know what they want to be or do or you know they could learn  something and maybe help other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at the same time and we sure our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> sure need help so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um-hum would uh would you be more in favor of uh you know like a local
 		uh my only experience with it i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> for a while and uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Salvador</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX> for instance everybody had what they called there social year
 	
 	
 		hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh really uh
 	
 	
 		that they that they had to put in and basically it was a uh repayment for for uh high school education
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and most of them joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> and it was done internally i just there was very little external i think
 		possibly what uh they're thinking about here more external <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> type things where we're sending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off shore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think that would be real interesting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do but i guess my concern about that would be the cost involved trying to train <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a new language and ship them you know to other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and but i don't know if you did it internally and it was just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in your own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> then maybe maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that are so poor that they wouldn't be able to
 		really you know
 		send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know to do that
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't i don't know how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> works i guess i was of age when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> came in and all that
 	
 	
 		i didn't know
 		yeah i was too i thought seriously about joining at that time i thought it was a fantastic idea
 	
 	
 		did you ever get any information on it like
 	
 	
 		i sent off for stuff on it but i don't remember that much about it i know that they trained you in the language and um
 	
 	
 		that's that's what i was wondering about was whether they actually
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you actually got paid too while in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> it wasn't much but i guess they you could put some money aside while you were there your expenses were covered
 	
 	
 		yeah was it
 		yeah wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>'s mama that was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> or some such thing
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so yeah yeah
 		but it might be interesting to see what would happen if you took <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at a and then took then to another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> instead of having being exposed to all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and violence and sex and everything here and take them
 		to some other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that had different moral values something like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> where they couldn't drink
 	
 	
 		where they couldn't do that yeah you might end up with a revolution i don't know which end though yeah
 	
 	
 		really  yeah i hadn't thought about that um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's that's been interesting though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that have been over you know coming back right now you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you wonder if being exposed to that for a while what percentage of them would actually say hey that's not a bad way to do it because from what i understand from some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i know crime
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is punishable just almost uh instantly and
 	
 	
 		public hangings and yeah
 	
 	
 		in public yeah  and this sort of thing you know so you don't have just a whole lot of what we consider street crimes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i've heard that like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and stuff there is virtually no such thing as rape because if you rape somebody you'd be murdered them  you know on the you know <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> so yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah  well i guess that's uh the price of freedom i guess is a little anyway the uh uh the the public service thing again i i i
 		i guess in my own having had the whole <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> to you know give it a great deal of thought here  uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i think i agree with you <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> percent about it being some sort of voluntary but when you do that then it becomes almost uh
 		or it can be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will kind of set up their own little club
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		and uh but if
 		you know if you start
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that might benefit most from it might not go in that situation you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that really are trapped in a ghetto or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		might not go if it was voluntary but i don't know how they'd enforce it if it was
 	
 	
 		yeah well if they went AWOL what are you going to do shoot them put them in jail
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know send them over to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>  have a vacation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> for a year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah right
 		yeah
 		i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> always talked about uh he was in uh CCC during uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> and he was uh a rock rib <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">republican</ENAMEX> and the only good thing he could ever say about uh the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> was uh civilian conservation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX> he because he was in it he thought that was great the rest of it was all hog wash but the that was great
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well it seems like it would develop pride you know in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if if it's in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> it would certainly help them to appreciate some of the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		things that we have here and develop some pride in them if it was handled that way i i it would take quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think it might build jobs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know that were administrating and running and training and coordinating and all that so maybe that part of it would be helpful too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah the only
 	
 	
 		i'd like to have a volunteer come here and rake <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX> and  mow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		well you know that brings up the interesting subject too you know what would you have who who who would determine what these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know if uh
 		you know if it's run by the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCC</ENAMEX> was run by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> and in effect
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and  the only opposition to it really was that it was you know starting starting some sort of a military elitist type
 		you know special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX> of cadre of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that sort of thing and uh when the politics get real confusing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah really there could be um some uh scandals involved if you know it wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were really fair and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		leaving it you know in a legal way or something they could send all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over to uh you know one particular part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> or one particular project that somebody had paid somebody to you know get supported or
 	
 	
 		yeah well we've we've gotten to the point where you know if if if well
 	
 	
 		it would be open for
 	
 	
 		if the racial make up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was such and such you know they'd have to do that percentage of work and what is perceived to be that part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and you know all this kind of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah that could be a complicated too couldn't it yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah suppose uh
 		well you know they they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> who were construction oriented and they went and they they built uh  can't think of a good example a swimming poo l or anything
 		you know and one you can you can only build it in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place you know and know matter where you build it somebody else is going to scream well you didn't build <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> over here
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true unfair or something yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i think uh
 		
 
 		oh boy
 		it's one of those things on the surface you know it seems like a great idea it's like a
 		joke i heard once about uh
 		elephant foot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> you know it's easy to do once you find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX> foot
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's it's uh it's the logistics of the thing that uh that that gets you going
 	
 	
 		yeah really
 		yeah well it seems like there's there's a lot you don't hear much on the news about young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really you know wanting to do anything good or anything like that but you know i'm sure that there are a lot of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there that really do have
 		good hearts and are willing to help and serve and that kind of thing i just i saw on the news <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> that the uh
 		the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that used to be the littlest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cosby show Kisha Knight Pullman</ENAMEX> was starting a i guess now she's practically a teenager
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		she started some type of um  national um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> for youth to volunteer to teach tutor other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to read and you know do different service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> like that and trying to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> more directed towards
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know helpful things and i know even like in the high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> there's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple</NUMEX> high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that have wanted to start like a um
 		minority you know um i think it was in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> area they wanted to start like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> instead of they said every all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs kids</ENAMEX> could join to belong
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they didn't have anything positive the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> could be doing helping you know so they were trying to start that out so if there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there that are
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		willing to you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are willing to sacrifice their time and energy gosh we ought to use them you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if their willing to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's it's just the you know here you to the logistics of the thing again you know who
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		who's going to run it you know what how oh it's just so many
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah well like like i said at the beginning i've got so many connections with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> my daughter-in-law is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Panamanian</ENAMEX> you know and they have situations like like that down there where they
 	
 	
 		hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they have these the social
 		in some sort of way if you want to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Salvadorians</ENAMEX> did they'd go to school in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornell Iowa</ENAMEX> of all places
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and when they came back they'd have to serve this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this this year</TIMEX> and it turned out to be kind of a joke the ones i knew you know always chose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> because they didn't do anything
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		and they had all kinds of uh things they could go into agricultural and you know really you know good stuff but uh unless there was a flood or a fire or something like that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it was so many of them in it that at any particular chance your chance of having to do something was very slim it was very slim and so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um the there is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and also women <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aren't
 		um nearly as frequent and also that have elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> once their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have left that can volunteer to go on a mission
 		and um they're all over the world and its it is an incredible logistics i mean they have a training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> where they teach them it's called the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Missionary Training Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and they have to be taught the language
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">customs</ENAMEX> and all those kinds of things and then they um you know go and actually live in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for the the uh young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> do it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay then that's uh kind of  a private
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		organization you know i'm i'm familiar with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor pilot</ENAMEX> was a
 		was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mormon</ENAMEX> he was because he was a good construction uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor instructor pilot</ENAMEX> because he considered himself indestructible
 	
 	
 		oh  he had a direct connection somewhere uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah right he felt that he really had an in so you know he things he would do with an airplane but any rate that's off the subject no i haven't seen i haven't seen
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah but see they don't get paid for it and um but there is funding that that comes they're supposedly saving up on their own and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> helps them out some
 	
 	
 		you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you know that it is incredible
 		you you know
 	
 	
 		i seen how they were organized in in central and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> and uh it's uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's
 		very involved
 		
 		
 	