
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		have y'all been able to do much as a family these days
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 	
 	
 		have y'all been able to do much as a as a full family <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> all of you
 	
 	
 		oh yes we've um been um
 		we've gone other you know all kinds of places we go out to dinner we take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know whenever we he my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has time off or something we take them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> or we you know we we do everything we can possibly as a family
 	
 	
 		do you work outside the home
 	
 	
 		no i don't
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't either it makes a little bit easier i think that way
 	
 	
 		yeah it does and and then uh you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> enjoys spending time with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know he'll he'll take them out just to be with them so he they can have time with him and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so you have a break too
 	
 	
 		right so and we uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we try to teach our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> as much as we can at home you know we have we try to spend like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> we call it family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> um
 		you know have little lessons with them and you know just see count see how things are going in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
 		you know teach them about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> or something like that bring out pictures of them so they get to know them and
 		we just do all kinds of fun things like that and
 	
 	
 		uh we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that's far away it sounds like you might too
 	
 	
 		yeah we do so they you know the only way they know their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> is by pictures so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um
 	
 	
 		and phone calls that's about about it
 	
 	
 		yeah right and uh
 		you know they we you know we go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> or we go in the backyard and
 		sit down and
 	
 	
 		that's what yeah that's what we mostly do pretty simple things especially since my youngest one is  excuse me only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen months</TIMEX> she she's really getting to the age where she's playing and likes to go places
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		and with you know me being at home and just having the one income you know you don't have this lot of extra money to to do a lot of
 		you know extra things so you you make more fun than you know you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just think it's wonderful just maybe to go get an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream cone</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		that that's right
 		oh that's a big thrill for them
 	
 	
 		yeah or um you know go get a bag of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M's</ENAMEX> or something like that they they think that's a lot of fun so we just we try to spend as much time as we can we
 		you know our whole our whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> are divided are devoted to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> except for we might go out you know one <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> or something but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> you know it's all devoted to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they come go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> with us and
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		have um have you ever been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> no it's called the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Science Place</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes yes that's what
 	
 	
 		we just we haven't lived here too long we went there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple weeks ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> thought that was wonderful
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		
 
 		oh yeah we i guess there's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Science Place One and Science Place Two</ENAMEX> we've only been in i think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Science Place Two</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i is
 		i'm not sure which one we went into it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year or so ago</TIMEX> when we went
 	
 	
 		the one we went in had um the thing that sticks out most in my mind is a like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> place area that really seemed i mean they really seemed to go wild in there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah they had a lot of fun in there and um there's uh there's some petting you know like uh
 		uh i think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Owens Country Farms</ENAMEX> has a free petting you know like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> that you can go to and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> can pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		where's that
 	
 	
 		that's on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano Road</ENAMEX> um  it's like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> you go up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano Road</ENAMEX> it's like a little bit past <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano Road</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's a lot of fun they have tours going through there and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> think that was a lot of fun too and
 	
 	
 		oh that does sound like fun it's a little bit of a ways
 	
 	
 		we take you know whenever we take them to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showbiz</ENAMEX> or they think it's wonderful just to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> you know they don't go for the food they go for the to play around and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		there's another place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mesquite</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Monkey</ENAMEX> Business
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's a indoor fun <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and it has a bunch of different rides for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that sounds fun too
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> get in free and it's like during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> it's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> dollars admission for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> all day
 	
 	
 		and and you said about about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> is the petting
 	
 	
 		the petting farm yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that sounds fun i think maybe we'll try to do that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mesquite</ENAMEX> is um Scyene exit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it it's uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just had a wonderful time there they you know you just pay that admission and then all the the the rides are free you know they of course they have all the little video games and you know those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">little quarter</TIMEX> rides you know to
 		and stuff like that but they thought that was a lot of fun you can have birthday parties there and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think that was better than like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showbiz Pizza</ENAMEX>
 		because there's more for them to do
 	
 	
 		because they can just do you don't have to have tokens for everything yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		so they had a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		that does sound like fun well i've gotten some good ideas from you
 	
 	
 		yeah i we try to do a lot of things as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and you know inexpensively as possible so
 	
 	
 		definitely
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i think i don't know if we've done <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> but i'm sure that'll be
 	
 	
 		yeah that'll be good yeah well it's good talking to you
 	
 	
 		be good was it good talking to you i had a good i really appreciate your suggestions
 	
 	
 		oh no problem well take care bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	