
 
     		
 	
 		okay uh first um i need to know uh how how do you feel about uh about sending um an elderly uh family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> to a nursing home
 	
 	
 		well of course it's you know it's it one of the last few things in the world you'd ever want to do you know unless it's just you know really you know for and for their uh you know for their own good
 	
 	
 		yes yeah
 	
 	
 		i'd be very very careful and uh you know checking them out uh our had to place my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> in a nursing home she had a rather massive stroke about uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six eight months ago</TIMEX> i guess
 		and uh we were i was fortunate in that
 		i was personally acquainted with the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who uh ran the nursing home in our little hometown
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so i was very comfortable you know in doing it when it got to the point that we had to do it but there's well i had an occasion for my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> who
 		had fell and needed to be you know could not take care of herself anymore was confined to a nursing home for a while that was really not a very good experience uh
 		it had to be done in a hurry i mean we didn't have you know like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> to check all of these places out
 		and it was really not not very good uh
 		deal we were not really happy with the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that we finally had fortunately she only had to stay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> and she was able to to return to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> again
 		but it's really a big uh big decision as to you know when to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know is there something else we could have done you know in checking out all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> that uh might be available course there's you know there's not one on every corner especially in you know smaller areas smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah probably the hardest thing in in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> she had to be put in nursing home and um she had used a walker for for quite sometime probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six to nine months</TIMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she had a fall and uh finally uh she had uh <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's Disease</ENAMEX> and it got so much that she could not take care of her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> she then she lived in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		hm
 		right
 	
 	
 		that was even harder actually because it was you know it was just a change of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		change of location and it was very disturbing for her because she had been so used to traveling i mean she traveled she had she had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> all across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and you know she spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months</TIMEX> out of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> just visiting her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and um that was pretty heartrending for her i think when she finally came to the realization that you know no i cannot i cannot take care of myself
 	
 	
 		oh i can imagine
 		um-hum that's tough that's really tough
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean for somebody who is you know for most of their life has has uh
 		not just merely had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> but had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> ran everything because her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was away in the coal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> and you know facing that situation it it's quite a dilemma i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> excuse me go ahead
 	
 	
 		yeah well my uh my uh probably one of the biggest decisions i think that was very strengthened for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was rather than have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> make that decision
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		than just delegate it i think that they they had a great deal of um all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> got together and they actually had a conference and i mean it was just it was probably one of the most strengthening things for our family
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		getting down together and doing that and and just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were involved in the decision because it involved just them and you know making that decision and then
 	
 	
 		that's right it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		finding a place and everybody had duties to perform you know whether it was just you know giving money or whether it was actually taking part in in a lot of the decision making you know like finding a a proper nursing home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yep
 		you were very fortunate
 	
 	
 		and they i know they and well they had well they had they had seen it coming so so i mean it i mean i i i i hardly i i truly wish that if something like that were to happen that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> would do something like that for me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		absolutely unfortunately unfortunately at a lot of times it
 		responsibilities like that seem to fall to you know maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well we we yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh it's usually not a very smooth smooth thing we were uh lucky  i was lucky too that i only have my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh fortunately we agreed you know on exactly you know what we thought should be done
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> also was very very independent she had her own still had her own little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and still driving her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> at age eighty three
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we were lucky in that in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> respect in that after she had her stroke she wasn't really you know really much aware of what was going on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that nursing home life would not have been you know anything of her choosing of course she would she would not have been happy there at all but uh as it turned out the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> took care of that concern for us
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well with my with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> i think it was it was such that uh that she did not have the problem with
 		
 
 		she was very well aware and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> came and visited her at least her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> came and visited her and also her uh several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> came and visited her everyday
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		and i think that when she passed away it was probably one of the greatest
 		um i i i think it would be it was more of a relief for her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and um i mean but she was truly she was truly aware i mean i i didn't i don't know how i would how i would deal if if one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> came with with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> or something like that which is which is far more devastating
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum that'd be tough
 		yes absolutely
 	
 	
 		and um
 		i i think i think that what one thing that was that they were really concerned with probably was the fact
 		it wasn't necessarily you know like the quantity of care but the quality of care that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that work there were very
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		were very interested that to make it as close a home environment as possible i i think i think i think you know for myself i i see that as probably the the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes yeah we were fortunately
 	
 	
 		what everything would hinge upon is it how close is it to a home environment that's the that's probably the major question
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		that's right um-hum
 		yeah i think a great strides are being made nowadays in in caring for the elderly you know in several in a whole lot of areas because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is getting older you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah you know it's it's interesting that that a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is changing because
 		you know uh now that so many more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> where they have had extended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> for such a long time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um in matter of fact in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> we used to have extended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> it wasn't but i guess as we become more industrialized and more you know less in a rural situation
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's right
 		yes
 	
 	
 		we we don't we we we choose not to deal with the extended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> because we feel it's kind of cumbersome when in reality it makes things much much easier
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 		sure absolutely and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are scattered so much nowadays
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah yeah i i i think that perhaps perhaps the extended family
 		you know that that it may be one of the solutions to a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">thi ngs</ENAMEX> even even even child care you know i mean of course there there comes other issues you know whether or not
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> would we feel they're gonna be a good  they're gonna be a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caretaker</ENAMEX> for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but i mean they raised us after all
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah just because they're grandparents just yeah just because they're grandparents that doesn't automatically make them a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> carer
 	
 	
 		yeah but uh i'm i i think that you know i mean we always uh i mean i've i've had a a lot of good experiences with uh with many many people
 		especially where they've had uh extended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and i and and i i kind of see that that you know perhaps
 		you know we may need to like get close to the family environment and and get down to the values of you know i mean uh it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		money seems to be too big of an issue with with with with with with what's going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and i i think i think that we may not you know that may be
 	
 	
 		oh yeah sure realistically it is yes
 	
 	
 		you know perhaps if we put money on the back burner that may that may choose to alleviate a lot of the problems i mean  i mean we may not we may not have as  high a standard of living but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that would certainly help yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the quality but actually have a truer standard of living
 	
 	
 		right that's just a matter of defining priorities i guess or some priorities anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think your right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay well
 		i guess that was it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> was good talking to you yeah take care bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay all right hey bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	