
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> this is Lois
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 		hi
 		hi this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i called you know from that the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI Database Calling Instructions</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i got a call <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> too this is a different subject though
 	
 	
 		yeah this is about changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh there's really a lot isn't there i mean there really is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's kind of an easy thing to talk about
 	
 	
 		oh i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> would be the main wouldn't it it uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um i think you have to push <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and then we can start recording it
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 		all right are you ready now okay like i said i guess it would be the work force you know as far as changes in the generations
 	
 	
 		okay yes
 		yes i know because
 		i know when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was a you know going into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> there wasn't very many opportunities for her i guess she's in her late forties you were expected to stay home and take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i've never faced that at all
 	
 	
 		um no i think now now you go to work when they're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks old</TIMEX> you know and you stay there and i feel like the next generation you'll probably just work right along with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah um-hum i think it's definitely gotten better
 	
 	
 		oh i do too much and it's just gonna get better it really is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are in every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> now i mean i can't think of a field that they're not involved in
 	
 	
 		oh i can't either not a one
 	
 	
 		i know at least in the medical field it seems like they've come out with a lot further advances as far as female <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> and things since women have gotten into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> field i don't think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> really took the time to work on that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> you know there seems to be lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> involved
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		hopefully the next generation it won't even be an issue i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will just look at you as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and not as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> i think that would be the best goal
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 		oh i do too just your qualifications and that would be it
 	
 	
 		uh-huh exactly not what color you are how old you are what if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> or female that would be wonderful i guess it's kind of an ideal world though huh
 	
 	
 		yes yeah yes
 		um yeah
 		yeah i kind of think maybe in time that you know you'll go by social security numbers you know and that way they can't say well they picked the male over a female or female over a male you know you yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		exactly or the way you look or the way you you know your age or anything i think that'd be a wonderful way to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah they'll just i do too just go by your social security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> and then look at your qualifications that you know that you have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and then
 	
 	
 		and if you get it you know then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		also with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the work force they've gotten a lot more options as far as you know what's it called job sharing like if you and another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> were to share the same full time job or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah uh-huh as a matter of fact that's what i'm doing um-hum it sure is it sure is
 	
 	
 		is it
 		that would be great
 		or a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> i know now and my uh one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> when she went on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOA</ENAMEX> to have her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> we hooked up a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a terminal at her house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she you know we could send her messages and and she kept in touch like that and basically just worked out of her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i would just take her the actual paperwork once uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week or two</TIMEX> and that worked out great too
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yes that is
 	
 	
 		i mean that's a real attractive option if you have the the technology for it all it was was you know i mean she just used a phone modem and she was like she was sitting in the office
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i think that's real nice too to come up with different options do you like the job sharing
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh i do i really do i think it's great
 	
 	
 		do you
 		do you work like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		uh well like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> she'll work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> and i'll work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and the next week</TIMEX> you know i'll work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX> and she'll work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX> we just share off like that
 	
 	
 		hm
 		oh is oh that's great
 		uh-huh do you get the full benefits
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah we get the full benefits but we've just really got a wonderful system that we're working under yeah
 	
 	
 		oh that's wonderful
 		yeah especially with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and so many things going on that would be great
 	
 	
 		yes
 		it really is and that way we're not really missing anything out you know of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		either way yeah  you have your career and your home life and that'd be a nice way to especially if you have young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum yes oh it is
 		it is well both of ours is school age but we don't want to miss any of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTA's</ENAMEX> and you know all of that so so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh no i think yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s just in day care but even that they have extracurricular activities and the older they get the more that you're involved in that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yes i think it's great i really and i look for more of that in the next generation
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i do too especially as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> get up in management and and can be in on those decision making you know when that subject comes up they can say yes that would be wonderful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes oh i do too yes
 	
 	
 		plus i bet it cuts cuts down on your absenteeism because you've got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> off that you can do everything so you don't have to you know unless you're just really sick or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s sick
 	
 	
 		but yeah yeah because most time now you know it's just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> or just forget it yeah
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh yeah i have to plan way in advance because or what i've done is found like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> with extended <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> that's been real helpful too like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> stays open till <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine in the evening</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so that's real helpful so you don't  you know have to do it  during office <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> run out on your <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch hour</TIMEX> i don't know how many times i've done that to do something <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> or any uh kind of errand
 	
 	
 		to do yeah
 		um-hum yeah i think we've really come a long ways in that because yes
 	
 	
 		so
 		uh-huh i guess i take it for granted kind of because i just it's always been that way but i know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah but i can remember remember back growing up my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> i mean it was she always worked but it wasn't that easy for her to just take off
 	
 	
 		oh no i can remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> getting in trouble if you know one of us was sick and i know she probably didn't make hardly anything you know compared to the work that she did
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		where oh yeah yes
 	
 	
 		i think there's still some discrimination there where as you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> work in the same job i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> get paid more but i think that's improving it's such a slow process it's frustrating but
 	
 	
 		oh i do too
 		yes yes yes
 	
 	
 		i mean you can see that it's wrong and you just wanna make it right but at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> are moving forward
 	
 	
 		um-hum they really are
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it's getting better not worse
 		well i should probably get back to my job
 	
 	
 		i know i know the feeling well it was okay and i sure will and bye-bye
 	
 	
 		call again
 		okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	