
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 29, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial questions the wisdom of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anti-terrorist</ENAMEX> missile strikes. While the strikes were ethically justified,
they may spur further terrorism in revenge. Seeking justice in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> would
have been more prudent, if more difficult. ... A story trumpets the
latest advance in toilets. A renowned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> toilet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> has invented
a commode that analyzes your urine's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood sugar</ENAMEX>--a boon to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diabetics</ENAMEX>. Next
step: urine sampling toilets that check your liver's health and test for
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 14 & 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 29, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A story
says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are wrong to fear that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> resignation will lead to
disastrous midterm election results. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> lost many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">seats</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s
resignation because of a struggling economy, not because of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>. It's too
late for strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to emerge <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter turnout</ENAMEX> won't be
depressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s departure. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should go. ... The
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB"</ENAMEX> column scolds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> for claiming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is no
longer effective: "Since when do we kick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> because they
are no longer effective?... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX> was a laughingstock in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>, but he stayed in office. ... Perhaps no <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX> was lamer than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX>, yet resignation was never a serious issue."

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 27, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
piece wonders why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> buy bottled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> tap <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is safe, and
any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chlorine</ENAMEX> taste evaporates if the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is left to settle for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX>.
Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bottlers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Pellegrino</ENAMEX>), who capture minerals
and rich flavor, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bottlers</ENAMEX> seek sterility and tastelessness. ...
A story tsk-tsks the West for accepting the election victory of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hun</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> A former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hun Sen</ENAMEX> used threats and bribes to ensure
his victory, but international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitors</ENAMEX> concluded that a rigged election was
better than no election at all.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 27, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A
fascinating story explains the life cycle and social customs of honeybees.
Hives feature the mathematical genius of honeycombs and precise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">labor</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> guard the hive entrance, others collect nectar, others dry
nectar by beating their wings, others groom the queen, others manufacture an
antiseptic salve that coats the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">hive</ENAMEX>, etc. ... From the "Index":
"Average number of public school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> expelled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each school day last year</TIMEX>
for gun possession: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX>."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Premiere</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 27, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A
dispatch from the porn industry's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> awards ceremony entertainingly and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comically</ENAMEX> explains the modern porn ethos: bravado, shamelessness, and (believe
it or not) increasing degradation of and violence toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. The
piece is bylined with pseudonyms but bears the unmistakable mark of comic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">novelist David Foster Wallace</ENAMEX>: excessive footnotes, excessive and
nontraditional abbreviations, excessive and occasionally cloying
self-consciousness, gratuitous use of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> phrases, and employment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 cent</NUMEX>
words such as "cathedra," "synecdoche," and "clerestories."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 25, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crisis</ENAMEX>" is the
tag on both covers, lumping together <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> revelations and
missile strikes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's immense package wins on star power: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> describes his counseling session with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX> (they
will stand by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> contributes a long
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essay</ENAMEX> urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> not to resign but to "repair the breach" between
himself and the public. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> run articles on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> (she was in the
dark about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">veep</ENAMEX>'s
campaign finance scandal will haunt him, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
character flaws make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> look great). The similar missile strike stories
include maps of the attack sites and diagrams of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tomahawk</ENAMEX> missile but
little news.

            The news overshadows <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News ' celebrated college rankings, which are relegated to the back of the
issue. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> cops out of picking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">America's best university</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> tie for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amherst</ENAMEX> is the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> runs thumbnail sketches of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next summer</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Big Summer Movies</ENAMEX>. Get
ready for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers II</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarzan</ENAMEX> and, of course, the new
Star Wars .

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 7 and 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 25, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
package <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assesses</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s legacy. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>, setting
the general tone, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has failed to accomplish anything lasting or to
advance a coherent agenda. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Nero</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>,"
compare him to ineffectual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover Cleveland</ENAMEX>,
and bemoan his inability to carry through promises about health care, race,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, and job training.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 25, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
Standard calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s resignation or impeachment. If he's not
ousted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will remain an "unquestioned and unrepentant villain." A
related article calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to resign (or perhaps we
could impeach them, too?). They should be ashamed of having lied for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who lied to them. Another piece claims the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> establishment
has finally turned against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and so the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> must necessarily follow.
Also, the Standard prints the draft of the mea culpa speech that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Begala</ENAMEX> wrote and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> ignored. The draft contains clear
and forthright apologies and no mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31, 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 21, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A special
issue, published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days early</TIMEX>, is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> article blitzkrieg of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
coverage. The lead story recounts the tense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> countdown to testimony,
speculates on how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> felt during the ordeal (betrayed, then stalwart), and
dissects the legal equivocations in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Speech</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's exclusive: While
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s testimony "generally matched" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s, he flatly refused to answer
explicit questions about sex before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> and "did not acknowledge
engaging in [oral sex] with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>." ... Another story says that
turning over the infamous blue dress to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> was never part of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s immunity package. By design, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> never had the dress
tested to determine its "smoking gun" potential. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> got immunity, her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> tossed the dress to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> as a freebie anyway. ... Another article
says that scandal-weary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will seek a "straight-shooting" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. But is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> the one for the job? Can he weather the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal?
He's jammed between a rock (disloyalty) and a hard place (loyalty). And don't
forget all his dubious fund-raising phone calls--they may still lead to an
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> investigation.

            More Flytrap
...

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
