
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Dec. 6</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
editorial argues that "road pricing" will solve the world's traffic problems by
making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> pay for their privilege. Charging varying amounts for driving at
peak and off-peak times will cut down on congestion and pollution. Revenues
could fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> transportation. A profile salutes pathological downsizer
"Chainsaw" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Dunlap</ENAMEX> for having the guts to fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in order to turn
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> around. The profile also asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap's</ENAMEX> slash-and-burn
technique would be ineffective for all but the sickest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. (For

                  Slate
               's take on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX>, see "The Chainsaw
Capitalist.") <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks ago</TIMEX> there was a media flurry about a computer
that composed classical music. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , a computer that
can improvise jazz. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> enters parameters of style and tempo. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">computer</ENAMEX>'s getting better: Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> can no longer distinguish it from a
live <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5</TIMEX>)
            

            Following
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's lead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> puts <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amistad</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s new
film about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> revolt, on the cover. Among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> related stories: a rave
review for the film and an appreciation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Quincy Adams</ENAMEX>, a major
Amistad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and "one of the only genuine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> ever to
occupy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>." An article says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> military is too weak to
invade other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> (good news), but also too weak to prevent its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>
from selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> (bad news). Also, a report from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mass</ENAMEX>-marriage ceremony: Most of the newlyweds will go back to their own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hometowns</ENAMEX> after the wedding. They may or may not see their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> in the
future.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 4</TIMEX>)
            

            Yet
another "special issue"--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>. The subject of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-odd
stories: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> religion. A story follows a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> living in
suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> ridiculed her head scarf, so she took it off.
Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> doesn't like her punk nose ring, but she leaves it in. An article
describes a new medical study about prayer: When devout "healers" prayed for
the health of arthritic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>--without the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' knowledge--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' health improved. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> are dubious. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unitarian</ENAMEX> recounts her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">epiphany</ENAMEX>: A voice in the woods told her to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>. Also, kudos for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama Freethought Association</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> of atheists in the heart of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bible Belt</ENAMEX>. They meet on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> and lampoon <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>: "Right about now,"
says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> are sitting in church, waving a book that makes no
sense and that most of them haven't even read."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 2</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mags</ENAMEX> discover the same
trend: the exodus to exurbia. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story on small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> follows several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> who
gave up fast-track lives to settle down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>. Why the migration?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecommuting</ENAMEX> and the great job market make mobility easier than ever. A
shorter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> story labels these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dropouts</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Young Unhappy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professionals</ENAMEX>" (unhappy, that is, till they drop out).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover
package, pegged to the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s film <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amistad</ENAMEX> ,
assesses the legacy of slavery. Among the conclusions: A national apology for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slavery</ENAMEX> would be hollow and facile, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> should erect a slavery memorial
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mall</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> interviews <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hope Franklin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the
presidential advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> on race. (He's against an apology, and for
affirmative action. See "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sound of One Hand Talking</ENAMEX>" for 
                  Slate
               's take on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>.) An accompanying review raves about Amistad
(though the magazine inexplicably calls it "controversial").

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> breaks the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Ford Jr.</ENAMEX> will become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>, who has been running the family-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit Lions</ENAMEX> for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two years</TIMEX>, will be the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> to head the automaker in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> also reports on the making of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> . The film cost
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX>, and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> are terrified. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Cameron</ENAMEX>
contributes a short defense of his movie, but an accompanying review pans it:
great special effects, hackneyed story.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 2</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News kicks off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas shopping season</TIMEX> with a cover
story on junk mail. Lots of insider info about how junk mailers reel you
in: real stamps, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pseudo-official</ENAMEX> envelopes, and "P.S." messages. Some high-end
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> make more money by selling their mailing lists than by selling their
products. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Requisite</ENAMEX> statistic: On average, each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> receives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">553</NUMEX> pieces
of junk mail a year.) A story praises the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity Foundation</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that investigates fraud by televangelists and publishes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Door</ENAMEX> . The annual
guide to personal finance advises <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to stop worrying about
inflation: It's gone.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 2</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> chronicles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s quest to buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Dodgers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>, who has decided that sports will be his international TV anchor, is
trying to monopolize broadcast rights for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California</ENAMEX> sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> rival <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX> may try to block approval of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$311-million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> bid. A profile of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> takes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">usual Gore</ENAMEX> psychoanalysis a step further. It agrees that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s outer
robotic-ness masks a warm jocularity, but argues that the warm jocularity
itself masks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s fundamental emotional coolness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> admits that his "no
controlling legal authority" press conference was a mistake. A "Comment" by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have switched places.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> used to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of "noble aspirations" and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> used to
be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of "just causes." Now <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> tout bland aspirations (like
racial healing) while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> fervently champion causes like tax reform and
school vouchers.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 2</TIMEX>)
            

            A cover
story makes the case for national education reform. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Decentralization</ENAMEX>, the usual
conservative solution, isn't helping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. National policies could increase
the number of charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, cripple local education <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracies</ENAMEX>, and limit
the power of evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>. A piece calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s race commission the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disgrace Commission</ENAMEX>." It's a group of affirmative-action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> appointed
to rubber-stamp <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> policies, the article says. The most interesting
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is the letters page, where gay-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>
exchange fire with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s recent piece attacking
them.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
