
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Feb. 21</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
editorial warns of imminent violent revolution in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> hopes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s ouster and urges the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> to withhold support if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX> carries through with
his own self-serving economic plan. ... An article casts doubt on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Branson</ENAMEX>'s foray into the railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Branson</ENAMEX>
hopes to exploit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s rail privatization with the strength of his Virgin
brand. So far, his handful of rail routes are losing money, and he hasn't made
the trains run on time (literally). ... A study explains why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>
can't grow back missing body parts: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regeneration</ENAMEX> (in amphibians) requires
tumorlike growth. We traded in this ability for a complex immune system that
can fight tumors.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 20</TIMEX>)
            

            A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-story cover package gauges the impact of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> crisis. An article
warns <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> not to gloat over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s economic woes: We need a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
to keep the world economy stable. An essay argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> should save
ailing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> from short-term disaster but not dictate long-term economic
policy, as it has in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. And a story rejects the conventional wisdom that
prosperity leads to democratization. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Asia</ENAMEX>, democratization will have to
come from the newly poor middle class. ... The editorial says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> should not be forced to testify against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, as this
would <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) destroy what little privacy the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> family has left; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) reduce
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>' effectiveness as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> seeks to evade their gaze; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
necessitate a tightknit, loyal presidential entourage, like that of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb. 19</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
piece rates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> as he prepares his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pluses: 1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, his boring personal life is his best asset. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) He's
made loads of influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Harkin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-percent behind him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s minuses: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) He's still
wooden. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Except for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, no sitting veep has won since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1836</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-percent behind him. ... An article longs for the bygone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of rock
"concept" albums. What happened? CD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>: They let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> program the track
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequence</ENAMEX>, wrecking album continuity.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb. 19</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> derides the lack of "authentic" pop-music acts. To succeed, rock bands
now either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) fake an earnest devotion to kitschy music, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) earnestly devote
themselves to inauthentic, radio-friendly music. ... The cover story
repeats the usual criticisms of managed care: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> are rewarded for choosing
the cheapest treatment over the best <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and denying membership to unhealthy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Solution: Remove the profit motive from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>. ... From the
"Index": "Percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> under the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> who own a pair of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dockers Khakis: 72</ENAMEX>."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 17</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , which took
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> vacation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, returns with a cover story about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> and her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Lewis</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> shared secrets
and a passion for powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> excerpts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s e-mails to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> wonders why "the big creep" didn't call on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX>.
After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> consecutive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> covers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> cuts its scandal coverage
drastically, limiting itself to a short piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>; an update on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> trial; and a sidebar on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> bird flu warns that a worldwide
epidemic is still possible. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> note that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1918</TIMEX> flu, which killed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 20 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, also came from birds and started slowly before
spreading around the globe. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> publishes a comprehensive
map of how we'd attack <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. (The first wave will be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cruise-</ENAMEX>missile strikes on radar and communications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>. Then we'll send the
heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX>.) Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> (see below), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> thinks air
strikes can't kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titanic</ENAMEX> phenomenon: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo di</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caprio</ENAMEX> and the strong, liberated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> like the action and the idea of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX> going down with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 17</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story points out: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Killing Saddam</ENAMEX> would require a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>- to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-month</TIMEX> troop buildup and massive ground invasion. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) We tried to kill him
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'91</TIMEX> and couldn't. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Assassination is illegal under an executive order.
... An article explains where to find privacy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peepholes</ENAMEX> look in on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> can know when meetings are ending,
but the peeper can't view the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s adjacent study has no
peephole, and a secret tunnel underneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> could be used for a
rendezvous. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> decides the only real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> story is
how the scandal affects Wall Street. Answer: It doesn't, since
economic policy won't change even with an impeachment. The millennium bug, on
the other hand, might cause a big crash.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 23 & March 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 17</TIMEX>)
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> honors <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> with a special issue. The tone: triumphalism.
A piece celebrates the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> economy, whose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> hot industries, high-tech
and entertainment, show no signs of cooling off. The secret to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>'s success? Lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> and very flexible, "network-based"
economies. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> examines <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interval Research Corp.</ENAMEX>, the secret
high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tank</ENAMEX> funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Allen</ENAMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have made computers
that imitate touch and sense emotion in human voices. (For

                  Slate
               's take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Interval</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>' "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millionerds</ENAMEX>.")
... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> describes her ridiculous life as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B-movie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> in the
'70s. Among her "starring" roles: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> version of Jaws
and an alien disguised as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avon Lady</ENAMEX>. She also had a date with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cary Grant</ENAMEX>,
stripped for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> , and refused <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX>.
... A profile of movie/music/gay-rights titan <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Geffen</ENAMEX> calls him the
"most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>," but notes that he's too cool and distant to
be very happy. ... The issue manages to tear itself away from the lives
of the rich and famous only once: An article chronicles the miserable lives of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s "ghosts," the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">illegals</ENAMEX> who live in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shacks</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Backbreaking</ENAMEX> labor and evading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border Patrol</ENAMEX> are their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main
activities. The ravine where they live is named, appropriately, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olvidados</ENAMEX>"--"the forgotten ones."

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 17</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story slams <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>. Once a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> with
incestuously tight ties to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> is now in the
administration and stoking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s claims of a "right-wing conspiracy."
... An essay contrasts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Hamilton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamilton</ENAMEX>
admitted to adultery, proving his essential honesty, and maintained his
political popularity; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, however, is a baldfaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are the new locker-room braggarts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> scandal has
brought out sexually explicit crassness in female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katie Roiphe</ENAMEX>, Erica
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jong</ENAMEX>) that puts even the lewdest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to shame. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> can still get away with
it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> can't.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
