
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 4</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial warns big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">telecom companies</ENAMEX> that their
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> are numbered. Supposed advantages at home (a trusted brand, political
influence) will be useless in the booming international market. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Risk-averse,</ENAMEX>
slow-moving <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaurs</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Telecom</ENAMEX>) will be crushed by quicker,
hungrier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> with newer technology (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WorldCom, Qwest</ENAMEX>). ... An
editorial urges the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to take a more
commanding role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has tried American
patience with its reluctance to accede to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> redeployment agreement.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> must now use its clout to arbitrate a solution once and for
all. ... A story says the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">moonshine</ENAMEX> industry is still huge in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern United States</ENAMEX>, but it has left behind its rustic past. Modern
moonshiners cost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in lost taxes, often carry heavy
arms, and are moving into the drug trade.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 3</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story defends pork-barrel spending. Pork represents a tiny portion of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">federal</ENAMEX> budget, and it greases the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> of politics. Conceding tiny bits of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> (job programs for border <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>) to pass huge legislation (NAFTA) is a
wise trade-off. ... An article slams <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> proposal. Widely hailed as "courageous," the plan is just a
politically motivated concession to privatization <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hawks</ENAMEX>. (For more on the plan,
see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newt Gingrich Save Social Security</ENAMEX>?" in 
                  Slate
               .) ...
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB</ENAMEX>" claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s scandal woes stem from his triangulating politics.
When a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> co-opts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX>'s ideas, staunching policy debate, the
opposition resorts to personal attacks (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>).

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 2</TIMEX>)
            

            Another
special issue (they win--we've run out of jokes about this). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> articles
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chronicle</ENAMEX>--exhaustively--"the joy and guilt of modern motherhood." High
banality quotient: A piece follows a stay-at-home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> who left a law practice
to rear <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. She wouldn't change a thing about her rewarding life.
Another follows a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who works full time and lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and nanny care for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. She wouldn't change a thing about her rewarding life, either. Also,
photo essays cover the boom in multiple births (triplets, quads, etc.--many
cute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>) and the new maternity fashions.

            

               
                  Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 2</TIMEX>)
            

            The
celebrity-obsessed magazine surpasses itself in the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX> issue.
Glam-filled recapping of the ceremony and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, plus grades for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfits</ENAMEX>, all with a delightfully high level of bitchiness.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EW</ENAMEX> 's fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> loves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Hunt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> dress but thinks she's too
waify: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Rivers</ENAMEX> squawks, "She weighs less than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Winslet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>."
Throughout, much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> (e.g., jilted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie Driver</ENAMEX> glared at ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beau Matt Damon</ENAMEX>
when he won his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriting</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> and steered clear of the it-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> at the
parties).

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newsweeklies</ENAMEX> disagree on
the causes on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jonesboro</ENAMEX> killings. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story blames the murders on everything from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mortal Kombat</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Park</ENAMEX> to absentee parenting. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover focuses
more on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> culture but prefers to pronounce this a "senseless
tragedy." Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> print schematics of the crime scene-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time 's</ENAMEX> is
more realistic and chilling.

            On the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX>'s assassination, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> excerpts
a new book that claims to prove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Earl Ray</ENAMEX> was indeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s killer and
that he acted alone. The piece systematically rejects all the popular
conspiracy theories (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, white supremacists, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raul</ENAMEX>," etc.). ...

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> discovers the latest trend among <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> millionerds:
etiquette training. For <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> a lesson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geeks</ENAMEX> learn how to use the right fork
and make small talk. ("But enough about me. How much are you worth?")

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> investigates <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> exports of electric shock devices.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Manufacturers</ENAMEX> of stun <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, sold domestically to police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, have
shipped shock batons and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tasers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, where they are allegedly used to torture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>. ... A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> article says <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>, the soon to be released male
anti-impotence <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>, may also be used for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. The pill would increase blood
flow to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s genitals, improving sensation and lubrication. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Administration</ENAMEX> has not yet approved its use for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31</TIMEX>)
            

            Apropos
of nothing (again), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> goes with a military cover: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Submarine</ENAMEX>!" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three weeks ago</TIMEX>, it published an equally untimely
cover on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX>.) Inside: a description
of life aboard a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sub</ENAMEX> and an examination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subs</ENAMEX>' changing roles (less
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX>, more espionage). The pullout cross section of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sub</ENAMEX> is fascinating.
... A story reports on the focus-grouping of classical music. Classical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stations</ENAMEX> now use market research to determine playlists. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorry</ENAMEX>, solo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">violinists</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX> find you "intrusive.")

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31</TIMEX>)
            

            A piece
likens the recent surge in multiple personality disorder to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> hysteria. Real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPD</ENAMEX> is incredibly rare, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">therapists</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> and
early '90s "diagnosed" it in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>: They hypnotized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> by
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX>, persuaded them that they had been sexually abused by family
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, and then induced them to discover other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX>. Lawsuits by
damaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> limits on therapist payments have ended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPD</ENAMEX> craze.
... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickman Ewing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX>, is profiled: A born-again
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and a moralist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ewing</ENAMEX> is engaged in a vendetta against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>.
Of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> deposition, he says, "She was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>--on all topics."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ewing</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, seems to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zealot</ENAMEX> in the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.
... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Film</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX> writes a long harangue against the modern
movie industry. Chief complaints: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Studios</ENAMEX> prefer cheap irony to real emotion,
and young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moviegoers</ENAMEX> don't care about seeing good movies--they prefer
mass-market schlock to complex films such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A. Confidential</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31</TIMEX>)
            

            In the
cover story, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabomber</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gelernter</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kaczynski</ENAMEX> should
have been executed. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaczynski</ENAMEX> will be able to use his prison cell as a
bully pulpit, writing more screeds and receiving press attention. Kaczynski
"traded up; he used to live in an unimproved shack in the wilderness."
... An essay calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to address <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> immediately.
The new plan from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, is a good starting
point because it incorporates some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> ideas on privatization.
... An article claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> was right to sack his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>, since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> was anti-market and anti-reform. With a
relatively calm and stable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> picked the right time to shake
things up.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
