
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  The
Edge
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet</ENAMEX>'s
trademark dialogue helps overcome the banal premise of his screenplay: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billionaire</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthony Hopkins</ENAMEX>) and a fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alec Baldwin</ENAMEX>) who
hate each other are stranded in the wilderness with a mean bear. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bear</ENAMEX>'s
performance is deemed a "milestone in ursine acting" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). The beauties of nature are also said to come to the film's
assistance. Some complain about the swaggering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mametian</ENAMEX> machismo: He "has done
little more than tone up a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>'s Journal fantasy" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official site.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Peacemaker</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks SKG</ENAMEX>). Disappointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> rate the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg-Katzenberg-Geffen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>'s debut just "a notch better than the
average predictable action thriller" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). Stars
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Clooney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX> are said to be perfectly likable but utterly
humorless, and the nuclear-terrorism story line is called suspenseful but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trite</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks</ENAMEX> had a chance to do something different, instead they played
it safe" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Clips</ENAMEX> are available here.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  Big
Trouble: A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder in a Small Western Town Sets Off a Struggle for the Soul of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Anthony Lukas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). Acclaim for the
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s historical epic, completed just before his
suicide in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>. Reviewers praise the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lukas</ENAMEX> made use of a historical
incident--the assassination of an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1905</TIMEX>, allegedly by radical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unionists</ENAMEX>--to examine the violent side of class warfare. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukas</ENAMEX>' eclectic cast
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Darrow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.H. Harriman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX>) rivals that of
"some unwritten <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.L. Doctorow</ENAMEX> novel" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Remnick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ).
"This book is to 'true crime' stories what <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX> is to most war
novels" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Wills</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> ). The major
complaint: too many digressions, inflating the book to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800-plus</NUMEX> pages. (See
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Wilentz</ENAMEX>'s review in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  Timequake
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Vonnegut</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Putnam</ENAMEX>). Muted objections to what
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slaughterhouse</ENAMEX> Five <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> has called his "last" work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call
the book--fragments from an uncompleted sci-fi novel about a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> "timequake"
that forces <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to relive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>--"random" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Bradbury</ENAMEX>, the London
Times ) and "misbegotten" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.S. Klapp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vonnegut</ENAMEX>'s very effort evokes a note of elegy. "[S]ince it comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vonnegut</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s favorite grumpy old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, you've got to love him" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Disch</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> Out of Mind
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>), and 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Babylon</ENAMEX>
               , by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stones</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virgin</ENAMEX>). The simultaneous release of
albums from '60s rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> occasions studies in contrast. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX>'s bluesy album
wins accolades for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">introspective</ENAMEX> lyrics about mortality and is judged his best
work in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, "attesting to the creative renaissance of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> still bent
on defying expectations and spurning trends" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edna Gundersen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stones</ENAMEX>' new songs are called "uninspired retreads"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Cromelin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ), and their much-hyped world
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tour</ENAMEX>--which uses giant nude inflatable dolls as set pieces--is pronounced
"tasteless" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> ). (See the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stones</ENAMEX>' tour site.)

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER : "Ambush</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 25</TIMEX>). Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> describe the top-rated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drama</ENAMEX>'s live broadcast as a welcome throwback to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1950s</NUMEX> television. "A walk on a
high wire ... thrilling to see it all come off so well," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX>. But many also say the conceit of the episode--that a
film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> is documenting life in an emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>--was a cheap ploy to cover
up gaffes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caryn James</ENAMEX> says it undermined the whole
episode, making "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ambush"</ENAMEX> "something the show has never been before and isn't
likely to be again: terminally dull."

            

               Art
            

            

               "Sensations: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young British Artists</ENAMEX> From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saatchi Collection</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy of Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>). Outrage greets the stodgy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s exhibition of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brash</ENAMEX>, hipster "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Britpack</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> express outrage that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">academy</ENAMEX> stamped its approval on works like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus Harvey</ENAMEX>'s painting of a
spread-legged naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and his portrait of a notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child murderer</ENAMEX>, done
in a mosaic of simulated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s handprints. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Academy of Porn</ENAMEX>,"
sneers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Mail</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> dismiss the controversy as old
hat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britpack</ENAMEX> "represent the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX>," says the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Levy</ENAMEX>.

            

               Updates
            

            In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinesh D'Souza</ENAMEX> rejects the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX>' take on race as baselessly optimistic. "If there is a
case for feeling good about the prospects of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African Americans</ENAMEX>, the case is not
effectively made here." ... Bucking the consensus on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Ice</ENAMEX>
Storm, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kauffmann</ENAMEX> excoriates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ang</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>]verything in his directing, absolutely everything, is banal."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- The
Royals , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kitty Kelley</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Underworld</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don DeLillo</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
Apes , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Will Self</ENAMEX>;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rauschenberg: A Retrospective"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Guggenheim Museums and Ace Gallery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>);

            
               Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thousand</ENAMEX>
Acres ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ice</ENAMEX>
Storm ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Veronica's Closet</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
Confidential ;

            
               Movie -- In &
Out ;

            

               Television -- Nothing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacred</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn South</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Hayes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candle</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wind 1997</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elton John</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Jewish Heritage</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Living Memorial</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:</TIMEX>

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story of Painting</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- Ally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McBeal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>);

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- She's So</ENAMEX>
Lovely ;

            

               Movie -- <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The Farewell
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Symphony</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund White</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Nation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indivisible</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abigail Thernstrom</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">27:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G.I.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Mimic</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- Already
Dead: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gothic</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denis Johnson</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Best</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Winslow Taylor</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Enigma of Efficiency</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kanigel</ENAMEX>;

            
               Music -- The
Dance , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleetwood Mac</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good News</ENAMEX> (UPN).

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
