
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Contact
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). A movie made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Zemeckis</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forrest Gump</ENAMEX> ) from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Sagan</ENAMEX> novel about the search for
extraterrestrial life is declared pretentious. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s mail
seems penetrating in comparison," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kempley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reviewers deem</ENAMEX> most vapid the heavy-handed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> about the meaning
of life between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX>'s obsessed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew McConaughey</ENAMEX>'s New
Agey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>, as always, is "fiercely intelligent" but her character is
"grindingly sincere" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX>: "[She] does not need a long trip into space. She needs to get (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
a square meal inside her, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) some rest, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) laid." (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kerr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contact</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               
                  Shall <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Dance</ENAMEX>?
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> foresee art-house success for
this film about a buttoned-down <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> whose midlife crisis drives
him to take dance lessons. Reviews praise the movie's depiction of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">repressed Japanese</ENAMEX> middle class and its "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ginger sweetness"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
Maslin, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). But some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> complain it's too languid
and drawn out. "Even when the catharsis we yearn for arrives, it's tinged with
restraint," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Glieberman</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerr</ENAMEX> reviews the
movie for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lawyerland: What Lawyers Talk About When They Talk About the Law</ENAMEX>
               ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Joseph</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar, Straus & Giroux</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Johns</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Joseph</ENAMEX>'s anthology of conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> is deemed humorous but "pointless" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Long</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> is "good at catching the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Lehman-Haupt</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> "are
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet</ENAMEX>'s or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Bogosian</ENAMEX>'s ranters" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Lopate</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> ). But beneath the froth the book offers little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insight</ENAMEX> into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> work, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long</ENAMEX> says; it's really about "what colorful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> talk
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> when they're trying to be colorful."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Straight Man</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Russo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> applaud
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russo</ENAMEX>'s sendup of life at a small western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>, in which an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> loses his job, becomes unhinged, commandeers a local TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX>, and threatens to murder a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>, Straight
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> , like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russo</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> novel Nobody's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fool</ENAMEX> , comically but
sympathetically plumbs "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working class</ENAMEX> in the age of downsizing"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Cryer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ). Others just like its humor. The book, raves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haven</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , has "pitch-perfect dialogue,
persuasive characterization and a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">progression</ENAMEX> of scenes ... crackling with
an impudent screwball energy reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard Hawks</ENAMEX>'s movies." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> plugs the book here.)

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  Roar
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mondays</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. EDT/PDT</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s knockoff of the
popular syndicated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior adventure</ENAMEX> show <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xena</ENAMEX> is
said to lack the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> irony of the original. The most "shamefully derivative
hour in recent network history," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> .
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unintentionally laughable</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times ' Caryn James</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carson</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> suggests the only reason to watch is
"because you're dying to know how the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> got in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>." Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
predict that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roar</ENAMEX> , like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xena</ENAMEX> , will be a cult hit.

            

               Theater
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Amy's View</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
Hare, criticized in the past for his "preachy politics," is said to have
finally found "his way beyond polemic" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lahr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hare</ENAMEX>'s new play about a self-centered film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> is hailed as a "coup de théâtre " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Wolf</ENAMEX>,
Variety ), both for its social critique (of the amorality of the news
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>) and for its sensitivity "about such personal matters as loss, grief and
stoical survival" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benedict Nightingale</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hare</ENAMEX>'s
enthusiasts declare it time for canonization.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> in
Black ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Women With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ford</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Scripture: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Making the Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Maier</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX> Without
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face: The Autobiography of Communism's Greatest Spymaster</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Markus Wolf</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne McElvoy</ENAMEX>;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Haring</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum of American Art</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oz</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            

               Music --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilith Fair</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Batman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Robin</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Face/Off</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promesse</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Musical</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ragtime</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puttermesser Papers</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Ozick</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- How Proust
Can <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Change Your Life: Not a Novel</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alain de Botton</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Bright Angel Time</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha McPhee</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Speed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- My Best</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friend's Wedding</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe Theatre</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kidnapping</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel García Márquez</ENAMEX>, translated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grossman</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diving</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Butterfly</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Dominique Bauby</ENAMEX>, translated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Leggatt</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The God of
Small Things , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arundhati Roy</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perfect</ENAMEX>
Storm , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sebastian Junger</ENAMEX>;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice Biennale</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Con</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulee</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gold</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pillow</ENAMEX>
Book ;

            
               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wu</ENAMEX>-Tang
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Forever , Wu-Tang Clan</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Without a
Doubt , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Clark</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Carpenter</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Firewall</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Iran-Contra Conspiracy and Cover-Up</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence E. Walsh</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Promiscuities: The Secret Struggle for Womanhood</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Gross Indecency: The Three Trials of Oscar Wilde</ENAMEX> .

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
