
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 19</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 19, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            For the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> straight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, the cover editorial urges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to resign. He
may survive impeachment proceedings, but he will be so distracted by the fight
as to be unable to lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The honorable thing to do is hand the
reins to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. An accompanying essay predicts that this scandal will
cause several changes in the future, among them, a reduction in the power of
the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> and more restraint on the part of the press. (See
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">International Papers</ENAMEX>" for what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> has to say on independent
counsels.) ... A story says that eating breakfast helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do well in
school. A study in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who ate a free
school breakfast <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each morning</TIMEX> got higher grades and were better behaved than
their nonbreakfast-eating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Sept. 18, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A special
issue on television. The lead essay claims that television has always been the
same--game shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> shows, sitcoms, dramas--and always will be. The
difference will be specialization: gay game shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-American</ENAMEX> sitcoms, etc.
... A story says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> got rooked when it renewed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.R.</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13</NUMEX>
million an episode. Left hitless when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> ended and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> stole
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> was forced to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$286 million</NUMEX> a year for the medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drama</ENAMEX>, "more than twice" what it "had totaled in profits <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX>."
... A hilarious section lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> describe the TV shows they
would most want to produce. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Shandling</ENAMEX> offers <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill and Bill</ENAMEX> , a
"<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half-hour</TIMEX> semi-erotic situation comedy" in which the romantic leads are a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> and his talking pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conan O'Brien</ENAMEX> suggests Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Eye</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Camden</ENAMEX> is the elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the free
world. He's also a crime buff, and whenever his official duties take him within
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 feet</NUMEX> of a jewel theft, murder or art forgery, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Camden</ENAMEX> can't help turning
amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sleuth</ENAMEX>." ... Also, various celebs pen odes to their favorite TV
shows--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Simpsons</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ford</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Rogers</ENAMEX>'
Neighborhood , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deepak Chopra</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">The X-Files</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               
                  New 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Sept. 18, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
cover articles belittle the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on legal grounds, the other on
literary grounds. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> story argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has found no grounds for
impeachment, only "technical violations of criminal law that have no obvious
connection to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s official duties, which was precisely the vision
[of impeachment] that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Framers</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">of the Constitution</ENAMEX>] rejected." The piece
refutes all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> supposedly impeachable offenses. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> essay
wittily assesses the literary value of the report, comparing it with classic
novels of adultery such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madame Bovary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Karenina</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
offers unnecessarily colorful detail: "Instead of prosecuting a case, his
narrative enacts a drama, and makes sympathetically banal what might have been
merely illegal."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Sept. 17, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF</ENAMEX>
excerpts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new books about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>. Passages from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s new
autobiography emphasize his profound respect for the game of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX>, and the star <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> who came before him. Excerpts from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Halberstam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Making of a Legend</ENAMEX> chronicle <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s
rise from a talented but unknown high schooler to the best college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Central theme: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s love and respect for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Smith</ENAMEX>, the
legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> who shaped him at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of North Carolina</ENAMEX>. ...
An essay mocks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay McInerney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bret Easton Ellis</ENAMEX> for their obsession
with fashion models (both are releasing new books about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>). A male
fascination with female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> indicates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) adolescence or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) homosexuality.
The article notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Easton Ellis</ENAMEX> is gay and makes veiled remarks about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McInerney</ENAMEX>'s sexuality. ... Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF</ENAMEX> 's list of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New</ENAMEX>
Establishment: The Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leaders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Age</ENAMEX>" include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sumner Redstone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Sept. 17, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            Well
timed for the bear market, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> publishes a doom and gloom issue. The
cover essay compares our present economy to the bubble of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>. It
predicts a brutal worldwide depression, leading to totalitarianism and world
war. History will view us as it views <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz Agers: superficial</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greedy</ENAMEX>, and
oblivious.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
21
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 15, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> all
around. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> mags excerpt the report at length (not edited for bawdy
language, but with parental warnings). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's coverage seems most pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]here is reason to recoil at
some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s tactics; he included far more sexual detail than was necessary
to prove his point, and at times ignored or discounted evidence that
contradicts his case." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> runs an essay from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>
claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will never resign and will fight to the finish, but
"won't be revered as our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>." Both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> advise on how to explain the seamy details to your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> (be honest yet elliptical; whatever you do, don't talk about the cigar).
Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> analyze the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> on impeachment, focusing on the ambiguous phrase "high crimes and
misdemeanors." They conclude this means whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> wants it to mean.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 15, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            An essay
partially blames all-news TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. Channels such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> have an incentive to create must-see news stories that drive up ratings.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> keep up with "event" stories (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>) or risk becoming social
outcasts, unable to talk about what everyone is talking about. ... A
story argues that pain is all in the mind and that we should treat, not
dismiss, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with unexplained chronic ailments. There needn't be a
physical injury for the brain to send pain signals, and that pain is as real to
the sufferer as it would be if she'd hit her thumb with a hammer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> are
seeking superstrong, nonaddictive painkillers and may have found them in
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> extracted from certain snails and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">frogs</ENAMEX>. (Full disclosure: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> is by 
                  Slate
                medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atul Gawande</ENAMEX>.) ... A
special fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> includes a profile of the late <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British-American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles James</ENAMEX>, a look at high fashion in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> (once denim, now
foreign couture--that is, until the ruble crashed), and a review of a new Coco
Chanel biography.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 15, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
Standard drools over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report and calls for a lightning
impeachment process. The editorial argues that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> is asking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
to judge acceptable a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> revealed to the world as a lout and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> must refuse the request and remove him." How excited is the
Standard ? An article predicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>. ... A funny piece reports from an academic conference on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pornography</ENAMEX>. Tweedy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> and porn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">starlets</ENAMEX> mingle at presentations such
as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cum Shots: History</ENAMEX>, Theory, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research</ENAMEX>." (Isn't this also a chapter
heading in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report?)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 28</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 15, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> remains above the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> fray, barely acknowledging <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">goings-on</ENAMEX>. Instead, the cover
piece is a long essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arundhati Roy</ENAMEX> mourning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s
acquisition of the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>. She complains that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> has it backward: The
country resists <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westernization</ENAMEX> in the cultural realm (literature, fashion,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>) but joins the West in nuclear proliferation.

            More Flytrap
...

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
