
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Art
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giambattista Tiepolo</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1696-1770</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">revisionism</ENAMEX> achieves critical mass. With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> paintings and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> etchings at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
different shows at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> and drawings by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pierpont Morgan Library</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX> town," says Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Solomon</ENAMEX>. "These shows make it clear that the once
accepted view of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX> was wrong," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>. (The conventional wisdom on the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>: He was said to be "a decadent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> of
aristocratic taste"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX>; "an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of pomposity, cynicism, and costume
drama"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Haskell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> .) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> sees new
levels of wit in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>'s paintings: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he distanced, self-aware theatrics of
his style--his parade of visual language as a source of delight--make him look
modern." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX> sees precocious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">postmodernism</ENAMEX>: "[H]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ow</ENAMEX> do you achieve greatness
in an age when everything has already been done? The answer: You recycle." But
Haskell damns all efforts to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> for our time: "[We] are
most reluctant to admit that the finest art can flourish in harmony with the
ruling classes and without the tensions that beset us now, so that, where
necessary, we try to detect such tensions in the art of the past." (Check out
the Web site of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retrospective</ENAMEX> held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. It has reproductions and
commentary.)

            

               Event
            

            

               Halftime at <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> XXXI (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox TV</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Avenue</ENAMEX> typically debuts
its flashiest commercials during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> predicted that
these would hold more appeal than the game itself. On the other hand, the death
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura "Dinky" Patterson</ENAMEX> during a rehearsal for a bungee-jumping routine led
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to question whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> had finally gone overboard. But
reviews of all the halftime spectacle were favorable. "An eventful game
combined with a cavalcade of crafty commercials kept <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> XXXI lively and
entertaining <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>
(making its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> telecast) proved that it could cover the big game
with as much "zest and panache" as the bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' picks:
performances by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Brown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZZ</ENAMEX> Top (though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> '
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Sandomir</ENAMEX> complained that they lip-synced badly); an ad showing a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">digitized Fred Astaire</ENAMEX> dancing with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dirt Devil</ENAMEX> vacuum; and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa Check Card</ENAMEX>
commercial starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>. Nonetheless, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott</ENAMEX> complains that "too often, the effect was of ... being cajoled or maybe
bullied into being entertained by a boor repeatedly accosting you to ask,
'Having fun yet?' " (See "TheWeek/The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX>" for more on the game itself.)

            

               Movie
            

            

               
                  Kolya
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> compare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kolya</ENAMEX> , the top-grossing
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, to such 1960s New Wave classics as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiri Menzel</ENAMEX>'s
Closely <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Watched Trains</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">1966) and Milos Forman</ENAMEX>'s Loves of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blonde</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kolya</ENAMEX> is also damned with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">condescending</ENAMEX> praise.
The plot--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> comes to love adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>--is familiar; the "directorial style
is unobtrusive and free of flourishes" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Stein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan Sverak</ENAMEX> "really knows how to give it that warm, ironic Mittel
Europa charm and subtlety," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Thomas</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . "[S]entiment with sly political humor," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX> of the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> predicts that it will
become "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Il Postino</ENAMEX> ." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax plugs Kolya</ENAMEX> at its
site, where you can download video and stills.)

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Island of the Colorblind</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Sacks</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). Reviews are
unusually mixed for a book by the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacks</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Island of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colorblind</ENAMEX> , which explores both <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">achromatopsia</ENAMEX> (color-blindness)
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">lytico-bodig</ENAMEX> (a disorder similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's</ENAMEX>)--and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Micronesia</ENAMEX>, is being
dismissed as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> botanical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">treatise</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> travelogue. "Apart from observing
the unsurprising fact that color-blind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weavers</ENAMEX> are skilled at distinguishing
subtle tones, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacks</ENAMEX> can do little more than give us an
ordinary-if-well-written travel essay," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.M. Thomas</ENAMEX> in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> . "Whereas descriptions of human illness are
inherently interesting, it is difficult for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to get as worked up
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cycads</ENAMEX> and ferns as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacks</ENAMEX> seems to be," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Abraham Verghese</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacks</ENAMEX>' eclecticism doesn't bother <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s Luc
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sante</ENAMEX>, though: "This oddness is a measure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> that unifies it."
And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacks</ENAMEX> succeeds for all the familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacks</ENAMEX> reasons:
Because he shows "how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who are truly isolated and insulated by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> can retain their humanity, their dignity." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> excerpts the book at its site.)

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  The
Steward of Christendom
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Academy of Music</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Majestic Theater</ENAMEX>).
The best thing about this play, apparently, is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donal McCann</ENAMEX> ( The
Dead , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stealing Beauty</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCann</ENAMEX> plays a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70-year-old</TIMEX> ex-superintendent
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>-run <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> who is now committed to an insane asylum
and brooding over his past. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCann</ENAMEX>'s performance is said to be almost
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unbearable</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Lyons</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCann</ENAMEX>
"fearlessly exposes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> probing his own wounds." New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX> says, "It is all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCann</ENAMEX>'s play, and can he play!" Neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyons</ENAMEX> likes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sebastian Barry</ENAMEX>'s work ( Steward
is one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> dramas about his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinfolk</ENAMEX>), however. "[L]<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ike Beckett</ENAMEX> written
for soap opera," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyons</ENAMEX>; its "sometimes poetic, sometimes pseudo-poetic,
and intermittently flat prose" seems a pale imitation of, alternately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Neill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Joyce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Leonard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Friel</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>.
But the New York 
               Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX> claims the play "bears the
rare mark of theatrical greatness: it is rooted in specific, even earthy
details but it sets off echoes that go way beyond its sad story." (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Academy of</ENAMEX>
Music plugs the play at its site.)

            

               Movie
            

            

               
                  Fierce Creatures
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). The verdict on Fierce
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Creatures</ENAMEX> : nowhere near as funny as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Fish Called Wanda</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>).
Shots of cute <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are deemed an inadequate substitute for the cutting wit
that made the earlier film (by the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>, and also written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cleese</ENAMEX>)
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> hit. "Instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX> 's delicious anti-PC nastiness (flattened
lapdogs, stuttering jokes) and bawdy high-spiritedness, Fierce piles on
sight gags as crass commercialism runs amok in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszczyna</ENAMEX>. "It feels like it's been directed by a
taxidermist," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Feinstein</ENAMEX>. Other problems:
no story line, cheap puns, and heavy-handed sexual innuendo. "There is a
curious antiquarian feeling, in fact, to the whole leering enterprise," says
The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desson Howe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> insist the film still has its virtues:
Every so often, "something wickedly inspired will come along" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howe</ENAMEX>); the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>'s still "more agreeable than most of the slapdash laugh-machines around"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>). (See the official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fierce Creatures</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le</ENAMEX>
Divorce
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Johnson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutton</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Johnson</ENAMEX> ( The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shadow</ENAMEX>
Knows , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lying Low</ENAMEX> ) updates <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Portrait of a Lady in a</ENAMEX> "comedy of
manners" about an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film</ENAMEX>-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dropout</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. The novel
"reminds us that even in our own day, it remains, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry James</ENAMEX> said, a
complex fate to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Bradbury</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review</ENAMEX> . In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriele Annan</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s contribution to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innocents</ENAMEX>-abroad novel is her spirit of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">lighthearted seriousness: Le Divorce</ENAMEX> "takes desertion, suicide, and
murder in its stride, as though they were merely obligatory literary devices."
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> shortcoming: The plot "veers into melodrama that seems a bit outsize for
the scale of events that lead to it" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Lehmann-Haupt</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Divorce</ENAMEX> page on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutton</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               Updates
            

            Evita: In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enrique Krauze</ENAMEX> lists
the horrors of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perónism</ENAMEX> glossed over by the musical and film: the torture and
murder of political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>, often under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> tutelage; the sheltering of war
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>, possibly for personal profit; the destruction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Argentine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>; the laying of the cornerstone for the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dirty Wars</ENAMEX>" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> and
1980s. "It must not be forgotten ... that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> also
represented the worst of this tradition, the worst of our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>," writes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krauze</ENAMEX>. ... <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>: In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Wills</ENAMEX> concludes that "the real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> scandal ... has nothing to do
with sex or personality or ideology. It has to do with the bottomless demands
for cash in the technology of modern politics." ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> have
speculated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Greider</ENAMEX> wrote his book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One World, Ready or</ENAMEX>
Not to refute <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Fukuyama</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End of History</ENAMEX>," an essay celebrating the
global triumph of liberalism. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fukuyama</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> , says
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> is correct to "criticiz[e] the tendency of
many to throw up their hands in the face of the global economic juggernaut and
become politically passive in the face of its economic imperatives."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns:
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">22: Behind the Oval Office: Winning the Presidency in the Nineties</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Whole Wide World; The Inauguration</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jefferson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One World, Ready or Not: The Manic Logic of Global Capitalism</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William B. Greider</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idomeneo</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart</ENAMEX>, performed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Placido Domingo</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Opera Orchestra</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chorus</ENAMEX>, conducted
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Levine</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albino Alligator</ENAMEX> ; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Naked Truth</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">15: La Cérémonie ; The Prospect Before Her: A History of Women</ENAMEX> in
Western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1500-1800</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olwen Hufton; King</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> ; and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Forum</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beavis and Butt-Head Do America ; Slouching to Gomorrah: Modern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liberalism</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Decline , by Robert Bork; Politically Incorrect</ENAMEX>
With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Maher</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>); Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Son ; Christian Dior: The Man</ENAMEX>
Who <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Made the World Look New</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marie</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France Pochna</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yves Saint</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Laurent: A Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Rawsthorn</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evita ; Portrait of a Lady ; Life of Picasso</ENAMEX>, Volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1907-1917</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Richardson</ENAMEX>; Once Upon a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattress</ENAMEX> (The Broadhurst
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet ; and The Odyssey</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX>,
translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Fagles</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
