
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Edition</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucasfilm Ltd./20th Century</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>). Critical response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi</ENAMEX> is subdued compared with the frenzy over
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> films in the restored Star Wars trilogy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> deem the
movie less metaphysical and more theme-parkish than its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>. Its
faults: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ewoks</ENAMEX>, teddy-bearish-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rebel allies</ENAMEX>, are ubiquitous and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">annoying; Mark Hamill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie Fisher</ENAMEX> are too old for their parts. "You can
also feel the technological revolution in movies that Star Wars ushered
in beginning to turn on itself," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holden</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the re-released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">trilogy</TIMEX>'s official Web site.)

            
               
                  City
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industry</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orion Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Irvin</ENAMEX>'s ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Widows</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peak</ENAMEX> ) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of Industry</ENAMEX> is praised for not being a hyperstylized
Tarantinoesque crime movie. Its deadpan attitude and traditional plot--thieves
heist jewelry and then double-cross one another--are said to hark back to
classic film noir. "What's refreshing, and even sort of charming, about this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thriller</ENAMEX> is that it's so obviously the work of diehards--of talented
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traditionalists</ENAMEX> who are dedicated to taking care of business" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafferty</ENAMEX>, The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). Also lauded: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>, which features
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Hutton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Dorff</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvey Keitel</ENAMEX>; and the movie's refusal to
glamorize the criminal life. (Orion
serves up stills and clips on its site.)

            

               Opera
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie O</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Opera Studio</ENAMEX>). Mixed reviews for a campy
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">rock</ENAMEX>-opera about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Onassis</ENAMEX>' ascent to iconhood. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Cunningham</ENAMEX> says it's a "mindless <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">100-minute</TIMEX> cult fantasy"--a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the opera is set at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">loft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>
schmoozes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Callas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grace Kelly</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
extols the "poetic" libretto by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Koestenbaum</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> Under My
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Skin: Interpreting An Icon</ENAMEX> , as well as its "brilliantly eclectic score" and
its general irreverence (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> is played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Heaston</ENAMEX>, who is short,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stout</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>).

            

               Theater
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antony</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleopatra</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph Papp Public Theater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX> calls this production of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>
play, directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Redgrave</ENAMEX>, "jaw-droppingly bizarre." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redgrave</ENAMEX>'s
portrayal of the queen of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">the Nile</ENAMEX> as an aging, cigarillo-smoking ditz,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obsequious</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antony</ENAMEX>, is judged daffy but charming, except by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX>, who wishes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redgrave</ENAMEX> would be "seductively womanly."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are skeptical of anachronistic touches in the production, including
loud sirens, camcorders, and video projections of political speeches.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Winer</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redgrave</ENAMEX>'s decision to play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antony</ENAMEX>'s suicide
scene as a joke "unforgivable." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Public Theater</ENAMEX>
site plugs the play.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> Novellas
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Leavitt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houghton Mifflin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co.</ENAMEX>). Reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leavitt</ENAMEX>'s collection of novellas focus on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, The
Term Paper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist</ENAMEX> , which caused a scandal when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> pulled it at
the last minute. The fiction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> quit, claiming the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief had been
afraid that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leavitt</ENAMEX>'s explicit gay sex scenes would alienate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leavitt</ENAMEX>'s take on sex is
"adolescent" and "does nothing to illuminate its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>' lives." Others find
the collection uneven. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Term Paper</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist</ENAMEX> does earn some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">praise</ENAMEX>, though, for its playful reference to another crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leavitt</ENAMEX>'s life:
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Spender</ENAMEX>'s allegation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leavitt</ENAMEX> plagiarized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spender</ENAMEX>'s memoirs in an earlier novel.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deadly Feasts: Tracking the Secrets of a Terrifying New Plague</ENAMEX>
               ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rhodes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). A history of mad-cow <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> by
veteran science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rhodes</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Making of the Atomic Bomb</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> praise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodes</ENAMEX>' lucid explication of complex virology as well as his
range--the book includes digressions on political and literary themes and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> on the scandal surrounding a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> Prize-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on the disease
who recently pleaded guilty to molesting a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>. The book is said to
degenerate into a jeremiad when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhodes</ENAMEX> anoints mad-cow disease "the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>
Death."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Resurrection: The Struggle</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Russia</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Remnick</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remnick</ENAMEX>'s sequel to his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prize-winning Lenin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomb</ENAMEX> is a "compelling postscript" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Laqueur</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ). Reviewers focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Remnick's</ENAMEX> access to political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX>, especially his extended interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Gorbachev</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir</ENAMEX>
Zhirinovsky, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennady Zyuganov</ENAMEX>. Critics also welcome his ambivalence on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s future: Unlike most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX>, "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remnick</ENAMEX> does not manage his
material so as to prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is bound to succeed, or doomed to fail"
(the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economist</ENAMEX> ).

            
               
                  The
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arched Bridge</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismail Kadare</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hodgson</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arcade</ENAMEX>). High praise for a newly translated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> novel by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>
Kadare, about a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">medieval village</ENAMEX> at the dawn of capitalism. "Translated ...
into prose of crystalline clarity and grace, it is ... a slim, dark tale that
bears some kinship to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.M. Coetzee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Waiting for the Barbarians</ENAMEX> "
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick McGrath</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). High praise also for
Kadare, a perennial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> says
his defection to the West in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> helped topple <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>.
However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> attacks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, calling him an
apologist for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enver Hoxha</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> provides a biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kadare</ENAMEX> and a list of his
published works.)

            

               Updates:
            

            More
attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX> and her adult-incest memoir, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kiss</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Eberstadt</ENAMEX> implies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX> is
making it all up. "Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX> has written a failed--that is to say, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unconvincing</ENAMEX>--memoir. ... For all we know, she did all these things and more.
Any speculations to the contrary would be indecent." In the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Wolcott</ENAMEX> speculates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Kiss to</ENAMEX>
invite "humiliation upon her [own] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> ... as misery was invited on her."
... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX> refuses to board the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, condemning the shock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock</ENAMEX> for his megalomania, his "fifties
idea of sexual humor," and his crimes against "dignity" and "high-mindedness."
... The backlash against the backlash against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helfgott</ENAMEX> has begun. An editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> argues,
"Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helfgott</ENAMEX> babbles and probably makes more mistakes per evening than the
famously unentertaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Brendel</ENAMEX> has made in a lifetime. So what. Here's
someone whose fierce love of music is making <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of others listen to
classical music."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns:
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Private
Parts ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Jungle 2</ENAMEX>
Jungle ;

            
Thing Happened on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Way</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss: A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Memoir</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giovanni</ENAMEX>'s
Gift , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradford Morrow</ENAMEX>;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exiles</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Émigrés</ENAMEX>: The Flight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Artists</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>";

            

               Television -- The Practice .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Donnie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brasco</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smilla</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sense of Snow</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Helfgott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Tour</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crisis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Feds</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arsenio</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- Just
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shoot Me</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crazy</ENAMEX>
Rhythms: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All That Jazz</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Garment</ENAMEX>;

            
               Books --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Novel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roundup</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- The Last Night of Ballyhoo</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>
Strikes Back: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Special Edition</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Lost</ENAMEX>
Highway ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rosewood</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schindler</ENAMEX>'s List ;

            
               Television -- Miss
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boys</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Monster:</ENAMEX>
Living <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Off the Big Screen</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gregory Dunne</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Sphinx: The Character of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph J. Ellis</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whittaker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Tanenhaus</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:</TIMEX>

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie
               --Absolute
Power ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Blood</ENAMEX> and
Wine ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gladstone</ENAMEX>: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Jenkins</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asylum</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick McGrath</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Hungry
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ghosts: Mao's Secret Famine</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jasper Becker</ENAMEX>;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Darger</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unreality</ENAMEX> of Being."

            
               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
