
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Dec. 13</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
editorial advises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thabo Mbeki</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>'s likely next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, to uphold
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensible</ENAMEX> (i.e., free market) economic policies in order to "retain the
confidence of outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>." He must also balance "white fears against
black demands for change." Problem: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Africans</ENAMEX> don't love and respect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mbeki</ENAMEX>
as they do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX>. A story explains the success of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>: Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s litigiousness, high health-care costs, and
excessive regulation (all less pronounced in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture
encourages risk-taking and backs it with big bucks. An article says monkeys
work as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coconut pickers</ENAMEX> in many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Monkeys</ENAMEX> are excellent harvesters
and work for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanuts</ENAMEX> (actually, for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>). They do get sick
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> off. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tamagotchi</ENAMEX> virtual pet have a new product: a
virtual nanny. The motorized <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">nanny</ENAMEX> presses your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamagotchi</ENAMEX>'s buttons when you
are otherwise occupied. (There is no "shake violently" function yet.)

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 11</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story pulls back the curtains on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebration</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that
opened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months ago</TIMEX>. Celebration is architecturally impressive and fosters
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">old-time community</ENAMEX> values, but it's also a miniature <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>. Residents cede
political rights (including voting) to a totalitarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>; clashes (mostly
over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>) have already begun. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> interviews new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vartan Gregorian</ENAMEX> (former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Public Library</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown University</ENAMEX>). He hopes to direct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie</ENAMEX> money toward some of his
interests: campaign-finance reform, immigration, the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aging of America</ENAMEX>. Also, a story examines the proliferation of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">300-pound</NUMEX> players
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>. There are now nearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">240</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">300 pounds</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as many as a decade ago</TIMEX>. (Most are offensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linemen</ENAMEX>.) Surprisingly, very
few use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX>. Their secret? A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>-calories-per<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-day</TIMEX> diet.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> cover story <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assesses</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s chances in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">2000</ENAMEX> race:
He has the right political instincts, but he's still too wooden. He should try
to imitate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s rapport with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> on the campaign trail. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> finds him paranoid about competition for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
nomination. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rivals</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX> will damage <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> by linking him to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> can't distance himself too much from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover
story looks at interfaith marriages. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stat</ENAMEX>: More than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> marry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gentiles</ENAMEX>.) The predictable conclusion: Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interfaith couples</ENAMEX> choose one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX> and stick to it, others let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> decide. (See

                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" on mixed marriage.)

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> story says the electric-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> movement is running out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX>. Rentals of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">EV1</NUMEX> have been sluggish, and oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are funding
anti-electric-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">slams</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s Internet-porn conference for producing
platitudes rather than action.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> notes the marketing overkill of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX> movie:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heineken</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smirnoff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ericsson</ENAMEX> are running commercials that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX>
both their products and the movie.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story reports on the apocalypse, collecting popular
prophecies on how it will happen. Favorite portents: the formation of the state
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the millennium</TIMEX>, the continued reign of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>,
and black <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> ("swarming locusts" to the prophets). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
wonders if the apocalyptic obsession <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX> distrust of public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. An essay claims the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to block
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Lann Lee</ENAMEX>'s nomination as civil-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s support
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> could win <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-American</ENAMEX> votes for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9</TIMEX>)
            

            A special
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cartoon Issue</ENAMEX>" prints <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of new drawings and old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Businessman</ENAMEX>
talking on the phone: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s out. How about never--is never good for
you?"). There are features on "desert <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>" cartoons, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX> cartoons, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">racist</ENAMEX> (now regretted) cover cartoons. A profile of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illustrator Thomas Nast</ENAMEX> credits him with popularizing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Santa Claus</ENAMEX>, electing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulysses Grant</ENAMEX>, and ruining <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William "Boss</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tweed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nast</ENAMEX> had as much cultural
influence then as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Limbaugh</ENAMEX> has now. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX> writes about his aborted
cartooning career. An essay notes disapprovingly that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> are behaving more
and more like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>: They wear childish clothes (jeans and sneakers), watch
childish movies ( <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jurassic Park</ENAMEX> ), drive childish <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> (sport utility
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vehicles</ENAMEX>), and eat childish <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX>). And, of course, they read
magazines full of cartoons.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9</TIMEX>)
            

            An
editorial points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> law lets our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> block the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>
from searching sensitive security sites, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> is doing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. An essay chides <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for swamping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCaughey</ENAMEX> septuplets with
gifts while ignoring most needy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Also, a piece urges the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> to cease their negative portrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX>. While emphasizing
the recent fund-raising scandals involving "mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> are ignoring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>'s record turnout by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
