
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  U-Turn
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures</ENAMEX>). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> attack <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX>'s latest
movie, saying it exhibits his usual self-indulgence. Deemed particularly
offensive are the skewed camera angles and choppy editing--"the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Fat</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Over</NUMEX>-Produced and Over-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Directed Oliver Stone</ENAMEX> treatment" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hunter</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). The plot--which has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Penn</ENAMEX> stranded in a bizarre
desert <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and caught between a real-estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nick Nolte</ENAMEX>) and his
stepdaughter/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Lopez</ENAMEX>), each of whom asks him to murder the
other--is called "a primer in hard-boiled clichés" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> ). Exempted from the general drubbing is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Bob Thornton</ENAMEX>'s funny
turn as an unhygienic redneck mechanic. (See the official site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington Square</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). Applause for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europa</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agnieszka Holland</ENAMEX>'s feminist adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry James</ENAMEX>'
novel, starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Finney</ENAMEX> as an overbearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Jason Leigh</ENAMEX>
as his stubborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington Square</ENAMEX> is said to compare favorably
with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last winter</TIMEX>'s revisionist <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Portrait of a Lady</ENAMEX> , since it "respects
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">complexities</ENAMEX> and bitter ironies" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). Critics
also praise its "brusque, energetic pace" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leigh</ENAMEX>'s "heartbreakingly good" performance ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX> ). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kauffmann</ENAMEX> dissents, calling the film "ill at
ease, uncomfortable, straining for effect." (Download a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> here.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soul Food</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). Like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Waiting to</ENAMEX>
Exhale , this film about the black bourgeoisie rakes in unexpectedly huge
receipts--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30.4 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> praise the film for
featuring a hard-working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s usual black "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pimps</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">junkies"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). Others say it just
replaces a negative stereotype with a schmaltzy one: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]t pushes emotional
buttons with all the subtlety of a poke in the baby-back ribs" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Corliss, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photos</ENAMEX> and the like are available here.)

            

            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bilbao</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> anoint <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gehry</ENAMEX>'s sprawling, postmodern <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">titanium</ENAMEX>-and-stone edifice "one of the
greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twentieth century</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvin Tomkins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for a photo.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gehry</ENAMEX> wins praise for his idiosyncratic,
"cartoonish" style--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Muschamp</ENAMEX> calls his
innovations reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Lloyd Wright</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> worry that the
magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> will overshadow the art it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, which will be mostly
borrowed from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>.

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  Toward <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the End of Time</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">47 th</NUMEX> book is pronounced a "rare misfire" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Giles</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). Set in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2020</TIMEX> after a nuclear war, it is lambasted as
consisting mainly of an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s "bombast" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Eder</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ) about death, sex, and excrement. "How could such a gifted writer
produce such a lousy book<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). One
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">admirer is Margaret Atwood</ENAMEX>, writing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> :
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Updike</ENAMEX> "manages an amazing range of emotions with his usual grace and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dexterity</ENAMEX>." (Another is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Berman</ENAMEX>. Click here for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX> and here for an excerpt from the book.)

            

               Death
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923-1997</TIMEX>). Upon his death, the pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> ascends from the
controversial to the canonical. Having endlessly debated the staying power of
his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX> comic-strip sendups, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> now conclude his art will last.
"With good humor and icy elegance ... <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX> was able to construct an art
that approached real monumentality," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>. Critics
also say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX> succeeded as both technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> and social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commentator</ENAMEX>, and that he was ahead of his time: "[H]e was a saboteur, offering
1990s irony in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kimmelman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The
Edge ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peacemaker</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Big Trouble:</ENAMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder in a Small Western Town Sets Off a Struggle for the Soul of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Anthony Lukas</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timequake</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Vonnegut</ENAMEX>;

            
               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> Out of
Mind , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylon</ENAMEX> , by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Stones</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER : "Ambush</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensations: Young British Artists From the Saatchi Collection</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Academy of Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- The
Royals , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kitty Kelley</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Underworld</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don DeLillo</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
Apes , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Will Self</ENAMEX>;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rauschenberg: A Retrospective"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Guggenheim Museums and Ace Gallery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>);

            
               Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thousand</ENAMEX>
Acres ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ice</ENAMEX>
Storm ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Veronica's Closet</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
Confidential ;

            
               Movie -- In &
Out ;

            

               Television -- Nothing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacred</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn South</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Hayes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candle</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wind 1997</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elton John</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Jewish Heritage</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Living Memorial</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:</TIMEX>

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story of Painting</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- Ally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McBeal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>);

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- She's So</ENAMEX>
Lovely ;

            

               Movie -- <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The Farewell
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Symphony</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund White</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Nation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indivisible</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abigail Thernstrom</ENAMEX>.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
