
   
   
      
         
            

             

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Nov. 27</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story blasts the flat tax, which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are adopting as their top
legislative priority. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> lies when it says the flat tax would cut tax
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> for middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. In fact, the flat tax would "massively"
redistribute income to the rich. (The national sales tax, another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX>,
is an equally regressive scheme, and totally unenforceable.) The editorial
endorses progressive tax reform: Cut rates but scrap loopholes such as the
mortgage-interest deduction for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowners</ENAMEX>. An article by a constitutional
lawyer wonders whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kaczynski</ENAMEX>'s diary should be admissible in court and
decides that it should be. A key reason: The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth Amendment</ENAMEX> does not protect
self-incriminating diaries because diary writing is voluntary, not compelled by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Nov. 27</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last</ENAMEX>
Best <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friends Money Can Buy</ENAMEX>" follows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> home-health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> as they tend
to a dying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">99-year-old</TIMEX>. Conclusion: It's sad that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> to
care for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly relatives</ENAMEX>, but at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> are willing and
qualified. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> caregivers--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamaicans</ENAMEX>--are disappointed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">callousness</ENAMEX>. An article notes the rise of "whiteness studies" in academia. Grad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> say they are analyzing whiteness in order to undermine racial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supremacy</ENAMEX>. The author worries that they may only succeed in cementing racial
categories. A piece describes the quixotic quest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry McMurtry</ENAMEX>: He
is trying to turn his tiny, struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Archer City</ENAMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s used-book capital. He's already filled several commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>
with books. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> is helping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McMurtry</ENAMEX> recover from a long bout of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 25</TIMEX>)
            

            Twin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">septuplet</ENAMEX> covers. Both
mags have pieces on the science and ethics of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fertility drugs</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time's</ENAMEX> is more comprehensive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> has sidebars on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCaughey</ENAMEX> septuplets' forgotten older
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22-month-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mikayla</ENAMEX>), the horrors of multiple births gone wrong, and
adoption as an alternative to fertility <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> also runs a cautionary letter from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionne</ENAMEX>
quintuplets, who were born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>. Their upbringing was a nightmare. The
McCaugheys are already collecting from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">well-wishers</ENAMEX>: a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>-seat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">minivan</ENAMEX>, a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX>, diapers for life, and much more from corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
offers a time line of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' plans for a successful delivery. It also has
sidebars on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dionnes</ENAMEX> and other famous multibirths.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> identifies a new racial conflict: bilingual education. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX> resent
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>' perceived hoarding of scarce public-school funds. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> argues that killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> would be a
more effective method of deposing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> than a bombing campaign. Also in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , trend-spotting: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soup</ENAMEX> is "the new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>." Gourmet soup cafes
and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Soup Nazi</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wannabes</ENAMEX> are sprouting up all over trendy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 25</TIMEX>)
            

            A week
after its "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Buyer's Guide</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hottest Tech Toys</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> puts the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Annual Guide to Techno Life</ENAMEX>" on the cover. Highlights of the package: An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> says that wearable medical computers will diagnose
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> by "smelling" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. A fold-out
map details the wonders of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' wired <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
secretly pivoting bookshelves. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> hides a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, what does the other hide?) His
walkways, we note approvingly, are covered with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slate</ENAMEX> (or, as it's known here,

                  Slate
               ). And new
software will displace entire professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX>, by
automating complicated, arcane tasks. A piece pegged to the global-warming summit contends that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> can save <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and reduce greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX> by using
energy more efficiently.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 25</TIMEX>)
            

            A long
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> chronicles the skinhead war in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Antelope Valley</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>, neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>, speed-addicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> brawl with the multiracial "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharps</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Skinheads Against Racial Prejudice</ENAMEX>). Who's to blame? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX>, often speed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX> themselves, who are totally uninvolved in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' lives. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ex-JFK</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buddy Gore Vidal</ENAMEX> praises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Hersh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> bio and tells more stories
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s sex adventures and mendaciousness. He mocks the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
was a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, likening him to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Garfield</ENAMEX>. A piece belittles <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Prusiner</ENAMEX>'s prion theory, calling it "pathological science"
that is contrary to evidence and experience. It is very likely that a slow
virus, rather than simply a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, causes brain illnesses like mad-cow
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. (For another skeptical view, see 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, Wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a Minute</TIMEX>.") A
flattering profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> describes her as the least political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. She probably won't appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to investigate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funniest nugget</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of those close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> refers to her
in private as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martian</ENAMEX>."

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 25</TIMEX>)
            

            A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-story cover package calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s overthrow. To buttress
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> opposition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> should restore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio Free Iraq</ENAMEX>, end the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdish</ENAMEX>
civil war in the north, and indict him as a war criminal. If we attack
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">militarily</ENAMEX>, we must use ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>: As the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> proved, air power alone
won't cripple <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and won't topple <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>. An essay lavishly praises
antitrust law, which maintains open competitive markets with a minimum of
government interference.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 18</TIMEX>)
            

            A
posthumous profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodi Fayed</ENAMEX> says he was childish, profligate, unreliable,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paranoid</ENAMEX>, and drug-using. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> totally controlled him, his much-touted
involvement in film production has been wildly exaggerated, and his affair with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> would have fallen apart, as his many other glam romances did. A story
marvels at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX>' conspicuous consumption, which far outdoes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grotesque</ENAMEX> examples: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> watches, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14,000</NUMEX> bags, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,800</NUMEX> bottles of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, and
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX> sweaters are popular items, and some thirtysomethings are purchasing
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10-million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>-- with cash . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> exhaustively
chronicles the events at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">70 th precinct</NUMEX>, where the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plunger Cops" assaulted Abner Louima</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Bruder</ENAMEX>, one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>
accused, tells his story, blaming the others. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louima</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are depicted as
shameless money- and publicity-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX>. A piece about Internet gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> depicts him as a charming, naive young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who made a terrible mistake
in reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> beat his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX>'s lawsuit may well ruin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> and threaten Internet free
speech.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
