
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cop</ENAMEX>
Land
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty extra pounds</NUMEX> notwithstanding, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX>
fails to ascend to the ranks of his co-stars, the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character actors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Niro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey Keitel</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Liotta</ENAMEX>. He "comes alive ... only [in the]
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">climax</ENAMEX>, when he finally gets to pick up a gun," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> defies
the critical consensus and extols the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sly</ENAMEX>: "Watching Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX> quietly
hold his ground with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX>, ... it is not immediately apparent who was
lauded as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>'s greatest brooding film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>." (Miramax plugs the
movie here.)

            
               
                  The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> Monty
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox Searchlight Pictures</ENAMEX>). This "bittersweet" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
"working-class comedy" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Thomas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ) about
out-of-work, out-of-shape steelworkers turned male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strippers</ENAMEX> earns praise for
its politics and humor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> find the film's conceit--"that joblessness is a
humiliation well beyond nakedness"--to be "witty" and "trenchant" (the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times ' Maslin</ENAMEX>). The film also wins points from politically sympathetic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> who bemoan "how few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> films have dealt even as remotely as
well with ... downsizing, ... a heinous redistribution of wealth, [and] the
exaltation of capital" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full Monty</TIMEX> .)

            

               Music
            

            
               
                  Be
Here Now
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oasis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epic</ENAMEX>). Long compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> of pop "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unabashedly</ENAMEX> lay claim to the pantheon of rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greats</ENAMEX>" (Elysa
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardner</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> disagree. "The sheer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vitality</ENAMEX> and pure inner joy contained within the music disguises how dated it
really is," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil McCormick</ENAMEX>. Others dismiss
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> comparison as hype. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>]ot a particularly smart or involving album.
... If we want to hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>, we can listen to their Anthology
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher John Farley</ENAMEX>. (Link to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oasis</ENAMEX> pages.)

            

               Theater
            

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roundabout Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> agree that
the revived <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> hit musical about the making of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of</ENAMEX>
Independence has endured <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX>. "A surprisingly (if oddly) skilled
seducer," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX>. "[I]ts laurels weren't
just nods to jingoistic values in a time of social upheaval." Praise goes to
its book, written by a high-school history <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>: It invests the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' debate with a "thrill [that] is ... moral and intellectual" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyons</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ). Others take the occasion to recall,
resentfully, how the "reactionary" show beat out Hair for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Winer</ENAMEX> declares it "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>'s equivalent of an extremely
competent after-school special."

            
               
                  On
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Delacorte Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). Another extravagant
musical revival, it is said not to do justice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Bernstein</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>
original about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-hour</TIMEX> leave in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (which later became a Frank
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra-Gene Kelly</ENAMEX> movie). "A strained affair that ... leav[<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">es</ENAMEX>] the heart
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unengaged</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Scheck</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporter</ENAMEX> ). The litany of
problems starts with basics like the acting and dancing: Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> of unknowns
"is jarringly unbalanced," and "as a dance show, it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> left feet"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brantley</ENAMEX>).

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Wallace</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 24 and 26</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m. EDT/PDT</TIMEX>). Critics
complain that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Frankenheimer</ENAMEX>'s miniseries about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> and
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> plays fast and loose with history. (Most problematic: A
fictitious manservant, supposed to be a sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everyman</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contemplates assassinating Wallace</ENAMEX>.) In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biographer Stephan Lesher</ENAMEX> says the film reduces the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s appeal to simple
racism--a contention "every bit as anti-intellectual and demagogic as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>'s
own ... bigotry." But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Stein</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Sinise</ENAMEX>'s
"nuanced" portrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> redeems the series. (See the official site.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fan</ENAMEX>'s Notes
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Exley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Library</ENAMEX>), and 
                  Misfit: The
Strange Life of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Exley</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> seize upon the re-issue of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A Fan's Notes</ENAMEX> and upon this
biography of its eccentric, dipsomaniac <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> to sing his praises. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caldwell</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> declares A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notes</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX>'s
only hit, a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">masterpiece</ENAMEX>." The reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yardley</ENAMEX>'s book are less positive. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX>'s literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yardley</ENAMEX> is
said to use scant evidence--such as numerous <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late-night</TIMEX> phone calls from Exley
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1975 to 1992</TIMEX>--to draw conclusions about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX>'s self-absorption and
ambiguous sexuality. "Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yardley</ENAMEX>'s book has value as a study of just how
small and brief and enigmatic certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>' lives can be once you've
subtracted their work from the equation." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirn</ENAMEX>).

            

               
                  Apaches
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenzo Carcaterra</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballantine Books</ENAMEX>). Like his
previous book, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sleepers</ENAMEX> , which was adapted into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX> movie,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carcaterra</ENAMEX>'s latest novel is both an instant best seller and a critical flop.
Apaches , about ex-cops battling a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traffickers</ENAMEX> who smuggle
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> in the hollowed-out cadavers of kidnapped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>, is condemned for its
"gruesome banality, ... assembly line formulas and ... plain tastelessness"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bernstein</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Giles</ENAMEX>
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carcaterra</ENAMEX> is "one of the most intriguing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> around, with or without
his books. Preferably without." (See the elaborate Apaches
site.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">13:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Conspiracy</ENAMEX>
Theory ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Love</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serenade</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vibe</ENAMEX> and The 
               Keenen 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX>

               Wayans 
               Show ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Event/Television</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX>
Live ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sculpture of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angkor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ancient Cambodia: Millennium of Glory"</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simenon</ENAMEX>: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Assouline</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Rothschild</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Dispatches From the Freud Wars: Psychoanalysis and Its</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Passions</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Forrester</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Career
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Company</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Spawn</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Our Guys</ENAMEX>: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Glen Ridge Rape and the Secret Life of the Perfect Suburb</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lefkowitz</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> or
Fear<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: How Jews Can Survive in a Christian America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Abrams</ENAMEX>;

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palestrina</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Mrs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
Maps ;

            
               Architecture --National
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Airport</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Desserts: The Unauthorized Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oppenheimer</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book of Memories</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Nadas</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ivan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Imre Goldstein</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contact</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Shall We</ENAMEX>
Dance? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">;</ENAMEX>

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawyerland</ENAMEX>:
What Lawyers <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk About When They Talk About the Law</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Straight
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Russo</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX>'s
View .

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
