
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Feb. 14</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> cover story notes the globalization and professionalization of
the sex industry. The explosion of the sex trade in eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> has driven
down prices for prostitution and pornography worldwide. The real money is still
in upscale <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip clubs</ENAMEX>, high-class call-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> rings, and well-produced X-rated
videos. Good news for porn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>: The Internet makes it possible to learn which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brothels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip clubs</ENAMEX> are reliable. ... A piece frets that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> is damaging <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has no coherent economic
policy, the budget is a joke, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> is likely to be succeeded by a
hard-line authoritarian like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Lebed</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> hasn't escaped
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s economic crisis, warns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. Bad debts may total <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s GDP, and government control over private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> is
increasing. Unless <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> manages to dismantle its gigantic, interfering
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> (which is unlikely), it too will face economic disaster.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 13</TIMEX>)
            

            The
magazine bad-mouths its longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-story cover package.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> piece raps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">veep</ENAMEX>'s technorationalism: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> analysis
can solve any problem (environmental degradation, nuclear proliferation, etc.)
and doesn't understand emotionalism and power politics. This blind spot could
handicap his presidency. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> piece berates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> for supporting affirmative
action and accuses him of grossly distorting the views of affirmative-action
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. (For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Algorithms</ENAMEX>.")

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb. 12</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story predicts that memory-enhancing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> away. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX>
have already figured out how to give a fruit fly a photographic memory by
manipulating a genetic switch called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CREB</ENAMEX>. They are now seeking a similar
mechanism in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX> will be marketed initially to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>,
but expect aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> to grab them too. ... An article rejects
the notion that the Internet is distorting news. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> has sped up the news
cycle (just as the telephone did at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX>), but good
reporting is still good reporting. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will quickly learn to separate
reliable online journalism from garbage. (Full disclosure: 
                  Slate
               
Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX> wrote the piece.) ... A column by Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">guru Esther Dyson</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> has too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> and not
enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. Startups can't sustain themselves because they lack talented
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief operating officers</ENAMEX>, chief financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salespeople</ENAMEX>. Why does
no one seem to care? Most venture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX> and company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> are hoping
to make a short-term killing, not long-term profits.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 10</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> runs its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consecutive Lewinsky</ENAMEX> cover (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Trial by Leaks"</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> cuts back on the
scandal, putting the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Nagano Olympics</ENAMEX> on its cover. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover
package, an essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX> and Nathaniel
Speights claims that: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>'s media campaign is "designed to demonstrate
that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is a responsible young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who speaks the truth." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> was "very pleased" with the contents of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s oral proffer and
wanted to offer immunity but, for unspecified reasons, would not put the deal
in writing. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, "We've blown the opportunity to
wire her. She's radioactive because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> ." The cover package also wonders who's leaking information to the
press. (Why don't they ask their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>?) An article traces the path of the "semen-stained dress"
story: It bounced from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> to countless news outlets
without ever being substantiated. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's scoop of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
told her story to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Raines</ENAMEX>, who has met with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raines</ENAMEX> reportedly heard messages from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s
answering machine. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> run profiles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> (here's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>'s), more maps of who was where in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>,
and updated scandal time lines. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> adds profiles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adviser Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kaye</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nagano</ENAMEX>
wants to stage a humble "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Zen</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>, avoiding the glitz of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
games. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> package profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Stojko</ENAMEX>, the most exciting male figure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skater</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stojko</ENAMEX>'s problem: He lacks artistry because he's afraid of seeming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">effeminate</ENAMEX>. (Tactless comment: "I don't have a feminine side. Maybe if I were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gay</ENAMEX>, but I'm not.") An essay claims skating's quadruple jump (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stojko</ENAMEX>'s
specialty) is overrated, and shouldn't be a prerequisite for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> explicates curling (shuffleboard on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> with brooms), "the one game in
all the world wherein the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> move faster than the object they
put in play."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> excerpts a new book on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Di</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last days</TIMEX>. Revelation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>
might have been saved had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ambulance</ENAMEX> rushed her to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, rather than
treating her at the site.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 10</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> is back on track thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerstner</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerstner</ENAMEX> scrapped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>'s dress code, bought <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lotus Notes</ENAMEX> and
popularized it, and is planning big things for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> feels <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>. ... An article claims the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> is in trouble. In the wake
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX>'s departure, donations are down, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (notably the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research Council</ENAMEX>) have become more influential. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> recently
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are marveling at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s near-complete economic, military,
and cultural domination of the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreigners</ENAMEX> remain baffled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
scandal, however: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendee</ENAMEX> joked, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> ask why he hasn't had more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> ask why he didn't make her pregnant; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>
wonder why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> is still alive."

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 10</TIMEX>)
            

            A piece
enters the peculiar, charming world of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> re-enactors (or "living
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historians</ENAMEX>," as they call themselves). The hard-core ones spin their own
clothes, subsist on hardtack and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt pork</ENAMEX>, speak in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX>
dialect, and starve themselves in order to attain the gaunt look of Confederate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gross</ENAMEX> detail: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soaking</ENAMEX> uniform buttons in urine gives them a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distressed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> look.) ... An article says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> owes
his high approval ratings to our celebrity-oriented culture. Politics is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diversion</ENAMEX>, not serious business, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Entertainer</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> had been bored by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>: Thanks
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinterngate</ENAMEX>, they're watching it again. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Palladino</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX>," is profiled. His job is to stifle "bimbo eruptions"
by uncovering dirt about the accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. A former '60s radical, he's worked
for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Panthers, Hell's Angels, and Courtney Love</ENAMEX>. Right now he's evading a
subpoena from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 10</TIMEX>)
            

            A cover
piece <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">upbraids</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> for its wanton attitudes about sex. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX>
boomers tolerate his lying and deception about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> because their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reprehensible</ENAMEX> "central dogma" is that consensual sex "ought never to be subject
to moral scrutiny." ... A former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s says she is
"friendly, funny, reliable" and "believed in the integrity of public service."
She taped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to defend herself from the slurs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">lackeys</ENAMEX>.
... Also, yet another editorial declaring that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> must
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">remove Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>, not just bomb him. Despite bipartisan consensus for
toppling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s too "wobbly" to do it.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 10</TIMEX>)
            

            Lots of
art news. A pair of articles probe the weird, sinister <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wildenstein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, the
richest art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> in the world. Among many creepy details: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
which is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, probably bought and sold art for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Jocelyne
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wildenstein</ENAMEX>, who's in the midst of a bloody divorce with family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alec</ENAMEX>, has
had countless plastic surgeries in order to look like a jungle <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>. The photos
of her are truly strange. ... An article investigates the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200-million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum</ENAMEX> robbery of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. The suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> are
dead, and the suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mastermind</ENAMEX>, an art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myles Connor</ENAMEX>, is in
jail. Now a sleazy associate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connor</ENAMEX> is trying to return the paintings in
exchange for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5-million</NUMEX> reward. The author claims to have seen the stolen
artwork in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> warehouse. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Bernstein</ENAMEX> profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tommy</ENAMEX>
Boggs, who used his family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>--to become <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s über <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX>. Banal conclusion: He's a
fun-loving, good-hearted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, but he has done as much as anyone to build a
system where money buys political power. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>'s on the cover.
Photos with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> inside. Accompanying article says she's finally learning
to express her deepest emotions in public. God help us.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
