
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Career Girls</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">October Films</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Leigh</ENAMEX>'s latest film
about working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX> "trapped in the hopelessness of modern life" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Schickel, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ) is rated a notch below his acclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naked</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Secrets & Lies</ENAMEX> . The premise--ex-college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommates</ENAMEX> spend a weekend
together for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>--is overly "modest" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd McCarthy</ENAMEX>,
Variety ): "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>]othing much happens, dramatically speaking," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schickel</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence Rafferty</ENAMEX> says the film contains
"enough small truths and enough off-hand comic business to keep you reasonably
happy for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX> says it proves
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leigh</ENAMEX> "digs deeper into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> now working in movies."
(See the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Career Girls</ENAMEX> site.)

            
               
                  In
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Company of Men</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). Polarized reactions to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil LaBute</ENAMEX>'s low-budget debut about two <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> who scheme to seduce and
dump a deaf <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Some discern a feminist slant to the film's "ballsy
depiction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s inhumanity to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> praises
its "critical detachment" and "coolly stylized exaggeration," which make it
"impossible to mistake <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Company of</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> for simple bigotry."
Others perceive rank cynicism. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaBute</ENAMEX> "has
avoided the gray shades of life for in-your-face sensationalism. He's made a
horror movie designed to shock, and nothing else." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stills</ENAMEX> and clips are
available here.)

            

               
                  Spawn
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>). Based on a cult-hit comic book about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> who returns from the dead to destroy the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> as part of a
Faustian bargain, this live-action film crosses over to mass-market success
with both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>--the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles</ENAMEX> .
Spawn action figures have been selling out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, and the film
grossed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX> its opening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> praises it as "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">summer</ENAMEX>'s most spectacular concoction of visual effects and color." Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, however, echo the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>'s verdict: "an
incoherent blitz of noise, chintzy special effects and bargain-basement
allegory." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spawn</ENAMEX> 's site.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Glen Ridge Rape and the Secret Life of the Perfect Suburb</ENAMEX>
               , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Lefkowitz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California Press</ENAMEX>). A journalism <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>'s
account of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> incident in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX> raped a mentally
retarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. "Important," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> .
"[B]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rilliantly</ENAMEX> rendered," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> . Praise goes to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lefkowitz</ENAMEX>'s "painstaking" reporting. Shock is expressed at the
upper-middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s blasé reaction to rape (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> boasted
about it in their yearbook). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> fault <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lefkowitz</ENAMEX> for "sweeping
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">platitudes</ENAMEX> and clichés that trivialize" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Jenkins</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ) when he links the rape to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Glen Ridge</ENAMEX>'s obsession with sports.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fear: How Jews Can Survive in a Christian America</ENAMEX>
               , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Abrams</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Press</ENAMEX>). The ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>'s tract
against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> assimilation stokes an old debate most recently fueled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dershowitz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Vanishing American Jew</ENAMEX> . Political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> endorse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abrams</ENAMEX>' calls for a return to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orthodoxy</ENAMEX> and an alliance with evangelical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christians</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Abrams</ENAMEX> is a severe, insightful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of the assumptions
that have brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to its current predicament,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Miller</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> rebuke <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Abrams</ENAMEX> for his
alarmism about intermarriage. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> op-ed piece, J.J.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> says he relies on discredited studies in order to exaggerate the
"crisis."

            

               Death
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William S. Burroughs</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914-1997</TIMEX>). Obituaries of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Naked Lunch</ENAMEX> highlight his
importance as a countercultural role model, calling him "the non-conformist's
non-conformist" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ) who "inspired a who's who of pop
culture" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). They dwell on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beats</ENAMEX>, punk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rockers</ENAMEX>)
who embraced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX>, and retell bizarre anecdotes from his life
(he shot his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> accidentally, slept with little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, and hawked his
typewriter to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>). Yet none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">obits</ENAMEX> argues for his literary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">greatness</ENAMEX>, or that his writing should be read by future generations except for
reasons of historical curiosity.

            

               Opera
            

            

               
                  Palestrina
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans Pfitzner</ENAMEX>, performed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Opera</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Opera House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>). Controversy embroils the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans Pfitzner</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX> opera. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> argue
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfitzner</ENAMEX> has been unfairly ignored because of his friendship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, and
urge revision. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Ross</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestrina</ENAMEX> --about
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>-music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>--"a spectacle that is
magnificent on the surface and haunting at the core." Others, though, bash
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfitzner</ENAMEX>'s work as a pale imitation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagner</ENAMEX>, "massively bloated [and]
endlessly meandering," and say its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> performance would have been
"[b]<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">etter</ENAMEX> never, perhaps, than late" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Bernheimer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ).

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Mrs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
Maps ;

            

               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Airport</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book --
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Desserts: The Unauthorized Biography</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oppenheimer</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book of Memories</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Nadas</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ivan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Imre Goldstein</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contact</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Shall We</ENAMEX>
Dance? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">;</ENAMEX>

            
               Book--
               Lawyerland:
What Lawyers <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk About When They Talk About the Law</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Straight
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Russo</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>);

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Amy's View</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> in
Black ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Women With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ford</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Scripture: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Making the Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Maier</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX> Without
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face: The Autobiography of Communism's Greatest Spymaster</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Markus Wolf</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne McElvoy</ENAMEX>;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Haring</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum of American Art</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oz</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            

               Music --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilith Fair</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Batman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Robin</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Face/Off</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promesse</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Musical</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ragtime</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puttermesser Papers</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Ozick</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- How Proust
Can <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Change Your Life: Not a Novel</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alain de Botton</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bright Angel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha McPhee</ENAMEX>.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
