
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 15</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
editorial cautions that global deflation is possible if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> don't
"reform and revive" their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. The other potential causes of global
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deflation</ENAMEX>--excess supply and lagging demand--are easily remedied by liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> policies. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second week</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> calls for
military action if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> won't comply with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> demands: "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> is not a
theoretical threat to peace. He is a proven <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> profiles
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s "accidental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Allen</ENAMEX>, whose "fortune seems a
burden." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> is too rich to bother investing in tiny, exciting startups, but
too quirky to be a major deal-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 14</TIMEX>)
            

            An
editorial calls for unilateral military action by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to enforce
inspection of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> backs down. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> attributes the defeat of fast-track trade authority to a resurgence of
nationalism in both parties. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> stoked nationalist
fires in their presidential campaigns--now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is obsessed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
"sovereignty." The cover story mourns the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX> Sir
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Isaiah Berlin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>'s "objective pluralism" combined a hatred of both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">absolutism</ENAMEX> and relativism with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist</ENAMEX>'s love for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Nov. 13</TIMEX>)
            

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>
"special issue" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> addresses <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s split personality--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">joy</ENAMEX>-ride blockbuster vs. the soulful indie. An article says the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> can
learn from each other: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indies</ENAMEX> offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> development and plot, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">big-budget</ENAMEX> movies create "a coveted gloss and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> energy that cannot be
matched in the world of the shoestring budget." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX> converses with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> explains why some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> won't work with
him: "Usually in the pictures I make, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are not the most likable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." A profile says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julianne Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of gigahit <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lost</ENAMEX>
World and indie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boogie Nights</ENAMEX> , is as bewitching as her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore reads Joan Didion</ENAMEX> and owns nothing but a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX>. An interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarantino</ENAMEX> finds him supremely confident: "It ain't about the moment. I'm not
making films for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>--I'm making films for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years from now</TIMEX>."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 11</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> criticizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Hersh</ENAMEX>'s controversial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> book, The
Dark <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Side of Camelot</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX>'s juicy stories are recycled from other books,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> says, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> for damaging accusations are dubious or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">misquoted</ENAMEX>. (
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> reviews the book in his
column, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange Bedfellow</ENAMEX>.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11 th</NUMEX> medical
cover of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> tracks "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New Science of Impotence</ENAMEX>." New <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> make flaccid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> potent, but not without dangers (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> remained aroused for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 24</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>). The buzz on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>'s forthcoming potency <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>, is so good that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock has already soared <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">74 percent</NUMEX>. (See also

                  Slate
               's take on the culture of impotence.)

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> story says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi Strauss</ENAMEX> faces stiff competition from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trendier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diesel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Hilfiger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polo</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi</ENAMEX> relies on its famous
brand name--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> rely on their stylish cuts. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> story
counters the popular wisdom that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> is in trouble. (See

                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Falling Arches</ENAMEX>.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> still maintains a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>-percent
market share compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger King</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19 percent</NUMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reappraisal</ENAMEX> continues: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> is witty and charming, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">wonderful</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropist</ENAMEX>, and a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX> was.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 11</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News puts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unabomber</ENAMEX> case on the cover. An article outlines <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kaczynski</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX> defense. His lawyers
hope to ship his backwoods shack to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX> so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> will understand that
only a crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> could live there. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Una</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kaczynski</ENAMEX> pens a
plea for no death penalty: "There is no way around the fear and
sorrow that comes with knowing you may have a hand in causing the death of
someone you love ... these crimes were the product of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>, rather than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evil</ENAMEX>." Other stories warn of biological terrorism and detail the growing legion
of federal counter-terrorism programs. Also, an article says <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> bug is not the only computer
nightmare on the horizon. The new euro, based on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> different currencies,
could wreak havoc with financial computing.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 11</TIMEX>)
            

            A paean
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet</ENAMEX> explains his famous ear for dialogue: a childhood
with a tough labor<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-lawyer father</ENAMEX>. "In my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> ... we liked to while away the
evenings by making ourselves miserable, solely based on our ability to speak
the language viciously." His <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> marriage and his bucolic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> retreat
have soothed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mamet</ENAMEX> without softening his brutal work. An article doubts that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">new Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> publisher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Willes</ENAMEX> (a k a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cap'n Crunch"</ENAMEX>) is as
dangerous as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> fear. Willes may breach some barriers between editorial
and business, but his optimism about the newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> is inspiring--he
wants to raise circulation <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>. (See 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Assessment</ENAMEX> of
Willes for a similar take.) Also, the horrible life story of abortion-clinic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">murderer John Salvi</ENAMEX>. His loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> didn't recognize the incipient signs of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>, and so never sought psychiatric treatment for him.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 11</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
package crows over <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> election victories. An analysis of the elections
argues that "the lessons from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> are fairly simple. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> win if they
promise to cut taxes. They lose or come uncomfortably close to losing if they
don't." Another article says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> won re-election was his
strong connection to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s long-neglected outer-borough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>. A story
claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has moved to the left now that he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame duck</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> recently criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>-tax cut in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and attended the dinner
of a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, things he wouldn't have done before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> election.
Also, a review marks the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bonfire</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vanities</ENAMEX> , noting its undue pessimism: "After all, the economic boom
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1980s</ENAMEX> is still humming in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> itself is a vastly cleaner,
safer place than the city <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> described. ... Even the graffiti on the subway
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, so lovingly described in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bonfire</ENAMEX> , have been cleaned up."

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 11</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story calls the failure to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributor</ENAMEX> for the
new film version of Lolita <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more example of our misplaced puritanism:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Statutes like ... the Child Pornography Prevention Act</ENAMEX> are our home-grown
fairy tales, ghostly adumbrations of the hysteria that swept over us in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eighties</ENAMEX>. We know perfectly well that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are most at risk at home, from
their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult friends</ENAMEX>." An editorial blasts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.M. Rosenthal</ENAMEX>'s "shameless sycophancy" toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>. Also, an essay
says that working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> are the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">au pair</ENAMEX> murder case. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> have demonized them.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
