
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 30, 1998</TIMEX> )

            The
cover editorial deplores rich <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' lack of charity.
The newly wealthy don't give enough and don't give creatively. They are
breaking the "unspoken contract that underpins the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dream." ...
An editorial urges strong sanctions for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> in light of its nuclear tests.
We must deter potential future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">testers</ENAMEX> by making an example of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>,
despite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s inevitable claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> started it and that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> is a
richer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, better able to withstand sanctions. ... Latest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>
angle: Can it save endangered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>? Among the endangered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> poached for
aphrodisiacs are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX> (for their penises--made into a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX>) and rhinoceroses
(for their horns--made into a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">powder</ENAMEX>). We'll pass on "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>-penis <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>,"
apparently a hit in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 31</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 30, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story follows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> seeking opportunity amid the economic chaos in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> will determine which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and businesses
bounce back and which don't. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bet</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> to make it.) Big
surprise: The opening of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' books has shown they were horribly
run, debt-laden <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">messes</ENAMEX>, even during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the boom years</TIMEX>. ... A story wonders
why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Brown</ENAMEX> wants to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of the entire
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state, Brown</ENAMEX> now seeks to fix potholes. Minority mayoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> see
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paternalism</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s campaign. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX> black.)

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 29, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
piece says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have a new strategy for winning back <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
congressional seats: Be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. Some of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>" candidates
pro-life, pro-death-penalty, anti-union, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>-control, and
pro-school-prayer. Party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> will do anything to regain a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>.
... A story defends the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scholastic Assessment Test</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SATs</ENAMEX> are blamed for
perpetuating racial bias at elite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, but actually they are a good measure
of where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> stand and of what sort of education best suits them. ... A
story praises the experiment of a public boarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>. The
school, which receives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of its funding from donations, distances inner-city
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> from the distractions they face at home. While not workable on a grand
scale, the idea holds promise for areas where donations would be plentiful.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GQ</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 29, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A
chilling story about an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s murder of his mail-order <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> exposes
the dark side of the hired-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> industry. The brides (most of them <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Filipinas</ENAMEX>)
marry to escape poverty. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> promise money to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brides</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, then
often treat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> as sex slaves, or worse. ... An essay claims
popular culture is now so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>-oriented that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have no model for mature
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adulthood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX> personifies the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>--feminized and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">juvenile</ENAMEX>, with no interests beyond his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 27, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover piece
gushes over <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Truman Show</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX>'s forthcoming film. The movie,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who's unaware that his whole life is televised, leaves "the viewer
with a spectral feeling that somehow warms: the shiver of radiance." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carrey</ENAMEX>'s
performance is deemed brilliant. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> also raves, calling the film
"miraculous" and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Carrey</ENAMEX> vehicle "that is anywhere near as complicated
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrey</ENAMEX> himself." ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story praises the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Rivers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>-based crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighter/man</ENAMEX> of faith. Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
programs like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivers</ENAMEX>' combine religion, no-nonsense attitude, and partnerships
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> to keep good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and send irredeemable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to
jail.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> says organic
food often contains <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX> from rainwater or dust and is no more nutritious
or tasty than conventionally grown <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fare</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's package on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> antitrust case features an interview
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Klein</ENAMEX>; thumbnail sketches of the major
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>; a long rundown of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s many holdings, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX>, and
investments; and a short history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>'s meteoric rise and subsequent
fragility.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 27, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story says the antitrust case isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s biggest
worry. In fact, ingenious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PalmPilot</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s own
lumbering hugeness may be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s undoing. ... A story claims identity theft is the "crime of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Thieves</ENAMEX>
steal your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> number to gain loans and charge cards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX> hunt you, and once your credit rating goes south it's nearly
impossible to restore it.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 27, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> marvels at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>'s phenomenal skills as a ... corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pitchman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> is the greatest endorser in history because he's "at once
credible and incredible"--an unbelievable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> and a warm, charming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>, who's interviewed, comes across as very smart, rather conservative, and
much less avaricious than you might expect. There is a jaw-dropping list of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>-endorsed products, including potholders and first-aid kits. ... A
piece pegged to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> investigation deplores the law's increasing
indifference to privacy. Virtually any diary or utterance to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> can now
be used against you. Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years ago</TIMEX> such invasions would have been
unconscionable, but they are now commonplace, thanks to bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
decisions. Sadly, only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX> are battling this erosion of privacy.
... A review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim McDougal</ENAMEX>'s book says it's a "devastating portrait"
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and implicates the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> "in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least four</NUMEX> felonies."

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 27, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> installment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> 's attack on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Entertainment</ENAMEX>
State." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time</TIMEX> is television. A foldout chart shows that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>
virtually all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> and cable television. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exceptions</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, and the
Weather <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Articles</ENAMEX> chronicle the phenomenal efforts by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>,
especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX>, to protect their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchises</ENAMEX> by lobbying
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. How can regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> fight corporate television? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX>
urges challenges to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> licenses: Such challenges force TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> to pay attention to public-interest programming or risk going off the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">air</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 27, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
package condemns the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy and labels <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">upcoming China</ENAMEX> trip the "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square Summit</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is blasted for
taking donations from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, facilitating technology
transfer to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, and appeasing the still brutal, still <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictatorship</ENAMEX>. A piece acknowledges that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> also allowed
technology transfers to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> but says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> monitored such
transfers much better than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
