
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  The
Gospel According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Son</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX>'s latest act of literary chutzpah--an autobiography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>--fails
spectacularly. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX> calls it a "silly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-important</ENAMEX> and at times inadvertently comical book." Criticisms: The
language is stilted and predictable, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX>'s only additions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>
story being the lust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> feels in his heart and the hard time he has with
celebrity. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Kermode</ENAMEX> defends <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mailer</ENAMEX>; in an erudite reading of the book
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX>, he attributes to Mailer the subtlety of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologian</ENAMEX>--whose "powerful mind," however, "works in a specialized way, not
by theological argument but by telling or retelling a story."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Pastoral
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Roth</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houghton Mifflin</ENAMEX>). The best of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> novels published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX> by postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> novelists
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bellow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX>). Some say it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>'s best ever. "Never before has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX> written fiction with such clear conviction. Never before has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>
assembled so many fully formed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> or shuttled so authoritatively
through time" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.Z. Sheppard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). Narrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>'s fictional alter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ego Nathan Zuckerman</ENAMEX>, it is the story of an assimilated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> whose life is
shattered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weathermen Underground</ENAMEX>-style rebellion.
He has "created a resonant parable of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> innocence and disillusion"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kakutani</ENAMEX>). In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wood</ENAMEX>
calls the book a "little slow," lacking the manic energy of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX>
novels. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> plugs his book.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">W.B. Yeats: A Life</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apprentice Mage</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865-1914</TIMEX>
               , by R.F.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford University Press</ENAMEX>). Coming after a long line of mediocre
biographies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> volume of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-part biography by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Oxford historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Foster</ENAMEX> is greeted warmly. It "integrates <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> history
impressively into the complex fabric of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>'s life" says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Beckson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX> "would be relieved to know ...
that the biographer is himself a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, bearing with grace his knowledge
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> history, and writing with wit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> and, when appropriate,
considerable eloquence," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Flanagan</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book</ENAMEX>
Review . (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Wood</ENAMEX>'s enthusiastic review in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purple America</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Moody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little, Brown, and Co.</ENAMEX>). As with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moody's</ENAMEX> last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> novels ( <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garden State</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ice Storm</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>
can't decide whether the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> is a hip <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Updike</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX> wannabe.
(This novel deals with a decaying suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and a
decaying suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> nuclear power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Burroway</ENAMEX> calls him "a chronicler of the middle class for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">millennium</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheppard</ENAMEX> says that the novel's "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are
emotionally intricate, and its tensions adroitly controlled." Others think he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overwrites</ENAMEX>. "This is a novel that doesn't seem written, but declaimed, in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WASP Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> style, from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darien pulpit"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight Garner</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Television
            

            
               
                  In
the Gloaming
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>, click here for
a schedule). Who would criticize quadriplegic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Reeve</ENAMEX>'s
directorial debut? Almost nobody. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> concede the made-for-TV tawdriness
of this <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> movie starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Sean Leonard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Close</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget Fonda</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoopi Goldberg</ENAMEX>: pat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and a tear-jerker plot. But the screenplay
is said to redeem the melodrama. It is "artful and literate" says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX>. Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Tucker</ENAMEX>
says it "is superior to any domestic drama <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> has released in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a decade</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Marin</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> to brave
a negative judgment: "That [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reeve</ENAMEX>] can direct at all is impressive. Too bad the
movie isn't." (A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> for the show is available on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>'s site.)

            

               Opera
            

            
               
                  The
Ring of the Nibelung
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Wagner</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Opera Company</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). High praise for an all-star rendition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagner</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-opera
cycle (the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> installment was performed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>). Kudos mostly for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conductor James Levine</ENAMEX>'s "thrilling reading of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wagner's</ENAMEX> emotion-magnifying
score" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Kozinn</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Also lauded are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX>,
an ensemble of the world's greatest that includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Placido Domingo</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">soprano Deborah Voigt</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bass</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Morris</ENAMEX>. "This was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Age</ENAMEX> stuff--a
reminder that not all greatness lies in the past, that not all the best
performances are contained on crackly old recordings adorned with sepia
photographs," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Nordlinger</ENAMEX>.

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Murder at 1600
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Brothers</ENAMEX>). Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> murder
mystery and a chance to bash the genre. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gripes: 1</ENAMEX>) It' a product of classic
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> opportunism, cashing in on widepread cynicism about presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ethics</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) This particular instance of it stinks. "A whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> full
of clich√©s," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX>. Not even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley Snipes</ENAMEX>'
considerable charisma can compensate for the ridiculous plot. "Serviceable at
passing the time, if nothing else is available," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">s'</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>. (For stills, clips, and the like, see the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1600</TIMEX> site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kissed</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orion</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> mostly applaud this movie about a female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">necrophiliac</ENAMEX> who works in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral home</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delicacy</ENAMEX> and lyricism ... underscore
the mystical rather than gruesome aspects of ... a consuming addiction," says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Sragow</ENAMEX>, writing in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Times Los Angeles</ENAMEX> , calls Kissed "ridiculously earnest. I kept
hoping that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cleese</ENAMEX> would appear out of nowhere, and say, in the high
dudgeon of his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead Parrot</ENAMEX> routine, 'They're dead! They're deceased!' " (See
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kissed</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               Updates:
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> weigh in: In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Foreman</ENAMEX> bashes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">novelist Patrick Chamoiseau</ENAMEX>'s highly praised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>, calling it "ponderous, self-indulgent, and overwhelmingly
mediocre." Westerners only like it, he says, because they are obsessed with
"getting into the minds of 'primitive' ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns:
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16:</TIMEX>

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso: The</ENAMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anaconda</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grosse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pointe Blank</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- An
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Daughter</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naked</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Sedaris</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flower</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penelope Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Gut
Symmetries , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanette Winterson</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inventions</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Hare: Poems <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1909-1917</TIMEX> , by T.S.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliot</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Ricks</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:</TIMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doll</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX>
Road ;

            
               Movie -- Inventing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbotts</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- That Old</ENAMEX>
Feeling ;

            
               Book --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Ginsberg</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1926-1997</TIMEX>);

            
               Book -- After the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madness</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Own Prison Memoir</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sol Wachtler</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Big Picture</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Kennedy</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Chamoiseau</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose-Myriam R√</ENAMEX>©jouis and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Val Vinokurov</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics of Celebrity</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Wills</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Divorce</ENAMEX>
Culture , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Dafoe Whitehead</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sons</ENAMEX>
of Heaven <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Daughters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fernanda Eberstadt</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil</ENAMEX>'s
Own ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Chasing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Young Man From Atlanta</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:</TIMEX>

            
               Event -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">69 th Academy Awards</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1997 Biennial</ENAMEX>
Exhibition" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum of American Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willem de Kooning</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904-1997</TIMEX>);

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Liar</ENAMEX>
Liar ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Crash</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Selena</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The Coming
Conflict with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross H. Munro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bernstein</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Radical Son: A Journey Through Our Times</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horowitz</ENAMEX>.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
