
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 28</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, March 28</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , like everyone else, is baffled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s recent
dismissal of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>. The cover editorial says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is in surprisingly
decent economic shape, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s infirmity could quash reforms and lead to
"crony capitalism" or possibly even communism. ... An editorial slams
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s recent moves toward becoming a nuclear power. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hemmed</ENAMEX> in by unreliable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">neighbors</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> has not signed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nuclear</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Non-Proliferation Treaty</ENAMEX>, and will shortly hold a confidence vote to explore
going nuclear. The move would boost the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s popularity but would
provoke worldwide trade sanctions and heighten regional tensions. ... A
story explains a new theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">algae</ENAMEX> create wind. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Algae</ENAMEX> on the surface of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ocean</ENAMEX> emit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX> that heat the air. The pressure change stirs up wind, which
lifts the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">algae</ENAMEX> off the water and up into the clouds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">algae</ENAMEX> then travel in
the clouds and are redistributed by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 27</TIMEX>)
            

            A story
warns of the flood of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> merchandise about to hit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. Scandal-related
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T-shirts</ENAMEX>, wigs, berets, dolls, and sex toys are all part of what novelty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> hope will be an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80 million</NUMEX> payday. A pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriotic</ENAMEX> Profits hopes to block the exploitation. ... The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB"</ENAMEX> column
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> score poorly on standardized tests because they don't take
test-prep courses. A prep course, which typically costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$900</NUMEX>, can boost LSAT
scores <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> points on a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>-point scale. ... An article argues that,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buchananites</ENAMEX> to the contrary, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is not a nativist, xenophobic
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> generally support immigration, and our laws still welcome
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">law-abiding</ENAMEX>, self-supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 26</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>'s success in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> marks his arrival as the first
important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dag Hammarskjöld</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> was chosen
partly because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> thought he would be "more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>," but he has proved to be a wily <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiator</ENAMEX>, restrained and persuasive.
He now must convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to accept a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>--and
to pay the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> it owes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. (For 
                  Slate
               's take
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>.")
... A story follows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Bono</ENAMEX>'s bid to assume her late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX>'s
seat in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Widowhood</ENAMEX> wins votes: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1916 and 1993</TIMEX>, "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84 percent</NUMEX> of
first-time female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> who were running to succeed their
dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> won their races." <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 14 percent</NUMEX> of other first-time female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> won. Bono leads all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> despite lacking any political
experience. On her side: Her main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> is best known for having played <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Waltons</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> split over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's revelations: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Willey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Steele</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX>
asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> to lie to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> to confirm <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Willey</ENAMEX>'s
claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> groped her). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> took revenge on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaun Docking</ENAMEX> by faking a pregnancy and miscarriage and asking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> to lie about it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Landow</ENAMEX>, accused of trying to silence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s
testimony against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, may in fact have been the target of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s
romantic advances--"an easy mark for a calculating gold digger."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's story grants that some flaws have been exposed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Willey</ENAMEX>'s
character but asserts that her story regarding her encounter with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> (as
told to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last July</TIMEX>) has remained unchanged. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> print
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s letters to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, post-incident, in which she <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobbies</ENAMEX> for a job.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> goes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News , with a "news you can use" education cover package. It claims parents
are hiring tutors to supplement their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s public-school educations. Why?
To counteract mushy curricula (whole math, multiculturalism) and keep pace on
the highly competitive college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> (more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plagiarism</ENAMEX>) also ranks the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> public high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story, pegged to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> tour, says the continent
is not the economic basket case it used to be: A number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eritrea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mali</ENAMEX>) are embracing free market capitalism and thriving.
... Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> visits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and rejects
claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> exploits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> are "modern, clean, well
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lighted</ENAMEX> and ventilated, and paying decent wages by local standards." However,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> still have no voice at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and "fear reprisal from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>."
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24</TIMEX>)
            

            Like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> goes with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> cover story. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
calculates the cost of raising a child <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from birth to age 22</TIMEX>: more
than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.45 million</NUMEX>. Most of that is lost parental wages, but the average
middle-class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,920</NUMEX> per year to feed. Nachos aren't
cheap.
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> applauds the growing automation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computers</ENAMEX> using
statistical evidence make more accurate diagnoses than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, who are misled
by irrelevant "human" factors. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> have responded by becoming more
like computers: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> does nothing but hernia operations, and
its automaton-like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> have become the world's best hernia surgeons.
... An essay claims, regretfully, that we lose our taste for new music,
food, and fashion by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 35</TIMEX>. It's possible to have big, new ideas after that
age, but usually you have to change disciplines to do so. ... The lead
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> in the large fashion package is a profile of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">fabulous monster</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leigh</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowery</ENAMEX>, a profoundly weird, masochistic clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>/performance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowery</ENAMEX> wore scab makeup and pubic wigs, dribbled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glue</ENAMEX> over his skull, slept
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> cozy on his head, and vomited and shat on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
fashion world adored him, of course. (He was also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucian Freud</ENAMEX>'s chief
model.)

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> predicts a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> landslide in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> elections but a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> victory
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> (because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> want a split <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>). The scandals, plus the
traditional off-year swing against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, will drive voters
toward clean-cut <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> runs a
damaging still taken from an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> videotape: The prez is gripping the thigh
of the flight attendant seated next to him on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> campaign flight. In the
next frame (not shown), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendant</ENAMEX> allegedly pushes away <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s hand.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story defends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Carey</ENAMEX>, ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Teamsters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, claiming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> was unfairly
booted from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> without due process. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> may be guilty of
laundering campaign money, much evidence suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> was unaware of
their transgressions. ... An essay calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> to stop bashing
organized religion. There needs to be a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Left</ENAMEX>" that recognizes the
strong faith much of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> holds. ... A "manifesto" proclaims the
beginning of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Technorealism</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>: strong ambivalence toward
technology, shunning of both technophobia and technophilia. For

                  Slate
               's take on the movement, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Readme</ENAMEX>" from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
21.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
