
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Donnie Brasco
                (TriStar/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX>). Despite a general expression of
weariness with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> movies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donnie Brasco</ENAMEX> is deemed a critical success.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> give <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> reasons: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy pairing</ENAMEX> of unusual moral complexity
between an undercover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Depp</ENAMEX>) and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Pacino</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
Nuanced acting from the usually overwrought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacino</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> turn by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Depp</ENAMEX>, who
delivers "an intense, quietly flawless performance" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ). (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donnie Brasco</ENAMEX> site has stills, clips, and a game that enables
virtual infiltration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smilla</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sense of Snow</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox Searchlight Pictures/20 th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Fox</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> extol the charms of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Ormond</ENAMEX> but pan
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bille</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>'s adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Hoeg</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> best-selling
glaciological whodunit. "What will surprise everyone is the dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">iciness</ENAMEX>, the
burning coldness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ormond's Smilla</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX>. The
movie itself is said to be a muddle. The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafferty</ENAMEX> describes it as "a ghost story that thinks it's a murder mystery,"
complete with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arctic Circle</ENAMEX> chase scenes at the end. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soggy Euro</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pudding</ENAMEX>," says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Independent</ENAMEX> .

            

               Music
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helfgott World Tour</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> decry the exploitation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Helfgott</ENAMEX>,
the mentally ill former piano <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prodigy</ENAMEX> and subject of the biopic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shine</ENAMEX> ,
as a "freak show" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> ). They point out that during
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> leg of his tour in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, he lost his place in midperformance,
screamed while playing, and wandered into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Helfgott</ENAMEX>
Plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachmaninov</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCA</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/Victor</ENAMEX>), currently No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Billboard</ENAMEX> 's
classical-music charts, is "more listenable than his live recitals," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , but it is "still muddy, noisy and boring."

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crisis Center</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fridays</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m. EST</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s
latest dramatic series insufferable. Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX> says
the show, which focuses on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>, "has
the disconcerting effect of a neon sign flashing, 'We're doing television that
makes a difference.' " (In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> episode, underage <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clothed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> are prevented from committing suicide, and a kidnapped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> with
spina bifida is returned to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX> suggests another name for the
series: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Bunch of Klutzes Who Should Mind Their Own Business</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s plug for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crisis Center</ENAMEX> .)

            

               
                  Feds
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesdays</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. EST</TIMEX>). Law & Order
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Wolf</ENAMEX>'s latest law-enforcement drama is anointed the
best among the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">midseason</TIMEX> shows. Despite the familiarity of its premise
(government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> hunt down <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX> and prosecute them), it is said to be
less than formulaic. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Leonard</ENAMEX> praises the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>, which
includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Brown</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Days and Nights</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Dodd</ENAMEX> ) and Regina
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> ( I'll Fly Away ). (See the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Feds</ENAMEX> page on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>
site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Arsenio</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesdays</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 p.m. EST</TIMEX>). Former late-night
talk-show host <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arsenio Hall</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> that he wanted his sitcom
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a</NUMEX> cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sportscaster</ENAMEX> to be a conventional comedy about black urban
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> agree that it's a conventional comedy. "The show has all
the flair of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> shirt set off by a rep tie," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ginia Bellafante</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  Just <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shoot Me</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, premieres <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 4</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 p.m. EST</TIMEX>;
regular air time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesdays</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 p.m. EST</TIMEX>). Yet another sitcom about a
single female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, this one has a high-profile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Segal</ENAMEX>;
sex, lies, and 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">videotape</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Giacomo</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday</ENAMEX>
Night 
               Live 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Spade</ENAMEX>). "If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> wanted to clone its sitcoms, you
think it could aim higher than Suddenly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX> and The 
               Naked
Truth ," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Roush</ENAMEX>. (Preview the show on the
Just <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shoot Me</ENAMEX> page.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Crazy 
                  Rhythms: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All That Jazz</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leonard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garment</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Books</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Garment</ENAMEX> emerges as the
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>--a charming neurotic, free of self-importance and attentive to
emotional nuance. Reviewers focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garment</ENAMEX>'s past as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clarinetist</ENAMEX>, on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s insecurities, and on the unlikely friendship between the anti-Semite
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Count Metternich</ENAMEX>, meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas DeFrank</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>).

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novel Roundup</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> award measured
praise to 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lives of the Monster Dogs</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirsten Bakis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Straus & Giroux</ENAMEX>), and 
                  Fugitive Pieces
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anne Michaels</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lives of the Monster Dogs</ENAMEX> tells the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> outfitted
with voice boxes and prosthetic hands who move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and become
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">socialites</ENAMEX>. "Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bakis</ENAMEX>, with admirable audacity, has set herself the almost
impossible task of making these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs 'human</ENAMEX>' and just misses the mark," says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> . Fugitive Pieces is a poetic telling of the life of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX>-turned-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>. "Her prose does not race; it hovers,
insinuating its way in and around timeless mysteries," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . Both
novels, however, are said to be excessively self-conscious. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> also
considers 
                  Necessary Madness
               , by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenn Crowell</ENAMEX> (G.P.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Putnam's</ENAMEX>), noteworthy. The book itself, the story of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, is unimpressive. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s precociousness has already
led to the sale of the foreign rights and to a major movie deal.

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Night</TIMEX> of Ballyhoo
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Hayes Theater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>). The new play by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Uhry</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Driving Miss Daisy</ENAMEX> )--a romantic comedy about self-hating
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> on the eve of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>--is said to teeter between the "the
serious-comedy tradition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Simon</ENAMEX>'s autobiographical trilogy" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
Winer, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ) and sitcom schmaltz. "Its form is the theatrical
equivalent of comfort <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, something for those who like their nostalgia
repackaged in the guise of something new," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brantley</ENAMEX>. Variety predicts several <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tony Award nominations</ENAMEX>.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>
Strikes Back: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Special Edition</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Lost</ENAMEX>
Highway ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rosewood</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schindler</ENAMEX>'s List ;

            
               Television -- Miss
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boys</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Monster:</ENAMEX>
Living <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Off the Big Screen</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gregory Dunne</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book--
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Sphinx: The Character of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph J. Ellis</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whittaker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SamTanenhaus</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:</TIMEX>

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie
               --Absolute
Power ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Blood</ENAMEX> and
Wine ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gladstone</ENAMEX>: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Jenkins</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asylum</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick McGrath</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Hungry
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ghosts: Mao's Secret Famine</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jasper Becker</ENAMEX>;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Darger</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unreality</ENAMEX> of Being."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:</TIMEX>

            
               CD -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Boone</ENAMEX> in a
Metal Mood: No More Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nice Guy</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Boone</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dante</ENAMEX>'s
Peak ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- When We Were</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kings</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prisoner</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mountains</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falls</ENAMEX>
Away: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Memoir , by Mia Farrow</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Before the
Dawn: An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Autobiography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Adams</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- A Supposedly
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fun Thing</ENAMEX> I'll <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never Do Again: Essays and Arguments</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Foster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chris Rock Show</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- Personal
History , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Graham</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- What It Means
to Be a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Libertarian: A Personal Interpretation</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Do the
Windows <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open</ENAMEX>? , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Hecht</ENAMEX>;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Gridlock'd</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Waiting for</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guffman</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willem de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kooning: The Late Paintings, the 1980s"</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Men Are</ENAMEX>
From <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mars, Women Are From Venus</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Event --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On Cultural Power: The Wilson-Brustein Discussion</ENAMEX>."

            
               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
