
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Ronin
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Artists</ENAMEX>). The only thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> can agree on about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Manchurian Candidate</ENAMEX> ) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankenheimer</ENAMEX>'s supposed "comeback" film
is that the car chases are so phenomenal that they redefine the form. As for
whether the rest of the film (in which a group of post-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mercenaries</ENAMEX> led by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX> pursues a mysterious suitcase around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>)
succeeds, that depends on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>. Some call the film "empty--a joyless
thrill ride" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). Others find the
MacGuffin-ish plot "rife with delicious ambiguity" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael O'Sullivan</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). (Visit the official site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Legend</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Entertainment/TriStar Pictures</ENAMEX>). A
clever idea--incorporating common urban myths into a traditional horror
movie--paired with so-so execution results in a lukewarm set of reviews.
Despite the shock-film novelty of poodles in microwaves, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> dismiss
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Legend</ENAMEX> as yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scream</ENAMEX> wannabe--long on fresh-from-TV
teen cuties and short on substance or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>. In other words, "a teen-age
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moviegoer</ENAMEX>'s dream" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Gates</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) but "utterly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uninspired"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ty Burr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). (Join an online chat about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Legend</ENAMEX> .)

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  Two
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Cities</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Edgar Wideman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houghton-Mifflin</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Cliff</ENAMEX> calls
the latest novel from the much-lauded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of The 
               Cattle
Killing "a stunning portrait of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> lives ... in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX>-colored
landscape of the present" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> ). Mixing intimate life stories
with larger elements of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>'s urban landscape such as Move, the
radical back-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that was firebombed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, the
novel shifts seamlessly among viewpoints and time frames. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> concur
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff</ENAMEX>'s assessment, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bernstein</ENAMEX> writes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review</ENAMEX> that the book is "so focused on darkness and degradation as to
be demagogic in its effect" and calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wideman's</ENAMEX> version of history "distorted"
and "troubling." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kirn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brent Staples</ENAMEX>' discussion of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Cities</ENAMEX> in 
                  Slate
               's "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Club</ENAMEX>.")

            

               Opera
            

            
               
                  A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Streetcar Named Desire</ENAMEX>
                (performed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Opera</ENAMEX>). Flawed
but not without merit, classical phenomenon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">André Previn</ENAMEX>'s operatic adaptation
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee Williams</ENAMEX> play is called "an unexpected letdown" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terry</ENAMEX>
Teachout, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). Noting that the "formidable reputation" of the play is
"itself an obstacle" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Ross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> seem
apologetic for their negative reviews. After describing the production as
heavy-handed in its use of melodrama, or the music clichéd, each reviewer makes
a point of singling out a few elements of the show for praise.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katrine Ames</ENAMEX> is the opera's most passionate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX>, calling
the score "rich with color, by turns lush, frantic, heartbreaking, even funny."
(Here is a calendar of performance dates.)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  Painted From Memory
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Costello</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burt Bacharach</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX>). Expecting kitschy nouveau-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are pleased to find a
"sublime and subtle beauty" in the heartfelt, rich album from this unlikely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pair</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Browne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costello</ENAMEX>'s lyrics are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pared-down</ENAMEX> and unusually taut, and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bacharach</ENAMEX>'s arrangements for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-piece
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orchestra</ENAMEX> should make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babyface</ENAMEX> weep in envy" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Kot</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> ). Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costello</ENAMEX>'s voice is not quite up
to the task presented by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bacharach</ENAMEX>'s complex melodies, but this is deemed only
a minor irritation. (Listen to a clip from the album.)

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  Felicity
                (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Early</ENAMEX> reviews for this
sensitive, intelligent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>-goes-to-college drama--by far the most "hotly
anticipated new show" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Newman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times )--are mildly approving, but the show doesn't come close to meeting
the high expectations created by the pre-season buzz. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> calls it "pretty good, gooey, yearning, adolescent fun," and
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Tucker</ENAMEX> calls it "a solid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> soap opera."

                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kerr</ENAMEX> is more positive than most, placing it far
above <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX> (a common comparison) for the way it "adores its
confused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and burrows inside their heads to find a deeper humor,
warmer but also more raw." (Read the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerr</ENAMEX>'s review.)

            

               Art
            

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Eyck</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruegel</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Early Netherlandish Painting</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of</ENAMEX>
Art" (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> gush over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>'s exhibit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>
paintings from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>. (The paintings are from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>'s collection
but are ordinarily scattered around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>.) The straightforward
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chronological</ENAMEX> order and detailed explanations of the workshop system of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, coupled with the high caliber of the art, makes for a show that is "both
intellectually stimulating and unexpectedly poignant" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Stevens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> ). This "dazzling show of strength" is a testament to the "unrivalled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Netherlandish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> who invented the oil paint medium" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holland</ENAMEX>
Cotter, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (Find out more
about the exhibition.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">23:</TIMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
Report ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bag</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bones</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Model
Behavior , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay McInerney</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Birds</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorrie Moore</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Rush</ENAMEX>
Hour ;

            
               Movie -- Permanent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Midnight</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- A Soldier's Daughter Never Cries</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rounders</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- One True</ENAMEX>
Thing ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birch</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Touch of
Evil ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melissa Müller</ENAMEX>;

            
               Music -- Mechanical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX>;

            

               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teatro</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Nelson</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Without
Limits ;

            
               Movie -- Knock
Off ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next Stop</ENAMEX>
Wonderland ;

            
               Death --Akira
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurosawa</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madman</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Winchester</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- At Home in the World</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Maynard</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Blade</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Why Do
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fools Fall in Love</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farming</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bones</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edwidge Danticat</ENAMEX>;

            

               Music -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Miseducation of Lauryn Hill</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lauryn Hill</ENAMEX>.

            
               --Eliza
Truitt
            

         
      
   
