
   
   
      
         
            

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 3, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story reviews a new book calling for more single-child <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. The book
argues that only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> receive closer parental attention and that limiting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> will stop environmental decay. In fact, says the review, only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are no better off than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, and overpopulation
may be an overhyped myth. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> start having fewer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> as technology and industry improve--conditions generally linked with
environmental decline. ... A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> essay says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are too
worshipful of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founding Fathers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. Our nitpicking
exegesis of ancient texts limits our ability to innovate.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 2, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A story
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">profiles Interior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Babbitt</ENAMEX>, now under investigation for lying to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babbitt</ENAMEX> is a fine, upstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> caught in an
inconsequential transgression. ... The cover piece celebrates <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardinal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX>'s remarkable home run prowess. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX> is having a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX>, compares favorably with the all-time greatest sluggers, and may
well crush the record for most homers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a season</TIMEX>. His secret: a smooth,
concise, brutally powerful swing--not to mention <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20-inch</NUMEX> biceps.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 30, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover package examines <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> culture. A photo essay shows
ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> posing with their firearms. An interview with new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle Association</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> reveals his extremism: He is quoted on white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supremacist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Duke</ENAMEX>'s
Web site and has said that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s cultural shock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> ... claim it's time
to place homosexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy scouts</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heston</ENAMEX> blames violent rap
lyrics for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s decline but does not apologize for his many ultraviolent
movie roles. (For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" in

                  Slate
               .) A separate article considers a new study arguing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">concealed</ENAMEX> weapons lower crime rates. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> debate the accuracy of the
study's statistics, gun rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> embrace its message that an armed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> is a safer society. Also, an essay wonders what makes teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> tick. Conclusion: a
combination of video games, insecurity, and pure, inexplicable evil.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's upbeat cover story profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Couric</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-host</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> . Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> died of colon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, but the
smart, bubbly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Couric</ENAMEX> is as charming as ever. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> love that she colors her own
hair, wears <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX> clothes, and flies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>. Inappropriately chipper line: "She's
also a morning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> still in mourning for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 30, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The big
news at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> isn't in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owner Mort Zuckerman</ENAMEX>
has fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fallows</ENAMEX>. ... The cover
story explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s new rulings on sexual harassment.
Central changes: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Complainants no longer need to show that their careers
suffered as a result of the harassment. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> cannot plead ignorance as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX> unless they've already instituted a "strong system of dealing with
[harassment] problems." An accompanying story covers the case of a pharmaceuticals <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> with a long and
slimy history of harassing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinates</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> decided it made better
financial sense to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and pay off all the complainants.
... An article says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> is playing the race card in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> wants to indict <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> because that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> pool is far whiter than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>'s. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ninety</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> percent of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> (compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>) say they believe investigations
into the allegations involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should 'stop now.' "

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 30, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            First
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Thomason</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Bloodworth-Thomason</ENAMEX> are profiled. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> lived
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first month</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>, urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to
fight back at every turn, and helped script his denial of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomasons</ENAMEX> hate the press and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> and encourage the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> to do the same. ... A story about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> immunity says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> are pursuing the wrong kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> hope to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control HIV</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> that kill the virus. But those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who seem to
be immune to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> have "cellular immunity," in which cells, rather than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibodies</ENAMEX>, kill HIV-infected cells. Conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vaccine</ENAMEX> research should stop
focusing so much on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody-based vaccines</ENAMEX> and should consider cellular
immunity. ... An essay about spin says it doesn't work because its
targets (us) are too conscious that they are being spun. The real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> triumph of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX> is direct mail: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obviousness</ENAMEX> and repetition get better results than
subtlety.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 30, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story compares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Graham</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> chaplains of
the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> has been a presidential suck-up since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX>
administration and still makes excuses for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alleged philandering.
But the piece wonders why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> has followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>'s lead. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX>
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was "immune to shame. Move past all the nice posturing and get
really down there in him, you find absolutely nothing ... nothing but an
appetite." Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> energetically defends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s foibles.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 6 and 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 30, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story debunks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> myth. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> may ooze charm, but he's a
regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">squirmy fish</ENAMEX> (or "squish," as an unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
conservative calls him) who avoids taking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> stands. And he's not well
prepared for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>, either: He doesn't know the issues.
(For 
                  Slate
               's take on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 27, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
editorial downplays the importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trip. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has
nothing to offer in the way of partnership with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, as its economy is
fragile and its leadership infirm. The summit is a good way to "talk over"
differences, but it will produce little of import. An accompanying essay argues
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> military lacks the strength and training to compete with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> one. In fact, after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> threats, "most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> believed that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> could have repelled a cross-straits invasion even without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Navy</ENAMEX>
becoming involved." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> continues to focus on economic rather than military
growth.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
