
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  The
Royals
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kitty Kelley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Books</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity biographer</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windsor</ENAMEX>-bashing book cashes in on the hoopla surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indignant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> accuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX> of purveying unsubstantiated rumors, "the sorts
of secrets only supermarket <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids covet</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). Others yawn at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX>'s gossip, including speculation that, as a
newlywed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth</ENAMEX> was sex-crazed. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]hose who hoped that the book
would be like a royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>--flirty, flighty, zesty, yeasty--will be
disappointed" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian Barnes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unwittingly</ENAMEX>, some say,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> actually humanizes the starchy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windsors</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  Underworld
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don DeLillo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scribner</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeLillo</ENAMEX>'s epic of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--which juxtaposes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Thompson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shot Heard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Round the World</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenny Bruce</ENAMEX> concert, and a lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergei Eisenstein</ENAMEX> film--is
pronounced a "masterwork" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom LeClair</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX> ). DeLillo
wins praise for his witty prose and inventive historical fiction, which
includes such postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Edgar Hoover</ENAMEX>.
"There's pleasure on every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> of this pitch-perfect evocation of a sour,
anxious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">half century</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Jones Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kirn</ENAMEX> is
virtually alone in finding the book indulgent and vapid. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excerpt from Underworld</ENAMEX> .)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> Apes
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Self</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grove/Atlantic</ENAMEX>). Reviews of the latest
farce from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> satirist both wince and smirk at its unrelenting
scatological humor and unflattering sendups of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacks</ENAMEX>. The book's conceit--an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> awakens in a world of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX> that mirrors
modern "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Swinging London</ENAMEX>"--is alternately judged a "slender idea for satire"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kakutani</ENAMEX>) and a hilarious metaphor for "the modern urban savanna" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Krist</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerr</ENAMEX>'s review in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and here for an excerpt from the book.)

            

               Art
            

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rauschenberg: A Retrospective"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Guggenheim Museums and Ace Gallery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Spanning 400</ENAMEX> works and filling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> venues, the exhibition of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collage artist</ENAMEX>'s oeuvre --possibly "the largest retrospective of a living
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> ever" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kimmelman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> )--draws respectful,
if qualified, reviews. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> excuse failed experiments (such as paintings on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aluminum</ENAMEX>) and recent assembly-line productions (the execution of his ideas by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dozen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX>) because of the importance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s conceptual
innovations. Many grumble that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators</ENAMEX> weren't more discriminating. New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Stevens</ENAMEX> imagines a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rauschenberg</ENAMEX> mocking the exhibition's
"pumped-up size." (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX> plugs the show.)

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thousand Acres</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Touchstone Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Smiley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prize-winning</ENAMEX> novel, which relocates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Lear</ENAMEX> on an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, has been
adapted into "an ungainly, undigested assembly of 'women's issues' " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>
Ebert, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call its screenplay
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soap</ENAMEX>-operatic: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lear</ENAMEX> figure (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Robards</ENAMEX>) molests his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lange</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Pfeiffer</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Jason Leigh</ENAMEX>), who babble in lengthy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pop</ENAMEX>-psych disquisitions. Blame also goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jocelyn Moorhouse</ENAMEX> ( How
to Make an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Quilt</ENAMEX> ), who quit the film midproduction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lange</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pfeiffer</ENAMEX> win compliments for strong performances, "emotionally in sync" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stills</ENAMEX> and clips are available here.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ice Storm</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox Searchlight Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ang Lee</ENAMEX>'s drama about suburban
sexual promiscuities is lauded as an authentic depiction of 1970s emotional
drift. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> "captures ... this garish and confused moment in history, with
surgical precision" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). Performances by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kline</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Allen</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigourney Weaver</ENAMEX> are said to be so solid that they
compensate for the unlikability of their characters. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> wins praise for his
"gently ironic touch" in adapting a novel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Moody</ENAMEX>, and for being "less
interested in assigning blame for all the misery than in simply documenting it"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daphne Merkin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). (The movie is plugged here. And
check out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slate "Diary</ENAMEX>" by
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ice Storm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Schamus</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Veronica's Closet</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thursdays</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 p.m.</TIMEX>). Finally, a sitcom
aired between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> that is said to live up to the
demands of its time slot. Praise goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirstie Alley</ENAMEX>, who plays an aging
ex-model now in the lingerie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>: "Less frenetic than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX>, more mature
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Mary"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
Shales dissents, calling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alley</ENAMEX> unwatchably neurotic and "in a virtually
perpetual feverish tizzy." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> promotes the show here.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
Confidential ;

            
               Movie -- In &
Out ;

            

               Television -- Nothing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacred</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn South</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Hayes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candle</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wind 1997</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elton John</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Jewish Heritage</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Living Memorial</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:</TIMEX>

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story of Painting</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- Ally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McBeal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>);

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- She's So</ENAMEX>
Lovely ;

            

               Movie -- <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The Farewell
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Symphony</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund White</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Nation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indivisible</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abigail Thernstrom</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">27:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G.I.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Mimic</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- Already
Dead: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gothic</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denis Johnson</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Best</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Winslow Taylor</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Enigma of Efficiency</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kanigel</ENAMEX>;

            
               Music -- The
Dance , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleetwood Mac</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good News</ENAMEX> (UPN).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cop</ENAMEX>
Land ;

            
               Movie -- The Full
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monty</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music -- Be Here</ENAMEX>
Now , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oasis</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- On the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Town</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX>);

            
               Books -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notes</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Exley</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Misfit: The Strange Life of Frederick</ENAMEX>
Exley , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Apaches</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenzo Carcaterra</ENAMEX>.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
