
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 28</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Feb. 28</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
crisis taught the world two lessons, according to the cover editorial: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
Diplomacy must be backed with the threat of violence. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) All <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> should
have stood together, instead of "taking an independent turn on the world stage
or scooping up lucrative contracts with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>." (That means you, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>!) ... An article says most corporate Web sites are badly
designed. Corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are too specialized (geared only toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>), and their jazzy graphics take too long to download.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 27</TIMEX>)
            

            The
editorial calls our failure to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> "perhaps the greatest debacle for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> foreign policy since the end of the cold war." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> agreement will
force no change in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s behavior and boosts his prestige in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world. ... The cover story says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> is hopelessly
divided by a disagreement over the correct size for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
right wants to dissolve the massive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracies</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX>
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> favor a powerful federal government
that will "use morality-driven, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> foreign policy and a series of grand
domestic initiatives to halt the right's drift into localism and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insularity</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb. 26</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story says the worship of newness is the key to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> economy. New
ideas (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3-D</NUMEX>-graphic modeling) earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions</NUMEX> and render old ideas (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2-D</NUMEX>-graphic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modeling</ENAMEX>) instantly worthless. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> move on to the next big thing
before the last big thing is even established. (Full disclosure:

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contributor Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> wrote the article. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>'
take on a related subject in 
                  Slate
               , see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scary Smart</ENAMEX>.")
... An article describes the calculated creation of a trashy hardcover
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thriller</ENAMEX>. The cynical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> analyzed best sellers, parroted them, and hired
extra <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> to fix the manuscript. They sold it for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX>. ... A
story marvels at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, ranked <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and
the best Ivy League <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> in a generation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX>'s fluid, artful passing
and selfless teamwork allow it to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> with more raw talent. The players
remain committed to their academic work. (No kidding.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 24</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX> ruins
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's unleash-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>-of-war cover package. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's war
preview includes a map listing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weaponry</ENAMEX> and its concentrations, thumbnail
sketches of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX>, a short essay from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>
explaining the need for a military strike, and a story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s
intricate security measures (he maintains surgically altered body doubles).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover package focuses on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s failure to sell the war to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> also runs an essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> in which he claims that removing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> would have upset the balance of power in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolly</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cloned sheep</ENAMEX> could be a fake. There is a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> chance that the clone was not of an adult ewe but of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> the
ewe was carrying.

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> article says 1950s "modern" furniture is back. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean</ENAMEX> lines and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blond wood</ENAMEX> are showing up everywhere, even in the furniture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friends</ENAMEX> .

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 24</TIMEX>)
            

            Graduate-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">school</ENAMEX> rankings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Winners</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> law, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> business,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> med, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> education, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> engineering. Mentioned only in
passing: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of American Law Schools</ENAMEX> requested that the magazine
stop publishing rankings because they're "misleading and dangerous." ...
An article says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' case has weakened. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> can prove
no workplace hardships (save for not getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Secretaries' Day</TIMEX>) and
can't use <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> evidence in her case. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> asks
novelists how they would solve
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> problem if it were their new book. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Collins</ENAMEX>:
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would] confess that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is his illegitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>,"
thereby explaining their close relationship and the need for secrecy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clancy</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> have a moral code from which they would not depart."

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 24</TIMEX>)
            

            A cover
feature on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>'s "religious war": The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> takes God's side.
Lawsuits are being waged to stop an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> from displaying the Ten
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commandments</ENAMEX> and to prevent a school district from allowing prayer before class
and games. Alabamians--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77 percent</NUMEX> of whom favor school prayer--are outraged by
the legal meddling, none more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fob James Jr.</ENAMEX>, a dynamite-fishing good
old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are allowed to establish religion. According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> only prohibits congressional establishment
of religion. ... Also, yet another editorial urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to
attack <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A fig</ENAMEX>-leaf compromise brokered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> would be
disastrous."

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
