
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31, 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 21, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A special
issue, published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days early</TIMEX>, is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> article blitzkrieg of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
coverage. The lead story recounts the tense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> countdown to testimony,
speculates on how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> felt during the ordeal (betrayed, then stalwart), and
dissects the legal equivocations in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Speech</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's exclusive: While
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s testimony "generally matched" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s, he flatly refused to answer
explicit questions about sex before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> and "did not acknowledge
engaging in [oral sex] with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>." ... Another story says that
turning over the infamous blue dress to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> was never part of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s immunity package. By design, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> never had the dress
tested to determine its "smoking gun" potential. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> got immunity, her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> tossed the dress to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> as a freebie anyway. ... Another article
says that scandal-weary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will seek a "straight-shooting" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. But is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> the one for the job? Can he weather the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal?
He's jammed between a rock (disloyalty) and a hard place (loyalty). And don't
forget all his dubious fund-raising phone calls--they may still lead to an
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> investigation.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 23, 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 20, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
piece profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Craig Venter</ENAMEX>, a hotshot multimillionaire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> who hopes
to map the entire human genome before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> does. Completing this
"Holy Grail" of genetics could hasten cures for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis</ENAMEX>, and even
HIV-related <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>. Venter claims he can map the genome faster and more
cheaply than the feds, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> worry that he could raise the cost of
medical research by patenting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA sequences</ENAMEX> that would otherwise be in the
public domain. ... An article marvels at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX>
required for every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> film: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX> , for example, employed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX>. Each auxiliary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> adds
humor, another adds plot structure, a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> adds dialogue that will appeal to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>. The voice of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> goes missing in action.
... A short article/diagram says <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> is not all bad. New
tobacco-based <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX>, which rely on splicing human genes into tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX>, are on the way. Bad news for cigarette fiends: The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX>--which
include antibiotics, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood substitutes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>--will be extracted
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, not smoked.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            Similar issues from top to
bottom, starting with large cover packages on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s testimony.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> touts its poll, which confirms the conventional wisdom that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should admit, apologize, and move on. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's literary
metaphor: the prez as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde</ENAMEX>, ricocheting between "solid and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">squalid</ENAMEX>, supersmart and superdumb." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover piece recaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> dogfight and opines that
"the damage has been done" to the presidency and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. A sidebar derides the "it wasn't sex" semantic escape <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
reportedly considering. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newsweeklies</ENAMEX>' bad luck: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> testimony
means the mags will be outdated by the time they hit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsstands</ENAMEX>.)

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> bombings
manhunt, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> zero in on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX>, the technosavvy,
multimillionaire <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> exile living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. They think it's unlikely
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> can capture him, and even if we do, it's not clear that he
can be prosecuted. (Here is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's version.) A tough-talk piece by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> makes the case for expanding the budget
for international affairs.

            Both
magazines cover the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glamour - Cosmopolitan</ENAMEX> shake-up: 70-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glamour Editor Ruth Whitney</ENAMEX> was axed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in favor of 41-year-old
Cosmo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie Fuller</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's longer piece likens this
to swapping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Hepburn</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> was revered for her
practicality, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fuller</ENAMEX> exudes buzz. (Here is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's shorter version.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 24 and 31</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A double
issue on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Private Lives</ENAMEX>": Much dirty laundry is aired. A piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Bellow</ENAMEX>
says his novel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herzog</ENAMEX> was inspired by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s affair with his best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>. ... The youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of famed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aviators</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anne</ENAMEX>
chronicles her life as another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindbergh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>. The kidnapping and murder of her
older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was rarely discussed, but "pretenders" claiming to be the missing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX> frequently showed up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s doorstep. ... A writer
describes his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> absurd <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in psychoanalysis. His <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80-year-old</TIMEX> analyst
rarely bothered to listen to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s problems. Instead, he liked to
discuss "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah Arendt</ENAMEX>'s sex life" and other literary gossip. When he wasn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gossiping</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> tended to fall asleep.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover
editorial urges <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> not to ignore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s other crimes
if he confesses to an affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. He still perjured himself in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> deposition and may well have obstructed justice. A related
piece says the scandal has paralyzed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>: Nothing
gets done in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potemkin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s recent daily
initiatives are merely cosmetic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Staffers</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, are trying to pretend
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> does not exist.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 15, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial on terrorism says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX>
hate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> because of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America's</ENAMEX> peacekeeping efforts in the region.
Compared to other Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is extremely hard on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, which draws the ire of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. A related piece forecasts scary "new terrorism," including
biological or poison <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> attacks within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and "cyber-attacks"
that could crash the world's financial and communications systems ... A
piece laments the "woes" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>, whose opinions on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>,
and even her pet eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> are ignored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, and
other policymakers. She seems to have "less leverage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> than
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>."

            More Flytrap
...

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Galbraith</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
