
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force One</ENAMEX>
               
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> find little resemblance between German
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfgang Petersen</ENAMEX>'s "hokey" action flick and his near-classic Das
Boot . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX>'s turn as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who goes mano a mano
with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> aboard his official <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> is deemed a "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s
fantasy of being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ). Reflecting a
general weariness with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> fare, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence Rafferty</ENAMEX> writes, "Let's hope they don't get any sillier than this."
But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX> praises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petersen</ENAMEX>'s ability to
"seduce you into greater and greater flights of preposterousness." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force One</ENAMEX> 's patriotic site, and
here
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kerr</ENAMEX>'s review of the movie in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>
               
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>). This <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Masterpiece Theatre</ENAMEX>-funded docudrama about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX>'s
unusually close "friendship" with her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> manservant is said to reflect
both the virtues and flaws of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> TV series: strong performances from
actors little known in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antony Sher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judi Dench</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connolly</ENAMEX>), but also a cloying pretentiousness and "decorousness" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). The movie "often feels pat and resolutely performed for
the camera, scene by scene," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgenstern</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Video</ENAMEX> and stills are available here.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star Maps</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Searchlight</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lukewarm</ENAMEX> reviews for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miguel Arteta</ENAMEX>'s debut film, about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teen-age Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> who aspires to make it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>,
who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pimps</ENAMEX> for him. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> agree the film is heavy on melodrama, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> is implausibly overbearing. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he metaphor ... of a father
selling his son's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> is too outré to have much resonance" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafferty</ENAMEX>, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). Arteta, however, receives praise for his "realistic" style and
"flair for caustic storytelling" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). "Star
Maps signals the arrival of a potentially major new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Slate</ENAMEX>'s take, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerr</ENAMEX>'s review.)

            

               Architecture
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Airport</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>). High marks for the new <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$450 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s
"downtown" <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> cite the "spacious" and "user-friendly" design by
the noted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Haven</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesar Pelli</ENAMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal</ENAMEX> is said to imitate
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Neo-Classical</ENAMEX> style, with rows of glass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">domes</ENAMEX> and corridors of
columns. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Forgey</ENAMEX> says the building bucks
recent trends in airport design that have "struggled to keep up with the
increasing popularity of air travel" by casting aside "such amenities as beauty
... comfort and convenience." Objecting to the enthusiasm is the New York
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Muschamp</ENAMEX>, who criticizes the presence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGI</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in the "new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Washington Mall</ENAMEX>," and sarcastically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wonders</ENAMEX>, "why shouldn't an airport strive to be <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Macy's?</ENAMEX>"

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>, Just
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Desserts: The Unauthorized Biography</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Oppenheimer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrow & Co.</ENAMEX>). The backlash against domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX> reaches
it zenith with a new biography, currently No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> '
Best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sellers</ENAMEX> list, which claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> is even more of a bitch than
previously believed. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> example: she allegedly plagiarizes recipes.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> don't quarrel much with the biography's slant, though they almost all
deride it as "mean-spirited." Maslin, however, instigates the backlash against
the backlash, calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> an "easy target," undeserving of such outraged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fulminations</ENAMEX>: "Now it can be told: little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart ate Gulden</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mustard</ENAMEX>
on white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> as an after-school snack."

            
               
                  A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of</ENAMEX>
Memories
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Nadas</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan Sanders</ENAMEX> with Imre
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldstein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar, Straus & Giroux</ENAMEX>). Newly translated into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Nadas</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">706</NUMEX>-page novel, written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, is virtually
enshrined into the canon by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. Reviews of this tale of a
bisexual <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> in 1970s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Berlin</ENAMEX> use such terms as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Proustian</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eva Hoffman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">masterpiece"</ENAMEX> (Stanislaw
Baranczak, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> ). Praise goes to the novel's lyrical prose,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">innovative</ENAMEX> (some say "difficult") <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>--which includes a novel within the
novel--and its arresting depiction of life behind the Iron Curtain. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baranczak</ENAMEX>'s
lavish review calls it "the book that you have been awaiting since you read
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Remembrance of Things Past , The Magic Mountain or The Man</ENAMEX>
Without Qualities ."

            

               Updates
            

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of</ENAMEX>
Books , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Walcott</ENAMEX> writes an effusion over his fellow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Chamoiseau</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>. "What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulysses</ENAMEX> did for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> it also did for
literature in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> , also a masterpiece, does the same for
another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Martinique</ENAMEX>, and for (here <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one swallows</NUMEX>) literature in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>."
... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panning Mason & Dixon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Wood</ENAMEX>
declares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Pynchon</ENAMEX>'s penchant for allegory tiresome and his alleged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cleverness</ENAMEX> to be overwrought and heavy-handed. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]oo much, even in this benign
book, seems willed, unfree, a hysteria that he forces onto his scenes because
without it they would not really exist."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contact</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Shall We</ENAMEX>
Dance? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">;</ENAMEX>

            
               Book--
               Lawyerland:
What Lawyers <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk About When They Talk About the Law</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Straight
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Russo</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roar</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Amy's View</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> in
Black ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Women With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ford</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Scripture: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Making the Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Maier</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX> Without
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face: The Autobiography of Communism's Greatest Spymaster</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Markus Wolf</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne McElvoy</ENAMEX>;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Haring</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum of American Art</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oz</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            

               Music --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilith Fair</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Batman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Robin</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Face/Off</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promesse</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Musical</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ragtime</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puttermesser Papers</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Ozick</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- How Proust
Can <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Change Your Life: Not a Novel</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alain de Botton</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Bright Angel Time</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha McPhee</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Speed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- My Best</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friend's Wedding</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe Theatre</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kidnapping</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel García Márquez</ENAMEX>, translated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grossman</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diving</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Butterfly</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Dominique Bauby</ENAMEX>, translated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Leggatt</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The God of
Small Things , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arundhati Roy</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perfect</ENAMEX>
Storm , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sebastian Junger</ENAMEX>;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice Biennale</ENAMEX>."

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
