
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A. Confidential</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). Raves for the adaptation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Ellroy</ENAMEX>'s acclaimed policier about the investigation of a mass
murder in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he best film of its type since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinatown</ENAMEX> ," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd McCarthy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> praise the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">all-star cast</ENAMEX> (which
includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Spacey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Basinger</ENAMEX>); the unpredictable plot twists; and the
use of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, made to evoke the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of classic film noir, as a backdrop.
The big surprise is the discovery of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curtis Hanson</ENAMEX>, who was
roundly drubbed for a previous film, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Hand That Rocks the Cradle</ENAMEX> .
"Nothing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanson</ENAMEX>'s previous work ... suggested that he would come up with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">film like L.A. Confidential</ENAMEX> " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX>, The 
               New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for stills and clips.)

            
               
                  In
& Out
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX>). A sitcom-ish comedy about an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> high school
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teacher</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Kline</ENAMEX>), the mystery of whose sexual orientation becomes the
object of a media hunt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Rudnick</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey</ENAMEX> )
strains to make the humor accessible to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle America</ENAMEX>: "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nearly every gag</TIMEX> is
pitched and underlined in the most obvious way," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX>. Some say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kline</ENAMEX>'s screwball performance rescues the film: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kline</ENAMEX>
triumphs over an incoherent idea" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ). ( In &
Out is plugged here.)

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  Nothing Sacred
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thursdays</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m. EDT/PDT</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> coo
about this new show featuring an inner-city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> who sends a parishioner to
an abortion clinic and considers breaking his own celibacy vows. The subject of
religious ambivalence is called daring, the treatment of it smart and
sophisticated. "I can't imagine how [it] ever got on the prime-time schedule,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Leonard</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kirn</ENAMEX>,
however, dissents, condemning Nothing Sacred as self-righteous "phony
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">iconoclasm</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> promotes the show.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn South</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mondays</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m. EDT/PDT</TIMEX>). What's most
original about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD Blue</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Bochco</ENAMEX>'s newest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> show,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say, is the level of gore. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nine</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> into the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> episode, a
sniper blows a chunk of brains out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. While this latest
ensemble show about an urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> precinct echoes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bochco</ENAMEX>'s other work (mainly
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hill Street Blues</ENAMEX> ), it is called "self assured and polished" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shales</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> praise its social conscience,
taking especial note of its unsparing depictions of police brutality. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">plugs</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn South</ENAMEX> .)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Hayes</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. EDT/PDT</TIMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> new
law-and-crime dramas set in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, this one--starring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD Blue</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Caruso</ENAMEX>--wins praise as "a smartly conceived genre piece" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caryn James</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Writer-producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Pileggi</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GoodFellas</ENAMEX> ) gets credit for the show's verisimilitude. Caruso, as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dour</ENAMEX>, crusading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, is called, alternatively, "credible" and "likable"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shales</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ), and humorless and "as virtuous as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvin</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ). (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s preview.)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Candle</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Wind 1997</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elton John</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocket/A&M</ENAMEX>). Overplay
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elton John</ENAMEX>'s funeral tribute to the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> provokes a backlash.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Schoemer</ENAMEX> says it's clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> "hastily reworked"
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> love letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX>. The new lyrics (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernie Taupin</ENAMEX>), she
says, are "as facile and pretty as a souvenir thimble"; the apparently hot new
genre of pop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">elegy</ENAMEX>, she adds, is tacky. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> also wins praise for refusing
to profit from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>'s death. "Even if the song continues to be inescapable, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> refuses to compound the hype," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pareles</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Heritage</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Living Memorial</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).
Overcoming skepticism about the need for yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust memorial</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> express mainly admiration. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> distinguishes itself, they say,
by focusing on aspects of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> culture other than the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are
shown as they might have liked to be remembered, rather than as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>). The
critics also praise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s somewhat eclectic displays--the shtetl
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wedding</ENAMEX> dresses, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> clips. The most poignant part is said to be
video interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>: "A faceless mass resolves eloquently
into a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kimmelman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). The
building itself--a gray granite <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hexagon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battery Park</ENAMEX>--does not fare <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half</TIMEX> as
well: It "conveys none of the brilliant complexity displayed inside" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert</ENAMEX>
Muschamp, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Update
            

            In a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lengthy New Republic</ENAMEX> review, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Wolfe</ENAMEX> mostly praises the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX>' tome on race: Their "tough-minded book serves the
cause of racial justice." Its "great strength is its insistence that some of
our most contentious questions have answers. Its most conspicuous weakness ...
is that it sometimes finds those answers too predictably."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:</TIMEX>

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story of Painting</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- Ally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McBeal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>);

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- She's So</ENAMEX>
Lovely ;

            

               Movie -- <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The Farewell
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Symphony</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund White</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Nation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indivisible</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abigail Thernstrom</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">27:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G.I.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Mimic</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Already Dead:</ENAMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gothic</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denis Johnson</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Best</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Winslow Taylor</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Enigma of Efficiency</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kanigel</ENAMEX>;

            
               Music -- The
Dance , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleetwood Mac</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good News</ENAMEX> (UPN).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cop</ENAMEX>
Land ;

            
               Movie -- The Full
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monty</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music -- Be Here</ENAMEX>
Now , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oasis</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- On the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Town</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX>);

            
               Books -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notes</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Exley</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Misfit: The Strange Life of Frederick</ENAMEX>
Exley , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Apaches</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenzo Carcaterra</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">13:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Conspiracy</ENAMEX>
Theory ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Love</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serenade</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vibe</ENAMEX> and The 
               Keenen 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX>

               Wayans 
               Show ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Event/Television</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks Live</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sculpture of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angkor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ancient Cambodia: Millennium of Glory"</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simenon</ENAMEX>: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Assouline</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Rothschild</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Dispatches From the Freud Wars: Psychoanalysis and Its</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Passions</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Forrester</ENAMEX>.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
