
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, March 21</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
editorial assesses <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s current recession, which has so far been mitigated
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s great accrued wealth. Keys to ending the downturn: instilling
consumer and investor confidence, increasing public spending on "modern
infrastructure" (computers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">telecoms</ENAMEX>), reducing government corruption, and
cutting corporate taxes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> think a full-bore crisis could be the best
thing for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s economy, giving it a fresh start. ... An article says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, reversing itself, now welcomes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
intervention in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> peace process. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, no longer
naive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">backers</ENAMEX> of the terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX>, have come to support
compromise. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has condemned all violence and formed ties with
both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. ... A story claims bacteria cause more ailments than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>
had previously realized, including stomach <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ulcers</ENAMEX>, hardening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arteries</ENAMEX>,
and some forms of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>. (A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sidebar</ENAMEX> recommends cooking with lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX>,
which can kill the little buggers.)

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20</TIMEX>)
            

            A cover
story by longtime affirmative action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Glazer</ENAMEX> acknowledges that
racial preferences may be necessary. Why? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Diversity profits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> by
introducing unfamiliar viewpoints, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) despite the civil rights movement,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> still lag far behind in key job qualifications (test scores, grades,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>). ... The editorial blasts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>'s recent apology to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>.
The statement is too self-absolving, deflecting blame away from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>: It
should have expressed abject contrition. ... An article assesses the
plague of allegedly post-feminist TV shows. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Veronica's</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Closet</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dharma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX> all pretend to be models of "do-me
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feminism</ENAMEX>," with sexually confident protagonists. But the heroines are actually
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">insecure</ENAMEX>, weak, and define themselves in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 19</TIMEX>)
            

            A
fascinating story profiles <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the nonretarded 8-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> retarded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. She will soon be smarter than her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> but is having trouble in
school--no one can help with homework, and she's picked up the slurring,
stilted speech patterns of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. Until recently, retarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> were
routinely sterilized, even though they usually give birth to developmentally
normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. ... The cover story claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Alcohol</ENAMEX> is just as
reprehensible as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX> and even more powerful. The difference: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> can stress liquor's ancillary health benefits and proudly point
to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Know When to Say When</ENAMEX>" ad campaign. Like the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panders</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Camel</ENAMEX> has nothing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Budweiser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">frogs</ENAMEX>
and lizards.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 17</TIMEX>)
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weeks</TIMEX> after cover stories in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsweeklies</ENAMEX> catch up with the hit
animated TV show <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story argues that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> successfully balances crudity (singing, dancing stool
samples) with inspired lunacy and sweetness (naive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9-year-olds</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ,
which runs an inside feature, thinks the show has slacked off lately and
is running out of ideas.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story is pegged to the release of testimony in the Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case. It sketches out a pattern of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> attempting to convince
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">multiple Clinton</ENAMEX> alleged paramours (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolly Kyle Browning</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>) to keep silent. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> claims that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s "calm demeanor masks a surprising volatility ... one never
knows when she may decide to end [a] friendship over some perceived slight."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's main story focuses on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>, who says the notorious
"talking points" looked to her like the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX>.
A sidebar breaks news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Landow</ENAMEX> chartered a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> to fly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> to his estate. Willey claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landow</ENAMEX> used her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX> stay at the estate
to badger her into saying "nothing happened" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 17</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story exposes chicanery in the death business. Funeral
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> lie to the bereaved and grossly overcharge for caskets and services.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> offers tips to cut costs (don't die), and covers a growing
movement: do-it-yourself embalming and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial</ENAMEX>. ... A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lachlan</ENAMEX> claims he will soon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inherit News Corp.</ENAMEX> Lachlan rides <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycles</ENAMEX>, sports big tattoos, and has yet
to demonstrate his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>. His <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX>--an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> rugby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>--lost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX> at least <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 million</NUMEX>. ... A
photo essay looks at life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. The pictures are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fascinating</ENAMEX>, though there aren't enough of them.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 17</TIMEX>)
            

            A
horrifying article describes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resistance Army</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>, a guerrilla
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of kidnapped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Kony</ENAMEX>--vicious, crazed, and
charismatic--has captured and indoctrinated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ugandan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kony</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Flies world</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> become brutal, heartless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kony</ENAMEX> in order to destabilize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>'s
government, which is backing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>. ... The requisite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
Tripp profile (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> above) says she is obsessed with marital
infidelity--her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was an adulterer--and has been embittered toward men
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">her</TIMEX> divorce. She's also a gossipy busybody. ... The opening
"Comment" claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s quashing of former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patten</ENAMEX>'s memoirs could prevent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> takeover of the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> covets the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> would not
tolerate it in the hands of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who is so willing to suppress news for
financial gain. ... Also, a rave for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primary Colors</ENAMEX> , "the
smartest movie ever made about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics." Primary Colors
rejects the smarmy populist demagoguery of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith Goes</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> .
Instead, it shows how politics is about choosing between imperfect, morally
compromising options.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 17</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> 's massive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> issue has all the glamour and sycophancy
you'd expect. Photo spread highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>-toy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Damon</ENAMEX> in a white sailor
suit and cap, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigourney Weaver</ENAMEX> reclining in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-to-toe mesh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Winslet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">underwater</ENAMEX>, and a surprisingly plump <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny DeVito</ENAMEX> dressed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Hitchcock</ENAMEX>.
... An article on the graying of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> says boomer studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> no
longer know which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> on: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad City</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman) and Sphere</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel L. Jackson</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tanked</ENAMEX>, but teen flicks <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scream 2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Know What You Did Last</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer</ENAMEX> hit pay dirt. The piece also mentions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX> was in a
deep funk after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Amistad</ENAMEX> got jilted for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX> noms. ... The
issue digs up gossip from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s ancient history: A silent-film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siren</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buster Keaton</ENAMEX> was "sexy," but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Chaplin</ENAMEX> didn't know how to seduce
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 17</TIMEX>)
            

            In the
cover story, evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.O. Wilson</ENAMEX> makes the case that human
morality is "empirical" law that evolved biologically, not "transcendental" law
that exists separate from human history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> argues that natural selection
created gene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> with certain moral traits, and these traits became the basis
for our societal standards. ... An article attempts to explain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
Shawn, the late, lamented, longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> . The
painfully shy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawn</ENAMEX> once declined an honorary degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> because of his
fear of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX>. He published <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> piece in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> under his
own byline: " <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'The Catastrophe</ENAMEX>,' about the destruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> by a meteor
while the rest of the world went about its business as usual."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 17</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX>'s apology, reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a week ago</TIMEX>, hits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsstands</ENAMEX>. The
once-conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> atones for his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Spectator</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sexcapades, which mentioned a harassment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> named
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula</ENAMEX>." Regretful for igniting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> scandal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX> admits the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> article was spurred by an "open political agenda." (For other
possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> apologies, see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">So Sorry</ENAMEX>" in

                  Slate
               .) ... A story wonders if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>'s SportsCenter
can stay fresh and irreverent. SportsCenter gained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> by tweaking the
sports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>--now it is the sports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 17</TIMEX>)
            

            Speaking
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , the much ballyhooed challenge to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illustrated</ENAMEX> , makes its debut. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> goes with larger pages but far
shorter articles than its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>. The effect: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports</ENAMEX> news for Attention Deficit
Disorder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>: lots of bite-sized items on very busy pages, lots of photo
portraits of sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>, none of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SI</ENAMEX> 's in-depth features. ...
Hoping to launch with a bang, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> breaks the news that the scoring
record broken (in controversial fashion) by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Connecticut</ENAMEX>
basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> Nykesha Sales may in fact still stand. Videotape shows that
Sales was wrongly credited with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> points in a previous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. Conn.</ENAMEX> game--she
needs another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> points to break the record for real.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
