
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Private Parts
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). Shock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Stern</ENAMEX>
successfully transforms himself into a likable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Everyman</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> profile compares him to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenny Bruce</ENAMEX>. The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX> says the film, though packaged as "psychosexist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">autobiography</ENAMEX>," is actually "romantic fiction." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> '
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> credits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Thomas</ENAMEX> ( The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady Bunch Movie</ENAMEX> ) with
making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> "into the biggest, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dorkiest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> imaginable." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX> calls it "the shrewdest piece of spin doctoring since Triumph
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> ." (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Private Parts</ENAMEX> site includes assorted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Stern</ENAMEX> games, stills,
and clips.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jungle 2 Jungle</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). Considering the drubbing
given the original--a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> comedy titled <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Little Indian</ENAMEX>, Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> --reception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> remake seems almost positive. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reviewers</ENAMEX> call
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Allen</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Improvement</ENAMEX>) affable. The new screenplay also adds
"farcical plot and sight gags to provide hilarity" to the story of the
relationship between a commodity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX> and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> he finds in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dissenters</ENAMEX> call the plot
ridiculous and the gags tiresome. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> plugs the movie at its site.)

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  A
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. James Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoopi Goldberg</ENAMEX> replaces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Lane</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Sondheim</ENAMEX>'s musical
comedy, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> like her just fine. "She's a time-traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plautus</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>, using her distinctive street smarts to find her way,
both as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performer</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>'s self-mocking approach is said to redeem the production
from an otherwise overwrought book.

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss: A Memoir</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). Reviewers dismiss
this memoir about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>'s incestuous affair with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> as a product
of talk-show culture. "Who controls the narrative? Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mim Udovitch</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ). The main gripes: that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Kiss</ENAMEX> represents an act of
self-plagiarism, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel recounts the same story; that her
prose is by turns flat and overheated, "chockablock with romance-novel clichés"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>); and that her need to confess is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-indulgent</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss</ENAMEX> is about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who can't get over herself,"
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Crossen</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giovanni</ENAMEX>'s Gift
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradford Morrow</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
recently featured this literary murder mystery as a case study in
"breakthrough" marketing--its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Viking</ENAMEX>, hoped to position it as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">middlebrow</ENAMEX> hit, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annie Proulx</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Shipping News</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> aren't
cooperating. "If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert James Waller</ENAMEX> had taken an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> degree or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle</ENAMEX>
Steel had read classics at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorbonne</ENAMEX>, this is the sort of book they might
write," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kirn</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> 
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review</ENAMEX> .
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read an excerpt from the book.)

            

               Art
            

            "Exiles
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Émigrés</ENAMEX>: The Flight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Artists</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler"</ENAMEX> (The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 11</TIMEX>). This exhibit, bankrolled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX>, is judged to be of greater historical than artistic
merit. It illustrates the influence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">émigrés</ENAMEX> on postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exposes American</ENAMEX> reluctance to rescue the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> persecution.
Despite the inclusion of canvases by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvador Dali</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Beckmann</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Chagall</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernand Léger</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piet Mondrian</ENAMEX>, the art is said to be unexceptional, since
only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beckmann</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mondrian</ENAMEX> did their best work in exile.

            

               Television
            

            
               
                  The
Practice
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. EST</TIMEX>). The Practice is deemed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> of law. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX> says the show,
about an unglamorous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> take on lowlifes as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and work in
shabby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, skillfully interweaves several plots into a single episode.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> predict stardom for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylan McDermott</ENAMEX>, who plays the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s site offers you clips, and the show's official
site lets you tour the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Update
            

            Defying
the critical consensus, The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX> pans
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donnie Brasco</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Newell "</ENAMEX>doesn't see anything funny
in wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>; I have an awful feeling he may even think of them as slightly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wise</ENAMEX>."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns:
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Donnie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brasco</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smilla</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sense of Snow</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Helfgott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Tour</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crisis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Feds</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arsenio</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- Just
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shoot Me</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crazy</ENAMEX>
Rhythms: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All That Jazz</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Garment</ENAMEX>;

            
               Books --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Novel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roundup</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- The Last Night of Ballyhoo</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>
Strikes Back: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Special Edition</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Lost</ENAMEX>
Highway ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rosewood</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schindler</ENAMEX>'s List ;

            
               Television -- Miss
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boys</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Monster:</ENAMEX>
Living <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Off the Big Screen</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gregory Dunne</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Sphinx: The Character of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph J. Ellis</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whittaker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Tanenhaus</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:</TIMEX>

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie
               --Absolute
Power ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Blood</ENAMEX> and
Wine ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gladstone</ENAMEX>: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Jenkins</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asylum</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick McGrath</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Hungry
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ghosts: Mao's Secret Famine</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jasper Becker</ENAMEX>;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Darger</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unreality</ENAMEX> of Being."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:</TIMEX>

            
               CD -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Boone</ENAMEX> in a
Metal Mood: No More Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nice Guy</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Boone</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dante</ENAMEX>'s
Peak ;

            
               Movie -- When We
Were <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prisoner</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mountains</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falls</ENAMEX>
Away: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Memoir , by Mia Farrow</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Before the
Dawn: An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Autobiography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Adams</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- A Supposedly
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fun Thing</ENAMEX> I'll <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never Do Again: Essays and Arguments</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Foster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chris Rock Show</ENAMEX> .

            
               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
