
   
   
      
         
            

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 23, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story identifies a new trend: "Explornography: The vicarious thrill of
exploring when there's nothing left to explore." Our obsession with buying
expensive outdoor gear leads us to find excuses to use it, resulting in utterly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pointless</ENAMEX>, dangerous journeys. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, who dogsleds through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arctic</ENAMEX>,
decides that the greatest thrill lies in returning home with all his toes.
... An essay argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> is power-hungry, irresponsible,
and unstable and that we should stop cutting him slack. Though he successfully
sucks up to the West, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> is bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, because he makes empty
promises to maintain control.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GQ</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 23, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A story
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">profiles Mark Willes</ENAMEX>, publisher of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . While
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> detest his eagerness to mix business and editorial (ad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> work together to plan profitable special sections), this is nothing new
in the newspaper world. The real danger is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX> will stray too far
toward service journalism, becoming "a promoter of an all-too-familiar kind of
newspaper: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that has increasingly little to do with news." (For

                  Slate
               's take, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX>.) ... A story claims <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is woefully unprepared for
biological or chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> attacks. By the time a toxic attack is discovered
and appropriately dealt with, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will be sick or
dying. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should improve its medical response rather than spend
more on anti-terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SWAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 22, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            Dueling cover lines.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Escape</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Outta Here</ENAMEX>!" The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> cover
package celebrates the resurgence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>. Secrets to the game's success:
nicer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballparks</ENAMEX> with better food; the chase for the home run, RBI, and winning
percentage records; and likable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Griffey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover
story slams modern vacations: All the good spots are swamped with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. An
accompanying piece lauds several "unspoiled hideaways"--which will now
undoubtedly be swamped with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> story
distinguishes between "buzz" and "hype": buzz is "genuine, street-level
excitement," while hype is "propaganda" created by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>.
Easier definition: pre- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> coverage = buzz; post- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
coverage = hype.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's trend story: infant massage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Babies</ENAMEX>, especially preemies, are
more relaxed, have better digestion, and are generally happier when they are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">massaged</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 22, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Smith</ENAMEX>) but an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> standby: rankings. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> are rated in several specialties and in overall quality. The overall
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayo Clinic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Hospital</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>. An accompanying story identifies a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> job: "hospitalist." A hospitalist
"oversees the care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> while they are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>," discussing
treatment options, following <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, and trying
to cut costs.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 22, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ex-Editor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX> writes a valedictory, thanking her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, "an extraordinary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> striving to make and remake <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s finest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>."
New <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Remnick</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue lacks none of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s obsession with
entertainment: It includes a profile of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> -style hype <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">for Saving Private Ryan</ENAMEX> (disguised as an
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX> piece gushes: The film's
opening combat footage "may be looked back upon as one of the greatest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX> in the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>." ... A story exposes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruthless dictator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Taylor</ENAMEX>. Though elected democratically and supported
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylor</ENAMEX> uses embezzlement, torture,
and murder to subjugate his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and boost his own wealth. ... A
delightful piece reviews a newly published collection of obituaries culled from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . The piece argues that reading early <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> obits reminds us how unheroic modern times are, and insists that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">obits</ENAMEX> are more fun: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> wit finds its highest expression in archly
noting others' deaths.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 22, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story reviews new biographies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Harding</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvin Coolidge</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Conclusions: 1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harding</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his day</TIMEX>, plagued by scandals of his
own making, aided by a strong-willed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> who ignored his foibles, ultimately
achieving nothing. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coolidge</ENAMEX> is underrated: His <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX> reserve hid a sharp
wit and thoughtful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>, and he fought for small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and low
taxes. ... An essay urges <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to lighten up. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> years
have seen huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> victories on health care, the balanced budget, and welfare
reform. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Right-wingers</ENAMEX> should be proud, not disappointed.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 18</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 18, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
editorial welcomes the resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryutaro Hashimoto</ENAMEX>
but frets that his departure will hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> economy. Hashimoto deserved
to go because he failed to reform the banking system or to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s
financial descent, but it will take time to choose a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> and
even more time for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> to push through reforms. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> notes an unpublicized cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> strike: It is delaying
the launch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>'s new sport utility <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the GMT800</TIMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUV</ENAMEX> is
expected to be wildly profitable, but a delayed launch will let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> start. ... A story says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> now eschew
insurance, favoring predictive models that help manage risk. Sometimes, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can foresee insurance will be unnecessary: While an earthquake in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> snapped many telephone poles, the phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> made back its losses
as "worried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> started calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>"--long distance.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
