
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  The
Lost World
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). As invariably occurs upon the release
of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX> blockbuster, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> complain about the lack of plot and the
unconvincing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> shell out a record-setting amount of money
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">opening weekend</TIMEX> (in this case, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$92.7 million</NUMEX>). "Essentially a digital
version of your basic, primeval <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BOO</ENAMEX>! flick," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kroll</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . Yet even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> love the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaurs</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost</ENAMEX>
World is the very essence of a thrill ride, shamelessly designed, ... [but]
there's some passion in the action, a lilt to the chases, a fluid lyricism in
the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX> move across hapless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> who cross their paths" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
Morgenstern, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ). (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lost World</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               
                  Addicted to Love
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). The critical consensus on this
romantic comedy: more sadism than laughs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffin Dunne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> Meg
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Broderick</ENAMEX> meant to turn the darker sides of voyeurism and
revenge into lighthearted fare; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say they failed. "It gives us the
impression that we're supposed to take drastic, irrational revenge as a larky
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laff riot</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Thomas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pans</ENAMEX> also for the
normally sunny <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX>, miscast here as a leather-clad bitch bent on punishing her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ex</ENAMEX>: "The same way a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Care Bear</ENAMEX> is a teeth-baring grizzly" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszczyna</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Addicted to Love</ENAMEX> site has a plot summary as well as stills
and clips.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brassed Off</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>). Mixed reviews for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> "working class
comedy" about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Yorkshire</ENAMEX> coal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX> downsized by Thatcherism, and about their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass band</ENAMEX>. The movie's simple-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX>-baiting "wears its bleeding heart
conspicuously on its sleeve," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .
"You might feel like one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX>--manipulated, misled and
maneuvered into an emotional corner," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX>, however, praises the movie's
feel for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, "forced to sustain their flagging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> by
quickness of wit." (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Click here for Brassed Off</ENAMEX> 's site.)

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Murder One</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 25, 26</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. EDT/PDT</TIMEX>). Producer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Bochco</ENAMEX>'s legal drama, a critical darling but a popular flop, enjoys a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-part <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last hurrah</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> delivers the kibosh. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say they are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grateful</ENAMEX> for these final installments, which concern a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vigilante</ENAMEX> who blows away
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17 paroled convicts</TIMEX>. "As improbable yet as irresistible as any beach book you
may be hoarding" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). Encomiums for the show compare it to
Law & Order and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD Blue</ENAMEX> , which "have made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> a golden
era of TV crime dramas" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Rosenberg</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Theater
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King David</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Amsterdam Theater</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> stages its first
production in its refurbished <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">42 nd</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Street</ENAMEX> theater. So far, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theater</ENAMEX> has got the better marks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX> calls
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s musical version of the biblical story, with a score by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Menken</ENAMEX>
( The Little Mermaid ) and lyrics by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Rice</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evita</ENAMEX> ), "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goliath</ENAMEX>
of a yawn." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Winer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> deems the score forgettable, "an
ambitious and derivative example of the
it's-so-loud-and-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">humorless</NUMEX>-it-must-be-art style." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX>
suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David "</ENAMEX>may well be the worst musical ever perpetrated. ...
It's a new genre, a horrortorio." (See the "Summary
Judgment" entry for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Amsterdam</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flaming Pie</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCartney</ENAMEX>'s album
occasions re-evaluations of the most mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beatle</ENAMEX>--turns out he's not the
empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunesmith</ENAMEX> he seemed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s and '80s</TIMEX>. "He is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">keeper</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flame</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Spitz</ENAMEX>, "and has handled
megastardom with level-headedness and acumen." The new album, which is rife
with unabashed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fab Four</ENAMEX> nostalgia, draws warm praise. "The old bloke sounds
more inspired and, well, less goofy than he has in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elysa Gardner</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ). However, a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> call the songs more Wings
than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>: "He has done some sucky stuff in his long and partially
illustrious career, but it has to be said that, overall, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCartney</ENAMEX> has never
sounded less necessary" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Gill</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> ). (See the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flaming Pie</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Che</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guevara</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revolutionary Life</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Lee Anderson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grove Press</ENAMEX>). The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> major biography of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> guerrilla--along with several forthcoming
movies and his appearance on watch faces and album covers--is said to mark a
reprise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che Chic</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> as a pop icon, devoid of political import. The
biography itself, which uses unpublished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diaries</ENAMEX> and untapped <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archives</ENAMEX>, is praised for having done a "masterly job in evoking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX>'s complex
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, in separating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from the myth" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Canby</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Review</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Schwartz</ENAMEX> calls it
tainted for having received "official support" from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> and for
abetting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> revival.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rage for Fame: The Ascent of Clare Boothe Luce</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvia Jukes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). A very friendly reception for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> volume of a
biography of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the best-connected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist-playwright-congresswoman-ambassadors</ENAMEX> in history, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Luce</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> has written a model biography of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who, if born a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, could easily have been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luce</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend Gore Vidal</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> . Reviews dwell on the book's dishy
detail, derived from Luce's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diaries</ENAMEX>. Time deems the book "definitive"
but too harsh: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> struggles for fairness but portrays Luce as a
calculating, self-indulgent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> whose fixed eye on the main chance rendered
her oblivious to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of others." (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talbot</ENAMEX>'s review in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. An excerpt is also
available.)

            

               Art
            

            
               New
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galleries</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> rave
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>'s renovation of its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>, which have, as a
result, doubled their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> has finally given a "great art tradition
... the epic-scale <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> home it deserves" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland Cotter</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). Enthusiasts praise the addition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> major works, including
Riverbank , one of the world's earliest landscape paintings, known as the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona Lisa</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> art." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s collection, which ranges from the Tang
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynasty</ENAMEX> to the present, can now be called "the most comprehensive view of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> painting to be found outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Stevens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ).
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>'s site.)

            

               Update
            

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lisa Schiffren</ENAMEX> lambastes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wasserstein</ENAMEX>: She "is credited with being the bard of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. One wonders whether she is conscious of the fact that, taken as a whole,
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oeuvre</ENAMEX> can be read as a superb indictment of the feminist way of life. ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy Wasserstein</ENAMEX>'s uncommon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are uncommonly unhappy, their lives a
mockery of all."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">21:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Underboss</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sammy the Bull Gravano's Story of Life</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Maas</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The Actual: A
Novella , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Bellow</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blaine: Street Magic</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Event --<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX>
International <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Film Festival</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Night Falls</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Love</ENAMEX>!
Valour! Compassion! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">;</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- The Wizard of Oz</ENAMEX> .

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">14:</TIMEX>

            
               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amsterdam Theater</ENAMEX>;

            
               Event --<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX>
International <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Film Festival</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s
Day ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifth</ENAMEX>
Element ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Designated Mourner</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odyssey</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courage</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stand Alone: Letters From Prison and Other Writings</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei Jingsheng</ENAMEX>,
translated and edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristina M. Torgeson</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Time Bind:</ENAMEX>
When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Becomes Home and Home Becomes Work</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlie Russell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hochschild</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Candide</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newseum</ENAMEX>.

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dixon</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Pynchon</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Television</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Visions: The Epic History of Art in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Visions</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward</ENAMEX> Just;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reading</ENAMEX> in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seamus Deane</ENAMEX>;

            
               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delano Roosevelt Memorial</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- The
Last <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Don</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Children of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Breakdown</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Volcano</ENAMEX> ;

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michele</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Reunion</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop</ENAMEX> -- Share My
World , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary J. Blige</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Locked in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Anything Your</ENAMEX>
Little <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heart Desires: An American Family Story</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Bosworth</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hystories</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hysterical Epidemics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Media</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Showalter</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Titanic</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Foxes</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Dance --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Honor of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Divine Lou Harrison</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark Morris Dance Group</ENAMEX>.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
