
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Conspiracy Theory
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> chide the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donner</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lethal Weapon</ENAMEX> ) film as irredeemably far-fetched: A paranoid New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> cabbie (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Gibson</ENAMEX>) and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX>) are chased by government
assassins when one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabbie</ENAMEX>'s fantastic theories turns out to be true.
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>]e don't believe a word of this," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> is dubious about the casting: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
talks to himself and mails long, delusional screeds to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> is not usually
the dreamboat type." A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> discern "tongue-in-cheek" humor in the use
of sex symbol <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibson</ENAMEX> as a "poster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>," and declare the film
smarter than "other high-ticket summer fare" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ).
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Conspiracy Theory</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Serenade</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>). A warm reception for rookie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley Barrett</ENAMEX>'s "clever, deadpan comedy" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>
vying for the affection of a thrice-divorced radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DJ</ENAMEX> who moves to their
outback <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. "A wickedly funny examination of obsessive romantic behavior,"
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>. Praise goes also to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barrett</ENAMEX>'s
gentle satire of the culturally backward outback (the radio station doesn't
even have a CD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>). Her idiosyncratic script and direction earn her
comparisons to acclaimed antipodean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auteurs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Campion</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillian Armstrong</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Video</ENAMEX> clips and stills are available here.)

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  Vibe
                
               and 
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Keenen Ivory Wayans Show</ENAMEX>
                (check
local listings for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> and times). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> scoff at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new late-night
talk shows, hosted by black <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stand-up comics</ENAMEX>, as poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replicas</ENAMEX> of the early '90s
hit The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arsenio Hall Show</ENAMEX> . Vibe , produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quincy Jones</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keenen</ENAMEX> , made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> of the comedy series <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Living</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Color</ENAMEX> , are pronounced "indistinguishable" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Collins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ) and
"hard to stay awake through" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Rosenberg</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angles Times</ENAMEX> ).
The main gripes are that the programs stick to a "banal" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caryn James</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) talk show formula and have even less bite than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letterman</ENAMEX>'s or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Leno</ENAMEX>'s network show.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Event/Television</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Garth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks Live</ENAMEX>
                (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 8</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>;
broadcast live on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>). Bemused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> scratch their heads at the huge turnout
(estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as high as 1.1 million</NUMEX>) for the country music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">megastar</ENAMEX>'s
live-broadcast concert. "So what ends up being the cultural event of the summer
in the culture capital of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>?" asks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michele</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>. Some see the concert as evidence of marketing acumen and a
self-aggrandizing streak in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s'</TIMEX> best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>' "neatly
calibrated spectacle" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Pareles</ENAMEX>, also in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ), which
included lots of smoke, lights, and cameos (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Joel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don McLean</ENAMEX>), was,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> says, "originally conceived as a mega-infomercial for his new CD."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> plugs its broadcast.)

            

               Art
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sculpture of Angkor and Ancient Cambodia: Millennium of Glory</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Gallery of Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> show of
classical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodian</ENAMEX> art in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> is said to "carry the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of a
revelation" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland Cutter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> calls the pieces, which mostly depict <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> and other deities and date
to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>, "some of the greatest stone carving and bronze
work in human history." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> expect extra attention for the show because of
the recent political turmoil in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>. An editorial in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> urges holding on to the art until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> is restored in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>. (See the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Gallery</ENAMEX> site. For a backgrounder on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodian</ENAMEX> conflict, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist</ENAMEX>.")

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Simenon: A Biography
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Assouline</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschild</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). The biography of the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of pulp
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fiction</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903-1989</TIMEX>), who wrote <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 400</NUMEX> novels and bedded even more women
(he estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10,000</NUMEX>), is deemed masterful, "absorbing," and "definitive"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deirdre Bair</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simenon</ENAMEX> wins
praise for its defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simenon</ENAMEX>'s oeuvre , often dismissed as hackery,
and for its candid treatment of his misogyny and anti-Semitism. "Unlike
altogether too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographers</ENAMEX>, [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Assouline</ENAMEX>] is capable of distinguishing
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> and the song," says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luc Sante</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatches From the Freud Wars: Psychoanalysis and Its Passions</ENAMEX>
               ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Forrester</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University Press</ENAMEX>). A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> don's assessment of
recent indictments of psychoanalysis--including its alleged sexism,
pseudoscience, and ineffectiveness--is deemed "dispassionate" (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sarah Boxer</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ) by some, wishy-washy by others. Freudians
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">claim Forrester</ENAMEX> brings the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>'s hyperbolic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> down to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>, while
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freudians</ENAMEX> say he pulls his punches. The book "strands the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> in the
musty groves of academe and mutes the passions of the subtitle," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jungian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Douglas</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post Book World</ENAMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University Press</ENAMEX> plugs the book.)

            

               Updates
            

            The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Lane</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> of a
Kidnapping merely extends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel Garc√</ENAMEX>≠a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M√°rquez</ENAMEX>'s record of "dishonest"
journalism. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he magical realist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> is himself close to the people
and the events that he is writing about, but does not feel the need to disclose
this fully to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>." ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX> adds to
the ruckus over <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Company of Men : It</ENAMEX> "is a repellent experience--a
schematic, coldly cynical work that pretends to expose coldness and cynicism."
... In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Kimball</ENAMEX> attacks the
recently deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William S. Burroughs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ginsberg</ENAMEX> for their "pretentious, proselytizing pornography ... the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beats</ENAMEX>
really do mark an important moment in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture, not as one of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">achievements</ENAMEX>, but as a grievous example of its degeneration."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Career
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Company</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Spawn</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Our Guys</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Glen Ridge Rape</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Secret Life of the Perfect Suburb</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lefkowitz</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> or
Fear<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: How Jews Can Survive in a Christian America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Abrams</ENAMEX>;

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palestrina</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Mrs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
Maps ;

            

               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Airport</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book --
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Desserts: The Unauthorized Biography</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oppenheimer</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book of Memories</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Nadas</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ivan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Imre Goldstein</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contact</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Shall We</ENAMEX>
Dance? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">;</ENAMEX>

            
               Book--
               Lawyerland:
What Lawyers <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk About When They Talk About the Law</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Straight
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Russo</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>);

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Amy's View</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> in
Black ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Women With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ford</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Scripture: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Making the Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Maier</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX> Without
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face: The Autobiography of Communism's Greatest Spymaster</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Markus Wolf</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne McElvoy</ENAMEX>;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Haring</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum of American Art</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oz</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            

               Music --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilith Fair</ENAMEX>.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
