
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 25</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial claims that the conflict in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> no
longer poses a threat to the world because it has become a localized crisis. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, peace will come and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> will emerge with its borders intact.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Complication</ENAMEX>: To keep its borders stable, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> will have to stop treating its
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli Arabs</ENAMEX> like an "unwanted presence." ... A paternalistic editorial calls <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s Latinos "a
minority worth cultivating." The piece praises <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latinos</ENAMEX> for being the
"uncomplaining greasers of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy," and doing "the
jobs that others refuse to do." Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Latinos</ENAMEX> have no
racial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ax</ENAMEX> to grind and so can act as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builders</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>" between blacks
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. ... A story exposes the undercover <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">shilling</NUMEX> of many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. Guaranteed that the clips will never air outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, several major
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> have filmed ads for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> TV: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX> for a credit card,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham sausage</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $4 million</NUMEX> for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> spot.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 11</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 24</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> gubernatorial race mourns the decline of that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
politics. Independently wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> win <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> with no political
background or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>. Career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, with solid ideas, can't raise
enough money to keep up. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> use ballot initiatives for
serious policy changes, they don't mind electing do-nothing plutocrats.
... A story says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is terrified of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, because he
knows a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> dirt that he hasn't yet dished. His recent assignments
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> (commentating on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX> cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>,
writing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> ) suggest he's turned on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
... An article deplores the glut of tell-all books by prospective
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ashcroft</ENAMEX>). The
books, which ignore public policy, are shameless attempts by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humanize</ENAMEX> themselves for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. ... Yehuda Amichai contributes a pair of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poems</ENAMEX> and a personal essay about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> anniversary.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 23</TIMEX>)
            

            In the
cover story, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> seeks the gene that causes an abnormal number of cleft
lips and palates in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Philippine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> working in
remote areas face ethical unease: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locals</ENAMEX>, valued for their genetic isolation,
often don't understand what the research is for and rarely benefit from it.
(Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">islanders</ENAMEX> thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s cleft lips resulted from their parents
eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken anuses</ENAMEX>.) ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Budget Committee</ENAMEX> and a long-shot candidate for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential nomination in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ohioan</ENAMEX> lacks "gravitas" but is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">passionate</ENAMEX>, good with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, highly religious, and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>--all positives
in the election game.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 21</TIMEX>)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> covers on money.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> claims we're all "married to the market": <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> invest more
than ever before (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' financial assets are in the stock
market), and a crash would so cripple the economy that even noninvestors would
suffer. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> accompanying articles argue that the boom will continue (because
unemployment and inflation remain low) or will not (because price-to-earnings
ratios are too high). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>-merger cover story assesses the future of money: It will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) digital
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) concentrated in superbanks that handle investments and banking.
Conspiracy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> beware: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> is investing in a chip that can store
electronic cash, your medical history, and "keys" to your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and office.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> claims <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m. to 8 p.m.</TIMEX> has become "crime time" for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>. Working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> unsupervised during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX> (thanks
to budget cuts in after-school programs), leading to greater <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">delinquency</ENAMEX>. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , meanwhile, claims that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m. to 8 p.m.</TIMEX> has become God time for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> are reintroducing prayer to public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.
After-school prayer clubs skirt church-state separation laws and are popping up
"in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 1</NUMEX> out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." Religious teens
wear <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">wristbands</ENAMEX> marked "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.W.J.D.</ENAMEX>" ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Would Jesus Do?</ENAMEX>").

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 21</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story is skeptical about charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> can
succeed when dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> push innovative curricula, but in many charter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> profits are more important than education. At some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> charter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> attend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only four hours a day</TIMEX> and learn from computers instead of
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>. ... A story argues that suburban sprawl penalizes urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>.
Low-density areas don't pay enough taxes to subsidize the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and
sewers they require. City <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> end up paying the difference. This lowers
downtown property values and spurs middle-class flight. ... A story says <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">U.S. $100</NUMEX> bills reside in foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> currency circulating abroad functions as "an interest-free
loan to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>" and demonstrates extreme worldwide confidence in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 27 and May 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 21</TIMEX>)
            

            A
"special <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> issue" should be called a special western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> issue,
given that it notices only the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>. Highlights: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> excerpts the wrenching diary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor</ENAMEX>
Klemperer, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> who managed to survive <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dresden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. (He
was married to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aryan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.) He loses <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, job, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">possessions</ENAMEX>, dignity:
"The sadistic machine simply rolls over us." ... A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Juan Carlos</ENAMEX> applauds him for transforming a backward fascist dictatorship
into a thriving, tolerant democracy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> saved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> by surrendering his
own power to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>: Now even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">socialists</ENAMEX> want to preserve the monarchy.
... A piece says peace in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> depends on new definitions of
old words: "terrorist," "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>," "culture" and, most of all, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>."
The peace agreement is premised on the notion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> can live happily
without the feeling that they belong to "a well-defined <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>." ... A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> visits the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Billund</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of the "greatest toy
in the world," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lego</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lego</ENAMEX>-obsessed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> parts charming to ... one
part creepy." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lego</ENAMEX> is not just plastic bricks anymore: It also sells backpacks,
shoes, umbrellas, etc.--anything a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> needs.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 21</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story argues that we should build more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>. Public transportation has
failed (it's neither convenient nor cost efficient), and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> love their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> are congested not because we lack alternative transportation,
but because we lack superhighways and connecting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>. (See

                  Slate
               's dialogue "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The War on Cars</ENAMEX>.")

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
