
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 20, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s economic woes are real
and are not going away. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> must reform its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and maintain loose fiscal
and monetary policy (even though that means a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cheapened yen</NUMEX>), or the rest of
the world will soon feel the aftershocks of its recession. Dilemma for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>:
We should be raising interest rates to keep our overheating economy in check,
but a rate hike would worsen <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s problems by hurting its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">debtors</ENAMEX>. ...
A story says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>' investing habits are a good gauge of where the
market is heading. Lately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> have been overwhelmingly selling their own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' shares. ... An essay urges <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> to withdraw its soccer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> if it is unable to squelch the violence of hooligan
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> have already begun rioting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 19, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven F. Goldstone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR Nabisco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX>. Unlike other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco VIPs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldstone</ENAMEX> willingly admits the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weed</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">addictive</ENAMEX>, carcinogenic, and evil (and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> may have marketed cigarettes
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>), yet he's leading the fight against congressional sanctions. Goldstone
finally decided a settlement didn't make fiscal sense and that he'll continue
to manufacture cigarettes until <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> itself is illegal. ... A story
says exiled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissident</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei Jingsheng</ENAMEX> may not be the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> for
his cause. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei</ENAMEX>'s a weak political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX>, and his long imprisonment has left
him naive about the workings of the modern world. (He still views <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maoist</ENAMEX>.) Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei</ENAMEX>'s indomitable charm and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> make him a formidable foe
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. ... An article traces a promising development in the search
for an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> cure. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> quit drug regimens and find their immune
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>, having been bolstered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, are suddenly able to fight the
virus without help. This could lead to a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, June 18, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s hottest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> is exposed. The hilarious cover story chronicles
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX>'s misadventures in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> and his misogynist,
potty-mouthed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entourage</ENAMEX> don't tip at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> (or strip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>), brawl with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">detractors</ENAMEX>, throw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>, and ooze sleaze. Sample: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo</ENAMEX>'s bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys phoned actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Berkley</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showgirls</ENAMEX> ) at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all hours</TIMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, hoping she'd leave her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> and join them for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>. When her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boyfriend</ENAMEX> finally told them to stop bothering her, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo's</ENAMEX> posse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sucker</ENAMEX>-punched him.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, June 18, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> 's coup: face time with the reclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>. The piece
finds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> bitter at his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX> and deeply suspicious of the
white world. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> counsels successful young black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that, upon leaving
their neighborhoods, "you won't ever really be able to go back. But you may
find you're never fully accepted up ahead, either, that you've landed between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worlds</ENAMEX>. That's the way I feel sometimes, even now, and it can make you angry."
... A story says the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> other than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
are (in descending order): <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Moody</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Foster Wallace</ENAMEX> contribute short
fiction to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> reading package.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's Content</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July/August 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, June 17, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The debut
issue of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> billing itself the "independent voice of the information
age." Overall tone: sanctimony, exemplified by the series of "lessons" to the
press at the end of the cover story ("no one should read or listen to any media
outlet that consistently shows that it is the lapdog of big, official power
rather than a respectful skeptic"). The much-touted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> page cover piece
("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pressgate</ENAMEX>") carefully reconstructs coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal,
congratulating a few responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and tsk-tsking almost everybody else
for uncritically accepting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s leaks. It blames the scandal on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s desire for a book contract; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucianne Goldberg</ENAMEX>'s hatred of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and lust for attention; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s self-righteousness. The piece
also breaks the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> admits leaking to the press--something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
had previously denied. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Actor George Clooney</ENAMEX> pens an editorial urging
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> to be more truthful. Speaking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal, about which
several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press outlets</ENAMEX> tried to interview him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clooney</ENAMEX> writes, "I am an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>
(unless you saw <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> ), so how could my thoughts on this subject be
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">newsworthy?</ENAMEX>" Exactly. ... Throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, short pieces offer
insider looks at the media biz, including a feature listing selected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>' salaries.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 16, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">celebrates Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>'s reign as the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> ever and
weighs the evidence about whether His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airness</ENAMEX> will retire. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conclusion</ENAMEX>: No one
knows for sure whether he'll stay or go.) A sidebar claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> is only the
second greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> in history, behind <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pele</ENAMEX>. An accompanying piece
doubts we will see another hoopster like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>--his dedication to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and
to improving his game is unmatched by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. ...

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover piece hypes the new <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X-Files</ENAMEX> movie, profiling its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creator</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>--all of whom sound obnoxious. Sidebars explain the show's
alleged symbolism. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scully</ENAMEX>'s crucifix signifies "her faith in God, vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mulder</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paranormal</ENAMEX> paganism.")

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> says our defense
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> could lead to a war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Tensions are escalating over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>'s
independence, and we will be forced to take sides. An interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> finds him fiercely pro-independence and fairly confident of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
backing. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> is the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> to discover that "crank"
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">smokable methamphetamine</NUMEX>) is sweeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">heartland</ENAMEX>. The speed-like substance
can be cooked up at home and attracts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, who often use it as a diet
aid.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> charts <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> toward world domination. Single pills
can cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $175</NUMEX> on foreign black markets, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> take
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Viagra Tours</ENAMEX>" to find the drug legally. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-impotence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> will soon be
approved for use on several continents.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 16, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            Several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> after a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> scare piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hepatitis C</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> '
cover story calls the virus the "next epidemic." The disease
infects <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times as many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> does, with no visible symptoms and
no effective cure. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hep</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> is transmitted much like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> (blood transfusions,
sharing needles, sex) and silently eats away at the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX>. ... An
interesting piece illustrates the utter chaos of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s economy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> literally pay their taxes in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vodka</ENAMEX> and do most of their business in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">barter</ENAMEX>. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> finds a new tourist
hot spot: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. Beautiful historical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> and friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> abound. Just
ignore all the signs reading "Down with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.A.</ENAMEX>"--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>, don't show too
much ankle.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 22 and 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 16, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
summer fiction issue's star attraction: excerpts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kerouac</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>,
including notes from a cross-country trip with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal Cassady</ENAMEX>. (Those travels
helped inspire On the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Road</ENAMEX> .) Kerouac mocks his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Ginsberg</ENAMEX>,
honors the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spirituality of Hashish</ENAMEX>," and records a "batting average" for
writing. ("After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s work, my 'batting average' rose to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.306</NUMEX>. The point is,
I've got to hit like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX>.") ... <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Half a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> offer brief
memoirs of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Miller</ENAMEX> recalls <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '20s</TIMEX>, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> slept in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX> to escape the heat. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Short</ENAMEX> story
contributors include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Munro</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Annie Proulx</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 16, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story analyzes the split between "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>" and conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winnetka</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, are pleased that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is
prosperous and peaceful, and appalled by the vitriolic, negative activism of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> resent the passivity and sluggishness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. There's no easy way to reunite the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> wades into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> car-ornament controversy, making the case that the
ornament showing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> with legs and the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX>" is a grotesque affront
to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX> ornament offends because it assumes that all
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> who have a plain <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ornament</ENAMEX> are know-nothing creationists.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
