
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Volcano
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). The backlash against
natural-disaster movies shifts into high gear. Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volcano</ENAMEX> 's
superior special effects, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> deem it inferior to the last volcano movie,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dante's Peak</ENAMEX> . Problems: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The plot, or the lack thereof. "Without
special effects as the main attraction, there would be no movie here at all,"
writes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Overacting by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee Jones</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Heche</ENAMEX>, in lieu of actual roles to play. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) A volcano that is
both implausible and boring. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volcano</ENAMEX> is a movie without a villain or a
mystery. The volcano has no quirks of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>, because it has no
personality. Defeating it is a breeze, because it is dumb, mechanical, and
predictable" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Plotz, Slate</ENAMEX>. Also see the official Volcano page.)

            
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Reunion</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Classic</ENAMEX> chick flick or a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bad Bill & Ted</ENAMEX> knockoff? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maslin</ENAMEX> says that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mira Sorvino</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mighty Aphrodite</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Kudrow</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX> ), in
their roles as bimbettes avenging the wrongs of high school, "elevat[e]
bubble-headedness to new levels of comic ingenuity." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desson Howe</ENAMEX> calls the film a "sublime comedy" about "bitchiness
[and] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">oneupwomanship</ENAMEX>." But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd McCarthy</ENAMEX> says the movie "looks
like a peroxided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clueless</ENAMEX> wannabe straggling along to the party <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after it's over." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for
clips.)

            

               Pop
            

            
               
                  Share My World
               ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary J. Blige</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCA</ENAMEX>). A makeover for "the queen of hip-hop soul": from
gangsta <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> to pop diva crooning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Cole</ENAMEX> covers. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary J. Blige</ENAMEX> has been
to charm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allison Samuels</ENAMEX>. It works. "Blige
deserves a place among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pop</ENAMEX>'s premiere female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vocalists</ENAMEX>," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christopher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Farley</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . (You can hear clips from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blige</ENAMEX>'s latest album at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCA</ENAMEX>'s
site.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Locked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). Whatever their
ideological stripe, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> agree that the former labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>'s
self-deprecating style (he makes a lot of jokes about being short) masks a
massive ego (he thinks he has all the answers). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Ferguson</ENAMEX> says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> leaves the 'nuts and bolts' of politics a
supremely unhappy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, convinced as strongly as ever of his superiority to its
processes, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX>, and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who gave him the coolest job he'll
ever have." However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> do praise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s lucid prose, pointed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observations</ENAMEX>, and sense of humor: "There is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thurberesque</ENAMEX> side to him" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s review in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> plugs the book here.)

            

               
                  Anything <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Little Heart Desires: An American Family Story</ENAMEX>
               , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Bosworth</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). Not all memoirs are evil.
Critical approbation for this one about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosworth</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartley Crum</ENAMEX>, a
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who represented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Randolph Hearst</ENAMEX> and the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hollywood 10</ENAMEX>"
and committed suicide during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> era. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosworth</ENAMEX>, the biographer of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Arbus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomery Clift</ENAMEX>, "provides a vivid sense of upper-middle-class
life in the early <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, when prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> suddenly turned their
backs on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crum</ENAMEX> and called them <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> dupes," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deacon</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> . In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lingeman</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bosworth "</ENAMEX>tells her elegiac story in a tone that is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">admirably</ENAMEX> restrained, in prose that conveys strong feeling by
understatement."

            
               
                  Hystories: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hysterical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epidemics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Media</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Showalter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University</ENAMEX>
Press). The feminist literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>'s claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> and
chronic-fatigue syndromes are merely psychological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maladies</ENAMEX> meets with
predictably high levels of vitriol. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Tavris</ENAMEX> takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Showalter</ENAMEX> to task for using literary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freudianism</ENAMEX> to explain real problems: "Sometimes a headache is a 'language of
distress' and sometimes it's a tumor." Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tavris</ENAMEX> says recent revelations
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> may indeed have been exposed to chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> belie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Showalter</ENAMEX>'s case. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freudian Frederick Crews</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">describes Showalter</ENAMEX>'s theory of hysteria as itself an "attempt to whip up a
little hysteria." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University Press</ENAMEX> plugs the book.)

            

               Theater
            

            

               
                  Titanic
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lunt-Fontanne Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). Surprisingly, the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> spectacular isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>'s all-time biggest flop. But "that is
probably the most exciting thing that can be said about it," says the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> complain that the musical fails to
deliver the extravagant sets and staging they've come to expect from theatrical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blockbusters</ENAMEX>. By sidestepping obvious clich√©s (rushing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX>, crashing waves)
in an effort "to make a sensitive and tasteful show about a trashy subject,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Winer</ENAMEX>, the production achieves only "banality."

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Foxes</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vivian Beaumont Theater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).
Apparently, not even the sure-fire plot machinations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lillian Hellman</ENAMEX> and
beguiling wiles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stockard Channing</ENAMEX> can rescue this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Center</ENAMEX>
production from its pretensions. The play "is so wildly miscast and so
haplessly misconceived that it is hard to figure out what its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> exactly
had in mind," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brantley</ENAMEX>. (His best guess: a
Freudian essay on lovelessness and neurosis.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Rose</ENAMEX> calls the production "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preachy</ENAMEX> bore."

            

               Dance
            

            "In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honor of the Divine Lou</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark Morris Dance Group</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Academy of Music</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
City). The bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> of modern dance takes on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Harrison</ENAMEX>, the eclectic
classical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>. "As you watch the stage, your brain seems to get bigger,
your life more interesting," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acocella</ENAMEX>. The main attraction: a live orchestra (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yo-Yo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma</ENAMEX> played opening
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>). Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' much-praised penchant for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> with unusually shaped
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>. "It is unique among the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> of its kind in looking utterly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human</ENAMEX>, like a cross-section of real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who just happen to move vividly or
be capable of generating a potent atmosphere" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tobi Tobias</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Update
            

            More Mailer
bashing: In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Moore</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX>'s
retelling of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>' life reads "like a simplified novelization [of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gospels</ENAMEX>]
for grade-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>." In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Wood</ENAMEX> says, "Each
new book by him is worse than the last; he has become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bibliographer</ENAMEX>'s
definition of nostalgia. He remembers that one must be daring as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, but
has forgotten to what end."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns:
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">23:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gospel</ENAMEX>
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Son</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Pastoral , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Roth</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.B. Yeats</ENAMEX>:
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apprentice Mage</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865-1914</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.F. Foster</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Purple</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Moody</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloaming</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- The Ring of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nibelung</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Murder at</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1600</TIMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Kissed</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16:</TIMEX>

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso: The</ENAMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anaconda</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grosse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pointe Blank</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- An
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Daughter</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naked</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Sedaris</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flower</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penelope Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Gut
Symmetries , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanette Winterson</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inventions</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Hare: Poems <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1909-1917</TIMEX> , by T.S.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliot</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Ricks</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:</TIMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doll</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX>
Road ;

            
               Movie -- Inventing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbotts</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- That Old</ENAMEX>
Feeling ;

            
               Book --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Ginsberg</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1926-1997</TIMEX>);

            
               Book -- After the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madness</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Own Prison Memoir</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sol Wachtler</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Big Picture</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Kennedy</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Chamoiseau</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose-Myriam R√</ENAMEX>©jouis and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Val Vinokurov</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics of Celebrity</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Wills</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Divorce</ENAMEX>
Culture , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Dafoe Whitehead</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- When the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sons</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heaven Meet the Daughters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fernanda Eberstadt</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil</ENAMEX>'s
Own ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Chasing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> .

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
