
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empire Strikes Back</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Edition</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucasfilm Ltd.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Fox</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> film in the Star Wars trilogy takes in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24</NUMEX>
million its opening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> and receives rave reviews. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empire Strikes</ENAMEX>
Back is the best of three Star Wars films," declares the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>. "It managed to prefigure the power-mad <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80</TIMEX>'s," says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darth Vader</ENAMEX> to
merger-and-acquisitions-mad corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">titans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Skywalker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leia</ENAMEX>
are said to have matured into actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> (as opposed to cartoon ones),
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoda</ENAMEX> makes his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> appearance, "emerg[ing] from murky nature to
become the spiritual center of the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> 
               Wars game," says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Stack</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate's Louis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menand</ENAMEX> explains Star Wars ' appeal. You can also visit the official
Star Wars site. )

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lost Highway</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">October Films</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> denounce <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lynch</ENAMEX>'s
latest picture as a soulless knockoff of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lynch</ENAMEX> movies ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Velvet</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wild</ENAMEX> at 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heart , Twin Peaks: Fire Walk With Me</ENAMEX> ).
"We've visited this planet before," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX>. Among the elements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lynch</ENAMEX>'s
self-plagiarism: an eerie soundtrack, creepy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> ( femmes fatales ,
scary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX>, ghoulish freak), and lots of tawdry sex. Also, a shaggy-dog plot
that defies the laws of time and space. "The cries of 'Cheat!' that attended
the later episodes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Twin Peaks</ENAMEX> are likely to be heard again," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>. On the other hand, the film is said to look
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>--"magnificent in the painterly way Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynch</ENAMEX> pioneered," says the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lost Highway</ENAMEX>'s official site serves up bizarre
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promos</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  Rosewood
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Brothers</ENAMEX>). Based on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hitherto</ENAMEX> little-known <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923</TIMEX>
incident in which a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> pillaged a black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosewood</ENAMEX> is
deemed important as history but insignificant as art. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Singleton</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boyz N the Hood</ENAMEX> ) is accused of sentimentalizing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resorting</ENAMEX> to action-film banalities--"a sorry assortment of dramatic and visual
clichés that were retired from service, or should have been, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades ago</TIMEX>," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgenstern</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosewood</ENAMEX>'s
home page has video clips and the like.)

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schindler</ENAMEX>'s List
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 23</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> earns kudos for its
"sensitive" presentation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust epic</ENAMEX>, which it
showed without ads, under the sponsorship of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>. But the praise is tempered
by the observation that the film came in a package deal with Jurassic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> and was broadcast in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of February</TIMEX> sweeps. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> note two
other ironies: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schindler</ENAMEX>'s List is the most graphic program ever
shown on network television. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> has its own unacknowledged history of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-Semitism</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Ford</ENAMEX> once gave his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> free copies of The
Protocols of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elders of Zion</ENAMEX> .)

            
               
                  Miss
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evers' Boys</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>; click here for times). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Feldshuh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> Prize-winning
play about the notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tuskegee Experiment</ENAMEX> has been adapted for television to
general acclaim. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfre Woodard</ENAMEX> displays "sinewy intelligence and grace" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ) and "unfailing dignity" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John O'Connor</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX> 
               Times ) in the role of a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> who recruits black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> for
a government research project about syphilis. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> go untreated, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>
die.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence Fishburne</ENAMEX> "underplays [one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>] to smoldering
effect" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leonard</ENAMEX>). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> plugs the movie at its site.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monster: Living Off the Big Screen</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gregory Dunne</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>). The inside story of how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Didion</ENAMEX> turned the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica</ENAMEX>
Savitch saga into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> picture Up Close and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personal</ENAMEX> makes
the cover of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , although
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">screenwriter Larry Gelbart</ENAMEX> summarizes, rather than evaluates, the book:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monster</ENAMEX> offers a crash course in getting a script through the hazards
of the present-day studio system." In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ,
producer/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Crichton</ENAMEX> applauds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX>'s breezy, professional tone:
"Shock and petty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moralizing</ENAMEX> are the mark of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review of Books</ENAMEX> complains that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX> is too breezy: "This is what
makes him so readable, but it doesn't give him a voice for brooding."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Sphinx</ENAMEX>: The Character of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Historian Ellis</ENAMEX> earns praise for his contribution to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX>
scholarship. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellis</ENAMEX>' twist: He's a moderate who neither censures the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> for his conflicted views on race nor dismisses
his political beliefs as insincere. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeffersonism</ENAMEX> is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintonism</ENAMEX>," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historian Sean Wilentz</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> ,
however, concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Sphinx</ENAMEX> makes manifest so many
inconsistencies in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s thought that it may unwittingly be "the most
critical biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX> published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>." (For more on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX> debate, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Greenberg</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High Concept</ENAMEX>.")

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whittaker Chambers</ENAMEX>: A Biography
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Tanenhaus</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>).
Tanenhaus elevates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> to the pantheon of great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> postwar
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> and declares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alger Hiss</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>, and no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> object. Even
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , famously defensive on the question of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX>, calls the
biography "an honest and indispensable book that goes a long way toward
restoring to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> an elementary human plausibility" (gosh, thanks).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tanenhaus</ENAMEX> accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> of having inadvertently instigated McCarthyism, and
"shows us <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>, his introversion, his sententiousness" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koch</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ). (Also, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s mildly
critical review by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Douglas</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Theater
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Square</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks ago</TIMEX>, art
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historian Simon Schama</ENAMEX> predicted in The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam Gems</ENAMEX>'
play about midcentury <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Spencer</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>
would be received--unfairly, claimed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schama</ENAMEX>--as "yet another formulaic
contribution to the flourishing genre of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as</NUMEX>-prick." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> have proven
him right. The play is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s life reduced to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Weddings</ENAMEX> and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Funeral</ENAMEX> , a quaint and titillating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomsbury</ENAMEX> parallelogram," says the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Lyons</ENAMEX>. All praise is reserved for the
production itself: "The staging is infinitely inventive," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Actor Anthony Sher</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>, is "astonishing, as
though he were plugged into a power source the rest of the world had yet to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">discover</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX>.

            

               Update
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jed Perl</ENAMEX> trashes the late paintings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willem de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kooning</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX> exhibition "is something new--the first
show dedicated to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's chic</ENAMEX>."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:</TIMEX>

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie
               --Absolute
Power ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Blood</ENAMEX> and
Wine ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gladstone</ENAMEX>: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Jenkins</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asylum</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick McGrath</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Hungry
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ghosts: Mao's Secret Famine</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jasper Becker</ENAMEX>;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Darger</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unreality</ENAMEX> of Being."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:</TIMEX>

            
               CD -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Boone</ENAMEX> in a
Metal Mood: No More Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nice Guy</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Boone</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dante</ENAMEX>'s
Peak ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- When We Were</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kings</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prisoner</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mountains</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falls</ENAMEX>
Away: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Memoir , by Mia Farrow</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Before the
Dawn: An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Autobiography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Adams</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- A Supposedly
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fun Thing</ENAMEX> I'll <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never Do Again: Essays and Arguments</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Foster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chris Rock Show</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- Personal
History , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Graham</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- What It Means
to Be a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Libertarian: A Personal Interpretation</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Do the
Windows <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open</ENAMEX>? , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Hecht</ENAMEX>;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Gridlock'd</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Waiting for</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guffman</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willem de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kooning: The Late Paintings, the 1980s"</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Men Are</ENAMEX>
From <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mars, Women Are From Venus</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Event --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On Cultural Power: The Wilson-Brustein Discussion</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">29:</TIMEX>

            
               Art --"Giambattista
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1696-1770</TIMEX>";

            
               Event --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halftime</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> XXXI;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kolya</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Island of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colorblind</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Sacks</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The
Steward of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Christendom</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Fierce
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Creatures</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Le Divorce</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Johnson</ENAMEX>.

            
               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
