
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 17</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial urges the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to lift its
embargo on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX> aging and the pope visiting, now is a good
time to reopen relations. Warmer dealings with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> might hasten its adoption
of a free-market economy. ... The requisite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economic crisis story
argues that the region's authoritarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regimes</ENAMEX> should be replaced by democratic
ones. ... A story spots a disturbing trend in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangladesh</ENAMEX>: Angered men
throw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s faces, disfiguring and blinding them. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Estimate</ENAMEX>: There
are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> attacks per year.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> blames a male backlash
against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bangladeshi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s growing economic independence. ... A profile
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">salutes</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buster Keaton</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aki Kaurismaki</ENAMEX> hates <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and directs
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sly</ENAMEX>, funny films. His latest is entirely silent.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 16</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story uses the trial of former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Espy</ENAMEX> to slam the
proliferation of picayune ethics laws. Special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> wield unchecked
power, settle political scores, and waste money. (Espy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Smaltz</ENAMEX>
spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 million</NUMEX> investigating a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,000</NUMEX> transgression.) Once we punished
sleazebags by ostracizing them; now we unnecessarily jail them. ...
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB</ENAMEX>" is skeptical of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> efforts to credit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> with the
current budget surplus. Doesn't that make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> responsible for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX>
recession, too? ... A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>-tapes scandal, a story
ridicules the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s new diversity training. Silly games and animated fables
anger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and stretch racial divides.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 18</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 15</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story laments the disappearance of abortionists. Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> don't learn the
techniques because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) they fear pro-life violence or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) they consider abortion
a low-rent procedure for second-class docs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly two-thirds</NUMEX> of abortion
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 or older</TIMEX>, and some serve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> in multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. ...
A profile cheers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherman Alexie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">essayist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filmmaker</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexie</ENAMEX>'s forthcoming film, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smoke Signals</ENAMEX> (produced, directed,
written by, and starring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Indians</ENAMEX>), depicts reservation life accurately
and touchingly. ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> recounts his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-long</TIMEX> experiment with
not talking on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX>. His weekly silence annoys some but affords him "flashes
of clarity." He also had "the best date of my life!": She did all the
talking.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 15</TIMEX>)
            

            A long
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> describes the pathos of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison rodeo</ENAMEX>. Life-without-parole
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>, for the entertainment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, sustain horrible injuries in
often degrading events (e.g., "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Inmate Poker</ENAMEX>": <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> sit at a table in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ring</ENAMEX>, while a bull is goaded to charge them. The last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX> to stand up
wins.) Despite the pain and humiliation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> love the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">rodeo</ENAMEX> and feel
"free" for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that one day</TIMEX>. ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> recounts his experience as a phone
psychic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Callers</ENAMEX>, overwhelmingly poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of color, think their lives are
entirely pre-scripted and want to be told what to do. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Psychics</ENAMEX> (generally not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">psychic</ENAMEX>) oblige. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> just want someone to talk to. (Cost: more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.00</NUMEX> a minute.) ... From the "Index": "Percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who
believe they are more likely to cheat at cards than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 19</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 13</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Great American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Storyteller</ENAMEX>." Her new novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> , follows black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> venturing
westward after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> says winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> was a bit
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>, as it distracted her from her work. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brent Staples</ENAMEX>' review in

                  Slate
               .) ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story tries to predict
the impact of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> hates communism but, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>, he also loathes heartless capitalism. He will request religious freedom
for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cubans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> hopes for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> coup: If the world's most saintly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> will
deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, why won't the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's scoops: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kaczynski</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have talked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> about avoiding
the death penalty; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaczynski</ENAMEX> wants to get life without parole, he
must cede any right to appeal the sentence. ... Also, a story says
chimps may have better language aptitude than previously thought. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chimps</ENAMEX> can
use word order to determine meaning ("bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>," not
"bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>"). Chimp neologism for a stale pastry: "cookie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rock</ENAMEX>."

            

               Time wonders if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> can be profitable in an e-mail age.
E-mail could steal <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of USPS business by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX>'s ace
in the hole: mountains of desirable marketing data. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
spots a new treatment for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>: The drug
buprenorphine relieves cravings and withdrawal symptoms, but packs only a small
high and is not addictive.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 19</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 13</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story worries that our military needs retraining. Budget
cuts and boring, noncombat peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> are atrophying our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>'
battle-readiness. ... A story cheers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> year in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX> uses immense charm, straight talk, and fluent
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> to get her way. Some criticize her "preoccupation with
image," but others call image-control essential to the job. ... A
package on abortion says <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, but
few talk about it. To remedy that, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> interviews several women
about their experiences (one was raped, another used abortions as birth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>). A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sidebar</ENAMEX> says <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-term</TIMEX> abortions are rare (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> of all cases)
but usually performed for nonmedical reasons.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 19</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 13</TIMEX>)
            

            A piece
says there's not enough evidence to indict <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Revelations: 1</ENAMEX>) Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> may be exhumed to determine whether she was assaulted
with a stun <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> suspect that her death was an
accident, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' real crime was covering it up. The piece praises
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">much-maligned</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder</ENAMEX> District <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Hunter</ENAMEX> for his impartiality, but
admits his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is too soft on punishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. ... An article
describes a new scheme to clean the sacred but polluted <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ganges</ENAMEX>. (It's teeming
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX>, since it's holy to be buried in it.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> propose using
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>-eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">algae</ENAMEX> to disinfect the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. ... Also, a long biography
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Baryshnikov</ENAMEX>. He's turning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> and just returned to the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 1974</TIMEX> defection. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thesis: Dance</ENAMEX> is the
substitute for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that he never really had. (His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> killed
herself when he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 19</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 13</TIMEX>)
            

            A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-story cover package mourns the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 th</NUMEX> anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe vs.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX> : The lead piece claims that abortion will be "the central issue" in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential campaign because the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> will likely have
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> seats to fill, enough to shift the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s balance against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Overturning Roe</ENAMEX> is the only way to restore a "politics of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republican</ENAMEX> self-government ... and moral decency." ... Also, another
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chestnut</ENAMEX>: An article asserts that the death penalty is used too
infrequently. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> have sentenced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> to death but,
thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">obstructionist lawyers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 432</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been executed.
... An article welcomes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Khatami</ENAMEX>'s
conciliatory comments but notes that it's still <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mullahs</ENAMEX> who
really control <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s military and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Best-case scenario: popular
unrest with the mullahs grows, leading to a middle-class democratic
revolution.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 13</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover report exposes a new campaign-finance scandal:
influence-buying in state judicial elections. Interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> fund a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s
campaign, then often appear before that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in court (e.g., "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Maupin</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $80,000</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> and gambling
interests, much of it while ruling favorably on a landmark casino case").
... A dispatch from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX> debunks claims of the welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s death.
Despite severe unemployment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Danes</ENAMEX> still live the good life (great health care,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX> of paid maternity leave, social harmony). Changes: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is
nudging the jobless to work and shifting from income taxes to "green" taxes on
fossil-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> use. ... Also, a letter from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX>
slams the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">treasury secretary</ENAMEX>'s work on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> crisis. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> plan bails out <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, rewards them
with cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> investment opportunities, and throws <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> into an
unnecessary recession.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9</TIMEX>)
            

            A profile
argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> secretly hates politics. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> bred him to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and he does his duty as a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, but he'd rather be doing almost
anything else. The piece reaffirms the cliché that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is a warm, funny guy
behind his wooden exterior. ... An essay wishes the New York
Times would ditch its new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dining In</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fine Arts</ENAMEX>," etc., help
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, and make the paper unwieldy to read. ...
Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair dubs Brown University</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jet-Set Ivy</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Super-rich,</ENAMEX>
super-hip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> (called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Euros</ENAMEX>," even when not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>) drive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraris</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wear Chanel</ENAMEX>, and hit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX> attracts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Ross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Capshaw</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itzhak Perlman</ENAMEX>),
and its grads dominate the music and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>-publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
