
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 16, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The lead
editorial frets over crises in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. The international community
must level sanctions on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> for its nuclear tests, or other near-nuke <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>)
will be tempted to conduct their own tests. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is using the
tests for political gain, because the economy is weak. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front</ENAMEX>, the editorial calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s army
to abandon him and for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> to withhold loans unless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX> steps down. ... An editorial claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is to blame for
the gradual breakdown of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
should stop feebly appeasing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and start making clear, unwavering demands.
... A book review tells the fascinating story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.C. Minor</ENAMEX>, major
contributor to the original <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oxford English Dictionary</ENAMEX> . A schizophrenic,
Minor was in the midst of a delusion when he shot a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. He filed his excellent
entries from a prison-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> for the criminally insane. "He was given <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
cells, one of which he turned into a library and filled with antiquarian books;
he was allowed to practise his flute and paint water-colours; and he was even
allowed a knife, to cut the pages of the old books, although in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> he used
it to slice off his penis."

            

               
                  Details , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 16, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A story
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">profiles Jared Paul Stern</ENAMEX>, promising young gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> for the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's "Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foppishly</ENAMEX> dressed and snottily mannered, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> always
gets his dish--but not without incurring the hatred of seemingly all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.
The piece points out that gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> are generally far more seasoned
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 27-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>'s success in the gossip world is seen by
many not only as an indictment of his moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--surely it should take
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to become this shallow?--but as a maddening violation of the
professional rules."

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
magazine apologizes for having published fabricated articles by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Glass</ENAMEX>
and announces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX>' dismissal as associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. It acknowledges that, as
has been widely reported, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> invented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, and events
in the recent article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hack Heaven</ENAMEX>" and other pieces. How did it happen? "For
reasons known only to him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> mounted what appears to have been quite an
elaborate effort, including the falsification of documents and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX>, to trick our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and elude our fact-checkers." (For more on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uproar</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Houses</ENAMEX>.") ... The cover story notes the growing
irrelevance of college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>. Once, they were revered public
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>; now, they spend <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> their time fund raising and most
of the rest on administration. They don't take high-profile stances for fear of
a backlash. (Full disclosure: 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Greenberg</ENAMEX> wrote the
piece.) ... An article says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are secretly planning a report
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s alleged "illegal collusion" with right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. At a time when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is being compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, the report would be
designed to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> look Nixonian.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 14, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            Another
special issue. Theme: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-olds</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Dozens</NUMEX> of photographs portray neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> in
school, on the family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, on inner city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>, and in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bedrooms</ENAMEX> (all of which are apparently decorated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanson</ENAMEX> posters). Basic
conclusion: Though cliquey, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-olds</TIMEX> are basically nice, innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> (who
really like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanson</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> on going out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>: "You even talk to
them--even if it's just over the phone." 13-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang member</ENAMEX>: "I
ain't down to die right now, for I'm barely having fun. I don't want to die
right now." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>: "I hate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in our grade--they're all so
boring! <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> usually think we're older, and we hang out with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-olds</TIMEX>.
They're just so much fun."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 14, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> profiles socially maladjusted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Forbes Nash Jr. Nash</ENAMEX> took
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> math <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> by storm in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '40s and '50s</TIMEX> and is often
considered the godfather of game theory. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, he succumbed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>, believing himself a "messianic figure of great but secret
importance" and writing cryptic messages, such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Tse-tung</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bar</ENAMEX> Mitzvah
was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 months</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 days</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brezhnev</ENAMEX>'s circumcision." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nash</ENAMEX>
suddenly regained his sanity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '80s</TIMEX> and then won the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Memorial Prize</ENAMEX> in economics.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 18</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 12, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> hoopla allows the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newsweeklies</ENAMEX> to strike a favorite pose: pretending to preach caution while
actually hyping madly. The large print on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover reads "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cancer</ENAMEX>
Cure," while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> puts a huge red <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> through the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cancer</ENAMEX>." Beneath,
they run sober (and nearly identical) small print: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Hope and the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hype--Behind the Latest Breakthroughs</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ; "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How to Tell the Hype</ENAMEX>
From the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Time</ENAMEX> . Their inside stories, too, are cautious, noting
that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-angiogenic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are extremely promising but not a miracle
cure. (Both mags rap the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> for its overenthusiastic
endorsement.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> runs an excellent chart of the various kinds of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> treatments. Requisite Wall Street angle: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> says biotech stocks
are undervalued; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> says they're still too volatile to be reliable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">investments</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> have been meeting secretly with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. Despite pressure from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> refuse to discuss any
specifics about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s meetings with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. ...

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's farewell to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> says that it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) has a much
smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> than many popular sitcoms of the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) is not
the first show "about nothing" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three's Company</ENAMEX> ); and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) is not even the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funniest</ENAMEX> show on television ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Simpsons</ENAMEX> ).

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> likens <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>'s new iMac to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen Beetle</ENAMEX>, saying it's
both fun and functional. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Jobs</ENAMEX> really does seem to have revived <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>,
which has now had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two profitable quarters</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX>. ... Also, a
profanity-laced jail interview with gangsta rap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suge Knight</ENAMEX>. He blames
his imprisonment on rivals jealous of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death Row Records</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 18</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 12, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            Its
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cover concurs with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-angiogenic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> won't work as well in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> as they do in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. It
also explains why human trials of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> can't begin for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a year</TIMEX>:
The current total supply of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is only enough to treat a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>.
... A piece describes the growing conflict between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skinheads</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rappers</ENAMEX>--in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>. Neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skinheads</ENAMEX>, who beat up an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American Marine</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, hate the (slightly) more racially tolerant rappers, who imitate
black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> fashion and music. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX> is being scapegoated for the wrong
reasons. In fact, criminal tax prosecutions are decreasing . Most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s stumbles are caused by outdated computers, not rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 18</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 12, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> profile says he is a moderate, inside-the-Beltway schmoozer, not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torquemada</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> as independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> was vigorous and
effective, but he has been bogged down by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s stonewalling and the decay
of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s original experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX> have been replaced by
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> with little prosecutorial experience. ... A respectful
profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Redford</ENAMEX>--pegged to his new movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Horse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whisperer</ENAMEX> --says he's "wraithlike" and private. But he is responsible for
"some of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most defining contemporary images: the investigative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, the loner, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> of the unregulated outdoors," etc. ...
A piece says major-league <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX> are injuring their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> more frequently
because the mound is too low, the strike zone is too small, and the rise of
other sports (<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>) has diminished the supply of major leaguers
with strong arms.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 18</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 12, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A long
story exposes wrongheaded sexual correctness in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Parker</ENAMEX>,
who sought to be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to fly an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-16</ENAMEX> in combat, complained that her
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air National Guard</ENAMEX> unit mistreated her, ending the careers of many of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>. In fact, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker</ENAMEX> was unqualified to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fly F-16s</ENAMEX>, was given favorable treatment by higher-ups because she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>,
destroyed morale by sleeping with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX>, and herself sexually harassed
male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>. Lesson: The gender wars are undermining military
effectiveness.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Plotz
            

         
      
   
