
   
   
      
         
            

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 9, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Arnault</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX> in charge of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Dior</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Givenchy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Vuitton</ENAMEX>, and other fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> hate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arnault</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American</ENAMEX>" business style (profits over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">politesse</TIMEX>) and disregard for fashion
history (he puts brash young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> in charge of hallowed clothing lines).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arnault</ENAMEX> uses the media buzz of couture shows to sell his real <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moneymakers</ENAMEX>:
perfume and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cosmetics</ENAMEX>. ... A story profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsey McCaughey Ross</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenant governor</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX>, who is now running as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX>. She's eccentric and demanding (she regularly fires
staff), but she's expected to win the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> nomination. No one questions
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCaughey Ross</ENAMEX>' intellect and wonkish understanding of policy. ... An
essay claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> are ushering in a new buzzword in the funeral
industry: choice. Well-made caskets were once the standard of perfection. Now,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> demand custom coffins, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> funerals, and crematory ashes FedExed
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> across the globe.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 7, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
issues, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> puts a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Big Summer Movie</ENAMEX> on the cover--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saving Private Ryan</ENAMEX> . While <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> has always received
realistic treatment on film, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> is only now being portrayed as
complex, gory, and miserable. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s opening, a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-minute</TIMEX> depiction of
D<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-Day</TIMEX>, features exploding limbs, shocking head wounds, and bowels that "ooze"
from a ripped-apart stomach.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story claims we're fed up with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> (despite printing a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time /CNN</ENAMEX> poll showing that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">88 percent</NUMEX> of us find our current insurance
coverage "good" or "very good"). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>' decision not to cover <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> has alerted
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to all the things their plans don't provide. The story urges us to
"speak up, not just to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> but to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> as
well."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> says self-esteem therapy may be bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>. High
self-esteem not justified by achievement can lead to higher aggression levels
when that inflated self-opinion gets challenged.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 7, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story says pro sports are in trouble. Overpaid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that abandon their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, and absurd ticket prices (average NHL ticket:
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40.64</NUMEX>) have angered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> to the point of revolt. With new sports becoming
popular on television (arena <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">X Games</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASCAR</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> have more choices
and less loyalty. ... A story goes behind the scenes with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>,
explaining how they create their front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> chooses
its lead story with exacting care and great pride, seeking input from every
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. Even with television and the Web, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' news judgment
is still the final word for many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>. (For 
                  Slate
               's take on
how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> became a more readable paper, see "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Changelings</ENAMEX>.")

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 7, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A story
claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX> has lost his long battle against modern architecture.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>' architecture <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX> is floundering and ridiculed, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> modernist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">architects</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rogers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Foster</ENAMEX>) are among the most respected in the
world, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handlers</ENAMEX> think his quest makes him look stodgy--a no-no
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. ... An article looks at the movie theater
business. Tickets bring in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just half</NUMEX> of the profits: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Concession</ENAMEX> stands are the
true focus, since they have an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> profit margin. Inside secret:
Theaters salt their food heavily so you'll want to buy more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soft drinks</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 7, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> has already locked up the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> nomination. Despite his centrist stance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has managed to enlist
the support of labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and progressives--essential to winning the
nomination. Why no challenge coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s left? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have decided
there's no chance another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> might win. ... An article describes
the rapid decline of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 million</NUMEX> votes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>,
but now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> has lost all touch. Still focusing on government spending and
the budget deficit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is ignoring the newer concerns of the "angry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">middle</ENAMEX>," such as safe drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and other quality-of-life issues.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 3, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story reviews a new book calling for more
single-child <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. The book argues that only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> receive closer
parental attention and that limiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> will stop environmental decay.
In fact, says the review, only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are no better off than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in big
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, and overpopulation may be an overhyped myth. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in
developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> start having fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> as technology and industry
improve--conditions generally linked with environmental decline. ... A
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> essay says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are too worshipful of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founding Fathers</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. Our nitpicking exegesis of ancient texts limits our
ability to innovate.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
