
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 31</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
should resign if there is even a "shred of truth" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> story, argues
a forceful cover editorial. Regardless of whether he committed any criminal
act, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should quit if he had sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and lied to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> about
it: "It would confirm a clear pattern of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Clintonite</ENAMEX> behavior, one of reckless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">risk-taking</ENAMEX> followed by deceit. ... That is unworthy of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>."
... A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> hints that he could be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>. If he sustains his righteous, conservative image, he'll fare
well in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>. Problem: He's still a dull <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> and
mediocre <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>. ... An article claims that once-secular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">embracing Islam</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> is building the world's largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> in order
to improve his reputation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> world. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> are returning to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> because it's their only relief from poverty, hunger, and
unemployment.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 30</TIMEX>)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX>
stories on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> predicts that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will try to dump <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
quickly if the allegations turn out to be true: They don't want him dragging
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> down to defeat in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998 or 2000</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> did the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will be happy to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cook slowly. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB"</ENAMEX> column says the
essential difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinterngate</ENAMEX> is that while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
may be personally slimy, his entire presidency is not founded on corruption and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deception</ENAMEX>. A piece condemns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> for standing by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. A
supposedly ardent feminist, she has smeared the reputations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accusers</ENAMEX> in order to protect her political power. ... The editorial
endorses a "just war" against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> but worries that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is too tarnished to
lead it.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 29</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story: a look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>'s life, post-trial. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> plays golf <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days a week</TIMEX>,
chats amiably with gawking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> outside his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and thinks he'll be a
star again. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> himself no longer knows if he's
guilty. The piece is the source of the startling, much-repeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> quote:
"Let's say I committed this crime. Even if I did do this, it would have to have
been because I loved her very much, right?" ... A story reports from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwarf convention</ENAMEX> that is the main courting ground for little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dwarf guys</ENAMEX>
complain that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwarf women</ENAMEX> won't date anyone under <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 feet</NUMEX> tall. Fact:
Dwarfs socially stratify each other based on extent of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deformity</ENAMEX>--achondroplastic dwarfs (more proportional, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nondeformed</ENAMEX> faces)
rule the roost. ... 
               Esquire profiles a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. He's not in it for the sex (which is solely for procreation),
he owes on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> mortgages, he's wanted by the law for bigamy (quadragamy?), and
he must remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> birthdays and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> wedding anniversaries in a single
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>. Why does he do it? It's his duty to God. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormon Church</ENAMEX>, which has
outlawed polygamy, excommunicated him.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 29</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
Kongers are increasingly restless about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> rule. As the economic crisis
rattles the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> want a larger voice in running it. The
worry: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> could become like its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> city <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shenzhen</ENAMEX>, which is
capitalist but wild, lawless, and cruel to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. ... A piece
describes the burgeoning market for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> girls: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beautiful</ENAMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> throw
themselves at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> in hopes of becoming kept <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistresses</ENAMEX>. A few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>
have actually moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> to get married. ... The cover story lionizes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Close</ENAMEX>, who manages to paint astonishing Pointillist portraits despite
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">near-total</ENAMEX> paralysis. His work is described as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friendly Art</ENAMEX>," a backlash
against modern art's harshness. Conclusion: He deserves the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400,000</NUMEX> he gets
for each painting because he's such a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> has the better
cover shot: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, wearing a dashing DKNY beret, standing next to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's coverage trumps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's. It publishes an
exhaustive account of the story to date. Its package includes a long, exclusive
excerpt from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> tapes and an essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">once-loyal Clintonite</ENAMEX> distances himself from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>: "Right now, I don't
know whether to be sad, angry, or both. But if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> charges are valid,
I know this: I'm livid." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> also explains its decision to hold
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. Primary reason: The tape <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
heard did not confirm or disprove the obstruction-of-justice allegation.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counters</ENAMEX> with an
evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX>'s take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s zipper problem and a defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>, who first leaked the story. (Full
disclosure: 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> wrote the Drudge
defense.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's main article emphasizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
reaction: While Bill crashed on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX>, she went into overdrive.

            In both
magazines: an examination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s legal case, a map of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> diagraming what (allegedly) happened where, a profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, a profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>, and an armchair analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
apparent sex compulsion.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News finishes a distant <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>: Its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> coverage lacks diagrams, legal
analysis, and juicy tidbits. The cover image--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> superimposed on a
shadowy photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>--is wan. An essay says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is blowing the scandal out of proportion,
and an article wonders how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> endures her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s infidelity.
(The theory: "Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is unfaithful, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> considers those who would
use that to ruin his political career as the really bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>. Not her Bill.")
... An article claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> fraud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crooks</ENAMEX>, bilk the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> per year. Phony
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> file false bills, and the system is so big that no one
notices. ... A survey on mutual funds warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fidelity</ENAMEX>, once a powerhouse, is
now merely average. The survey also advises <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to consider moving money
from stocks to bonds.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27</TIMEX>)
            

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
news: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>/book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucianne Goldberg</ENAMEX> describes her as
adventurous, aggressive, and rather amoral--a "seasoned Bond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>." Why did
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> get involved? "Because it's fucking fascinating. I love dish!" She
denies a rumor that she had an affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) A piece claims
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of the scandal. He may lose his job,
reputation, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>; the star-gazing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, by contrast, found fame and
power. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) In the "we never thought we'd read that in The 
               New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> " category, a story wonders whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will be remembered as the
" 'pussy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>.' " ... A long piece about fat condemns virtually all
popular diets (especially the high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, low carb ones). Weight depends more
on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and a chemical called leptin than on food intake. Good news for the
obese: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> believe they are close to understanding and controlling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leptin</ENAMEX>. ... Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> prints <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Hughes</ENAMEX>'
much-discussed new poems about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sylvia Plath</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27</TIMEX>)
            

            The
general theme of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> coverage: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s presidency is over. The editorial
argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has forfeited the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> chance <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> gave him in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.
He's now proved himself "pathological," "unbalanced," and "compulsive." He has
a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of infinite deception and self-deception." A piece urges
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to use this time of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> paralysis to push through their agenda,
especially a ban on partial-birth abortions and a tax cut. An article says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case will scare "many potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Deans</ENAMEX>" into coming forward and
revealing more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Clintonian</ENAMEX> crimes. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> warns that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> is going to win the current standoff with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>:
Even if we launch airstrikes, he will preserve his chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and his
hold on power. The only satisfactory option: A ground invasion that
deposes/kills him.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
