
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 11</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 11</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
editorial wonders if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citicorp</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelers</ENAMEX> merger
benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Financiers</ENAMEX> may be "mistaking size for profitability."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is indifferent to the merger's impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. ... An
editorial decides that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> recession, even a drastic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, will affect
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> economies very little. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> exports to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> count
for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 1 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> GDP, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> imports count only for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX>. The real danger to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy is Wall Street: The market
seems horribly overvalued, and a crash would be devastating now that so many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> invest there. ... The obituary remembers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Athelstan Spilhaus</ENAMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>," who died at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">86</NUMEX>. Spilhaus designed the weather balloon
that crashed in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roswell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.M.</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>, sparking <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">UFO</ENAMEX> conspiracy theories that
still fester.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 10</TIMEX> )

            The cover
story suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>' drastic shift towards social conservatism is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insincere</ENAMEX> and opportunistic. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aspirant</ENAMEX> has changed his
views in order to win over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religious Right</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that hounded him in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>). It's working. ... A story predicts the next tax revolt: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">self-employed workers</ENAMEX> pay twice as much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> tax, can't
deduct health insurance costs, file taxes several times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, and are
routinely audited. They're angry and they're not going to take it anymore.
... An article explains our forgiveness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alleged sins.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has positioned himself as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>" (strong, empathic, kind),
so we've rallied around him as we would a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> in crisis.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 9</TIMEX>)
            

            A piece
profiles an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX> tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX> whose nightmare of a job
mostly involves shutting down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> in arrears. He has been attacked with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, knives, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, and hurled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. Tip--"[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]f you're seizing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, do
it early in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>: 'You don't want to interrupt someone's lunch, make a big
thing out of it.' " ... The cover story fawns over <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoshio Taniguchi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of the design competition for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Art</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taniguchi</ENAMEX>'s quiet, thorough style (steeped in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> modernism)
beat out more flamboyant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrants</ENAMEX>. His design so subtly integrates its
additions that it hardly seems to change the existing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>. ... Also,
yet another article exploring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>'s growing unease with its actions
during and after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> still fail to face the moral crimes
they committed (e.g., laundering <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> gold and shunning terrified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">refugees</ENAMEX>) to maintain neutrality.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 7</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> run identical
cover photos ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> zooms in) for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> cover stories.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case may be stronger than it
looks, reporting that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX> "spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> in a hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> story broke and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Frank
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, who helped prepare her denial of a
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>) may have to turn over documents and testify--a
"significant" exception to attorney-client privilege. Also, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
Stephanopoulos essay urges <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to "step forward and tell us everything
about his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> lays out
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s probable strategy: The independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> will indict
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as an unindicted co-conspirator, likely forcing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prez</ENAMEX> to testify. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> also offers a sidebar on scandal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">profiteers</ENAMEX>,
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penthouse</ENAMEX> , and her book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Steele</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7,000</NUMEX> for selling a
photo to the National 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> ).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> , always
dedicated to useful advice, tells "When to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spank</ENAMEX>": A quick slap to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s wrist or buttocks is effective and not
emotionally damaging, as long as it is accompanied by a clear lesson and
explanation. ... A long article in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> enters the terrifying world of the
yakuza , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> organized-crime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">syndicates</ENAMEX>. Growing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> investment
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> may soon lead to a confrontation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakuza</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, who are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times more numerous than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Mafiosi</ENAMEX>,
hand out business cards with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> names printed on them and frequently sport
amputated pinkies ("cut to atone for a misdeed").

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's optimistic spin of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> 's success: It's not
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">inspiring Hollywood</ENAMEX> to make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> action blockbusters, it's inspiring
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> to make movies targeted at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 7</TIMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> begins <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its millennium</TIMEX> project with a special issue on
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leaders & Revolutionaries</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century</ENAMEX>." ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's
project will culminate in an issue ranking the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>.)
Among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> profiled in this issue: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX> (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiesel</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> (by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salman Rushdie</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Sanger</ENAMEX> (by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloria Steinem</ENAMEX>), and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Johnson</ENAMEX>). A sidebar ranks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoover</ENAMEX> last) and excerpts some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>'s greatest speeches (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLK</ENAMEX>, etc.). ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
snags an exclusive interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>:
"I think the evidence there is also compelling that her story isn't true. I
feel comfortable." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>: "I won't depart from my policy of not
commenting on Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 7</TIMEX>)
            

            A "Talk
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Town</ENAMEX>" item says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> may move its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nightly</TIMEX> news into <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">prime time</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westin</ENAMEX>, the top choice to replace the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roone Arledge</ENAMEX> as head of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
News, thinks <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX> news could draw an audience <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times larger than
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early-evening</TIMEX> news currently draws. ... An article on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s race notes the emergence of--groan--"socket moms." These affluent,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tech</ENAMEX>-savvy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are libertarian on social and economic issues but believe
government must do more for education and training. Gubernatorial candidate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Harman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, is their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">standard-bearer</ENAMEX>, as well as the most
charismatic of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. (Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Checchi</ENAMEX>, may spend
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> of his own money on the race.) ... A profile calls
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX> a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Spice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX>." She has transformed herself from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hardhearted Machiavelli</ENAMEX> to sassy political comedienne. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> love her
because she's a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> gossip.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 7</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vidal</ENAMEX> (under the halfhearted pseudonym "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.V."</ENAMEX>) rails against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abigail Thernstrom</ENAMEX>'s anti-affirmative-action <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
as "the worst history book of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>." The high-dudgeon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vidal</ENAMEX> offers personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anecdotes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abigail Thernstrom</ENAMEX>, at a dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, defended the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney King</ENAMEX> beating) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rehashes</ENAMEX> familiar arguments for affirmative action.
(The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thernstroms</ENAMEX> discussed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Race in America</ENAMEX>" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall Kennedy</ENAMEX> in a

                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>.")

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
