
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Event
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">69 th Academy Awards</ENAMEX>
               . The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> production budget and
performances by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celine Dion</ENAMEX> apparently were not enough to make this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar night memorable</ENAMEX>. Even a "semi-spontaneous tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad Ali</ENAMEX>
couldn't rescue the festivities," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Lowry</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . Redeeming features included the return of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of ceremonies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal</ENAMEX> and his "repeated relief from the pretentiousness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presenters</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shales</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Yu</ENAMEX>'s crack that her <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>'s
outfit cost more than her <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar-</ENAMEX>winning documentary; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Helfgott</ENAMEX>'s
performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rimsky-Korsakov's</ENAMEX> Flight of the 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bumblebee</ENAMEX> . (See
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Week/The Spin</ENAMEX>"
for more on the results.)

            

               Art
            

            
               "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biennial Exhibition"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum of American Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).
Usually the most controversial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> show in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s
much hyped selection of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two years</TIMEX> is deemed
smart but overly polite. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Stevens</ENAMEX> says "this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">biennial</TIMEX> is
rife with safe curatorial decisions and art that has already been widely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">certified</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kimmelman</ENAMEX> says the exhibit
reflects nothing less than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of contemporary art: derivative and
self-conscious. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX>'s site.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Willem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Kooning</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904-1997</TIMEX>). Obituaries of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> pronounce his death the
end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX>: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he almost terminally <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Warholized American</ENAMEX> art world loses ...
a link with its last heroic--indeed, its last sincere--grand style" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
Plagens, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). Critics also seize the opportunity to weigh in again
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Kooning</ENAMEX>'s late work, currently on exhibit at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>.
"These are among the saddest things ever made by a once-major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Kooning</ENAMEX>'s late work.)

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liar Liar</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). The latest comedy by smirkmeister
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ace Ventura</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pet Detective</ENAMEX> ), currently the No. 1 film at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">box</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, is deemed his most conventional movie yet. Carrey, playing a sleazy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> forced to tell the truth for a day, "removes the rubber nose and plays a
realistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita Kempley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). But the film
still relies on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carrey</ENAMEX>'s "kamikaze elan" to overcome its meager premise ("[a]
one joke movie"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszczyna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). And <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shadyac</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Nutty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> ) blunders in choosing, midfilm, "to calm down the proceedings,
[so that] our poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> is reduced to saying therapeutic things like ...'You
know, this truth stuff is pretty cool.' " (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liar Liar page</ENAMEX> is good for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> bashing, and serves
up stills and clips.)

            

               
                  Crash
                (Fine Line Features). Despite the ruckus surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cronenberg</ENAMEX>'s adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.G. Ballard</ENAMEX>'s novel Crash --the movie was
banned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and won a special prize at <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX> for "originality, daring,
and audacity"--it fails to shock. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX> calls the
quasipornographic narrative of car-crash <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> who go on to have a lot of
sex while driving "sexual without being sexy." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lane</ENAMEX>
calls it boring and pretentious: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Crash</ENAMEX> are so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unsmiling</ENAMEX>--so driven, in every sense--that they make you ashamed of ever having
enjoyed yourself." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cronenberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballard</ENAMEX> should not even get credit for coming
up with a novel idea, says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and women
who make TV commercials have sensed the connection between <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> and
eroticism for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>." (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luc Sante</ENAMEX>'s
review of the film in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. Crash's Web site deserves its NC-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> rating.)

            

               
                  Selena
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lukewarm</ENAMEX> reviews for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Norte</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Nava</ENAMEX>'s reverential biopic about the slain <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tejano</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>. Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">praise Nava</ENAMEX> for giving the film the same crossover appeal as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selena</ENAMEX> herself.
Others damn it as formulaic. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boilerplate</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> '
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, pointing out that the flashbacks are cheesy, the characters
stock, and the themes, such as the subplot about unrequited love, tired. (See
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bros.</ENAMEX>' site for the film. Also check out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kerr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jared Hohlt</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life and Art"</ENAMEX> column in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  The
Godfather
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX>). Once again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> declare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Ford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX>'s masterwork (re-released on its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 th</NUMEX> anniversary) the
quintessential <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> epic. "Every scene is weighted, emotionally
significant, resplendent with the thick texture of feeling and history," writes
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denby</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , however, pursues the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revisionist</ENAMEX> line. Cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Rothstein</ENAMEX> attacks the film's central
metaphor--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> as metaphor for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>--as untenable.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Haskell</ENAMEX> says the film "demeans and demotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> outrageously."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX> plugs the re-release on its site.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  The
Coming Conflict with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross H. Munro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bernstein</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> agree with the premise of this get-tough-on-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> polemic but
think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> bureau <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX>, go overboard with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
War rhetoric. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kagan</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' mild
policy prescriptions won't solve the problems they shrilly decry. If anything,
their book only makes things worse, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orville Schell</ENAMEX> in the New York
Times : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Munro</ENAMEX> "have unrepentantly plunged harpoons into the
tenderest interstices of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese-American</ENAMEX> relationship."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Radical Son: A Journey Through Our Times</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Horowitz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free</ENAMEX>
Press). The memoir of this former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Black Panthers</ENAMEX> turned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scourge</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Left</ENAMEX> draws cheers and jeers from predictable quarters. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Podhoretz</ENAMEX> compares <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horowitz</ENAMEX>'s conversion to conservatism to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whittaker Chambers</ENAMEX>' magisterial tale of apostasy, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Witness</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Leftists</ENAMEX>
dismiss the book as score-settling and name-calling. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas von Hoffman</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horowitz</ENAMEX> wastes "much too much space ...
calling his former radical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborators cowards</ENAMEX> and poltroons."

            

               Updates :

            After a
barrage of vicious pans, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> defend The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kiss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX>'s incest memoir. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Cheever</ENAMEX> says "the book brilliantly, heartbreakingly" lays out
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX>'s helplessness. Also see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luc Sante</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hey, Wait a Minute</ENAMEX>" in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX> attributes the Harrison hype to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywoodization</ENAMEX> of publishing. He quotes an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> who says, "We all know
that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX>"--who is highly photogenic--"were a dumpy-looking lady
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>-bottle glasses, none of this would have happened." ... The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Schwartz</ENAMEX> deems "irresponsible" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rhodes</ENAMEX>'
"apocalyptic" predictions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Deadly</ENAMEX>
Feasts that mad-cow disease could kill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX>.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns:
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Return of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Special Edition</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of</ENAMEX>
Industry ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antony</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleopatra</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novellas</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Leavitt</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Deadly
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Feasts: Tracking the Secrets of a Terrifying New Plague</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodes</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Resurrection:</ENAMEX>
The Struggle for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Russia</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Remnick</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three-Arched Bridge</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismail Kadare</ENAMEX>, translated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hodgson</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Private
Parts ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Jungle 2</ENAMEX>
Jungle ;

            
Thing Happened on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Way</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss: A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Memoir</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giovanni</ENAMEX>'s
Gift , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradford Morrow</ENAMEX>;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exiles</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Émigrés</ENAMEX>: The Flight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Artists</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>";

            

               Television -- The Practice .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Donnie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brasco</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smilla</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sense of Snow</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Helfgott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Tour</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crisis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Feds</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arsenio</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- Just
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shoot Me</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crazy</ENAMEX>
Rhythms: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All That Jazz</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Garment</ENAMEX>;

            
               Books --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Novel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roundup</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- The Last Night of Ballyhoo</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>
Strikes Back: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Special Edition</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Lost</ENAMEX>
Highway ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rosewood</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schindler</ENAMEX>'s List ;

            
               Television -- Miss
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boys</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Monster:</ENAMEX>
Living <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Off the Big Screen</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gregory Dunne</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Sphinx: The Character of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph J. Ellis</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whittaker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Tanenhaus</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX> .

            
               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
