
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  Behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winning the Presidency</ENAMEX> in the Nineties
               ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> bash him, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>'s entire life has been a dalliance with prostitution.
As a professional, he was an amoral whore; as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, he
was done in by the thing itself; then there's Behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> .
"The book is priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-eighth</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry Rowlands</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX>
fee--and ... will give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> a chance to peddle his wares," notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> . Ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hominems</ENAMEX> are the order of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>'s problems began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX>. Like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> he was born," says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte Hays</ENAMEX>. The book is said to have its uses,
however. "It is a ... revealing book," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX>, though only unintentionally. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' descriptions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s temper
tantrums, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX>, make them sound like "the kind normally associated
with autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--except in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s case they are overlaid with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-righteousness</ENAMEX> and megalomania." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX> is just about the book's only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>: "We owe it to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX>, whose
book is lively, readable and anecdotally rich, for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX>'s account of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> the game is played." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> skewers the book in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. Also, check out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> for the book, which includes an excerpt.)

            

               Movie
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whole Wide World</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> see this biopic
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert E. Howard</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Conan the Barbarian</ENAMEX> stories, as an
occasion to wax confessional, particularly on the subject of the writing life:
"It's rare to see the basic conditions of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s existence--the solitude,
the panic, the neediness, the unhealthy self-absorption--portrayed so starkly,"
says The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence Rafferty</ENAMEX>. The film "touches on
things of the mind and of the heart: writing, cultural hunger in rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>,
the roots of violence in art, the mystery of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>," says the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>. Not everyone is charmed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Dauphin</ENAMEX> complains that the film is mired in sentimental
cutesiness: "I can dig the urge to know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conan</ENAMEX>'s bulging biceps,
but I don't know if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wide World</ENAMEX> 's annoying, nutjob-cum-romantic-misfit
take on the subject was what I, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX>, or the world really needed."

            

               Event
            

            
               The
Inauguration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jefferson Clinton</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>). Expectations
were low--<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> inaugurals are not supposed to top the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>--but reviews are
negative nonetheless. Rhetorically, the speech is deemed to have been
unsuccessful. Presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Leuchtenburg</ENAMEX> was quoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdum</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> as saying that it was the "most banal
address by an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> I have ever heard." The problem, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Purdum</ENAMEX>,
was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> spent too much time "pouring <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over</NUMEX> past Presidential
speeches and anthologies of poetry." The upside was the speech's
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">uncharacteristic brevity--22 minutes</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw</ENAMEX>. Reviews of
inaugural pomp (appearances by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessye Norman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Banderas</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hootie</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blowfish</ENAMEX>, as well as a parade) range from outrage at the
"unseemly excess" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX>) to boredom, though
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>'s rendition of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Amazing Grace</ENAMEX>" was praised in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> as
"stirring." Television coverage struggled to make something out of nothing,
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shales</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> of live historical events appear to think they are
making documentaries about the events rather than transmitting them into
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>." (For more reactions to the inaugural, see the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatches</ENAMEX>"
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> and Karenna
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  One
World, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ready or Not: The Manic Logic of Global Capitalism</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. Greider</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). The latest manifesto from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Will Tell the People?</ENAMEX> ) condemns the globalization
of markets and leads <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> to reconsider their own enthusiasm for free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Greider</ENAMEX> brings "the global economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX> to life in all its splendor
and horror" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Miller</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). The passion of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">polemic</ENAMEX> recalls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rousseau</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter Russell Mead</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affairs</ENAMEX> ). But few are persuaded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greider</ENAMEX>'s conclusions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> have
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> main complaints: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) his shoddy economics (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) his tired
prescriptions--regulation, taxation, and protectionism; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) his continued
bashing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Board</ENAMEX> (a repetition of the theme of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">799</NUMEX>-page
Secrets of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> ). "This is a book that graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coffeehouse dissidents</ENAMEX> everywhere will enjoy," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mead</ENAMEX>. (Also, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Judis</ENAMEX>'
favorable review in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.)

            

               CD
            

            
               
                  Idomeneo
               , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart</ENAMEX>, performed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Placido Domingo</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera Orchestra</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chorus</ENAMEX>, conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Levine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche Grammophon</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Placido Domingo</ENAMEX>'s appearance "on the package, compellingly photographed in
costume as the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King of Crete</ENAMEX>," (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Tommasini</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ) is the main selling point for this new recording of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX>'s
more obscure operas--a fact that does not make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> happy. "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domingo</ENAMEX> is
no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozartean</ENAMEX>," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tommasini</ENAMEX>. "He misses some of the lightness and agility
demanded by florid passages." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> agree that the recording
succeeds--in spite of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domingo</ENAMEX>, and in spite of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Levine</ENAMEX>'s "overblown
conducting" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Blyth</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> )--mainly because of the
cast, which includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soprano</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecilia Bartoli</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Hampson</ENAMEX>. "[F]rom the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moment Cecilia Bartoli</ENAMEX>'s vibrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idamante</ENAMEX> arrives on stage, the performance
takes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>, her luscious, tight vibrato perfectly capturing the adolescent
trauma of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Pappenheim</ENAMEX>.

            

               Movie
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albino Alligator</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>). Has the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tarrantino</ENAMEX> crime flick
lost its charm? Reviews of the latest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> suggest the answer is yes. Critics
are unimpressed with first-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Academy Award-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spacey</ENAMEX>'s attempts at stylishness, particularly the relentless allusions to film
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">noir</ENAMEX>. The movie "reeks of film-student overkill" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszczyna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> ). It would only be allowed to "ooz[e] out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">storeroom</ENAMEX>" in
the otherwise fallow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month of January</TIMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX>
Taubin: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]ts devices are too shopworn to allow for a personal or original
point of view." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> says the film works
precisely because it is derivative--its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Dillon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>
Sinise, emulate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in The Usual 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Suspects</ENAMEX> , which gives
them "extraordinary opportunities to preen." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>'s
site for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albino Alligator</ENAMEX> has video and stills.)

            

               Television
            

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naked</ENAMEX>
Truth
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> canceled this sitcom <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> revived it and
put it in the slot after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> and before <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> wonder
whether the show can live up to its scheduling. Will its star, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tea</ENAMEX> Leoni
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flirting With Disaster</ENAMEX> ), "blossom into this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucille Ball</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bianculli</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> )? Are her comic skills on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">par</ENAMEX> with her sex appeal? ("[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hen</ENAMEX> she does a wobbly fall in a tight skirt and
heels, it's like the moment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bambi</ENAMEX> when the little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> fumbles and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skitters</ENAMEX> across a patch of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Tucker</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> .) Or is the show dreary and cliché-ridden? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caryn James</ENAMEX> calls the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> episode "dangerously <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shales</ENAMEX>, in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> has recycled garbage and gotten only new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">garbage</ENAMEX> in return." He suggests another title: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Ugly Truth</ENAMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> plugs the show at its site.)

            

               Updates
            

            In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poetry James Fenton</ENAMEX>
attacks The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Adam Gopnik</ENAMEX> for attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>'s biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso and for attacking Picasso</ENAMEX> himself. "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the long skirt with the cloche hat, doling out these white feathers to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> of the past, and hitting them over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with his parasol, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gopnik</ENAMEX>. ... As so often with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gopnik</ENAMEX>, the bad style leads the sense by the
nose." ... <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In The</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Wills</ENAMEX>, a classicist by
training, praises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Fagles</ENAMEX>' translation of The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odyssey</ENAMEX>
("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fagles</ENAMEX> is the best living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX> of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> drama, lyric poetry,
and epic into modern <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, and [ The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odyssey</ENAMEX> ] ... is his finest
work so far"). He attributes its success to feminism or, more specifically, to
"its entry into the psychological subtlety with which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX> presents <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>."
... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Terzian</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cronkite</ENAMEX>'s memoirs: "Anyone tempted to romanticize the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> people
should be reminded that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly twenty years</TIMEX>, 'the most trusted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>' was a TV news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> with a mustache and mellifluous baritone named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Cronkite</ENAMEX>."... Despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Globes</ENAMEX>, Evita
racks up more bad reviews. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kauffmann</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>: "She can sing, though there are too many times when she asks her
country not to cry for her. She can't act."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns:
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">La Cérémonie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MK2 Productions/Prokino Filmproduktion</ENAMEX>); The
Prospect <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Before Her: A History of Women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1500-1800</TIMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olwen Hufton</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>); and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tokyo International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Viñoly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beavis and Butt-Head Do America</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slouching</ENAMEX> to
Gomorrah: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Liberalism</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Decline</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ReganBooks/HarperCollins</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Politically Incorrect With Bill Maher</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">weeknights</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:05 a.m.</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>); Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother's Son</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Rock</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christian Dior</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Man Who Made the World</ENAMEX>
Look New , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie-France Pochna</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joanna Savill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arcade</ENAMEX>); and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yves Saint Laurent</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Rawsthorn</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nan A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talese/Doubleday</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evita</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood Pictures</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Portrait of a Lady</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gramercy</ENAMEX>);
Life of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>, Volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1907-1917</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Richardson</ENAMEX>, with the
collaboration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn McCully</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>); Once Upon a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattress</ENAMEX>
(The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadhurst Theatre</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>); and The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odyssey</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Fagles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin</ENAMEX>'s
Room (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New Fowler's Modern English Usage</ENAMEX> , edited by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.W. Burchfield</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford University Press</ENAMEX>); A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cronkite</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alias Grace</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Atwood</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nan A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talese/Doubleday</ENAMEX>); and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Whistle Down the Wind</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Theatre</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>).

            
               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
