
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Feb. 7</TIMEX>)
            

            A
cover editorial pegged to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visit argues
that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> are not as similar as they seem. While they share
broad principles (fiscal responsibility, free trade, etc.) and political
tactics (artful repackaging of conservative ideas), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> is much more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">left-wing than Clinton</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> is much more left-wing than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> has banned all handguns and favors <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s national
health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>, policies that would be inconceivable for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
... A piece dampens enthusiasm about recent rises in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s stock
markets: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economies are still in dire shape and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> are not doing
nearly enough to restore fiscal stability. ... Also, a long survey on
Central <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. Conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> and chaos.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 6</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
package reiterates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> 's line that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should try to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overthrow Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> piece argues that anything short of toppling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> would be pointless: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> will be recalcitrant till he falls. (It also
notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> don't favor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military intervention
nearly as much as they did during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>: We'll have to go it alone.)
Another article says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should not limit itself to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombing</ENAMEX> (the current battle plan): Only a long, insistent air campaign will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persuade Saddam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to attempt a coup. ... A story mocks a
right-wing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-hating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restore the Presidency</ENAMEX> to
Greatness: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> predicted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> would announce that
he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilma Clinton</ENAMEX>") during a guest appearance on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> .

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb. 5</TIMEX>)
            

            Would-be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Hoffa</ENAMEX> is a pale imitation of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, argues the
cover profile. Hoffa fils shares his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s virulent
anti-federal-government streak, but he lacks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>'s fire, organizing skill, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">toughness</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffa</ENAMEX> will likely win the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> election, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> is
too weakened by corruption and too bullied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and the feds to be the
force it once was. ... A survey of suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> finds they are
tolerant of atheists, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of other races, working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>--everyone but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>. Reason: They consider homosexuality an active choice. If they believed
homosexuality was innate, they'd tolerate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>, too. ... A photo essay
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">depicts Dzerzhinsk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, the world's "least-habitable," most-polluted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
Once the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> chemical-weapons production, it has a reservoir of
toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waste</ENAMEX> called the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Sea</ENAMEX>." Life expectancy for its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47 years</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42 years</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 3</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week 2</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Secret Sex Wars</ENAMEX>"; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time's</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. Inside both
magazines: maps of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX> in the alleged "right-wing
conspiracy" against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, profiles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> (steely-eyed in this time of crisis), and
still more pop-psychologizing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s personality.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's package
tracks the "secret war" behind the scenes, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>,
and private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives</ENAMEX> labor to contain bimbo eruptions. It runs several new
pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, including two that are embarrassingly revealing. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> says other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> might turn to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX> for
stability while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> reels. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> is calm and confident. A piece argues that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> should stop reporting on the scandal because the public has spoken in
favor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Wag the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Levinson</ENAMEX> writes that
his movie was just a joke but compares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s allegation of a
right-wing conspiracy to the distraction ploys found in the film.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> depicts him as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overzealous</ENAMEX>, and nerdy. In junior high, "his hobby was polishing shoes," says
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> also wonders how the scandal will affect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. From <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> 10-year-old
pundit: "I would rather see happy news. About <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX>." A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
rundown of how the scandal played across the world includes these words from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Great leaders</ENAMEX> are very good at sex: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleopatra</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genghis Khan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Napoleon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Zedong</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is also a capable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, so it is
normal for him to be very good at sex." ... Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essay</ENAMEX> makes the case for human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cloning</ENAMEX>. The risk is small,
and cloning could benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's disease</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX>, and severe
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">burns</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 3</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
package on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s swift comeback asserts that a right-wing conspiracy does exist, though it is less monolithic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> suggests. An essay claims the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> wields too much power:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s current investigation is an unconstitutional invasion of privacy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Psychiatrist Peter Kramer</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Listening</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX> ) says the same
qualities that make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> (risk-taking, abundant energy,
and narcissism) make him a likely womanizer. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> finds
a new marketing ploy for classical music: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mediaeval</ENAMEX> Baebes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">perform Gregorian</ENAMEX> chants, wear flimsy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garb</ENAMEX>, and chat about all things gothic.
Just like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>, each baebe has a nickname. (Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dragon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baebe</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9</TIMEX>

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 3</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' marriage is "stupefyingly weird" but founded on genuine passion,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">affection</ENAMEX>, and respect, argues a piece. She's not loyal for cold political
reasons, she's loyal because she " 'literally decides that she believes him.' "
... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> publishes a reconstructed image of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kennewick Man</ENAMEX>, the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9,000-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caucasoid</ENAMEX> skeleton found in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. (He is evidence
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucasians</ENAMEX> settled <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Indians</ENAMEX>.) Based on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">clay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kennewick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> looked like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Stewart</ENAMEX>. ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karla Faye Tucker</ENAMEX>, the pickax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> scheduled for execution <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">profiled</ENAMEX>. Once a drug-addled, vicious "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Tough Guy</ENAMEX>," she is now smart,
sweet, good, and truly religious. (For more on the story, see what the international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are saying.)

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 3</TIMEX>)
            

            A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-story, glee-filled cover package. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cover</ENAMEX> headline: "Yow!"; cover image:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as a centaur, cavorting with naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> lawn.) A
piece proposes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s best-case "alternative narrative": He bonded with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> over her unhappy childhood and gave her career advice; she became
obsessed with him and sent him gifts; he tried to help her while gradually
pushing her away. The problem with the story: It's not credible, given
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sexual history. ... <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> gushed about "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintonism</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> offers its own
definition (pegged to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX>): "Clintonism transforms your most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parochial</ENAMEX> worries into matters of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>," dealing with picayune issues rather
than genuine ones. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintonism</ENAMEX> lite"--is just as vapid.
... An article upbraids some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> for their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX>
foreign policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Libertarians</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> should stop wasting money on imperial
power, and cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> should stop exporting its
horrible values to the rest of the world. They're both wrong, says the
Standard .

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 3</TIMEX>)
            

            
               The
Nation shrugs about the scandal. General takes: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The sex was consensual.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> is corrupt and ideological. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The punditocracy is ignoring
the real story (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Grand Inquisition</ENAMEX>) in favor of salacious sex. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is payback for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s real sins--the destruction of social welfare
and support for the death penalty. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ex</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>,
who wrote a piece in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> about the need
to renew <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s social compact, writes a piece about the need
to renew <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s social compact. While <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is prosperous, we should
reduce inequality, strengthen public education, etc.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
