
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Chamoiseau</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose-Myriam R√</ENAMEX>©jouis
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Val Vinokurov</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pantheon</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamoiseau</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> novel, newly translated from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, wins him instant canonization and comparisons to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel Garc√</ENAMEX>≠a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M√°rquez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">V.S. Naipaul, Salman Rushdie</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michel de Montaigne</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This 150-year</TIMEX>
history of a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinique</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> garnered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prix</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goncourt</ENAMEX>. It earns praise for having restored grittiness to the whimsical
tradition of magical realism. And its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creole</ENAMEX>-inflected language is described as
"prose saturated in a kind of bemused gorgeousness" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bernstein</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX> dissents, calling
Chamoiseau too self-conscious, "a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C√</ENAMEX>©line who has read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L√</ENAMEX>©vi-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strauss</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Derrida</ENAMEX>.
... His narrative ... flows sluggishly, molasses flecked with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX> of sugar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cane</ENAMEX>."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">America: The Politics of Celebrity</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Wills</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). A universal pan for the hyper-prolific cultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>'s latest book. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wills</ENAMEX>' analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayne</ENAMEX> as a cultural icon is deemed
pretentious, long-winded, and jargon-filled. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of</ENAMEX>
Books , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wood</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wills</ENAMEX> resorted to "a bundle of rather weary
paradoxes: the lost but unforgettable frontier, the wilderness which is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>'s favorite dream." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excerpts</ENAMEX> of the book are available here.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Divorce Culture</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Dafoe Whitehead</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). Harsh words from
across the ideological spectrum for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitehead</ENAMEX>'s attack on divorce and the
permissive culture that tolerates it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX>
says her scholarship rates no higher than the "the popular 'expert opinion' and
self-help books she rightly criticizes." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talbot</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitehead</ENAMEX> and other "divorcephobes" ignore <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s history of
liberal divorce laws, the economics of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the workplace, and common
sense: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX> who make each other's lives a snarling misery probably won't
make their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s lives a bower of happiness." Even the conservative
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> faults <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitehead</ENAMEX> for shoddy scholarship and pop
psychology. (For more debate on divorce, see the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Blankenhorn</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sons</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heaven Meet the Daughters of the Earth</ENAMEX>
               , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernanda Eberstadt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eberstadt</ENAMEX>'s sendup of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> art world of the
1980s is pronounced a success. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roxana Robinson</ENAMEX>
says the novel--about an <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper West Side</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">patroness</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> painter
hailed as the "white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Basquiat</ENAMEX>"--has fun with "philosophical questions": "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where</ENAMEX>
is the useful intersection between art and commerce? How corrosive is fame?
What is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outsider Art</ENAMEX>, anyway<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Allen</ENAMEX> likes
the book, but complains that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eberstadt</ENAMEX>'s tone becomes "overly messianic": It
sometimes reads like a "pitch against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX>."

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Own</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>). Production problems and bad advance
press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boded</ENAMEX> ill for the latest thriller from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan J. Pakula</ENAMEX> ( All the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> ). Multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> tried their hand at the script, which
star <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX> publicly attacked. But the consensus is that the film emerges
solid--if uninspired--with grace notes of moral complexity. The friendship
between an honest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX>) and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terrorist</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX>) eschews the "black-and-white formulas" typical of suspense
films, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence Rafferty</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, finds the premise "an
astonishingly banal male-bonding motif." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Devil</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Own</ENAMEX> home page.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chasing Amy</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Smith</ENAMEX>'s low-budget romantic
comedy--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> in a series that began with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clerks</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>)--wins favor
for introducing a twist into the familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>-meets-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> plot--here, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> meets
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lesbian</ENAMEX>. "As obstacles in the course of true love go, that's fairly major,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafferty</ENAMEX>. The film is a "devastating critique of the hetero male ego,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . The direction, however, is dismissed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafferty</ENAMEX> as "amateurish." (Miramax
serves up stills and clips.)

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  The
Young <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man From Atlanta</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Longacre Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>). Mixed reviews for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> debut of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horton Foote</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> Prize-winning play. Critics
applaud performances by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rip Torn</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Larry Sanders Show</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX> as a middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> mourning their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s death: "They get
all the small regional footnotes of gesture and inflection just right. But
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> also convey the sense of an internal furnace of pain and anxiety
that gives <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fevered</ENAMEX> glow to such minutiae" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). However, the play itself is found wanting. Says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX>, "There's good down-home, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX>-fried atmosphere ... but where
the hell is the play?"

            

               Updates:
            

            In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Judt</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>'s claim in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whittaker Chambers</ENAMEX> attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alger Hiss</ENAMEX> because of spurned
gay love "a smear, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990s</TIMEX> style. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX>'s contemptible insinuations are a
reminder that there is nearly always something provincial and self-serving
about the response of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whittaker Chambers</ENAMEX>."...
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tatyana Tolstaya</ENAMEX> praises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Remnick</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resurrection</ENAMEX>, a book about post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, as "a satirist
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gogolian</ENAMEX> persuasion; he combines the grotesque with the lyrical."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns:
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:</TIMEX>

            
               Event -- The 69th
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy Awards</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1997 Biennial</ENAMEX>
Exhibition" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum of American Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willem de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kooning</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904-1997</TIMEX>);

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Liar</ENAMEX>
Liar ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Crash</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Selena</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The Coming
Conflict with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross H. Munro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bernstein</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Radical Son: A Journey Through Our Times</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horowitz</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Return of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Special Edition</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of</ENAMEX>
Industry ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antony</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleopatra</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novellas</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Leavitt</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Deadly
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Feasts: Tracking the Secrets of a Terrifying New Plague</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodes</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Resurrection: The Struggle</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Russia</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Remnick</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three-Arched Bridge</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismail Kadare</ENAMEX>, translated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hodgson</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Private
Parts ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Jungle 2</ENAMEX>
Jungle ;

            
Thing Happened on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Way</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss: A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Memoir</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giovanni</ENAMEX>'s
Gift , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradford Morrow</ENAMEX>;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exiles</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">√âmigr√©s</ENAMEX>: The Flight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Artists</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>";

            

               Television -- The Practice .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Donnie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brasco</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smilla</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sense of Snow</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Helfgott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Tour</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crisis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Feds</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arsenio</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- Just
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shoot Me</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crazy</ENAMEX>
Rhythms: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All That Jazz</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Garment</ENAMEX>;

            
               Books --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Novel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roundup</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- The Last Night of Ballyhoo</ENAMEX> .

            
               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
