
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Books

            

            

               
                  Underboss: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sammy the Bull Gravano's Story of Life</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>
               ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Maas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX>). Critical and commercial success for the
biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gravano</ENAMEX>, "the most famous snitch in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mob</ENAMEX> history," who brought down
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teflon Don" Gotti</ENAMEX>, offed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and ordered his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brother-in-law</ENAMEX>'s execution. Drawing on extensive interviews with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull</ENAMEX>, it
is a "brilliantly constructed and grimly fascinating ... morality play on the
subject of loyalty" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Westlake</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ).
Though it retreads tired observations about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> life, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Underboss</ENAMEX> still
enriches the "portrait of a subculture some of us can't get enough of" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Handy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). (HarperCollins plugs the book.)

            
               
                  The
Actual: A Novella
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Bellow</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX>). The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">81-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s
latest is admired as a "mature work": same old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bellovian</ENAMEX> subject (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> man
brooding over a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>), but a more subdued, elegiac tone. Almost everyone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lavishes</ENAMEX> praise on the book, not minding the absurdities they find in the plot
(such as the emergence of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">92-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trillionaire</ENAMEX> who befriends the brooding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>). "The Actual is not a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s piece of fiction. ... It is
instead something far more rare: the work of a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> still locked in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">unequal</ENAMEX> combat with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eros</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Begley</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review</ENAMEX> . "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellow</ENAMEX> writes now with as much authority and energy as he did
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century ago</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Roseanne</ENAMEX>
                (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m. EDT/PDT</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX>'s finale after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine seasons</TIMEX> leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers unimpressed</ENAMEX>, but it occasions encomiums for the
show's working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grit</ENAMEX>. "The most groundbreaking kitchen-sink sitcom since
All in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Family</ENAMEX> ," declares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Tucker</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> .
Most agree, however, that the show declined in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last years</TIMEX>, especially after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> won the lottery and the family forsook its proletarian
roots--while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> herself mutated from caustic social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> into pop
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">icon</ENAMEX>. "A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne Conner</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caryn James</ENAMEX>,
"was as bizarre as the conspicuous physical makeover that no one in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conner</ENAMEX>
family ever mentioned." (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> for the
show. Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Doyle</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatches</ENAMEX>" on sweeps month.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Blaine</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Street Magic</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 19</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m. EDT/PDT</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blaine</ENAMEX>,
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hipster magician</ENAMEX> with a goatee and no fancy equipment, is
proclaimed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performer</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Copperfield</ENAMEX>. "Instead of
ornate props and gorgeous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">showgirls</ENAMEX>, he shares his act lovingly with ordinary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John O'Connor</ENAMEX> in the New York
Times . But many find an average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performer</ENAMEX> behind the populist hype. "Corny
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card tricks</ENAMEX> and coin feints and levitation stunts [updated] with post-grunge
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chic</ENAMEX>," declares <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Handelman</ENAMEX>, adding that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blaine</ENAMEX>'s best magic
trick may be his own career." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s site asks: "Is he
an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Entertainer, a Con man, the Devil, or a Guru?</ENAMEX>")

            

               Event
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cannes</ENAMEX>
International <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Film Festival</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>). Complaints about <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX>' overwrought
glitz subside during the festival's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. It "reasserted its claim to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">seriousness</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Credit</ENAMEX> is given to
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palme d'Or</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Taste of Cherries</ENAMEX> , about
suicide; and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Eel</ENAMEX> , about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who murdered his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. Still,
some whining lingers. "The quintessential <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes fortnight</ENAMEX>, indeed, would
involve no films at all--just invitations to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> that never happen and
rumors of films that will never be made," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lane</ENAMEX>. (See the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" entry for <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first week</TIMEX>.)

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Night Falls</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> mostly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dismiss Serpico</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Lumet</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> st film as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hackwork</ENAMEX>. Rehashing his favorite subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> police corruption,
Lumet slaps together, they say, an implausible plot (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> after law school,
an ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> becomes a crusading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district attorney</ENAMEX>), formulaic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> (bad-ass
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>, idealistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>), and preachy moralizing. ("The
predictable lesson--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> isn't cut and dry--clogs the film's gears," says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Brace</ENAMEX>.) Among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lumet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angles Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Thomas</ENAMEX>, who says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> makes the unlikely
plot twists believable "the old-fashioned way: through interaction with a
screen full of strongly drawn, fully dimensioned, psychologically valid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>."

            

               
                  Love! Valour! Compassion!
                (Fine Line Features). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Terrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNally</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tony-</ENAMEX>winning play from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX> gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who vacation together
doesn't translate well to film, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say. They regard the adaptation, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stars Seinfeld</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shlub</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Alexander</ENAMEX>, as a "stodgy affair" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elliott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> ). And the hypercampy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> feel like
relics of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX> when gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were routinely lampooned--"more The

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Band than a gay Big Chill</ENAMEX> ," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX> of
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, in
dissent, extols the film's "richly nuanced" performances and its "intense mood
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chekhovian</ENAMEX> sadness." (A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> is available here.)

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wizard of Oz</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Square Garden</ENAMEX>). Outraged cries of "what were they
thinking?" greet this stage adaptation (starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne as the Wicked Witch</ENAMEX>
of the West) of the classic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX> movie. A "charmless, surprisingly chintzy
affair" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Evans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> ), the play features a script eviscerated of
interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sets</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Munchkinland</ENAMEX> that consists of wooden
cutouts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>-bottle vases, for example--would be "unimpressive even for a
cost-cutting resident theater." "If it only had a brain," wishes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Marks</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .

            

               Updates
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason & Dixon</ENAMEX> amasses more raves, notably from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menand</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T. Coraghessan Boyle</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book</ENAMEX> 
               Review . Writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boyle</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dixon</ENAMEX> is a groundbreaking book, a book of heart and fire and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, and
there is nothing quite like it in our literature, except maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V.</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gravity</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rainbow</ENAMEX> ."... The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jed Perl</ENAMEX> attacks
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Adam Gopnik</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Kimmelman for their elitist attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s popularity. "If they are frequently just plain hostile
to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>, it could be because they are annoyed at the thought that the public
doesn't really need a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX>'s help."

            Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">14:</TIMEX>

            
               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amsterdam Theater</ENAMEX>;

            
               Event --<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX>
International <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Film Festival</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s
Day ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifth</ENAMEX>
Element ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Designated Mourner</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odyssey</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courage</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stand Alone: Letters From Prison and Other Writings</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei Jingsheng</ENAMEX>,
translated and edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristina M. Torgeson</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Time Bind:</ENAMEX>
When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Becomes Home and Home Becomes Work</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlie Russell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hochschild</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Candide</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newseum</ENAMEX>.

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dixon</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Pynchon</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Television</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Visions: The Epic History of Art in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Visions</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward</ENAMEX> Just;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reading</ENAMEX> in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seamus Deane</ENAMEX>;

            

               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- The
Last <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Don</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Children of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Breakdown</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Volcano</ENAMEX> ;

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michele</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Reunion</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop</ENAMEX> -- Share My
World , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary J. Blige</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Locked in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Anything
Your <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Heart Desires: An American Family Story</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosworth</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hystories</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hysterical Epidemics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Media</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Showalter</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Titanic</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The
Little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Foxes</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Dance --"In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honor of the Divine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Harrison</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Morris Dance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">23:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gospel</ENAMEX>
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Son</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Pastoral , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Roth</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.B. Yeats</ENAMEX>:
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apprentice Mage</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865-1914</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.F. Foster</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Purple</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Moody</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloaming</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- The Ring of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nibelung</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Murder at</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1600</TIMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Kissed</ENAMEX> .

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
