
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  Con
Air
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Touchstone Pictures</ENAMEX>). This action flick, about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rogues</ENAMEX>' gallery
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> who hijack a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>, is deemed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>-blockbuster overkill: too many
ridiculous plot twists, too many explosions, too much ripping off of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predecessors</ENAMEX>. It is "so monumentally idiotic, frenzied and cheesy--the special
effects look like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tonka</ENAMEX> toys writ large--that it re-sets the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genre</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>. Reviewers split
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas Cage</ENAMEX>. He either "emerges intact from the rubble" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ) or proves "he can be as much of an overmuscled
jackass as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edelstein, Slate</ENAMEX>). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the
Con <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gold</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orion Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Fonda</ENAMEX>'s comeback--as a stoic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beekeeper</ENAMEX> facing down his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convict son</ENAMEX>'s thuggish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>--is called his first
worthy performance since <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Easy Rider</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>). "[A]fter all this time, a
role that suits his rocklike demeanor perfectly and makes virtues of his
expressive limitations" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence Rafferty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). Slow-paced
and minimalist, the film is hailed as an anti-blockbuster: It "achieves a rare,
and rarely earned, emotional depth ... ennobling and enriching without being
sticky or sanctimonious" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd McCarthy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> ). (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orion</ENAMEX>'s promotional site.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pillow Book</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinepix Film Properties</ENAMEX>). The latest from avant-garde
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Greenaway</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Cook, the Thief, His Wife & Her</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lover</ENAMEX> ) elicits a familiar critique: It's judged a visual knockout but
pretentious as hell. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say the movie, about a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s
peculiar fetish, has lots of gorgeous naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> but little plot or character
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>. A "cold, contemptuous, and interminable Oedipal saga," says the
Village <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J. Hoberman</ENAMEX>, "just a big, static snooze." The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, says the "audaciously
beautiful imagery, captivating symmetries and brilliantly facile tricks" redeem
the film.

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wu-Tang Forever</ENAMEX>
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wu-Tang Clan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCA/Loud</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> predict that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Staten Island</ENAMEX> rap <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>-track double CD--released along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wu-Wear</ENAMEX>,
a clothing line--will mark a breakthrough for hip-hop, as both hype and art.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wu-Tang Clan</ENAMEX> has entered the "stagnant hip-hop scene like a slap in the
face, parading its strikingly original gutter funk like a ghetto peacock" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diehl, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> admire the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s eclectic
influences--including funk, flamenco, and psychedelic--and its lyrics, "as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dense</ENAMEX>, obsessed, prolific and full of popular and arcane references as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pynchon</ENAMEX> novel" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Strauss</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Clips</ENAMEX> are available
here.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Without a Doubt
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Clark</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Carpenter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> don't seem to mind that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>'s angry memoir--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> No. 1 best seller--adds little to the vast body of literature
about the trial. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> do. "As her title suggests, self-reflection and an
appreciation of ambiguity are not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Clark</ENAMEX>'s strong points," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Willis</ENAMEX>
writes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> . The dead prose style, adds
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dana Kennedy</ENAMEX>, "reads as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> had dictated it
from her car phone." To the dismay of still others, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> neither confirms nor
denies the rumor that she and fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Darden</ENAMEX> slept
together.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Firewall: The Iran-Contra Conspiracy and Cover-Up</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence E.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.W. Norton</ENAMEX>). Too much minutiae, not enough revelations is the consensus
criticism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra Special Prosecutor</ENAMEX>'s chronicle of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year</TIMEX>
investigation. Wanting still to win the case, he rehashes arcane and forgotten
episodes from the Reagan-era scandal seemingly for his own benefit. "The leaden
account ... feels like it goes on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>). Only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Ireland</ENAMEX> finds merit in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX>'s brief
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> "a genuine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Promiscuities: The Secret Struggle for Womanhood</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Wave feminist</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> book--part memoir, part
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sociology</ENAMEX>, part political tract--gets praised for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lyrically</ENAMEX> rendered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anecdotes</ENAMEX> and slammed for shoddy thinking. The part about her sexual
coming-of-age in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> fares reasonably well. "[S]he melts together the
personal and political so gently we're barely aware of the difference," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Shapiro</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s politics are roundly ridiculed,
especially her idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> should retreat to the wilderness with older
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to perform ceremonial sex rites. "[S]he tries in vain to pass off tired
observations as radical aperçus, subjective musings as general truths, sappy
suggestions as useful ideas," writes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' Michiko
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kakutani</ENAMEX>.

            

               Theater
            

            

               
                  Gross <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Indecency: The Three Trials of Oscar Wilde</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minetta Lane</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). Applause for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this off-off</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> play (written by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moisés Kaufman</ENAMEX>, an unknown gay <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Venezuelan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dramatist</ENAMEX>), which finally hits the
big time. Rescued from obscurity <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months ago</TIMEX> by a rave from the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gross Indecency</ENAMEX> , about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">playwright</ENAMEX>'s famous <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">sodomy</ENAMEX> trials, started an open-ended <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> run last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. The play recounts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s downfall, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Patrick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stearns</ENAMEX>, "with the inevitability and much of the monumentality of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
tragedy." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX>, the lone sniper, says the play deserved
to languish in obscurity because of its "annoying cuteness."

            

               Updates
            

            In one of
the most scathing reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> book to date, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Gordon</ENAMEX> asks: "How can
someone who has published so much, some of it admirable, have written such a
bad book? A book whose badness leaves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> first with a sense of
reluctance (must I really go on?), then anger (how can he let himself get away
with this?), then embarrassment (it is unseemly to cast my eyes on such a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spectacle</ENAMEX>)." ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Praise</ENAMEX> continues to escalate for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Pastoral</ENAMEX> . In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post Book World</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Rifkind</ENAMEX> calls it "possibly the finest work of his career."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Trial and
Error ;

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dance Floor</ENAMEX>--HIStory in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mix</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock & Roll</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">VH1</NUMEX>);

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- Race, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crime</ENAMEX>,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Law</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall Kennedy</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
Woolf , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hermione Lee</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Kowloon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tong</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Theroux</ENAMEX>;

            
               Event -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
Awards;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Objects of Desire: The Modern Still Life"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern</ENAMEX>
Art).

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">28:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Lost</ENAMEX>
World ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Addicted to</ENAMEX>
Love ;

            
               Movie -- Brassed
Off ;

            
               Television -- Murder
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- King
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music -- Flaming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pie</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che Guevara</ENAMEX>:
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revolutionary Life</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Lee Anderson</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Rage</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fame</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Ascent of Clare Boothe Luce</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvia Jukes Morris</ENAMEX>;

            

               Art --<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galleries</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>).

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">21:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Underboss</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sammy the Bull Gravano's Story of Life</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Maas</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The Actual: A
Novella , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Bellow</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blaine: Street Magic</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Event --<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX>
International <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Film Festival</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Night Falls</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Love</ENAMEX>!
Valour! Compassion! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">;</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- The Wizard of Oz</ENAMEX> .

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">14:</TIMEX>

            
               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amsterdam Theater</ENAMEX>;

            
               Event --<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX>
International <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Film Festival</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s
Day ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifth</ENAMEX>
Element ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Designated Mourner</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odyssey</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courage</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stand Alone: Letters From Prison and Other Writings</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei Jingsheng</ENAMEX>,
translated and edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristina M. Torgeson</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Time Bind:</ENAMEX>
When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Becomes Home and Home Becomes Work</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlie Russell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hochschild</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Candide</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newseum</ENAMEX>.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
